{"question": "Q: ((7 - -1 + -1 + -4) - (-7 + 7 * 3 * -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 - -1 + -1 + -4) and B = (-7 + 7 * 3 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -1 + -1 + -4) = (((7 - -1) + -1) + -4) = ((8 + -1) + -4) = (7 + -4) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + 7 * 3 * -9) = (-7 + ((7 * 3) * -9)) = (-7 + (21 * -9)) = (-7 + -189) = -196.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (3 - -196) = 199.\n(Final response) So the answer is 199.", "correct_answer": "199", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 184, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 * 3 - -7) + (-9 * -6 + -3)) - ((2 + 6 * -2) + (4 * -4 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C + D))\", where A = (7 * 3 - -7), B = (-9 * -6 + -3), C = (2 + 6 * -2) and D = (4 * -4 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 3 - -7) = ((7 * 3) - -7) = (21 - -7) = 28.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -6 + -3) = ((-9 * -6) + -3) = (54 + -3) = 51.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + 6 * -2) = (2 + (6 * -2)) = (2 + -12) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * -4 * 5) = ((4 * -4) * 5) = (-16 * 5) = -80.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C + D)) = ((28 + 51) - (-10 + -80)) = (79 - (-10 + -80)) = (79 - -90) = 169.\n(Final response) So the answer is 169.", "correct_answer": "169", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 434, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-6 + 0 - -6) * (1 * 7 + 3)) + ((3 + 9 * -6) - (1 + 6 * 8))) + (((0 + -5 + 5) - (-5 * -4 * -7)) + ((8 * 2 * -3) + (-8 * 3 - 0)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C - D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-6 + 0 - -6), B = (1 * 7 + 3), C = (3 + 9 * -6), D = (1 + 6 * 8), E = (0 + -5 + 5), F = (-5 * -4 * -7), G = (8 * 2 * -3) and H = (-8 * 3 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 0 - -6) = ((-6 + 0) - -6) = (-6 - -6) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 7 + 3) = ((1 * 7) + 3) = (7 + 3) = 10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + 9 * -6) = (3 + (9 * -6)) = (3 + -54) = -51.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + 6 * 8) = (1 + (6 * 8)) = (1 + 48) = 49.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 + -5 + 5) = ((0 + -5) + 5) = (-5 + 5) = 0.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-5 * -4 * -7) = ((-5 * -4) * -7) = (20 * -7) = -140.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 * 2 * -3) = ((8 * 2) * -3) = (16 * -3) = -48.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 * 3 - 0) = ((-8 * 3) - 0) = (-24 - 0) = -24.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C - D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((0 * 10) + (-51 - 49)) + ((0 - -140) + (-48 + -24))) = ((0 + (-51 - 49)) + ((0 - -140) + (-48 + -24))) = ((0 + -100) + ((0 - -140) + (-48 + -24))) = ((0 + -100) + (140 + (-48 + -24))) = ((0 + -100) + (140 + -72)) = (-100 + (140 + -72)) = (-100 + 68) = -32.\n(Final response) So the answer is -32.", "correct_answer": "-32", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 257, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 * 3 + -6) * (-2 + 7 * -6)) - ((-4 - -6 + 6) * (4 * -4 + 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-9 * 3 + -6), B = (-2 + 7 * -6), C = (-4 - -6 + 6) and D = (4 * -4 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 3 + -6) = ((-9 * 3) + -6) = (-27 + -6) = -33.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 7 * -6) = (-2 + (7 * -6)) = (-2 + -42) = -44.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - -6 + 6) = ((-4 - -6) + 6) = (2 + 6) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * -4 + 8) = ((4 * -4) + 8) = (-16 + 8) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-33 * -44) - (8 * -8)) = (1452 - (8 * -8)) = (1452 - -64) = 1516.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1516.", "correct_answer": "1516", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 123, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 * 9 * 4) * (-2 * 8 - 9)) * ((-7 + 9 * 5) - (-4 - 2 * -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (2 * 9 * 4), B = (-2 * 8 - 9), C = (-7 + 9 * 5) and D = (-4 - 2 * -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 9 * 4) = ((2 * 9) * 4) = (18 * 4) = 72.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * 8 - 9) = ((-2 * 8) - 9) = (-16 - 9) = -25.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + 9 * 5) = (-7 + (9 * 5)) = (-7 + 45) = 38.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - 2 * -4) = (-4 - (2 * -4)) = (-4 - -8) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((72 * -25) * (38 - 4)) = (-1800 * (38 - 4)) = (-1800 * 34) = -61200.\n(Final response) So the answer is -61200.", "correct_answer": "-61200", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 355, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * -9 + 4 + 1) - (-2 * 8 * -9 * 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (5 * -9 + 4 + 1) and B = (-2 * 8 * -9 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * -9 + 4 + 1) = (((5 * -9) + 4) + 1) = ((-45 + 4) + 1) = (-41 + 1) = -40.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * 8 * -9 * 6) = (((-2 * 8) * -9) * 6) = ((-16 * -9) * 6) = (144 * 6) = 864.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-40 - 864) = -904.\n(Final response) So the answer is -904.", "correct_answer": "-904", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 198, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 * -3 - 6 - -2 + -1) - (3 + -6 + 2 + -8 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (2 * -3 - 6 - -2 + -1) and B = (3 + -6 + 2 + -8 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * -3 - 6 - -2 + -1) = ((((2 * -3) - 6) - -2) + -1) = (((-6 - 6) - -2) + -1) = ((-12 - -2) + -1) = (-10 + -1) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + -6 + 2 + -8 + 8) = ((((3 + -6) + 2) + -8) + 8) = (((-3 + 2) + -8) + 8) = ((-1 + -8) + 8) = (-9 + 8) = -1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-11 - -1) = -10.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10.", "correct_answer": "-10", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 83, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 * -2 + 7 - 7) - (0 + -9 + -7 - -3)) + ((-5 + 6 - -7 * 0) - (-7 * 4 * -6 - 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (2 * -2 + 7 - 7), B = (0 + -9 + -7 - -3), C = (-5 + 6 - -7 * 0) and D = (-7 * 4 * -6 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * -2 + 7 - 7) = (((2 * -2) + 7) - 7) = ((-4 + 7) - 7) = (3 - 7) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -9 + -7 - -3) = (((0 + -9) + -7) - -3) = ((-9 + -7) - -3) = (-16 - -3) = -13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 + 6 - -7 * 0) = ((-5 + 6) - (-7 * 0)) = (1 - (-7 * 0)) = (1 - 0) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 * 4 * -6 - 1) = (((-7 * 4) * -6) - 1) = ((-28 * -6) - 1) = (168 - 1) = 167.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-4 - -13) + (1 - 167)) = (9 + (1 - 167)) = (9 + -166) = -157.\n(Final response) So the answer is -157.", "correct_answer": "-157", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 523, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 + 0 + -3) + (5 * 0 + 1)) - ((-8 * 3 * 0) * (5 - -9 - 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-3 + 0 + -3), B = (5 * 0 + 1), C = (-8 * 3 * 0) and D = (5 - -9 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 0 + -3) = ((-3 + 0) + -3) = (-3 + -3) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * 0 + 1) = ((5 * 0) + 1) = (0 + 1) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * 3 * 0) = ((-8 * 3) * 0) = (-24 * 0) = 0.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - -9 - 8) = ((5 - -9) - 8) = (14 - 8) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-6 + 1) - (0 * 6)) = (-5 - (0 * 6)) = (-5 - 0) = -5.\n(Final response) So the answer is -5.", "correct_answer": "-5", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 360, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * 0 - 8) - (-4 - -4 - 3)) - ((-3 + 5 + -9) + (-7 - -2 - -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (3 * 0 - 8), B = (-4 - -4 - 3), C = (-3 + 5 + -9) and D = (-7 - -2 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 0 - 8) = ((3 * 0) - 8) = (0 - 8) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - -4 - 3) = ((-4 - -4) - 3) = (0 - 3) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + 5 + -9) = ((-3 + 5) + -9) = (2 + -9) = -7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -2 - -6) = ((-7 - -2) - -6) = (-5 - -6) = 1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-8 - -3) - (-7 + 1)) = (-5 - (-7 + 1)) = (-5 - -6) = 1.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1.", "correct_answer": "1", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 325, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - -4 - 4 - 3 + -5) + (1 * -8 + -8 - -3 + -6)) - ((6 - -4 + -9 + 6 * 7) + (-4 - -2 * -6 + -3 * -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C + D))\", where A = (1 - -4 - 4 - 3 + -5), B = (1 * -8 + -8 - -3 + -6), C = (6 - -4 + -9 + 6 * 7) and D = (-4 - -2 * -6 + -3 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -4 - 4 - 3 + -5) = ((((1 - -4) - 4) - 3) + -5) = (((5 - 4) - 3) + -5) = ((1 - 3) + -5) = (-2 + -5) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -8 + -8 - -3 + -6) = ((((1 * -8) + -8) - -3) + -6) = (((-8 + -8) - -3) + -6) = ((-16 - -3) + -6) = (-13 + -6) = -19.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - -4 + -9 + 6 * 7) = (((6 - -4) + -9) + (6 * 7)) = ((10 + -9) + (6 * 7)) = ((10 + -9) + 42) = (1 + 42) = 43.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -2 * -6 + -3 * -9) = ((-4 - (-2 * -6)) + (-3 * -9)) = ((-4 - 12) + (-3 * -9)) = ((-4 - 12) + 27) = (-16 + 27) = 11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C + D)) = ((-7 + -19) - (43 + 11)) = (-26 - (43 + 11)) = (-26 - 54) = -80.\n(Final response) So the answer is -80.", "correct_answer": "-80", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 182, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 + -6 - 9) - (-5 + 3 - 9)) + ((0 * 0 - -2) + (-6 - 2 - -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-3 + -6 - 9), B = (-5 + 3 - 9), C = (0 * 0 - -2) and D = (-6 - 2 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + -6 - 9) = ((-3 + -6) - 9) = (-9 - 9) = -18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + 3 - 9) = ((-5 + 3) - 9) = (-2 - 9) = -11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * 0 - -2) = ((0 * 0) - -2) = (0 - -2) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - 2 - -3) = ((-6 - 2) - -3) = (-8 - -3) = -5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-18 - -11) + (2 + -5)) = (-7 + (2 + -5)) = (-7 + -3) = -10.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10.", "correct_answer": "-10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 320, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * 7 - 9 - -8) - (-5 * -6 - 7 * -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (9 * 7 - 9 - -8) and B = (-5 * -6 - 7 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 7 - 9 - -8) = (((9 * 7) - 9) - -8) = ((63 - 9) - -8) = (54 - -8) = 62.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -6 - 7 * -6) = ((-5 * -6) - (7 * -6)) = (30 - (7 * -6)) = (30 - -42) = 72.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (62 - 72) = -10.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10.", "correct_answer": "-10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 247, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 + 3 + -8 + -8) * (8 - -5 * -9 * 7)) - ((5 - 5 * -2 - 6) - (-7 + -5 + 2 + -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (3 + 3 + -8 + -8), B = (8 - -5 * -9 * 7), C = (5 - 5 * -2 - 6) and D = (-7 + -5 + 2 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + 3 + -8 + -8) = (((3 + 3) + -8) + -8) = ((6 + -8) + -8) = (-2 + -8) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - -5 * -9 * 7) = (8 - ((-5 * -9) * 7)) = (8 - (45 * 7)) = (8 - 315) = -307.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 - 5 * -2 - 6) = ((5 - (5 * -2)) - 6) = ((5 - -10) - 6) = (15 - 6) = 9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + -5 + 2 + -9) = (((-7 + -5) + 2) + -9) = ((-12 + 2) + -9) = (-10 + -9) = -19.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((-10 * -307) - (9 - -19)) = (3070 - (9 - -19)) = (3070 - 28) = 3042.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3042.", "correct_answer": "3042", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 530, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 - -8 * -5 - 2 + 9) + (-3 - 7 + 1 + 3 + 3)) * ((-2 - 1 + -3 - -2 - 4) * (-7 - 8 - -7 - 8 + -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (4 - -8 * -5 - 2 + 9), B = (-3 - 7 + 1 + 3 + 3), C = (-2 - 1 + -3 - -2 - 4) and D = (-7 - 8 - -7 - 8 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - -8 * -5 - 2 + 9) = (((4 - (-8 * -5)) - 2) + 9) = (((4 - 40) - 2) + 9) = ((-36 - 2) + 9) = (-38 + 9) = -29.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - 7 + 1 + 3 + 3) = ((((-3 - 7) + 1) + 3) + 3) = (((-10 + 1) + 3) + 3) = ((-9 + 3) + 3) = (-6 + 3) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 - 1 + -3 - -2 - 4) = ((((-2 - 1) + -3) - -2) - 4) = (((-3 + -3) - -2) - 4) = ((-6 - -2) - 4) = (-4 - 4) = -8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - 8 - -7 - 8 + -2) = ((((-7 - 8) - -7) - 8) + -2) = (((-15 - -7) - 8) + -2) = ((-8 - 8) + -2) = (-16 + -2) = -18.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((-29 + -3) * (-8 * -18)) = (-32 * (-8 * -18)) = (-32 * 144) = -4608.\n(Final response) So the answer is -4608.", "correct_answer": "-4608", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 183, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 + 7 + 7) - (-8 - -5 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 + 7 + 7) and B = (-8 - -5 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 7 + 7) = ((7 + 7) + 7) = (14 + 7) = 21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - -5 + -9) = ((-8 - -5) + -9) = (-3 + -9) = -12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (21 - -12) = 33.\n(Final response) So the answer is 33.", "correct_answer": "33", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 16, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 + 7 - 4 - -1) + (1 - 5 + 1 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (2 + 7 - 4 - -1) and B = (1 - 5 + 1 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + 7 - 4 - -1) = (((2 + 7) - 4) - -1) = ((9 - 4) - -1) = (5 - -1) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - 5 + 1 + 8) = (((1 - 5) + 1) + 8) = ((-4 + 1) + 8) = (-3 + 8) = 5.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (6 + 5) = 11.\n(Final response) So the answer is 11.", "correct_answer": "11", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 38, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 + 3 + 5 + 3) - (1 * -2 - 6 * 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 + 3 + 5 + 3) and B = (1 * -2 - 6 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 3 + 5 + 3) = (((1 + 3) + 5) + 3) = ((4 + 5) + 3) = (9 + 3) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -2 - 6 * 1) = ((1 * -2) - (6 * 1)) = (-2 - (6 * 1)) = (-2 - 6) = -8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (12 - -8) = 20.\n(Final response) So the answer is 20.", "correct_answer": "20", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 290, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 + 0 + 2 - -3) + (2 * -9 * 5 - -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (0 + 0 + 2 - -3) and B = (2 * -9 * 5 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + 0 + 2 - -3) = (((0 + 0) + 2) - -3) = ((0 + 2) - -3) = (2 - -3) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * -9 * 5 - -3) = (((2 * -9) * 5) - -3) = ((-18 * 5) - -3) = (-90 - -3) = -87.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (5 + -87) = -82.\n(Final response) So the answer is -82.", "correct_answer": "-82", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 31, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 * -5 - 2) + (3 + 7 * 5)) - ((2 - -6 + 2) * (7 - 7 * 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-4 * -5 - 2), B = (3 + 7 * 5), C = (2 - -6 + 2) and D = (7 - 7 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -5 - 2) = ((-4 * -5) - 2) = (20 - 2) = 18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + 7 * 5) = (3 + (7 * 5)) = (3 + 35) = 38.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - -6 + 2) = ((2 - -6) + 2) = (8 + 2) = 10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 - 7 * 7) = (7 - (7 * 7)) = (7 - 49) = -42.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((18 + 38) - (10 * -42)) = (56 - (10 * -42)) = (56 - -420) = 476.\n(Final response) So the answer is 476.", "correct_answer": "476", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 132, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((6 - -4 - -9 + 1 * -7) - (-5 * -4 - -2 - 3 * 0)) * ((-4 - -7 - -9 - 1 - -7) + (1 + 1 - 6 + -3 * -1))) + (((-3 + -9 - 0 + 4 - 1) - (5 * -3 * 8 * -8 + 4)) + ((8 * 8 * -1 * 5 + 2) - (0 - -8 * -1 + 7 - 1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C + D)) + ((E - F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (6 - -4 - -9 + 1 * -7), B = (-5 * -4 - -2 - 3 * 0), C = (-4 - -7 - -9 - 1 - -7), D = (1 + 1 - 6 + -3 * -1), E = (-3 + -9 - 0 + 4 - 1), F = (5 * -3 * 8 * -8 + 4), G = (8 * 8 * -1 * 5 + 2) and H = (0 - -8 * -1 + 7 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -4 - -9 + 1 * -7) = (((6 - -4) - -9) + (1 * -7)) = ((10 - -9) + (1 * -7)) = ((10 - -9) + -7) = (19 + -7) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -4 - -2 - 3 * 0) = (((-5 * -4) - -2) - (3 * 0)) = ((20 - -2) - (3 * 0)) = ((20 - -2) - 0) = (22 - 0) = 22.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - -7 - -9 - 1 - -7) = ((((-4 - -7) - -9) - 1) - -7) = (((3 - -9) - 1) - -7) = ((12 - 1) - -7) = (11 - -7) = 18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + 1 - 6 + -3 * -1) = (((1 + 1) - 6) + (-3 * -1)) = ((2 - 6) + (-3 * -1)) = ((2 - 6) + 3) = (-4 + 3) = -1.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-3 + -9 - 0 + 4 - 1) = ((((-3 + -9) - 0) + 4) - 1) = (((-12 - 0) + 4) - 1) = ((-12 + 4) - 1) = (-8 - 1) = -9.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 * -3 * 8 * -8 + 4) = ((((5 * -3) * 8) * -8) + 4) = (((-15 * 8) * -8) + 4) = ((-120 * -8) + 4) = (960 + 4) = 964.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 * 8 * -1 * 5 + 2) = ((((8 * 8) * -1) * 5) + 2) = (((64 * -1) * 5) + 2) = ((-64 * 5) + 2) = (-320 + 2) = -318.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (0 - -8 * -1 + 7 - 1) = (((0 - (-8 * -1)) + 7) - 1) = (((0 - 8) + 7) - 1) = ((-8 + 7) - 1) = (-1 - 1) = -2.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C + D)) + ((E - F) + (G - H))) = (((12 - 22) * (18 + -1)) + ((-9 - 964) + (-318 - -2))) = ((-10 * (18 + -1)) + ((-9 - 964) + (-318 - -2))) = ((-10 * 17) + ((-9 - 964) + (-318 - -2))) = ((-10 * 17) + (-973 + (-318 - -2))) = ((-10 * 17) + (-973 + -316)) = (-170 + (-973 + -316)) = (-170 + -1289) = -1459.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1459.", "correct_answer": "-1459", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 309, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 * 0 - -6 + -4) - (-4 + 7 - 1 - 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (3 * 0 - -6 + -4) and B = (-4 + 7 - 1 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 0 - -6 + -4) = (((3 * 0) - -6) + -4) = ((0 - -6) + -4) = (6 + -4) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 7 - 1 - 9) = (((-4 + 7) - 1) - 9) = ((3 - 1) - 9) = (2 - 9) = -7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (2 - -7) = 9.\n(Final response) So the answer is 9.", "correct_answer": "9", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 57, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * 9 + -1 * -8) * (-3 * -4 + 5 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-9 * 9 + -1 * -8) and B = (-3 * -4 + 5 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 9 + -1 * -8) = ((-9 * 9) + (-1 * -8)) = (-81 + (-1 * -8)) = (-81 + 8) = -73.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * -4 + 5 * -3) = ((-3 * -4) + (5 * -3)) = (12 + (5 * -3)) = (12 + -15) = -3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-73 * -3) = 219.\n(Final response) So the answer is 219.", "correct_answer": "219", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 183, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 - -4 * -7) + (-8 * 6 * 6)) + ((-8 * 8 - 8) * (-8 * -1 + -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (8 - -4 * -7), B = (-8 * 6 * 6), C = (-8 * 8 - 8) and D = (-8 * -1 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - -4 * -7) = (8 - (-4 * -7)) = (8 - 28) = -20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * 6 * 6) = ((-8 * 6) * 6) = (-48 * 6) = -288.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * 8 - 8) = ((-8 * 8) - 8) = (-64 - 8) = -72.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 * -1 + -6) = ((-8 * -1) + -6) = (8 + -6) = 2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((-20 + -288) + (-72 * 2)) = (-308 + (-72 * 2)) = (-308 + -144) = -452.\n(Final response) So the answer is -452.", "correct_answer": "-452", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 330, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 + 5 + 6) - (1 + -6 * 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (3 + 5 + 6) and B = (1 + -6 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + 5 + 6) = ((3 + 5) + 6) = (8 + 6) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + -6 * 9) = (1 + (-6 * 9)) = (1 + -54) = -53.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (14 - -53) = 67.\n(Final response) So the answer is 67.", "correct_answer": "67", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 53, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 + 4 - 6 + -9 - -1 * 5) * (1 * -7 - -8 + -6 - 9 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (0 + 4 - 6 + -9 - -1 * 5) and B = (1 * -7 - -8 + -6 - 9 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + 4 - 6 + -9 - -1 * 5) = ((((0 + 4) - 6) + -9) - (-1 * 5)) = (((4 - 6) + -9) - (-1 * 5)) = (((4 - 6) + -9) - -5) = ((-2 + -9) - -5) = (-11 - -5) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -7 - -8 + -6 - 9 - 7) = (((((1 * -7) - -8) + -6) - 9) - 7) = ((((-7 - -8) + -6) - 9) - 7) = (((1 + -6) - 9) - 7) = ((-5 - 9) - 7) = (-14 - 7) = -21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-6 * -21) = 126.\n(Final response) So the answer is 126.", "correct_answer": "126", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 91, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((5 * 6 - -9 * -2 + 9) - (-5 - 5 * -9 * -1 + -8)) + ((7 * 7 - -8 * -7 * 2) * (0 * -9 - -6 * 2 * -9))) - (((-6 + -3 + -1 - 8 + 7) - (-5 + 0 * 7 + 9 - 4)) - ((-6 * -7 - 8 + 6 - 6) - (6 - -4 * -4 + -4 - -9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C * D)) - ((E - F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (5 * 6 - -9 * -2 + 9), B = (-5 - 5 * -9 * -1 + -8), C = (7 * 7 - -8 * -7 * 2), D = (0 * -9 - -6 * 2 * -9), E = (-6 + -3 + -1 - 8 + 7), F = (-5 + 0 * 7 + 9 - 4), G = (-6 * -7 - 8 + 6 - 6) and H = (6 - -4 * -4 + -4 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 6 - -9 * -2 + 9) = (((5 * 6) - (-9 * -2)) + 9) = ((30 - (-9 * -2)) + 9) = ((30 - 18) + 9) = (12 + 9) = 21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - 5 * -9 * -1 + -8) = ((-5 - ((5 * -9) * -1)) + -8) = ((-5 - (-45 * -1)) + -8) = ((-5 - 45) + -8) = (-50 + -8) = -58.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 * 7 - -8 * -7 * 2) = ((7 * 7) - ((-8 * -7) * 2)) = (49 - ((-8 * -7) * 2)) = (49 - (56 * 2)) = (49 - 112) = -63.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 * -9 - -6 * 2 * -9) = ((0 * -9) - ((-6 * 2) * -9)) = (0 - ((-6 * 2) * -9)) = (0 - (-12 * -9)) = (0 - 108) = -108.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-6 + -3 + -1 - 8 + 7) = ((((-6 + -3) + -1) - 8) + 7) = (((-9 + -1) - 8) + 7) = ((-10 - 8) + 7) = (-18 + 7) = -11.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-5 + 0 * 7 + 9 - 4) = (((-5 + (0 * 7)) + 9) - 4) = (((-5 + 0) + 9) - 4) = ((-5 + 9) - 4) = (4 - 4) = 0.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-6 * -7 - 8 + 6 - 6) = ((((-6 * -7) - 8) + 6) - 6) = (((42 - 8) + 6) - 6) = ((34 + 6) - 6) = (40 - 6) = 34.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (6 - -4 * -4 + -4 - -9) = (((6 - (-4 * -4)) + -4) - -9) = (((6 - 16) + -4) - -9) = ((-10 + -4) - -9) = (-14 - -9) = -5.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C * D)) - ((E - F) - (G - H))) = (((21 - -58) + (-63 * -108)) - ((-11 - 0) - (34 - -5))) = ((79 + (-63 * -108)) - ((-11 - 0) - (34 - -5))) = ((79 + 6804) - ((-11 - 0) - (34 - -5))) = ((79 + 6804) - (-11 - (34 - -5))) = ((79 + 6804) - (-11 - 39)) = (6883 - (-11 - 39)) = (6883 - -50) = 6933.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6933.", "correct_answer": "6933", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 320, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 * 3 - -5 * 7) + (4 - 7 - -9 + -1)) * ((-6 + -1 + 3 * 7) + (-7 - -4 * 4 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (2 * 3 - -5 * 7), B = (4 - 7 - -9 + -1), C = (-6 + -1 + 3 * 7) and D = (-7 - -4 * 4 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 3 - -5 * 7) = ((2 * 3) - (-5 * 7)) = (6 - (-5 * 7)) = (6 - -35) = 41.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 7 - -9 + -1) = (((4 - 7) - -9) + -1) = ((-3 - -9) + -1) = (6 + -1) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -1 + 3 * 7) = ((-6 + -1) + (3 * 7)) = (-7 + (3 * 7)) = (-7 + 21) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -4 * 4 + -1) = ((-7 - (-4 * 4)) + -1) = ((-7 - -16) + -1) = (9 + -1) = 8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((41 + 5) * (14 + 8)) = (46 * (14 + 8)) = (46 * 22) = 1012.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1012.", "correct_answer": "1012", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 480, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + 3 * -1 + 6) * (4 - 9 + -7 * 8)) - ((6 + 1 + 1 + -6) + (4 + -6 + 4 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-7 + 3 * -1 + 6), B = (4 - 9 + -7 * 8), C = (6 + 1 + 1 + -6) and D = (4 + -6 + 4 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 3 * -1 + 6) = ((-7 + (3 * -1)) + 6) = ((-7 + -3) + 6) = (-10 + 6) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 9 + -7 * 8) = ((4 - 9) + (-7 * 8)) = (-5 + (-7 * 8)) = (-5 + -56) = -61.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + 1 + 1 + -6) = (((6 + 1) + 1) + -6) = ((7 + 1) + -6) = (8 + -6) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + -6 + 4 * 0) = ((4 + -6) + (4 * 0)) = (-2 + (4 * 0)) = (-2 + 0) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-4 * -61) - (2 + -2)) = (244 - (2 + -2)) = (244 - 0) = 244.\n(Final response) So the answer is 244.", "correct_answer": "244", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 475, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 * 6 + -9 + 3) - (-6 * -2 + -2 - -9)) + ((-9 * 3 * -1 + -1) - (2 + 5 * 0 + -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (5 * 6 + -9 + 3), B = (-6 * -2 + -2 - -9), C = (-9 * 3 * -1 + -1) and D = (2 + 5 * 0 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 6 + -9 + 3) = (((5 * 6) + -9) + 3) = ((30 + -9) + 3) = (21 + 3) = 24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * -2 + -2 - -9) = (((-6 * -2) + -2) - -9) = ((12 + -2) - -9) = (10 - -9) = 19.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * 3 * -1 + -1) = (((-9 * 3) * -1) + -1) = ((-27 * -1) + -1) = (27 + -1) = 26.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 + 5 * 0 + -6) = ((2 + (5 * 0)) + -6) = ((2 + 0) + -6) = (2 + -6) = -4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((24 - 19) + (26 - -4)) = (5 + (26 - -4)) = (5 + 30) = 35.\n(Final response) So the answer is 35.", "correct_answer": "35", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 491, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * -8 + 3 * -7) * (4 - -2 - 9 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 * -8 + 3 * -7) and B = (4 - -2 - 9 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * -8 + 3 * -7) = ((9 * -8) + (3 * -7)) = (-72 + (3 * -7)) = (-72 + -21) = -93.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - -2 - 9 - -2) = (((4 - -2) - 9) - -2) = ((6 - 9) - -2) = (-3 - -2) = -1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-93 * -1) = 93.\n(Final response) So the answer is 93.", "correct_answer": "93", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 213, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - -8 + 0) - (-3 + -3 + -4)) + ((1 + 2 + 5) + (-7 - 5 + 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (1 - -8 + 0), B = (-3 + -3 + -4), C = (1 + 2 + 5) and D = (-7 - 5 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -8 + 0) = ((1 - -8) + 0) = (9 + 0) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + -3 + -4) = ((-3 + -3) + -4) = (-6 + -4) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 + 2 + 5) = ((1 + 2) + 5) = (3 + 5) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - 5 + 4) = ((-7 - 5) + 4) = (-12 + 4) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((9 - -10) + (8 + -8)) = (19 + (8 + -8)) = (19 + 0) = 19.\n(Final response) So the answer is 19.", "correct_answer": "19", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 428, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 + -1 * 7) + (-9 + 3 + 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (8 + -1 * 7) and B = (-9 + 3 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + -1 * 7) = (8 + (-1 * 7)) = (8 + -7) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 3 + 3) = ((-9 + 3) + 3) = (-6 + 3) = -3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (1 + -3) = -2.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2.", "correct_answer": "-2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 56, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 - -7 * -2) + (8 + 9 * 7)) * ((-6 * -5 - 6) - (4 - -8 + 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (5 - -7 * -2), B = (8 + 9 * 7), C = (-6 * -5 - 6) and D = (4 - -8 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - -7 * -2) = (5 - (-7 * -2)) = (5 - 14) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + 9 * 7) = (8 + (9 * 7)) = (8 + 63) = 71.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 * -5 - 6) = ((-6 * -5) - 6) = (30 - 6) = 24.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 - -8 + 8) = ((4 - -8) + 8) = (12 + 8) = 20.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((-9 + 71) * (24 - 20)) = (62 * (24 - 20)) = (62 * 4) = 248.\n(Final response) So the answer is 248.", "correct_answer": "248", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 397, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 * 2 + -8) - (4 + 5 + 7)) * ((-3 * 5 + 2) * (9 * -8 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (8 * 2 + -8), B = (4 + 5 + 7), C = (-3 * 5 + 2) and D = (9 * -8 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 2 + -8) = ((8 * 2) + -8) = (16 + -8) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 5 + 7) = ((4 + 5) + 7) = (9 + 7) = 16.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 * 5 + 2) = ((-3 * 5) + 2) = (-15 + 2) = -13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 * -8 * 5) = ((9 * -8) * 5) = (-72 * 5) = -360.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((8 - 16) * (-13 * -360)) = (-8 * (-13 * -360)) = (-8 * 4680) = -37440.\n(Final response) So the answer is -37440.", "correct_answer": "-37440", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 148, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 - -7 + -5) + (9 * 4 - -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-5 - -7 + -5) and B = (9 * 4 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -7 + -5) = ((-5 - -7) + -5) = (2 + -5) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 4 - -6) = ((9 * 4) - -6) = (36 - -6) = 42.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-3 + 42) = 39.\n(Final response) So the answer is 39.", "correct_answer": "39", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 84, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 + 0 + -1 + 8 - -6) * (-6 - 6 + -2 * 3 - -3)) + ((-5 - 8 - 9 - 1 - 1) - (-6 - 3 * 7 * 3 - 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-9 + 0 + -1 + 8 - -6), B = (-6 - 6 + -2 * 3 - -3), C = (-5 - 8 - 9 - 1 - 1) and D = (-6 - 3 * 7 * 3 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + 0 + -1 + 8 - -6) = ((((-9 + 0) + -1) + 8) - -6) = (((-9 + -1) + 8) - -6) = ((-10 + 8) - -6) = (-2 - -6) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - 6 + -2 * 3 - -3) = (((-6 - 6) + (-2 * 3)) - -3) = ((-12 + (-2 * 3)) - -3) = ((-12 + -6) - -3) = (-18 - -3) = -15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - 8 - 9 - 1 - 1) = ((((-5 - 8) - 9) - 1) - 1) = (((-13 - 9) - 1) - 1) = ((-22 - 1) - 1) = (-23 - 1) = -24.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - 3 * 7 * 3 - 3) = ((-6 - ((3 * 7) * 3)) - 3) = ((-6 - (21 * 3)) - 3) = ((-6 - 63) - 3) = (-69 - 3) = -72.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((4 * -15) + (-24 - -72)) = (-60 + (-24 - -72)) = (-60 + 48) = -12.\n(Final response) So the answer is -12.", "correct_answer": "-12", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 202, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 - -1 - -8) + (-5 - 9 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (3 - -1 - -8) and B = (-5 - 9 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - -1 - -8) = ((3 - -1) - -8) = (4 - -8) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - 9 + -9) = ((-5 - 9) + -9) = (-14 + -9) = -23.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (12 + -23) = -11.\n(Final response) So the answer is -11.", "correct_answer": "-11", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 49, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 - -2 - -9) - (-9 + -1 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-9 - -2 - -9) and B = (-9 + -1 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - -2 - -9) = ((-9 - -2) - -9) = (-7 - -9) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + -1 + -9) = ((-9 + -1) + -9) = (-10 + -9) = -19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (2 - -19) = 21.\n(Final response) So the answer is 21.", "correct_answer": "21", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 149, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 - -4 - 9) - (-5 + -7 - 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (2 - -4 - 9) and B = (-5 + -7 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - -4 - 9) = ((2 - -4) - 9) = (6 - 9) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + -7 - 9) = ((-5 + -7) - 9) = (-12 - 9) = -21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-3 - -21) = 18.\n(Final response) So the answer is 18.", "correct_answer": "18", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 5, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 * -2 + 2) * (-2 + 4 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-2 * -2 + 2) and B = (-2 + 4 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * -2 + 2) = ((-2 * -2) + 2) = (4 + 2) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 4 + -9) = ((-2 + 4) + -9) = (2 + -9) = -7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (6 * -7) = -42.\n(Final response) So the answer is -42.", "correct_answer": "-42", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 19, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - -4 * 3) + (9 * -9 - -9)) * ((7 + -3 + -5) - (-8 + -3 - 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (6 - -4 * 3), B = (9 * -9 - -9), C = (7 + -3 + -5) and D = (-8 + -3 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -4 * 3) = (6 - (-4 * 3)) = (6 - -12) = 18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * -9 - -9) = ((9 * -9) - -9) = (-81 - -9) = -72.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + -3 + -5) = ((7 + -3) + -5) = (4 + -5) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + -3 - 4) = ((-8 + -3) - 4) = (-11 - 4) = -15.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((18 + -72) * (-1 - -15)) = (-54 * (-1 - -15)) = (-54 * 14) = -756.\n(Final response) So the answer is -756.", "correct_answer": "-756", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 302, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + -2 * -6 * 9) * (4 - 6 - 4 * -8)) * ((-7 * 3 - 8 * 2) + (-4 * 7 * -9 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (7 + -2 * -6 * 9), B = (4 - 6 - 4 * -8), C = (-7 * 3 - 8 * 2) and D = (-4 * 7 * -9 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -2 * -6 * 9) = (7 + ((-2 * -6) * 9)) = (7 + (12 * 9)) = (7 + 108) = 115.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 6 - 4 * -8) = ((4 - 6) - (4 * -8)) = (-2 - (4 * -8)) = (-2 - -32) = 30.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * 3 - 8 * 2) = ((-7 * 3) - (8 * 2)) = (-21 - (8 * 2)) = (-21 - 16) = -37.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * 7 * -9 * -6) = (((-4 * 7) * -9) * -6) = ((-28 * -9) * -6) = (252 * -6) = -1512.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((115 * 30) * (-37 + -1512)) = (3450 * (-37 + -1512)) = (3450 * -1549) = -5344050.\n(Final response) So the answer is -5344050.", "correct_answer": "-5344050", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 559, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + -8 + 1 * 3) - (8 * 9 * 2 + 1)) * ((-9 + -4 * -4 - -8) + (-7 - 6 - 3 * -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (7 + -8 + 1 * 3), B = (8 * 9 * 2 + 1), C = (-9 + -4 * -4 - -8) and D = (-7 - 6 - 3 * -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -8 + 1 * 3) = ((7 + -8) + (1 * 3)) = (-1 + (1 * 3)) = (-1 + 3) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 9 * 2 + 1) = (((8 * 9) * 2) + 1) = ((72 * 2) + 1) = (144 + 1) = 145.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + -4 * -4 - -8) = ((-9 + (-4 * -4)) - -8) = ((-9 + 16) - -8) = (7 - -8) = 15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - 6 - 3 * -4) = ((-7 - 6) - (3 * -4)) = (-13 - (3 * -4)) = (-13 - -12) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((2 - 145) * (15 + -1)) = (-143 * (15 + -1)) = (-143 * 14) = -2002.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2002.", "correct_answer": "-2002", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 561, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 * 2 + -2) * (-7 * -4 + -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (0 * 2 + -2) and B = (-7 * -4 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * 2 + -2) = ((0 * 2) + -2) = (0 + -2) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * -4 + -4) = ((-7 * -4) + -4) = (28 + -4) = 24.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-2 * 24) = -48.\n(Final response) So the answer is -48.", "correct_answer": "-48", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 1, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 + 5 - 8 + -1) * (7 - 9 * 9 + -8)) * ((7 * 0 * -8 + -8) - (2 * -4 - 3 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-6 + 5 - 8 + -1), B = (7 - 9 * 9 + -8), C = (7 * 0 * -8 + -8) and D = (2 * -4 - 3 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 5 - 8 + -1) = (((-6 + 5) - 8) + -1) = ((-1 - 8) + -1) = (-9 + -1) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - 9 * 9 + -8) = ((7 - (9 * 9)) + -8) = ((7 - 81) + -8) = (-74 + -8) = -82.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 * 0 * -8 + -8) = (((7 * 0) * -8) + -8) = ((0 * -8) + -8) = (0 + -8) = -8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * -4 - 3 * 2) = ((2 * -4) - (3 * 2)) = (-8 - (3 * 2)) = (-8 - 6) = -14.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((-10 * -82) * (-8 - -14)) = (820 * (-8 - -14)) = (820 * 6) = 4920.\n(Final response) So the answer is 4920.", "correct_answer": "4920", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 455, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((7 - -6 + -2 - 2) * (-2 - 0 + -7 - -1)) - ((-5 + -5 - -8 * -7) + (-7 - -4 - -7 + 2))) * (((2 + -6 - 7 * -3) * (8 - -2 + -8 - 6)) - ((8 + 6 * 9 - -3) - (1 - 8 * -2 + 0)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C + D)) * ((E * F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (7 - -6 + -2 - 2), B = (-2 - 0 + -7 - -1), C = (-5 + -5 - -8 * -7), D = (-7 - -4 - -7 + 2), E = (2 + -6 - 7 * -3), F = (8 - -2 + -8 - 6), G = (8 + 6 * 9 - -3) and H = (1 - 8 * -2 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -6 + -2 - 2) = (((7 - -6) + -2) - 2) = ((13 + -2) - 2) = (11 - 2) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 0 + -7 - -1) = (((-2 - 0) + -7) - -1) = ((-2 + -7) - -1) = (-9 - -1) = -8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 + -5 - -8 * -7) = ((-5 + -5) - (-8 * -7)) = (-10 - (-8 * -7)) = (-10 - 56) = -66.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -4 - -7 + 2) = (((-7 - -4) - -7) + 2) = ((-3 - -7) + 2) = (4 + 2) = 6.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (2 + -6 - 7 * -3) = ((2 + -6) - (7 * -3)) = (-4 - (7 * -3)) = (-4 - -21) = 17.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (8 - -2 + -8 - 6) = (((8 - -2) + -8) - 6) = ((10 + -8) - 6) = (2 - 6) = -4.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 + 6 * 9 - -3) = ((8 + (6 * 9)) - -3) = ((8 + 54) - -3) = (62 - -3) = 65.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (1 - 8 * -2 + 0) = ((1 - (8 * -2)) + 0) = ((1 - -16) + 0) = (17 + 0) = 17.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C + D)) * ((E * F) - (G - H))) = (((9 * -8) - (-66 + 6)) * ((17 * -4) - (65 - 17))) = ((-72 - (-66 + 6)) * ((17 * -4) - (65 - 17))) = ((-72 - -60) * ((17 * -4) - (65 - 17))) = ((-72 - -60) * (-68 - (65 - 17))) = ((-72 - -60) * (-68 - 48)) = (-12 * (-68 - 48)) = (-12 * -116) = 1392.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1392.", "correct_answer": "1392", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 289, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - 5 + -1 + -3) * (0 * 6 - 1 * 9)) - ((5 * 6 - -2 - -4) + (3 + 2 - 2 + -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (1 - 5 + -1 + -3), B = (0 * 6 - 1 * 9), C = (5 * 6 - -2 - -4) and D = (3 + 2 - 2 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - 5 + -1 + -3) = (((1 - 5) + -1) + -3) = ((-4 + -1) + -3) = (-5 + -3) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 6 - 1 * 9) = ((0 * 6) - (1 * 9)) = (0 - (1 * 9)) = (0 - 9) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 * 6 - -2 - -4) = (((5 * 6) - -2) - -4) = ((30 - -2) - -4) = (32 - -4) = 36.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + 2 - 2 + -4) = (((3 + 2) - 2) + -4) = ((5 - 2) + -4) = (3 + -4) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-8 * -9) - (36 + -1)) = (72 - (36 + -1)) = (72 - 35) = 37.\n(Final response) So the answer is 37.", "correct_answer": "37", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 544, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * -2 + 5 + -9) + (0 - 0 + 5 + -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-9 * -2 + 5 + -9) and B = (0 - 0 + 5 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * -2 + 5 + -9) = (((-9 * -2) + 5) + -9) = ((18 + 5) + -9) = (23 + -9) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 0 + 5 + -4) = (((0 - 0) + 5) + -4) = ((0 + 5) + -4) = (5 + -4) = 1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (14 + 1) = 15.\n(Final response) So the answer is 15.", "correct_answer": "15", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 256, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + -6 + -9 * -7 - 3) + (5 - 2 + -2 * 6 * -6)) * ((5 * 6 - 4 * 3 + 8) * (-5 - -8 - 7 + 3 * 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-7 + -6 + -9 * -7 - 3), B = (5 - 2 + -2 * 6 * -6), C = (5 * 6 - 4 * 3 + 8) and D = (-5 - -8 - 7 + 3 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + -6 + -9 * -7 - 3) = (((-7 + -6) + (-9 * -7)) - 3) = ((-13 + (-9 * -7)) - 3) = ((-13 + 63) - 3) = (50 - 3) = 47.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 2 + -2 * 6 * -6) = ((5 - 2) + ((-2 * 6) * -6)) = (3 + ((-2 * 6) * -6)) = (3 + (-12 * -6)) = (3 + 72) = 75.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 * 6 - 4 * 3 + 8) = (((5 * 6) - (4 * 3)) + 8) = ((30 - (4 * 3)) + 8) = ((30 - 12) + 8) = (18 + 8) = 26.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - -8 - 7 + 3 * 1) = (((-5 - -8) - 7) + (3 * 1)) = ((3 - 7) + (3 * 1)) = ((3 - 7) + 3) = (-4 + 3) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((47 + 75) * (26 * -1)) = (122 * (26 * -1)) = (122 * -26) = -3172.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3172.", "correct_answer": "-3172", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 207, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 * -2 - -4 - -7) - (-7 * 2 + -5 - -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-2 * -2 - -4 - -7) and B = (-7 * 2 + -5 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * -2 - -4 - -7) = (((-2 * -2) - -4) - -7) = ((4 - -4) - -7) = (8 - -7) = 15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 2 + -5 - -1) = (((-7 * 2) + -5) - -1) = ((-14 + -5) - -1) = (-19 - -1) = -18.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (15 - -18) = 33.\n(Final response) So the answer is 33.", "correct_answer": "33", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 239, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 - 6 * 0) - (-8 * -6 + 6)) - ((-3 + 2 * 7) + (-2 * -4 - 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-5 - 6 * 0), B = (-8 * -6 + 6), C = (-3 + 2 * 7) and D = (-2 * -4 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - 6 * 0) = (-5 - (6 * 0)) = (-5 - 0) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * -6 + 6) = ((-8 * -6) + 6) = (48 + 6) = 54.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + 2 * 7) = (-3 + (2 * 7)) = (-3 + 14) = 11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * -4 - 5) = ((-2 * -4) - 5) = (8 - 5) = 3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-5 - 54) - (11 + 3)) = (-59 - (11 + 3)) = (-59 - 14) = -73.\n(Final response) So the answer is -73.", "correct_answer": "-73", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 149, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * -4 + -8) - (1 * 6 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 * -4 + -8) and B = (1 * 6 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * -4 + -8) = ((7 * -4) + -8) = (-28 + -8) = -36.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 6 + -1) = ((1 * 6) + -1) = (6 + -1) = 5.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-36 - 5) = -41.\n(Final response) So the answer is -41.", "correct_answer": "-41", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 18, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 - -5 - 0) - (9 - -9 + 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 - -5 - 0) and B = (9 - -9 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - -5 - 0) = ((0 - -5) - 0) = (5 - 0) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - -9 + 3) = ((9 - -9) + 3) = (18 + 3) = 21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (5 - 21) = -16.\n(Final response) So the answer is -16.", "correct_answer": "-16", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 38, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + 8 + -1 * -5) - (6 * 3 + 5 * 7)) + ((9 - -8 - -7 * 1) + (5 * 1 * 5 - 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (1 + 8 + -1 * -5), B = (6 * 3 + 5 * 7), C = (9 - -8 - -7 * 1) and D = (5 * 1 * 5 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 8 + -1 * -5) = ((1 + 8) + (-1 * -5)) = (9 + (-1 * -5)) = (9 + 5) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * 3 + 5 * 7) = ((6 * 3) + (5 * 7)) = (18 + (5 * 7)) = (18 + 35) = 53.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - -8 - -7 * 1) = ((9 - -8) - (-7 * 1)) = (17 - (-7 * 1)) = (17 - -7) = 24.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 * 1 * 5 - 5) = (((5 * 1) * 5) - 5) = ((5 * 5) - 5) = (25 - 5) = 20.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((14 - 53) + (24 + 20)) = (-39 + (24 + 20)) = (-39 + 44) = 5.\n(Final response) So the answer is 5.", "correct_answer": "5", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 501, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 + -7 * 0 * 7) - (-8 + 6 - -4 + 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 + -7 * 0 * 7) and B = (-8 + 6 - -4 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + -7 * 0 * 7) = (1 + ((-7 * 0) * 7)) = (1 + (0 * 7)) = (1 + 0) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 6 - -4 + 0) = (((-8 + 6) - -4) + 0) = ((-2 - -4) + 0) = (2 + 0) = 2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (1 - 2) = -1.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1.", "correct_answer": "-1", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 279, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 - -8 + 1 * -4) - (-2 - 1 + 5 - -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 - -8 + 1 * -4) and B = (-2 - 1 + 5 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - -8 + 1 * -4) = ((-1 - -8) + (1 * -4)) = (7 + (1 * -4)) = (7 + -4) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 1 + 5 - -8) = (((-2 - 1) + 5) - -8) = ((-3 + 5) - -8) = (2 - -8) = 10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (3 - 10) = -7.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7.", "correct_answer": "-7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 201, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 * 0 - 9 + 1) - (6 * 0 - -7 * 6)) * ((0 + 6 - -3 * 5) * (0 * -4 - 8 - -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-8 * 0 - 9 + 1), B = (6 * 0 - -7 * 6), C = (0 + 6 - -3 * 5) and D = (0 * -4 - 8 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 0 - 9 + 1) = (((-8 * 0) - 9) + 1) = ((0 - 9) + 1) = (-9 + 1) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * 0 - -7 * 6) = ((6 * 0) - (-7 * 6)) = (0 - (-7 * 6)) = (0 - -42) = 42.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 + 6 - -3 * 5) = ((0 + 6) - (-3 * 5)) = (6 - (-3 * 5)) = (6 - -15) = 21.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 * -4 - 8 - -5) = (((0 * -4) - 8) - -5) = ((0 - 8) - -5) = (-8 - -5) = -3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((-8 - 42) * (21 * -3)) = (-50 * (21 * -3)) = (-50 * -63) = 3150.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3150.", "correct_answer": "3150", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 599, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - -8 * -6 * -9) * (3 * 8 - -5 + 4)) - ((8 * -7 * -6 * 3) + (-7 + 5 * 0 * -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-9 - -8 * -6 * -9), B = (3 * 8 - -5 + 4), C = (8 * -7 * -6 * 3) and D = (-7 + 5 * 0 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - -8 * -6 * -9) = (-9 - ((-8 * -6) * -9)) = (-9 - (48 * -9)) = (-9 - -432) = 423.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 8 - -5 + 4) = (((3 * 8) - -5) + 4) = ((24 - -5) + 4) = (29 + 4) = 33.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -7 * -6 * 3) = (((8 * -7) * -6) * 3) = ((-56 * -6) * 3) = (336 * 3) = 1008.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + 5 * 0 * -9) = (-7 + ((5 * 0) * -9)) = (-7 + (0 * -9)) = (-7 + 0) = -7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((423 * 33) - (1008 + -7)) = (13959 - (1008 + -7)) = (13959 - 1001) = 12958.\n(Final response) So the answer is 12958.", "correct_answer": "12958", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 564, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * 2 - -9 * -6) - (2 - -9 - -9 * 2)) - ((3 + 3 + -1 - -9) - (-5 - -6 - -7 + 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-5 * 2 - -9 * -6), B = (2 - -9 - -9 * 2), C = (3 + 3 + -1 - -9) and D = (-5 - -6 - -7 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 2 - -9 * -6) = ((-5 * 2) - (-9 * -6)) = (-10 - (-9 * -6)) = (-10 - 54) = -64.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -9 - -9 * 2) = ((2 - -9) - (-9 * 2)) = (11 - (-9 * 2)) = (11 - -18) = 29.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + 3 + -1 - -9) = (((3 + 3) + -1) - -9) = ((6 + -1) - -9) = (5 - -9) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - -6 - -7 + 1) = (((-5 - -6) - -7) + 1) = ((1 - -7) + 1) = (8 + 1) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-64 - 29) - (14 - 9)) = (-93 - (14 - 9)) = (-93 - 5) = -98.\n(Final response) So the answer is -98.", "correct_answer": "-98", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 495, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((8 + 7 - -7 - 2 + -1) + (-9 - -7 - 4 + -9 - 5)) + ((3 * -1 + -3 + -4 + -4) * (-4 * 8 - -4 - 0 * -3))) + (((5 - -8 + -8 * -2 - 2) - (6 * 6 * 0 - -1 + 7)) - ((6 - -3 + -6 + 4 - 9) - (-7 * 9 * 3 + 0 * 0)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C * D)) + ((E - F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (8 + 7 - -7 - 2 + -1), B = (-9 - -7 - 4 + -9 - 5), C = (3 * -1 + -3 + -4 + -4), D = (-4 * 8 - -4 - 0 * -3), E = (5 - -8 + -8 * -2 - 2), F = (6 * 6 * 0 - -1 + 7), G = (6 - -3 + -6 + 4 - 9) and H = (-7 * 9 * 3 + 0 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 7 - -7 - 2 + -1) = ((((8 + 7) - -7) - 2) + -1) = (((15 - -7) - 2) + -1) = ((22 - 2) + -1) = (20 + -1) = 19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - -7 - 4 + -9 - 5) = ((((-9 - -7) - 4) + -9) - 5) = (((-2 - 4) + -9) - 5) = ((-6 + -9) - 5) = (-15 - 5) = -20.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 * -1 + -3 + -4 + -4) = ((((3 * -1) + -3) + -4) + -4) = (((-3 + -3) + -4) + -4) = ((-6 + -4) + -4) = (-10 + -4) = -14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * 8 - -4 - 0 * -3) = (((-4 * 8) - -4) - (0 * -3)) = ((-32 - -4) - (0 * -3)) = ((-32 - -4) - 0) = (-28 - 0) = -28.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (5 - -8 + -8 * -2 - 2) = (((5 - -8) + (-8 * -2)) - 2) = ((13 + (-8 * -2)) - 2) = ((13 + 16) - 2) = (29 - 2) = 27.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (6 * 6 * 0 - -1 + 7) = ((((6 * 6) * 0) - -1) + 7) = (((36 * 0) - -1) + 7) = ((0 - -1) + 7) = (1 + 7) = 8.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (6 - -3 + -6 + 4 - 9) = ((((6 - -3) + -6) + 4) - 9) = (((9 + -6) + 4) - 9) = ((3 + 4) - 9) = (7 - 9) = -2.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-7 * 9 * 3 + 0 * 0) = (((-7 * 9) * 3) + (0 * 0)) = ((-63 * 3) + (0 * 0)) = ((-63 * 3) + 0) = (-189 + 0) = -189.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C * D)) + ((E - F) - (G - H))) = (((19 + -20) + (-14 * -28)) + ((27 - 8) - (-2 - -189))) = ((-1 + (-14 * -28)) + ((27 - 8) - (-2 - -189))) = ((-1 + 392) + ((27 - 8) - (-2 - -189))) = ((-1 + 392) + (19 - (-2 - -189))) = ((-1 + 392) + (19 - 187)) = (391 + (19 - 187)) = (391 + -168) = 223.\n(Final response) So the answer is 223.", "correct_answer": "223", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 329, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 + 1 + -7) * (-8 + 4 + 5)) * ((-9 * -8 - -9) + (-7 - -6 - -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (4 + 1 + -7), B = (-8 + 4 + 5), C = (-9 * -8 - -9) and D = (-7 - -6 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + 1 + -7) = ((4 + 1) + -7) = (5 + -7) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 4 + 5) = ((-8 + 4) + 5) = (-4 + 5) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * -8 - -9) = ((-9 * -8) - -9) = (72 - -9) = 81.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -6 - -9) = ((-7 - -6) - -9) = (-1 - -9) = 8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((-2 * 1) * (81 + 8)) = (-2 * (81 + 8)) = (-2 * 89) = -178.\n(Final response) So the answer is -178.", "correct_answer": "-178", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 414, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 * 1 + 2 + -1) * (-1 - 0 - 9 + -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (8 * 1 + 2 + -1) and B = (-1 - 0 - 9 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 1 + 2 + -1) = (((8 * 1) + 2) + -1) = ((8 + 2) + -1) = (10 + -1) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 0 - 9 + -3) = (((-1 - 0) - 9) + -3) = ((-1 - 9) + -3) = (-10 + -3) = -13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (9 * -13) = -117.\n(Final response) So the answer is -117.", "correct_answer": "-117", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 227, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((9 + -5 - 6) + (-9 + -6 + 1)) - ((1 * -2 + -3) + (-4 + -5 + -4))) - (((6 + 4 - 7) + (-8 - -2 - 3)) + ((-3 + -6 + 5) + (8 * 4 * -9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) - (C + D)) - ((E + F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (9 + -5 - 6), B = (-9 + -6 + 1), C = (1 * -2 + -3), D = (-4 + -5 + -4), E = (6 + 4 - 7), F = (-8 - -2 - 3), G = (-3 + -6 + 5) and H = (8 * 4 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + -5 - 6) = ((9 + -5) - 6) = (4 - 6) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + -6 + 1) = ((-9 + -6) + 1) = (-15 + 1) = -14.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 * -2 + -3) = ((1 * -2) + -3) = (-2 + -3) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + -5 + -4) = ((-4 + -5) + -4) = (-9 + -4) = -13.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (6 + 4 - 7) = ((6 + 4) - 7) = (10 - 7) = 3.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-8 - -2 - 3) = ((-8 - -2) - 3) = (-6 - 3) = -9.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-3 + -6 + 5) = ((-3 + -6) + 5) = (-9 + 5) = -4.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 * 4 * -9) = ((8 * 4) * -9) = (32 * -9) = -288.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) - (C + D)) - ((E + F) + (G + H))) = (((-2 + -14) - (-5 + -13)) - ((3 + -9) + (-4 + -288))) = ((-16 - (-5 + -13)) - ((3 + -9) + (-4 + -288))) = ((-16 - -18) - ((3 + -9) + (-4 + -288))) = ((-16 - -18) - (-6 + (-4 + -288))) = ((-16 - -18) - (-6 + -292)) = (2 - (-6 + -292)) = (2 - -298) = 300.\n(Final response) So the answer is 300.", "correct_answer": "300", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 262, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 + -7 + -7 * 7) * (4 + 8 + 8 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-3 + -7 + -7 * 7) and B = (4 + 8 + 8 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + -7 + -7 * 7) = ((-3 + -7) + (-7 * 7)) = (-10 + (-7 * 7)) = (-10 + -49) = -59.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 8 + 8 + 8) = (((4 + 8) + 8) + 8) = ((12 + 8) + 8) = (20 + 8) = 28.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-59 * 28) = -1652.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1652.", "correct_answer": "-1652", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 174, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 + 8 + 4 * -4) + (-3 + 5 + -4 + 2)) - ((-7 - 4 - -6 * 7) + (-4 - -1 - -1 * -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-2 + 8 + 4 * -4), B = (-3 + 5 + -4 + 2), C = (-7 - 4 - -6 * 7) and D = (-4 - -1 - -1 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + 8 + 4 * -4) = ((-2 + 8) + (4 * -4)) = (6 + (4 * -4)) = (6 + -16) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 5 + -4 + 2) = (((-3 + 5) + -4) + 2) = ((2 + -4) + 2) = (-2 + 2) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - 4 - -6 * 7) = ((-7 - 4) - (-6 * 7)) = (-11 - (-6 * 7)) = (-11 - -42) = 31.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -1 - -1 * -9) = ((-4 - -1) - (-1 * -9)) = (-3 - (-1 * -9)) = (-3 - 9) = -12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C + D)) = ((-10 + 0) - (31 + -12)) = (-10 - (31 + -12)) = (-10 - 19) = -29.\n(Final response) So the answer is -29.", "correct_answer": "-29", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 572, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((8 + 9 - -3) + (5 * 7 * 0)) * ((-4 + -8 * -2) - (2 * 8 + -5))) - (((3 - -8 * -2) * (6 - -9 + 6)) + ((-1 - -4 * 3) + (0 * 4 + 6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C - D)) - ((E * F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (8 + 9 - -3), B = (5 * 7 * 0), C = (-4 + -8 * -2), D = (2 * 8 + -5), E = (3 - -8 * -2), F = (6 - -9 + 6), G = (-1 - -4 * 3) and H = (0 * 4 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 9 - -3) = ((8 + 9) - -3) = (17 - -3) = 20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * 7 * 0) = ((5 * 7) * 0) = (35 * 0) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + -8 * -2) = (-4 + (-8 * -2)) = (-4 + 16) = 12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * 8 + -5) = ((2 * 8) + -5) = (16 + -5) = 11.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (3 - -8 * -2) = (3 - (-8 * -2)) = (3 - 16) = -13.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (6 - -9 + 6) = ((6 - -9) + 6) = (15 + 6) = 21.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-1 - -4 * 3) = (-1 - (-4 * 3)) = (-1 - -12) = 11.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (0 * 4 + 6) = ((0 * 4) + 6) = (0 + 6) = 6.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C - D)) - ((E * F) + (G + H))) = (((20 + 0) * (12 - 11)) - ((-13 * 21) + (11 + 6))) = ((20 * (12 - 11)) - ((-13 * 21) + (11 + 6))) = ((20 * 1) - ((-13 * 21) + (11 + 6))) = ((20 * 1) - (-273 + (11 + 6))) = ((20 * 1) - (-273 + 17)) = (20 - (-273 + 17)) = (20 - -256) = 276.\n(Final response) So the answer is 276.", "correct_answer": "276", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 245, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 * 3 * 8 * 5) + (-3 * 3 - 9 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (1 * 3 * 8 * 5) and B = (-3 * 3 - 9 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * 3 * 8 * 5) = (((1 * 3) * 8) * 5) = ((3 * 8) * 5) = (24 * 5) = 120.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * 3 - 9 * -2) = ((-3 * 3) - (9 * -2)) = (-9 - (9 * -2)) = (-9 - -18) = 9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (120 + 9) = 129.\n(Final response) So the answer is 129.", "correct_answer": "129", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 44, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 + -6 - 5 * -5) + (-7 * -2 * -6 - 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (4 + -6 - 5 * -5) and B = (-7 * -2 * -6 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -6 - 5 * -5) = ((4 + -6) - (5 * -5)) = (-2 - (5 * -5)) = (-2 - -25) = 23.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * -2 * -6 - 0) = (((-7 * -2) * -6) - 0) = ((14 * -6) - 0) = (-84 - 0) = -84.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (23 + -84) = -61.\n(Final response) So the answer is -61.", "correct_answer": "-61", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 178, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 * 0 + 1) * (-3 - -4 + 6)) + ((-8 * 9 + 9) - (-4 - 9 - -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-3 * 0 + 1), B = (-3 - -4 + 6), C = (-8 * 9 + 9) and D = (-4 - 9 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * 0 + 1) = ((-3 * 0) + 1) = (0 + 1) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - -4 + 6) = ((-3 - -4) + 6) = (1 + 6) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * 9 + 9) = ((-8 * 9) + 9) = (-72 + 9) = -63.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - 9 - -4) = ((-4 - 9) - -4) = (-13 - -4) = -9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((1 * 7) + (-63 - -9)) = (7 + (-63 - -9)) = (7 + -54) = -47.\n(Final response) So the answer is -47.", "correct_answer": "-47", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 396, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 - 0 - 4) * (0 + 8 * -5)) - ((3 - -8 + 4) - (-6 * -2 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-6 - 0 - 4), B = (0 + 8 * -5), C = (3 - -8 + 4) and D = (-6 * -2 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 0 - 4) = ((-6 - 0) - 4) = (-6 - 4) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + 8 * -5) = (0 + (8 * -5)) = (0 + -40) = -40.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 - -8 + 4) = ((3 - -8) + 4) = (11 + 4) = 15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * -2 * 4) = ((-6 * -2) * 4) = (12 * 4) = 48.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((-10 * -40) - (15 - 48)) = (400 - (15 - 48)) = (400 - -33) = 433.\n(Final response) So the answer is 433.", "correct_answer": "433", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 313, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 - 7 * -2 * 4) * (2 + 7 - 9 - 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 - 7 * -2 * 4) and B = (2 + 7 - 9 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - 7 * -2 * 4) = (-5 - ((7 * -2) * 4)) = (-5 - (-14 * 4)) = (-5 - -56) = 51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + 7 - 9 - 1) = (((2 + 7) - 9) - 1) = ((9 - 9) - 1) = (0 - 1) = -1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (51 * -1) = -51.\n(Final response) So the answer is -51.", "correct_answer": "-51", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 231, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 - 2 * 3) - (-2 + 5 + -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (9 - 2 * 3) and B = (-2 + 5 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - 2 * 3) = (9 - (2 * 3)) = (9 - 6) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 5 + -7) = ((-2 + 5) + -7) = (3 + -7) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (3 - -4) = 7.\n(Final response) So the answer is 7.", "correct_answer": "7", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 8, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 - 0 - -4 * -7) - (6 - -2 + 5 + 8)) * ((-4 + 3 * 7 + 6) + (-9 - -2 + -8 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (3 - 0 - -4 * -7), B = (6 - -2 + 5 + 8), C = (-4 + 3 * 7 + 6) and D = (-9 - -2 + -8 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - 0 - -4 * -7) = ((3 - 0) - (-4 * -7)) = (3 - (-4 * -7)) = (3 - 28) = -25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - -2 + 5 + 8) = (((6 - -2) + 5) + 8) = ((8 + 5) + 8) = (13 + 8) = 21.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + 3 * 7 + 6) = ((-4 + (3 * 7)) + 6) = ((-4 + 21) + 6) = (17 + 6) = 23.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 - -2 + -8 * -5) = ((-9 - -2) + (-8 * -5)) = (-7 + (-8 * -5)) = (-7 + 40) = 33.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((-25 - 21) * (23 + 33)) = (-46 * (23 + 33)) = (-46 * 56) = -2576.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2576.", "correct_answer": "-2576", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 170, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 + 6 * 9 - 6) * (5 - -6 * 6 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 + 6 * 9 - 6) and B = (5 - -6 * 6 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + 6 * 9 - 6) = ((-5 + (6 * 9)) - 6) = ((-5 + 54) - 6) = (49 - 6) = 43.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - -6 * 6 - -2) = ((5 - (-6 * 6)) - -2) = ((5 - -36) - -2) = (41 - -2) = 43.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (43 * 43) = 1849.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1849.", "correct_answer": "1849", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 181, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * 8 - 2 + -5) - (-6 + 0 * 1 + 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 * 8 - 2 + -5) and B = (-6 + 0 * 1 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 8 - 2 + -5) = (((7 * 8) - 2) + -5) = ((56 - 2) + -5) = (54 + -5) = 49.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + 0 * 1 + 0) = ((-6 + (0 * 1)) + 0) = ((-6 + 0) + 0) = (-6 + 0) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (49 - -6) = 55.\n(Final response) So the answer is 55.", "correct_answer": "55", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 172, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - -9 * 5) * (2 * 6 * -2)) - ((8 * -9 - 2) + (-8 + -3 - -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-9 - -9 * 5), B = (2 * 6 * -2), C = (8 * -9 - 2) and D = (-8 + -3 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - -9 * 5) = (-9 - (-9 * 5)) = (-9 - -45) = 36.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 6 * -2) = ((2 * 6) * -2) = (12 * -2) = -24.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -9 - 2) = ((8 * -9) - 2) = (-72 - 2) = -74.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + -3 - -4) = ((-8 + -3) - -4) = (-11 - -4) = -7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((36 * -24) - (-74 + -7)) = (-864 - (-74 + -7)) = (-864 - -81) = -783.\n(Final response) So the answer is -783.", "correct_answer": "-783", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 144, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-6 * 0 - -6 + 0) + (-4 * 1 - -1 * 1)) - ((8 * -8 + 6 + 3) + (2 * -8 + 5 + -8))) - (((-4 + 2 + -9 * -7) - (-4 + -2 - 1 - -5)) + ((-1 - 0 * -4 + -5) + (6 + -2 * 5 + 5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) - (C + D)) - ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-6 * 0 - -6 + 0), B = (-4 * 1 - -1 * 1), C = (8 * -8 + 6 + 3), D = (2 * -8 + 5 + -8), E = (-4 + 2 + -9 * -7), F = (-4 + -2 - 1 - -5), G = (-1 - 0 * -4 + -5) and H = (6 + -2 * 5 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * 0 - -6 + 0) = (((-6 * 0) - -6) + 0) = ((0 - -6) + 0) = (6 + 0) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 1 - -1 * 1) = ((-4 * 1) - (-1 * 1)) = (-4 - (-1 * 1)) = (-4 - -1) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -8 + 6 + 3) = (((8 * -8) + 6) + 3) = ((-64 + 6) + 3) = (-58 + 3) = -55.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * -8 + 5 + -8) = (((2 * -8) + 5) + -8) = ((-16 + 5) + -8) = (-11 + -8) = -19.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-4 + 2 + -9 * -7) = ((-4 + 2) + (-9 * -7)) = (-2 + (-9 * -7)) = (-2 + 63) = 61.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-4 + -2 - 1 - -5) = (((-4 + -2) - 1) - -5) = ((-6 - 1) - -5) = (-7 - -5) = -2.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-1 - 0 * -4 + -5) = ((-1 - (0 * -4)) + -5) = ((-1 - 0) + -5) = (-1 + -5) = -6.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (6 + -2 * 5 + 5) = ((6 + (-2 * 5)) + 5) = ((6 + -10) + 5) = (-4 + 5) = 1.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) - (C + D)) - ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((6 + -3) - (-55 + -19)) - ((61 - -2) + (-6 + 1))) = ((3 - (-55 + -19)) - ((61 - -2) + (-6 + 1))) = ((3 - -74) - ((61 - -2) + (-6 + 1))) = ((3 - -74) - (63 + (-6 + 1))) = ((3 - -74) - (63 + -5)) = (77 - (63 + -5)) = (77 - 58) = 19.\n(Final response) So the answer is 19.", "correct_answer": "19", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 299, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * 2 - -3 * -3 * 8 * 2) + (-9 + 0 * -3 - 3 - -5 + -8)) - ((-2 - -2 - -5 - 2 * 3 * 0) * (6 * 3 - 2 * -8 + -2 * -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (3 * 2 - -3 * -3 * 8 * 2), B = (-9 + 0 * -3 - 3 - -5 + -8), C = (-2 - -2 - -5 - 2 * 3 * 0) and D = (6 * 3 - 2 * -8 + -2 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 2 - -3 * -3 * 8 * 2) = ((3 * 2) - (((-3 * -3) * 8) * 2)) = (6 - (((-3 * -3) * 8) * 2)) = (6 - ((9 * 8) * 2)) = (6 - (72 * 2)) = (6 - 144) = -138.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 0 * -3 - 3 - -5 + -8) = ((((-9 + (0 * -3)) - 3) - -5) + -8) = ((((-9 + 0) - 3) - -5) + -8) = (((-9 - 3) - -5) + -8) = ((-12 - -5) + -8) = (-7 + -8) = -15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 - -2 - -5 - 2 * 3 * 0) = (((-2 - -2) - -5) - ((2 * 3) * 0)) = ((0 - -5) - ((2 * 3) * 0)) = ((0 - -5) - (6 * 0)) = (5 - (6 * 0)) = (5 - 0) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 * 3 - 2 * -8 + -2 * -8) = (((6 * 3) - (2 * -8)) + (-2 * -8)) = ((18 - (2 * -8)) + (-2 * -8)) = ((18 - -16) + (-2 * -8)) = ((18 - -16) + 16) = (34 + 16) = 50.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-138 + -15) - (5 * 50)) = (-153 - (5 * 50)) = (-153 - 250) = -403.\n(Final response) So the answer is -403.", "correct_answer": "-403", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 231, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 + -4 * -8 + -5) * (-2 * -9 * 1 * 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 + -4 * -8 + -5) and B = (-2 * -9 * 1 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + -4 * -8 + -5) = ((-5 + (-4 * -8)) + -5) = ((-5 + 32) + -5) = (27 + -5) = 22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -9 * 1 * 5) = (((-2 * -9) * 1) * 5) = ((18 * 1) * 5) = (18 * 5) = 90.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (22 * 90) = 1980.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1980.", "correct_answer": "1980", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 287, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 + -8 * -3) - (-5 * 2 - 7)) * ((-2 * -8 + -4) + (3 + -2 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (6 + -8 * -3), B = (-5 * 2 - 7), C = (-2 * -8 + -4) and D = (3 + -2 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + -8 * -3) = (6 + (-8 * -3)) = (6 + 24) = 30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 2 - 7) = ((-5 * 2) - 7) = (-10 - 7) = -17.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 * -8 + -4) = ((-2 * -8) + -4) = (16 + -4) = 12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + -2 * 5) = (3 + (-2 * 5)) = (3 + -10) = -7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((30 - -17) * (12 + -7)) = (47 * (12 + -7)) = (47 * 5) = 235.\n(Final response) So the answer is 235.", "correct_answer": "235", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 380, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((4 - -1 * -5 - -3 * -2) + (2 - -1 + 6 * -1 - -9)) * ((6 * 1 - 8 - -3 * 6) - (-6 - -7 - 3 + 4 - 4))) + (((4 + -7 * 5 + -1 - 6) - (-2 * 4 - 5 + 0 * -5)) + ((-4 - 9 + 4 * 5 - 4) + (9 * 3 - 0 - 4 + 2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C - D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (4 - -1 * -5 - -3 * -2), B = (2 - -1 + 6 * -1 - -9), C = (6 * 1 - 8 - -3 * 6), D = (-6 - -7 - 3 + 4 - 4), E = (4 + -7 * 5 + -1 - 6), F = (-2 * 4 - 5 + 0 * -5), G = (-4 - 9 + 4 * 5 - 4) and H = (9 * 3 - 0 - 4 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - -1 * -5 - -3 * -2) = ((4 - (-1 * -5)) - (-3 * -2)) = ((4 - 5) - (-3 * -2)) = ((4 - 5) - 6) = (-1 - 6) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -1 + 6 * -1 - -9) = (((2 - -1) + (6 * -1)) - -9) = ((3 + (6 * -1)) - -9) = ((3 + -6) - -9) = (-3 - -9) = 6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 * 1 - 8 - -3 * 6) = (((6 * 1) - 8) - (-3 * 6)) = ((6 - 8) - (-3 * 6)) = ((6 - 8) - -18) = (-2 - -18) = 16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - -7 - 3 + 4 - 4) = ((((-6 - -7) - 3) + 4) - 4) = (((1 - 3) + 4) - 4) = ((-2 + 4) - 4) = (2 - 4) = -2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (4 + -7 * 5 + -1 - 6) = (((4 + (-7 * 5)) + -1) - 6) = (((4 + -35) + -1) - 6) = ((-31 + -1) - 6) = (-32 - 6) = -38.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-2 * 4 - 5 + 0 * -5) = (((-2 * 4) - 5) + (0 * -5)) = ((-8 - 5) + (0 * -5)) = ((-8 - 5) + 0) = (-13 + 0) = -13.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-4 - 9 + 4 * 5 - 4) = (((-4 - 9) + (4 * 5)) - 4) = ((-13 + (4 * 5)) - 4) = ((-13 + 20) - 4) = (7 - 4) = 3.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (9 * 3 - 0 - 4 + 2) = ((((9 * 3) - 0) - 4) + 2) = (((27 - 0) - 4) + 2) = ((27 - 4) + 2) = (23 + 2) = 25.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C - D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((-7 + 6) * (16 - -2)) + ((-38 - -13) + (3 + 25))) = ((-1 * (16 - -2)) + ((-38 - -13) + (3 + 25))) = ((-1 * 18) + ((-38 - -13) + (3 + 25))) = ((-1 * 18) + (-25 + (3 + 25))) = ((-1 * 18) + (-25 + 28)) = (-18 + (-25 + 28)) = (-18 + 3) = -15.\n(Final response) So the answer is -15.", "correct_answer": "-15", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 303, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 * 0 + 1 * 7) - (-6 * 8 + 2 * 3)) * ((-4 - 0 + -4 - 7) - (0 - 2 - -1 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-9 * 0 + 1 * 7), B = (-6 * 8 + 2 * 3), C = (-4 - 0 + -4 - 7) and D = (0 - 2 - -1 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 0 + 1 * 7) = ((-9 * 0) + (1 * 7)) = (0 + (1 * 7)) = (0 + 7) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 8 + 2 * 3) = ((-6 * 8) + (2 * 3)) = (-48 + (2 * 3)) = (-48 + 6) = -42.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - 0 + -4 - 7) = (((-4 - 0) + -4) - 7) = ((-4 + -4) - 7) = (-8 - 7) = -15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 - 2 - -1 * -1) = ((0 - 2) - (-1 * -1)) = (-2 - (-1 * -1)) = (-2 - 1) = -3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((7 - -42) * (-15 - -3)) = (49 * (-15 - -3)) = (49 * -12) = -588.\n(Final response) So the answer is -588.", "correct_answer": "-588", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 178, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 + -4 - 8 - 7) * (0 * -9 * -1 + -9)) + ((4 + -4 + -6 - 4) + (-6 - -1 * 0 * 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-2 + -4 - 8 - 7), B = (0 * -9 * -1 + -9), C = (4 + -4 + -6 - 4) and D = (-6 - -1 * 0 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -4 - 8 - 7) = (((-2 + -4) - 8) - 7) = ((-6 - 8) - 7) = (-14 - 7) = -21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * -9 * -1 + -9) = (((0 * -9) * -1) + -9) = ((0 * -1) + -9) = (0 + -9) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + -4 + -6 - 4) = (((4 + -4) + -6) - 4) = ((0 + -6) - 4) = (-6 - 4) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - -1 * 0 * 9) = (-6 - ((-1 * 0) * 9)) = (-6 - (0 * 9)) = (-6 - 0) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((-21 * -9) + (-10 + -6)) = (189 + (-10 + -6)) = (189 + -16) = 173.\n(Final response) So the answer is 173.", "correct_answer": "173", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 176, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 - 2 + 6) - (6 * -6 + -9)) + ((5 * 4 + 9) - (-6 + 1 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (8 - 2 + 6), B = (6 * -6 + -9), C = (5 * 4 + 9) and D = (-6 + 1 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - 2 + 6) = ((8 - 2) + 6) = (6 + 6) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -6 + -9) = ((6 * -6) + -9) = (-36 + -9) = -45.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 * 4 + 9) = ((5 * 4) + 9) = (20 + 9) = 29.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + 1 + -8) = ((-6 + 1) + -8) = (-5 + -8) = -13.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((12 - -45) + (29 - -13)) = (57 + (29 - -13)) = (57 + 42) = 99.\n(Final response) So the answer is 99.", "correct_answer": "99", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 447, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-7 + -6 - 7 * 3) + (2 - 5 + -9 + -1)) + ((1 * -1 + -5 - 6) - (5 - 7 + 0 * -6))) + (((-3 + -9 - -8 * -6) - (-9 + -7 - -7 * 3)) + ((3 - -5 + 1 - 5) + (0 + -3 + 0 + 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C - D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-7 + -6 - 7 * 3), B = (2 - 5 + -9 + -1), C = (1 * -1 + -5 - 6), D = (5 - 7 + 0 * -6), E = (-3 + -9 - -8 * -6), F = (-9 + -7 - -7 * 3), G = (3 - -5 + 1 - 5) and H = (0 + -3 + 0 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + -6 - 7 * 3) = ((-7 + -6) - (7 * 3)) = (-13 - (7 * 3)) = (-13 - 21) = -34.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - 5 + -9 + -1) = (((2 - 5) + -9) + -1) = ((-3 + -9) + -1) = (-12 + -1) = -13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 * -1 + -5 - 6) = (((1 * -1) + -5) - 6) = ((-1 + -5) - 6) = (-6 - 6) = -12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - 7 + 0 * -6) = ((5 - 7) + (0 * -6)) = (-2 + (0 * -6)) = (-2 + 0) = -2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-3 + -9 - -8 * -6) = ((-3 + -9) - (-8 * -6)) = (-12 - (-8 * -6)) = (-12 - 48) = -60.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-9 + -7 - -7 * 3) = ((-9 + -7) - (-7 * 3)) = (-16 - (-7 * 3)) = (-16 - -21) = 5.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 - -5 + 1 - 5) = (((3 - -5) + 1) - 5) = ((8 + 1) - 5) = (9 - 5) = 4.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (0 + -3 + 0 + 3) = (((0 + -3) + 0) + 3) = ((-3 + 0) + 3) = (-3 + 3) = 0.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C - D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((-34 + -13) + (-12 - -2)) + ((-60 - 5) + (4 + 0))) = ((-47 + (-12 - -2)) + ((-60 - 5) + (4 + 0))) = ((-47 + -10) + ((-60 - 5) + (4 + 0))) = ((-47 + -10) + (-65 + (4 + 0))) = ((-47 + -10) + (-65 + 4)) = (-57 + (-65 + 4)) = (-57 + -61) = -118.\n(Final response) So the answer is -118.", "correct_answer": "-118", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 271, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * -9 * 8) + (0 * -7 - 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-9 * -9 * 8) and B = (0 * -7 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * -9 * 8) = ((-9 * -9) * 8) = (81 * 8) = 648.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * -7 - 8) = ((0 * -7) - 8) = (0 - 8) = -8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (648 + -8) = 640.\n(Final response) So the answer is 640.", "correct_answer": "640", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 28, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-4 - -9 - 1 - -6) - (-8 * -5 * -2 + 0)) + ((-8 * -8 * 6 + -1) + (-7 - -3 - 4 + 4))) - (((5 - 0 - -7 - -8) * (1 * 2 * 4 + 9)) * ((7 + 5 * 7 + 2) * (-8 + 7 + 0 - 2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C + D)) - ((E * F) * (G * H)))\", where A = (-4 - -9 - 1 - -6), B = (-8 * -5 * -2 + 0), C = (-8 * -8 * 6 + -1), D = (-7 - -3 - 4 + 4), E = (5 - 0 - -7 - -8), F = (1 * 2 * 4 + 9), G = (7 + 5 * 7 + 2) and H = (-8 + 7 + 0 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - -9 - 1 - -6) = (((-4 - -9) - 1) - -6) = ((5 - 1) - -6) = (4 - -6) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * -5 * -2 + 0) = (((-8 * -5) * -2) + 0) = ((40 * -2) + 0) = (-80 + 0) = -80.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * -8 * 6 + -1) = (((-8 * -8) * 6) + -1) = ((64 * 6) + -1) = (384 + -1) = 383.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -3 - 4 + 4) = (((-7 - -3) - 4) + 4) = ((-4 - 4) + 4) = (-8 + 4) = -4.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (5 - 0 - -7 - -8) = (((5 - 0) - -7) - -8) = ((5 - -7) - -8) = (12 - -8) = 20.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (1 * 2 * 4 + 9) = (((1 * 2) * 4) + 9) = ((2 * 4) + 9) = (8 + 9) = 17.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 + 5 * 7 + 2) = ((7 + (5 * 7)) + 2) = ((7 + 35) + 2) = (42 + 2) = 44.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 + 7 + 0 - 2) = (((-8 + 7) + 0) - 2) = ((-1 + 0) - 2) = (-1 - 2) = -3.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C + D)) - ((E * F) * (G * H))) = (((10 - -80) + (383 + -4)) - ((20 * 17) * (44 * -3))) = ((90 + (383 + -4)) - ((20 * 17) * (44 * -3))) = ((90 + 379) - ((20 * 17) * (44 * -3))) = ((90 + 379) - (340 * (44 * -3))) = ((90 + 379) - (340 * -132)) = (469 - (340 * -132)) = (469 - -44880) = 45349.\n(Final response) So the answer is 45349.", "correct_answer": "45349", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 294, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 * 2 - -3 + -1 - -2) - (-8 - 6 + 8 * 0 + -4)) - ((3 * 7 - 8 - -3 * 4) - (5 + 1 * 4 * -2 * 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-6 * 2 - -3 + -1 - -2), B = (-8 - 6 + 8 * 0 + -4), C = (3 * 7 - 8 - -3 * 4) and D = (5 + 1 * 4 * -2 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * 2 - -3 + -1 - -2) = ((((-6 * 2) - -3) + -1) - -2) = (((-12 - -3) + -1) - -2) = ((-9 + -1) - -2) = (-10 - -2) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 6 + 8 * 0 + -4) = (((-8 - 6) + (8 * 0)) + -4) = ((-14 + (8 * 0)) + -4) = ((-14 + 0) + -4) = (-14 + -4) = -18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 * 7 - 8 - -3 * 4) = (((3 * 7) - 8) - (-3 * 4)) = ((21 - 8) - (-3 * 4)) = ((21 - 8) - -12) = (13 - -12) = 25.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 + 1 * 4 * -2 * 8) = (5 + (((1 * 4) * -2) * 8)) = (5 + ((4 * -2) * 8)) = (5 + (-8 * 8)) = (5 + -64) = -59.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-8 - -18) - (25 - -59)) = (10 - (25 - -59)) = (10 - 84) = -74.\n(Final response) So the answer is -74.", "correct_answer": "-74", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 184, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 * 0 - -9) * (4 + 4 + -1)) + ((4 + 3 * -4) * (-8 - -2 - -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (5 * 0 - -9), B = (4 + 4 + -1), C = (4 + 3 * -4) and D = (-8 - -2 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 0 - -9) = ((5 * 0) - -9) = (0 - -9) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 4 + -1) = ((4 + 4) + -1) = (8 + -1) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + 3 * -4) = (4 + (3 * -4)) = (4 + -12) = -8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - -2 - -7) = ((-8 - -2) - -7) = (-6 - -7) = 1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((9 * 7) + (-8 * 1)) = (63 + (-8 * 1)) = (63 + -8) = 55.\n(Final response) So the answer is 55.", "correct_answer": "55", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 329, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 * -4 * -4) * (-4 * -1 - -1)) - ((-4 * -6 + -3) - (-5 - 0 + 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-8 * -4 * -4), B = (-4 * -1 - -1), C = (-4 * -6 + -3) and D = (-5 - 0 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * -4 * -4) = ((-8 * -4) * -4) = (32 * -4) = -128.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * -1 - -1) = ((-4 * -1) - -1) = (4 - -1) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 * -6 + -3) = ((-4 * -6) + -3) = (24 + -3) = 21.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - 0 + 5) = ((-5 - 0) + 5) = (-5 + 5) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((-128 * 5) - (21 - 0)) = (-640 - (21 - 0)) = (-640 - 21) = -661.\n(Final response) So the answer is -661.", "correct_answer": "-661", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 120, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((6 - -2 * -3 - -9) * (-4 - -8 * 0 * -1)) - ((5 * 5 + 6 * -8) + (1 * 8 - -9 * 2))) + (((-4 - 7 + -8 + 8) * (-9 + 4 + 2 * -2)) - ((5 * -9 - 6 + 4) - (7 * 4 + 1 - -6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C + D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (6 - -2 * -3 - -9), B = (-4 - -8 * 0 * -1), C = (5 * 5 + 6 * -8), D = (1 * 8 - -9 * 2), E = (-4 - 7 + -8 + 8), F = (-9 + 4 + 2 * -2), G = (5 * -9 - 6 + 4) and H = (7 * 4 + 1 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -2 * -3 - -9) = ((6 - (-2 * -3)) - -9) = ((6 - 6) - -9) = (0 - -9) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - -8 * 0 * -1) = (-4 - ((-8 * 0) * -1)) = (-4 - (0 * -1)) = (-4 - 0) = -4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 * 5 + 6 * -8) = ((5 * 5) + (6 * -8)) = (25 + (6 * -8)) = (25 + -48) = -23.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 * 8 - -9 * 2) = ((1 * 8) - (-9 * 2)) = (8 - (-9 * 2)) = (8 - -18) = 26.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-4 - 7 + -8 + 8) = (((-4 - 7) + -8) + 8) = ((-11 + -8) + 8) = (-19 + 8) = -11.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-9 + 4 + 2 * -2) = ((-9 + 4) + (2 * -2)) = (-5 + (2 * -2)) = (-5 + -4) = -9.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (5 * -9 - 6 + 4) = (((5 * -9) - 6) + 4) = ((-45 - 6) + 4) = (-51 + 4) = -47.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (7 * 4 + 1 - -6) = (((7 * 4) + 1) - -6) = ((28 + 1) - -6) = (29 - -6) = 35.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C + D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H))) = (((9 * -4) - (-23 + 26)) + ((-11 * -9) - (-47 - 35))) = ((-36 - (-23 + 26)) + ((-11 * -9) - (-47 - 35))) = ((-36 - 3) + ((-11 * -9) - (-47 - 35))) = ((-36 - 3) + (99 - (-47 - 35))) = ((-36 - 3) + (99 - -82)) = (-39 + (99 - -82)) = (-39 + 181) = 142.\n(Final response) So the answer is 142.", "correct_answer": "142", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 272, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 * 7 * -5 - -6) + (-8 * -5 - -6 + 9)) + ((6 + 6 - -9 * -6) + (9 - 2 - -6 * 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-1 * 7 * -5 - -6), B = (-8 * -5 - -6 + 9), C = (6 + 6 - -9 * -6) and D = (9 - 2 - -6 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 7 * -5 - -6) = (((-1 * 7) * -5) - -6) = ((-7 * -5) - -6) = (35 - -6) = 41.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * -5 - -6 + 9) = (((-8 * -5) - -6) + 9) = ((40 - -6) + 9) = (46 + 9) = 55.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + 6 - -9 * -6) = ((6 + 6) - (-9 * -6)) = (12 - (-9 * -6)) = (12 - 54) = -42.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - 2 - -6 * 7) = ((9 - 2) - (-6 * 7)) = (7 - (-6 * 7)) = (7 - -42) = 49.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((41 + 55) + (-42 + 49)) = (96 + (-42 + 49)) = (96 + 7) = 103.\n(Final response) So the answer is 103.", "correct_answer": "103", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 457, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 + 7 - -2 * 5 - -5) - (-3 * -2 * -3 * 4 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-5 + 7 - -2 * 5 - -5) and B = (-3 * -2 * -3 * 4 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + 7 - -2 * 5 - -5) = (((-5 + 7) - (-2 * 5)) - -5) = ((2 - (-2 * 5)) - -5) = ((2 - -10) - -5) = (12 - -5) = 17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * -2 * -3 * 4 + 8) = ((((-3 * -2) * -3) * 4) + 8) = (((6 * -3) * 4) + 8) = ((-18 * 4) + 8) = (-72 + 8) = -64.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (17 - -64) = 81.\n(Final response) So the answer is 81.", "correct_answer": "81", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 73, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 * 0 + 5 * -4) * (-4 + 9 * -2 * 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 * 0 + 5 * -4) and B = (-4 + 9 * -2 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * 0 + 5 * -4) = ((-7 * 0) + (5 * -4)) = (0 + (5 * -4)) = (0 + -20) = -20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 9 * -2 * 5) = (-4 + ((9 * -2) * 5)) = (-4 + (-18 * 5)) = (-4 + -90) = -94.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-20 * -94) = 1880.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1880.", "correct_answer": "1880", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 35, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 - 7 + 6 * -1) * (5 - 4 * 2 + -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 - 7 + 6 * -1) and B = (5 - 4 * 2 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - 7 + 6 * -1) = ((-5 - 7) + (6 * -1)) = (-12 + (6 * -1)) = (-12 + -6) = -18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 4 * 2 + -3) = ((5 - (4 * 2)) + -3) = ((5 - 8) + -3) = (-3 + -3) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-18 * -6) = 108.\n(Final response) So the answer is 108.", "correct_answer": "108", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 157, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 + -1 - 8 + 6) + (2 - 9 * -7 - 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (3 + -1 - 8 + 6) and B = (2 - 9 * -7 - 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + -1 - 8 + 6) = (((3 + -1) - 8) + 6) = ((2 - 8) + 6) = (-6 + 6) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - 9 * -7 - 6) = ((2 - (9 * -7)) - 6) = ((2 - -63) - 6) = (65 - 6) = 59.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (0 + 59) = 59.\n(Final response) So the answer is 59.", "correct_answer": "59", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 236, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 - -1 - -4 + -3) * (0 - -5 * 3 * -8)) - ((-1 - 0 - 9 * 1) * (9 - -9 + 5 - -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-5 - -1 - -4 + -3), B = (0 - -5 * 3 * -8), C = (-1 - 0 - 9 * 1) and D = (9 - -9 + 5 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -1 - -4 + -3) = (((-5 - -1) - -4) + -3) = ((-4 - -4) + -3) = (0 + -3) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - -5 * 3 * -8) = (0 - ((-5 * 3) * -8)) = (0 - (-15 * -8)) = (0 - 120) = -120.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 - 0 - 9 * 1) = ((-1 - 0) - (9 * 1)) = (-1 - (9 * 1)) = (-1 - 9) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - -9 + 5 - -7) = (((9 - -9) + 5) - -7) = ((18 + 5) - -7) = (23 - -7) = 30.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-3 * -120) - (-10 * 30)) = (360 - (-10 * 30)) = (360 - -300) = 660.\n(Final response) So the answer is 660.", "correct_answer": "660", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 557, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 + 4 - 8) * (9 * 3 * 9)) - ((-7 - -5 + -3) + (-8 + 0 - 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (4 + 4 - 8), B = (9 * 3 * 9), C = (-7 - -5 + -3) and D = (-8 + 0 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + 4 - 8) = ((4 + 4) - 8) = (8 - 8) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 3 * 9) = ((9 * 3) * 9) = (27 * 9) = 243.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - -5 + -3) = ((-7 - -5) + -3) = (-2 + -3) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + 0 - 2) = ((-8 + 0) - 2) = (-8 - 2) = -10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((0 * 243) - (-5 + -10)) = (0 - (-5 + -10)) = (0 - -15) = 15.\n(Final response) So the answer is 15.", "correct_answer": "15", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 436, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 * -8 - -5 * -9) * (8 + -9 * 7 + -4)) * ((3 - -8 + 8 - 1) - (-4 - -1 + -5 - -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (9 * -8 - -5 * -9), B = (8 + -9 * 7 + -4), C = (3 - -8 + 8 - 1) and D = (-4 - -1 + -5 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * -8 - -5 * -9) = ((9 * -8) - (-5 * -9)) = (-72 - (-5 * -9)) = (-72 - 45) = -117.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + -9 * 7 + -4) = ((8 + (-9 * 7)) + -4) = ((8 + -63) + -4) = (-55 + -4) = -59.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 - -8 + 8 - 1) = (((3 - -8) + 8) - 1) = ((11 + 8) - 1) = (19 - 1) = 18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -1 + -5 - -6) = (((-4 - -1) + -5) - -6) = ((-3 + -5) - -6) = (-8 - -6) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((-117 * -59) * (18 - -2)) = (6903 * (18 - -2)) = (6903 * 20) = 138060.\n(Final response) So the answer is 138060.", "correct_answer": "138060", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 542, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 - -9 - 3) * (3 * -6 * 2)) * ((3 - 2 - 4) * (6 * -6 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-4 - -9 - 3), B = (3 * -6 * 2), C = (3 - 2 - 4) and D = (6 * -6 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - -9 - 3) = ((-4 - -9) - 3) = (5 - 3) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * -6 * 2) = ((3 * -6) * 2) = (-18 * 2) = -36.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 - 2 - 4) = ((3 - 2) - 4) = (1 - 4) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 * -6 + -1) = ((6 * -6) + -1) = (-36 + -1) = -37.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((2 * -36) * (-3 * -37)) = (-72 * (-3 * -37)) = (-72 * 111) = -7992.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7992.", "correct_answer": "-7992", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 358, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 * 9 + -5 - 7) + (-2 * -5 * -3 * 8)) * ((4 - 3 - 3 - -9) * (-3 - -8 * 6 + 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-2 * 9 + -5 - 7), B = (-2 * -5 * -3 * 8), C = (4 - 3 - 3 - -9) and D = (-3 - -8 * 6 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * 9 + -5 - 7) = (((-2 * 9) + -5) - 7) = ((-18 + -5) - 7) = (-23 - 7) = -30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -5 * -3 * 8) = (((-2 * -5) * -3) * 8) = ((10 * -3) * 8) = (-30 * 8) = -240.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - 3 - 3 - -9) = (((4 - 3) - 3) - -9) = ((1 - 3) - -9) = (-2 - -9) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 - -8 * 6 + 6) = ((-3 - (-8 * 6)) + 6) = ((-3 - -48) + 6) = (45 + 6) = 51.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((-30 + -240) * (7 * 51)) = (-270 * (7 * 51)) = (-270 * 357) = -96390.\n(Final response) So the answer is -96390.", "correct_answer": "-96390", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 533, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 * -4 * 7) - (2 + 8 - 1)) - ((-9 * -8 - -7) + (-2 * -9 - -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (8 * -4 * 7), B = (2 + 8 - 1), C = (-9 * -8 - -7) and D = (-2 * -9 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * -4 * 7) = ((8 * -4) * 7) = (-32 * 7) = -224.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + 8 - 1) = ((2 + 8) - 1) = (10 - 1) = 9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * -8 - -7) = ((-9 * -8) - -7) = (72 - -7) = 79.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * -9 - -5) = ((-2 * -9) - -5) = (18 - -5) = 23.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-224 - 9) - (79 + 23)) = (-233 - (79 + 23)) = (-233 - 102) = -335.\n(Final response) So the answer is -335.", "correct_answer": "-335", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 349, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 + -6 + 4) + (6 * -7 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 + -6 + 4) and B = (6 * -7 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + -6 + 4) = ((-6 + -6) + 4) = (-12 + 4) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -7 + -9) = ((6 * -7) + -9) = (-42 + -9) = -51.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-8 + -51) = -59.\n(Final response) So the answer is -59.", "correct_answer": "-59", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 24, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 * -1 + 9) - (-9 - 6 - 8)) * ((-9 - 9 - 9) * (-2 + -1 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (8 * -1 + 9), B = (-9 - 6 - 8), C = (-9 - 9 - 9) and D = (-2 + -1 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * -1 + 9) = ((8 * -1) + 9) = (-8 + 9) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 6 - 8) = ((-9 - 6) - 8) = (-15 - 8) = -23.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 - 9 - 9) = ((-9 - 9) - 9) = (-18 - 9) = -27.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 + -1 * 4) = (-2 + (-1 * 4)) = (-2 + -4) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((1 - -23) * (-27 * -6)) = (24 * (-27 * -6)) = (24 * 162) = 3888.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3888.", "correct_answer": "3888", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 311, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 + -6 * -8) - (-4 - -9 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 + -6 * -8) and B = (-4 - -9 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + -6 * -8) = (1 + (-6 * -8)) = (1 + 48) = 49.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - -9 - 2) = ((-4 - -9) - 2) = (5 - 2) = 3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (49 - 3) = 46.\n(Final response) So the answer is 46.", "correct_answer": "46", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 1, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 + -8 - 2) + (9 * 6 - -3)) * ((-3 + -4 - -9) + (4 - -4 - 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (4 + -8 - 2), B = (9 * 6 - -3), C = (-3 + -4 - -9) and D = (4 - -4 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -8 - 2) = ((4 + -8) - 2) = (-4 - 2) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 6 - -3) = ((9 * 6) - -3) = (54 - -3) = 57.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -4 - -9) = ((-3 + -4) - -9) = (-7 - -9) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 - -4 - 8) = ((4 - -4) - 8) = (8 - 8) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-6 + 57) * (2 + 0)) = (51 * (2 + 0)) = (51 * 2) = 102.\n(Final response) So the answer is 102.", "correct_answer": "102", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 424, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 * 1 - -3) - (-9 - -7 + -8)) + ((-7 - 5 - -1) + (1 - -8 + 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (4 * 1 - -3), B = (-9 - -7 + -8), C = (-7 - 5 - -1) and D = (1 - -8 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 1 - -3) = ((4 * 1) - -3) = (4 - -3) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - -7 + -8) = ((-9 - -7) + -8) = (-2 + -8) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - 5 - -1) = ((-7 - 5) - -1) = (-12 - -1) = -11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 - -8 + 8) = ((1 - -8) + 8) = (9 + 8) = 17.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((7 - -10) + (-11 + 17)) = (17 + (-11 + 17)) = (17 + 6) = 23.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23.", "correct_answer": "23", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 336, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-1 * 9 * 3 - 8) + (-2 - -2 + 3 + 2)) * ((3 + -6 - -8 + -8) - (5 - -8 * -5 * 4))) * (((-2 * 1 * -2 * 6) + (-2 + 2 + -7 - -9)) * ((3 * -9 - 8 * 3) + (8 - 9 * -5 + -7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C - D)) * ((E + F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (-1 * 9 * 3 - 8), B = (-2 - -2 + 3 + 2), C = (3 + -6 - -8 + -8), D = (5 - -8 * -5 * 4), E = (-2 * 1 * -2 * 6), F = (-2 + 2 + -7 - -9), G = (3 * -9 - 8 * 3) and H = (8 - 9 * -5 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 9 * 3 - 8) = (((-1 * 9) * 3) - 8) = ((-9 * 3) - 8) = (-27 - 8) = -35.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - -2 + 3 + 2) = (((-2 - -2) + 3) + 2) = ((0 + 3) + 2) = (3 + 2) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + -6 - -8 + -8) = (((3 + -6) - -8) + -8) = ((-3 - -8) + -8) = (5 + -8) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - -8 * -5 * 4) = (5 - ((-8 * -5) * 4)) = (5 - (40 * 4)) = (5 - 160) = -155.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-2 * 1 * -2 * 6) = (((-2 * 1) * -2) * 6) = ((-2 * -2) * 6) = (4 * 6) = 24.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-2 + 2 + -7 - -9) = (((-2 + 2) + -7) - -9) = ((0 + -7) - -9) = (-7 - -9) = 2.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 * -9 - 8 * 3) = ((3 * -9) - (8 * 3)) = (-27 - (8 * 3)) = (-27 - 24) = -51.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 - 9 * -5 + -7) = ((8 - (9 * -5)) + -7) = ((8 - -45) + -7) = (53 + -7) = 46.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C - D)) * ((E + F) * (G + H))) = (((-35 + 5) * (-3 - -155)) * ((24 + 2) * (-51 + 46))) = ((-30 * (-3 - -155)) * ((24 + 2) * (-51 + 46))) = ((-30 * 152) * ((24 + 2) * (-51 + 46))) = ((-30 * 152) * (26 * (-51 + 46))) = ((-30 * 152) * (26 * -5)) = (-4560 * (26 * -5)) = (-4560 * -130) = 592800.\n(Final response) So the answer is 592800.", "correct_answer": "592800", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 278, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 + -9 + -4) - (6 - 1 - -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-4 + -9 + -4) and B = (6 - 1 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -9 + -4) = ((-4 + -9) + -4) = (-13 + -4) = -17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - 1 - -1) = ((6 - 1) - -1) = (5 - -1) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-17 - 6) = -23.\n(Final response) So the answer is -23.", "correct_answer": "-23", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 76, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-3 * 1 * 2) - (2 - -9 - 1)) * ((2 + -4 + 3) - (2 - 0 * -3))) - (((8 - -2 * -1) - (1 * -6 * 5)) * ((7 + -9 - 3) + (0 * 1 - 4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C - D)) - ((E - F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (-3 * 1 * 2), B = (2 - -9 - 1), C = (2 + -4 + 3), D = (2 - 0 * -3), E = (8 - -2 * -1), F = (1 * -6 * 5), G = (7 + -9 - 3) and H = (0 * 1 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * 1 * 2) = ((-3 * 1) * 2) = (-3 * 2) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -9 - 1) = ((2 - -9) - 1) = (11 - 1) = 10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + -4 + 3) = ((2 + -4) + 3) = (-2 + 3) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 - 0 * -3) = (2 - (0 * -3)) = (2 - 0) = 2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (8 - -2 * -1) = (8 - (-2 * -1)) = (8 - 2) = 6.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (1 * -6 * 5) = ((1 * -6) * 5) = (-6 * 5) = -30.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 + -9 - 3) = ((7 + -9) - 3) = (-2 - 3) = -5.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (0 * 1 - 4) = ((0 * 1) - 4) = (0 - 4) = -4.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C - D)) - ((E - F) * (G + H))) = (((-6 - 10) * (1 - 2)) - ((6 - -30) * (-5 + -4))) = ((-16 * (1 - 2)) - ((6 - -30) * (-5 + -4))) = ((-16 * -1) - ((6 - -30) * (-5 + -4))) = ((-16 * -1) - (36 * (-5 + -4))) = ((-16 * -1) - (36 * -9)) = (16 - (36 * -9)) = (16 - -324) = 340.\n(Final response) So the answer is 340.", "correct_answer": "340", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 260, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + -7 + 9 - 1) * (4 + 8 + 6 * 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-1 + -7 + 9 - 1) and B = (4 + 8 + 6 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + -7 + 9 - 1) = (((-1 + -7) + 9) - 1) = ((-8 + 9) - 1) = (1 - 1) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 8 + 6 * 5) = ((4 + 8) + (6 * 5)) = (12 + (6 * 5)) = (12 + 30) = 42.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (0 * 42) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 298, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 + -3 - 3) - (5 * -2 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (2 + -3 - 3) and B = (5 * -2 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + -3 - 3) = ((2 + -3) - 3) = (-1 - 3) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * -2 + 8) = ((5 * -2) + 8) = (-10 + 8) = -2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-4 - -2) = -2.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2.", "correct_answer": "-2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 33, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 * 3 - 2 * -8) - (-2 - 9 + -9 + -5)) - ((1 * 3 - 9 - -5) - (9 + -1 * 5 + 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (1 * 3 - 2 * -8), B = (-2 - 9 + -9 + -5), C = (1 * 3 - 9 - -5) and D = (9 + -1 * 5 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * 3 - 2 * -8) = ((1 * 3) - (2 * -8)) = (3 - (2 * -8)) = (3 - -16) = 19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 9 + -9 + -5) = (((-2 - 9) + -9) + -5) = ((-11 + -9) + -5) = (-20 + -5) = -25.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 * 3 - 9 - -5) = (((1 * 3) - 9) - -5) = ((3 - 9) - -5) = (-6 - -5) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -1 * 5 + 5) = ((9 + (-1 * 5)) + 5) = ((9 + -5) + 5) = (4 + 5) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((19 - -25) - (-1 - 9)) = (44 - (-1 - 9)) = (44 - -10) = 54.\n(Final response) So the answer is 54.", "correct_answer": "54", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 474, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 * 2 + -5) * (-8 - 6 + -3)) - ((0 - -2 + 4) - (-7 + -1 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (5 * 2 + -5), B = (-8 - 6 + -3), C = (0 - -2 + 4) and D = (-7 + -1 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 2 + -5) = ((5 * 2) + -5) = (10 + -5) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 6 + -3) = ((-8 - 6) + -3) = (-14 + -3) = -17.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 - -2 + 4) = ((0 - -2) + 4) = (2 + 4) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + -1 + -8) = ((-7 + -1) + -8) = (-8 + -8) = -16.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((5 * -17) - (6 - -16)) = (-85 - (6 - -16)) = (-85 - 22) = -107.\n(Final response) So the answer is -107.", "correct_answer": "-107", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 301, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 + -9 - 8 + 9) - (-5 * -8 - 5 * -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (4 + -9 - 8 + 9) and B = (-5 * -8 - 5 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -9 - 8 + 9) = (((4 + -9) - 8) + 9) = ((-5 - 8) + 9) = (-13 + 9) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -8 - 5 * -6) = ((-5 * -8) - (5 * -6)) = (40 - (5 * -6)) = (40 - -30) = 70.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-4 - 70) = -74.\n(Final response) So the answer is -74.", "correct_answer": "-74", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 189, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((0 * -7 - 3 * 1 * 6 + -4) - (-3 - -9 + -9 + -9 + 9 - 3)) + ((6 + 1 - -5 * -5 * -4 + -5) - (-9 - -4 + -3 - -9 - 6 * 0))) * (((4 * -5 * 4 + -9 * -1 + -3) + (3 - -1 * 1 * 1 - 3 * 1)) - ((8 + 9 * 4 - 5 - 5 * 1) - (-6 * -6 - 4 - -7 + 7 * -6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E + F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (0 * -7 - 3 * 1 * 6 + -4), B = (-3 - -9 + -9 + -9 + 9 - 3), C = (6 + 1 - -5 * -5 * -4 + -5), D = (-9 - -4 + -3 - -9 - 6 * 0), E = (4 * -5 * 4 + -9 * -1 + -3), F = (3 - -1 * 1 * 1 - 3 * 1), G = (8 + 9 * 4 - 5 - 5 * 1) and H = (-6 * -6 - 4 - -7 + 7 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * -7 - 3 * 1 * 6 + -4) = (((0 * -7) - ((3 * 1) * 6)) + -4) = ((0 - ((3 * 1) * 6)) + -4) = ((0 - (3 * 6)) + -4) = ((0 - 18) + -4) = (-18 + -4) = -22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - -9 + -9 + -9 + 9 - 3) = (((((-3 - -9) + -9) + -9) + 9) - 3) = ((((6 + -9) + -9) + 9) - 3) = (((-3 + -9) + 9) - 3) = ((-12 + 9) - 3) = (-3 - 3) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + 1 - -5 * -5 * -4 + -5) = (((6 + 1) - ((-5 * -5) * -4)) + -5) = ((7 - ((-5 * -5) * -4)) + -5) = ((7 - (25 * -4)) + -5) = ((7 - -100) + -5) = (107 + -5) = 102.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 - -4 + -3 - -9 - 6 * 0) = ((((-9 - -4) + -3) - -9) - (6 * 0)) = (((-5 + -3) - -9) - (6 * 0)) = (((-5 + -3) - -9) - 0) = ((-8 - -9) - 0) = (1 - 0) = 1.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (4 * -5 * 4 + -9 * -1 + -3) = ((((4 * -5) * 4) + (-9 * -1)) + -3) = (((-20 * 4) + (-9 * -1)) + -3) = (((-20 * 4) + 9) + -3) = ((-80 + 9) + -3) = (-71 + -3) = -74.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (3 - -1 * 1 * 1 - 3 * 1) = ((3 - ((-1 * 1) * 1)) - (3 * 1)) = ((3 - (-1 * 1)) - (3 * 1)) = ((3 - (-1 * 1)) - 3) = ((3 - -1) - 3) = (4 - 3) = 1.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 + 9 * 4 - 5 - 5 * 1) = (((8 + (9 * 4)) - 5) - (5 * 1)) = (((8 + 36) - 5) - (5 * 1)) = (((8 + 36) - 5) - 5) = ((44 - 5) - 5) = (39 - 5) = 34.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-6 * -6 - 4 - -7 + 7 * -6) = ((((-6 * -6) - 4) - -7) + (7 * -6)) = (((36 - 4) - -7) + (7 * -6)) = (((36 - 4) - -7) + -42) = ((32 - -7) + -42) = (39 + -42) = -3.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E + F) - (G - H))) = (((-22 - -6) + (102 - 1)) * ((-74 + 1) - (34 - -3))) = ((-16 + (102 - 1)) * ((-74 + 1) - (34 - -3))) = ((-16 + 101) * ((-74 + 1) - (34 - -3))) = ((-16 + 101) * (-73 - (34 - -3))) = ((-16 + 101) * (-73 - 37)) = (85 * (-73 - 37)) = (85 * -110) = -9350.\n(Final response) So the answer is -9350.", "correct_answer": "-9350", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 332, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 * -1 + -8) + (8 - 2 - -5)) * ((0 - -6 * -6) * (-1 - -4 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-9 * -1 + -8), B = (8 - 2 - -5), C = (0 - -6 * -6) and D = (-1 - -4 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * -1 + -8) = ((-9 * -1) + -8) = (9 + -8) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 2 - -5) = ((8 - 2) - -5) = (6 - -5) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 - -6 * -6) = (0 - (-6 * -6)) = (0 - 36) = -36.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 - -4 * 0) = (-1 - (-4 * 0)) = (-1 - 0) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((1 + 11) * (-36 * -1)) = (12 * (-36 * -1)) = (12 * 36) = 432.\n(Final response) So the answer is 432.", "correct_answer": "432", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 350, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 + 4 * 0 * 8) + (-2 + 6 * 6 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-5 + 4 * 0 * 8) and B = (-2 + 6 * 6 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + 4 * 0 * 8) = (-5 + ((4 * 0) * 8)) = (-5 + (0 * 8)) = (-5 + 0) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 6 * 6 * 4) = (-2 + ((6 * 6) * 4)) = (-2 + (36 * 4)) = (-2 + 144) = 142.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-5 + 142) = 137.\n(Final response) So the answer is 137.", "correct_answer": "137", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 177, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 * -6 + -7 + 0 - -6 + 7) * (-4 + 4 - 3 * -8 - -3 - 1)) * ((-5 - 7 * 4 + 9 + -1 * -5) * (3 + -8 - -8 - 3 + 1 + 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-3 * -6 + -7 + 0 - -6 + 7), B = (-4 + 4 - 3 * -8 - -3 - 1), C = (-5 - 7 * 4 + 9 + -1 * -5) and D = (3 + -8 - -8 - 3 + 1 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * -6 + -7 + 0 - -6 + 7) = (((((-3 * -6) + -7) + 0) - -6) + 7) = ((((18 + -7) + 0) - -6) + 7) = (((11 + 0) - -6) + 7) = ((11 - -6) + 7) = (17 + 7) = 24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 4 - 3 * -8 - -3 - 1) = ((((-4 + 4) - (3 * -8)) - -3) - 1) = (((0 - (3 * -8)) - -3) - 1) = (((0 - -24) - -3) - 1) = ((24 - -3) - 1) = (27 - 1) = 26.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - 7 * 4 + 9 + -1 * -5) = (((-5 - (7 * 4)) + 9) + (-1 * -5)) = (((-5 - 28) + 9) + (-1 * -5)) = (((-5 - 28) + 9) + 5) = ((-33 + 9) + 5) = (-24 + 5) = -19.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + -8 - -8 - 3 + 1 + 5) = (((((3 + -8) - -8) - 3) + 1) + 5) = ((((-5 - -8) - 3) + 1) + 5) = (((3 - 3) + 1) + 5) = ((0 + 1) + 5) = (1 + 5) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((24 * 26) * (-19 * 6)) = (624 * (-19 * 6)) = (624 * -114) = -71136.\n(Final response) So the answer is -71136.", "correct_answer": "-71136", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 216, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 - -6 - -4) * (-2 * -2 * -9)) + ((8 * -3 * 5) + (-7 - 4 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-2 - -6 - -4), B = (-2 * -2 * -9), C = (8 * -3 * 5) and D = (-7 - 4 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -6 - -4) = ((-2 - -6) - -4) = (4 - -4) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -2 * -9) = ((-2 * -2) * -9) = (4 * -9) = -36.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -3 * 5) = ((8 * -3) * 5) = (-24 * 5) = -120.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - 4 * -5) = (-7 - (4 * -5)) = (-7 - -20) = 13.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((8 * -36) + (-120 + 13)) = (-288 + (-120 + 13)) = (-288 + -107) = -395.\n(Final response) So the answer is -395.", "correct_answer": "-395", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 427, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 - -8 - 3 * -8) * (-7 * 4 - -3 + -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (0 - -8 - 3 * -8) and B = (-7 * 4 - -3 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - -8 - 3 * -8) = ((0 - -8) - (3 * -8)) = (8 - (3 * -8)) = (8 - -24) = 32.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 4 - -3 + -3) = (((-7 * 4) - -3) + -3) = ((-28 - -3) + -3) = (-25 + -3) = -28.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (32 * -28) = -896.\n(Final response) So the answer is -896.", "correct_answer": "-896", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 150, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 - 9 * 7 * 4) * (-7 + -7 + 8 + -3)) + ((-5 - 7 + 0 + 1) - (2 - -6 + -1 * 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (3 - 9 * 7 * 4), B = (-7 + -7 + 8 + -3), C = (-5 - 7 + 0 + 1) and D = (2 - -6 + -1 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - 9 * 7 * 4) = (3 - ((9 * 7) * 4)) = (3 - (63 * 4)) = (3 - 252) = -249.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -7 + 8 + -3) = (((-7 + -7) + 8) + -3) = ((-14 + 8) + -3) = (-6 + -3) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - 7 + 0 + 1) = (((-5 - 7) + 0) + 1) = ((-12 + 0) + 1) = (-12 + 1) = -11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 - -6 + -1 * 3) = ((2 - -6) + (-1 * 3)) = (8 + (-1 * 3)) = (8 + -3) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((-249 * -9) + (-11 - 5)) = (2241 + (-11 - 5)) = (2241 + -16) = 2225.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2225.", "correct_answer": "2225", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 482, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 * 7 - -1 * 9 + -2) - (-3 * -6 * 2 - 2 + -6)) - ((5 - -4 - -5 * 1 + -7) * (-8 + 0 * -7 + 1 + 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-3 * 7 - -1 * 9 + -2), B = (-3 * -6 * 2 - 2 + -6), C = (5 - -4 - -5 * 1 + -7) and D = (-8 + 0 * -7 + 1 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * 7 - -1 * 9 + -2) = (((-3 * 7) - (-1 * 9)) + -2) = ((-21 - (-1 * 9)) + -2) = ((-21 - -9) + -2) = (-12 + -2) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * -6 * 2 - 2 + -6) = ((((-3 * -6) * 2) - 2) + -6) = (((18 * 2) - 2) + -6) = ((36 - 2) + -6) = (34 + -6) = 28.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 - -4 - -5 * 1 + -7) = (((5 - -4) - (-5 * 1)) + -7) = ((9 - (-5 * 1)) + -7) = ((9 - -5) + -7) = (14 + -7) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + 0 * -7 + 1 + 9) = (((-8 + (0 * -7)) + 1) + 9) = (((-8 + 0) + 1) + 9) = ((-8 + 1) + 9) = (-7 + 9) = 2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((-14 - 28) - (7 * 2)) = (-42 - (7 * 2)) = (-42 - 14) = -56.\n(Final response) So the answer is -56.", "correct_answer": "-56", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 200, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 - 8 * -2) - (9 + -4 + 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (3 - 8 * -2) and B = (9 + -4 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - 8 * -2) = (3 - (8 * -2)) = (3 - -16) = 19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + -4 + 5) = ((9 + -4) + 5) = (5 + 5) = 10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (19 - 10) = 9.\n(Final response) So the answer is 9.", "correct_answer": "9", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 85, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - -1 - 0) + (6 - -6 - 7)) + ((3 + -7 + 6) * (9 + 8 - -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (6 - -1 - 0), B = (6 - -6 - 7), C = (3 + -7 + 6) and D = (9 + 8 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -1 - 0) = ((6 - -1) - 0) = (7 - 0) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - -6 - 7) = ((6 - -6) - 7) = (12 - 7) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + -7 + 6) = ((3 + -7) + 6) = (-4 + 6) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + 8 - -2) = ((9 + 8) - -2) = (17 - -2) = 19.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((7 + 5) + (2 * 19)) = (12 + (2 * 19)) = (12 + 38) = 50.\n(Final response) So the answer is 50.", "correct_answer": "50", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 391, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 * -9 + -8 + 0 + 6 * 0) * (7 - -2 * -8 - -9 - -6 - 8)) - ((-5 + -7 * 6 * -6 * 4 * -3) - (1 + -7 * -2 + 3 - -8 + 7))) + (((-1 * -3 * 2 * 5 * 3 - 1) + (5 - -2 - 5 * 3 + -5 * -7)) + ((6 - 0 - 6 + -2 + 8 - -7) - (-8 + -5 * 5 * 7 - 8 - 5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C - D)) + ((E + F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (2 * -9 + -8 + 0 + 6 * 0), B = (7 - -2 * -8 - -9 - -6 - 8), C = (-5 + -7 * 6 * -6 * 4 * -3), D = (1 + -7 * -2 + 3 - -8 + 7), E = (-1 * -3 * 2 * 5 * 3 - 1), F = (5 - -2 - 5 * 3 + -5 * -7), G = (6 - 0 - 6 + -2 + 8 - -7) and H = (-8 + -5 * 5 * 7 - 8 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * -9 + -8 + 0 + 6 * 0) = ((((2 * -9) + -8) + 0) + (6 * 0)) = (((-18 + -8) + 0) + (6 * 0)) = (((-18 + -8) + 0) + 0) = ((-26 + 0) + 0) = (-26 + 0) = -26.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - -2 * -8 - -9 - -6 - 8) = ((((7 - (-2 * -8)) - -9) - -6) - 8) = ((((7 - 16) - -9) - -6) - 8) = (((-9 - -9) - -6) - 8) = ((0 - -6) - 8) = (6 - 8) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 + -7 * 6 * -6 * 4 * -3) = (-5 + ((((-7 * 6) * -6) * 4) * -3)) = (-5 + (((-42 * -6) * 4) * -3)) = (-5 + ((252 * 4) * -3)) = (-5 + (1008 * -3)) = (-5 + -3024) = -3029.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + -7 * -2 + 3 - -8 + 7) = ((((1 + (-7 * -2)) + 3) - -8) + 7) = ((((1 + 14) + 3) - -8) + 7) = (((15 + 3) - -8) + 7) = ((18 - -8) + 7) = (26 + 7) = 33.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-1 * -3 * 2 * 5 * 3 - 1) = (((((-1 * -3) * 2) * 5) * 3) - 1) = ((((3 * 2) * 5) * 3) - 1) = (((6 * 5) * 3) - 1) = ((30 * 3) - 1) = (90 - 1) = 89.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 - -2 - 5 * 3 + -5 * -7) = (((5 - -2) - (5 * 3)) + (-5 * -7)) = ((7 - (5 * 3)) + (-5 * -7)) = ((7 - 15) + (-5 * -7)) = ((7 - 15) + 35) = (-8 + 35) = 27.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (6 - 0 - 6 + -2 + 8 - -7) = (((((6 - 0) - 6) + -2) + 8) - -7) = ((((6 - 6) + -2) + 8) - -7) = (((0 + -2) + 8) - -7) = ((-2 + 8) - -7) = (6 - -7) = 13.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 + -5 * 5 * 7 - 8 - 5) = (((-8 + ((-5 * 5) * 7)) - 8) - 5) = (((-8 + (-25 * 7)) - 8) - 5) = (((-8 + -175) - 8) - 5) = ((-183 - 8) - 5) = (-191 - 5) = -196.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C - D)) + ((E + F) + (G - H))) = (((-26 * -2) - (-3029 - 33)) + ((89 + 27) + (13 - -196))) = ((52 - (-3029 - 33)) + ((89 + 27) + (13 - -196))) = ((52 - -3062) + ((89 + 27) + (13 - -196))) = ((52 - -3062) + (116 + (13 - -196))) = ((52 - -3062) + (116 + 209)) = (3114 + (116 + 209)) = (3114 + 325) = 3439.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3439.", "correct_answer": "3439", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 349, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 - -4 * 3 + -8) + (7 - -8 - 1 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (5 - -4 * 3 + -8) and B = (7 - -8 - 1 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - -4 * 3 + -8) = ((5 - (-4 * 3)) + -8) = ((5 - -12) + -8) = (17 + -8) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - -8 - 1 * -2) = ((7 - -8) - (1 * -2)) = (15 - (1 * -2)) = (15 - -2) = 17.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (9 + 17) = 26.\n(Final response) So the answer is 26.", "correct_answer": "26", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 229, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - -4 - -6) - (9 - -8 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 - -4 - -6) and B = (9 - -8 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -4 - -6) = ((1 - -4) - -6) = (5 - -6) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - -8 - 3) = ((9 - -8) - 3) = (17 - 3) = 14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (11 - 14) = -3.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3.", "correct_answer": "-3", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 22, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 * 0 * 5 * 7) - (9 + -4 * 6 * -3)) * ((7 - -8 + -6 - 4) + (-5 + -5 * -4 - -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-1 * 0 * 5 * 7), B = (9 + -4 * 6 * -3), C = (7 - -8 + -6 - 4) and D = (-5 + -5 * -4 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 0 * 5 * 7) = (((-1 * 0) * 5) * 7) = ((0 * 5) * 7) = (0 * 7) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + -4 * 6 * -3) = (9 + ((-4 * 6) * -3)) = (9 + (-24 * -3)) = (9 + 72) = 81.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 - -8 + -6 - 4) = (((7 - -8) + -6) - 4) = ((15 + -6) - 4) = (9 - 4) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 + -5 * -4 - -9) = ((-5 + (-5 * -4)) - -9) = ((-5 + 20) - -9) = (15 - -9) = 24.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((0 - 81) * (5 + 24)) = (-81 * (5 + 24)) = (-81 * 29) = -2349.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2349.", "correct_answer": "-2349", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 175, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 - -5 - -4) - (7 - 7 + 7)) + ((7 + 3 * -3) - (-4 + 4 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-5 - -5 - -4), B = (7 - 7 + 7), C = (7 + 3 * -3) and D = (-4 + 4 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -5 - -4) = ((-5 - -5) - -4) = (0 - -4) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - 7 + 7) = ((7 - 7) + 7) = (0 + 7) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + 3 * -3) = (7 + (3 * -3)) = (7 + -9) = -2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + 4 * -1) = (-4 + (4 * -1)) = (-4 + -4) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((4 - 7) + (-2 - -8)) = (-3 + (-2 - -8)) = (-3 + 6) = 3.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3.", "correct_answer": "3", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 327, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 * 1 + 2) - (-5 * -4 + -1)) + ((6 - 9 - 0) - (8 * -4 + 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-4 * 1 + 2), B = (-5 * -4 + -1), C = (6 - 9 - 0) and D = (8 * -4 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * 1 + 2) = ((-4 * 1) + 2) = (-4 + 2) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -4 + -1) = ((-5 * -4) + -1) = (20 + -1) = 19.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 9 - 0) = ((6 - 9) - 0) = (-3 - 0) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * -4 + 6) = ((8 * -4) + 6) = (-32 + 6) = -26.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-2 - 19) + (-3 - -26)) = (-21 + (-3 - -26)) = (-21 + 23) = 2.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2.", "correct_answer": "2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 423, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 + -8 - -5) * (-6 - -6 + -3)) - ((3 + -6 - -9) + (-2 * -5 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (4 + -8 - -5), B = (-6 - -6 + -3), C = (3 + -6 - -9) and D = (-2 * -5 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -8 - -5) = ((4 + -8) - -5) = (-4 - -5) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - -6 + -3) = ((-6 - -6) + -3) = (0 + -3) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + -6 - -9) = ((3 + -6) - -9) = (-3 - -9) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * -5 * 5) = ((-2 * -5) * 5) = (10 * 5) = 50.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((1 * -3) - (6 + 50)) = (-3 - (6 + 50)) = (-3 - 56) = -59.\n(Final response) So the answer is -59.", "correct_answer": "-59", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 318, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 + 5 + -3) + (-5 - 8 + 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-7 + 5 + -3) and B = (-5 - 8 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 5 + -3) = ((-7 + 5) + -3) = (-2 + -3) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - 8 + 9) = ((-5 - 8) + 9) = (-13 + 9) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-5 + -4) = -9.\n(Final response) So the answer is -9.", "correct_answer": "-9", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 6, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 * 5 + 5) * (0 + -8 - -7)) * ((-5 * -2 + 2) - (-3 * -2 + -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-8 * 5 + 5), B = (0 + -8 - -7), C = (-5 * -2 + 2) and D = (-3 * -2 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 5 + 5) = ((-8 * 5) + 5) = (-40 + 5) = -35.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -8 - -7) = ((0 + -8) - -7) = (-8 - -7) = -1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * -2 + 2) = ((-5 * -2) + 2) = (10 + 2) = 12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * -2 + -2) = ((-3 * -2) + -2) = (6 + -2) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((-35 * -1) * (12 - 4)) = (35 * (12 - 4)) = (35 * 8) = 280.\n(Final response) So the answer is 280.", "correct_answer": "280", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 354, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + -5 - 6 - 5) - (-4 + 3 + 6 + 8)) + ((-4 * -4 + -6 - 4) - (-8 + -6 - -7 - 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-7 + -5 - 6 - 5), B = (-4 + 3 + 6 + 8), C = (-4 * -4 + -6 - 4) and D = (-8 + -6 - -7 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + -5 - 6 - 5) = (((-7 + -5) - 6) - 5) = ((-12 - 6) - 5) = (-18 - 5) = -23.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 3 + 6 + 8) = (((-4 + 3) + 6) + 8) = ((-1 + 6) + 8) = (5 + 8) = 13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 * -4 + -6 - 4) = (((-4 * -4) + -6) - 4) = ((16 + -6) - 4) = (10 - 4) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + -6 - -7 - 5) = (((-8 + -6) - -7) - 5) = ((-14 - -7) - 5) = (-7 - 5) = -12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-23 - 13) + (6 - -12)) = (-36 + (6 - -12)) = (-36 + 18) = -18.\n(Final response) So the answer is -18.", "correct_answer": "-18", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 454, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((9 * -1 * -5) + (0 + -9 + -4)) + ((-7 + 2 * 1) + (2 * -5 - -4))) + (((7 - -9 - -7) + (4 + -8 - -6)) * ((-5 - -1 - -7) - (0 + 5 - 7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C + D)) + ((E + F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (9 * -1 * -5), B = (0 + -9 + -4), C = (-7 + 2 * 1), D = (2 * -5 - -4), E = (7 - -9 - -7), F = (4 + -8 - -6), G = (-5 - -1 - -7) and H = (0 + 5 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * -1 * -5) = ((9 * -1) * -5) = (-9 * -5) = 45.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -9 + -4) = ((0 + -9) + -4) = (-9 + -4) = -13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + 2 * 1) = (-7 + (2 * 1)) = (-7 + 2) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * -5 - -4) = ((2 * -5) - -4) = (-10 - -4) = -6.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (7 - -9 - -7) = ((7 - -9) - -7) = (16 - -7) = 23.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (4 + -8 - -6) = ((4 + -8) - -6) = (-4 - -6) = 2.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-5 - -1 - -7) = ((-5 - -1) - -7) = (-4 - -7) = 3.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (0 + 5 - 7) = ((0 + 5) - 7) = (5 - 7) = -2.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C + D)) + ((E + F) * (G - H))) = (((45 + -13) + (-5 + -6)) + ((23 + 2) * (3 - -2))) = ((32 + (-5 + -6)) + ((23 + 2) * (3 - -2))) = ((32 + -11) + ((23 + 2) * (3 - -2))) = ((32 + -11) + (25 * (3 - -2))) = ((32 + -11) + (25 * 5)) = (21 + (25 * 5)) = (21 + 125) = 146.\n(Final response) So the answer is 146.", "correct_answer": "146", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 264, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 + 4 - 4 + -6 * 5 - 4) - (-9 - 0 - -8 + -2 + -9 * -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (8 + 4 - 4 + -6 * 5 - 4) and B = (-9 - 0 - -8 + -2 + -9 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 4 - 4 + -6 * 5 - 4) = ((((8 + 4) - 4) + (-6 * 5)) - 4) = (((12 - 4) + (-6 * 5)) - 4) = (((12 - 4) + -30) - 4) = ((8 + -30) - 4) = (-22 - 4) = -26.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 0 - -8 + -2 + -9 * -1) = ((((-9 - 0) - -8) + -2) + (-9 * -1)) = (((-9 - -8) + -2) + (-9 * -1)) = (((-9 - -8) + -2) + 9) = ((-1 + -2) + 9) = (-3 + 9) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-26 - 6) = -32.\n(Final response) So the answer is -32.", "correct_answer": "-32", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 111, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 - 5 + -4) + (-7 * 1 * -1)) * ((9 * 4 - -3) - (0 + -4 + 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (0 - 5 + -4), B = (-7 * 1 * -1), C = (9 * 4 - -3) and D = (0 + -4 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - 5 + -4) = ((0 - 5) + -4) = (-5 + -4) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 1 * -1) = ((-7 * 1) * -1) = (-7 * -1) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 * 4 - -3) = ((9 * 4) - -3) = (36 - -3) = 39.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + -4 + 4) = ((0 + -4) + 4) = (-4 + 4) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((-9 + 7) * (39 - 0)) = (-2 * (39 - 0)) = (-2 * 39) = -78.\n(Final response) So the answer is -78.", "correct_answer": "-78", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 129, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-1 - 3 * 6 + -5 + -2) * (3 + 2 * 5 + -8 - 2)) * ((-8 * 8 * 6 - -5 + 1) * (8 * -8 * -7 + -9 - 5))) * (((-5 + 4 * 2 - -1 + -8) + (5 * 6 + 8 + -5 * -9)) + ((5 - -2 * -5 + 1 * 2) - (2 * -3 + 0 - -6 + 0)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (-1 - 3 * 6 + -5 + -2), B = (3 + 2 * 5 + -8 - 2), C = (-8 * 8 * 6 - -5 + 1), D = (8 * -8 * -7 + -9 - 5), E = (-5 + 4 * 2 - -1 + -8), F = (5 * 6 + 8 + -5 * -9), G = (5 - -2 * -5 + 1 * 2) and H = (2 * -3 + 0 - -6 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - 3 * 6 + -5 + -2) = (((-1 - (3 * 6)) + -5) + -2) = (((-1 - 18) + -5) + -2) = ((-19 + -5) + -2) = (-24 + -2) = -26.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + 2 * 5 + -8 - 2) = (((3 + (2 * 5)) + -8) - 2) = (((3 + 10) + -8) - 2) = ((13 + -8) - 2) = (5 - 2) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * 8 * 6 - -5 + 1) = ((((-8 * 8) * 6) - -5) + 1) = (((-64 * 6) - -5) + 1) = ((-384 - -5) + 1) = (-379 + 1) = -378.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * -8 * -7 + -9 - 5) = ((((8 * -8) * -7) + -9) - 5) = (((-64 * -7) + -9) - 5) = ((448 + -9) - 5) = (439 - 5) = 434.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-5 + 4 * 2 - -1 + -8) = (((-5 + (4 * 2)) - -1) + -8) = (((-5 + 8) - -1) + -8) = ((3 - -1) + -8) = (4 + -8) = -4.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 * 6 + 8 + -5 * -9) = (((5 * 6) + 8) + (-5 * -9)) = ((30 + 8) + (-5 * -9)) = ((30 + 8) + 45) = (38 + 45) = 83.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (5 - -2 * -5 + 1 * 2) = ((5 - (-2 * -5)) + (1 * 2)) = ((5 - 10) + (1 * 2)) = ((5 - 10) + 2) = (-5 + 2) = -3.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (2 * -3 + 0 - -6 + 0) = ((((2 * -3) + 0) - -6) + 0) = (((-6 + 0) - -6) + 0) = ((-6 - -6) + 0) = (0 + 0) = 0.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G - H))) = (((-26 * 3) * (-378 * 434)) * ((-4 + 83) + (-3 - 0))) = ((-78 * (-378 * 434)) * ((-4 + 83) + (-3 - 0))) = ((-78 * -164052) * ((-4 + 83) + (-3 - 0))) = ((-78 * -164052) * (79 + (-3 - 0))) = ((-78 * -164052) * (79 + -3)) = (12796056 * (79 + -3)) = (12796056 * 76) = 972500256.\n(Final response) So the answer is 972500256.", "correct_answer": "972500256", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 325, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + 2 + 9) * (5 + 6 * 1)) * ((0 - -5 * -2) + (5 - 2 + 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (1 + 2 + 9), B = (5 + 6 * 1), C = (0 - -5 * -2) and D = (5 - 2 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 2 + 9) = ((1 + 2) + 9) = (3 + 9) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 6 * 1) = (5 + (6 * 1)) = (5 + 6) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 - -5 * -2) = (0 - (-5 * -2)) = (0 - 10) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - 2 + 9) = ((5 - 2) + 9) = (3 + 9) = 12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((12 * 11) * (-10 + 12)) = (132 * (-10 + 12)) = (132 * 2) = 264.\n(Final response) So the answer is 264.", "correct_answer": "264", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 443, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 + 3 + 9 * 7) + (-7 * -6 * -3 * -5)) + ((1 + -2 + 7 * 9) - (0 + -9 + 7 + -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (8 + 3 + 9 * 7), B = (-7 * -6 * -3 * -5), C = (1 + -2 + 7 * 9) and D = (0 + -9 + 7 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 3 + 9 * 7) = ((8 + 3) + (9 * 7)) = (11 + (9 * 7)) = (11 + 63) = 74.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * -6 * -3 * -5) = (((-7 * -6) * -3) * -5) = ((42 * -3) * -5) = (-126 * -5) = 630.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 + -2 + 7 * 9) = ((1 + -2) + (7 * 9)) = (-1 + (7 * 9)) = (-1 + 63) = 62.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + -9 + 7 + -9) = (((0 + -9) + 7) + -9) = ((-9 + 7) + -9) = (-2 + -9) = -11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((74 + 630) + (62 - -11)) = (704 + (62 - -11)) = (704 + 73) = 777.\n(Final response) So the answer is 777.", "correct_answer": "777", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 538, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 * 8 + 4 * 7 + 7) * (1 + 4 + 9 + -3 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (6 * 8 + 4 * 7 + 7) and B = (1 + 4 + 9 + -3 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * 8 + 4 * 7 + 7) = (((6 * 8) + (4 * 7)) + 7) = ((48 + (4 * 7)) + 7) = ((48 + 28) + 7) = (76 + 7) = 83.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + 4 + 9 + -3 + 8) = ((((1 + 4) + 9) + -3) + 8) = (((5 + 9) + -3) + 8) = ((14 + -3) + 8) = (11 + 8) = 19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (83 * 19) = 1577.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1577.", "correct_answer": "1577", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 62, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - 3 - -3 + 1) - (-6 * -9 * -7 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 - 3 - -3 + 1) and B = (-6 * -9 * -7 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - 3 - -3 + 1) = (((1 - 3) - -3) + 1) = ((-2 - -3) + 1) = (1 + 1) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * -9 * -7 - -4) = (((-6 * -9) * -7) - -4) = ((54 * -7) - -4) = (-378 - -4) = -374.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (2 - -374) = 376.\n(Final response) So the answer is 376.", "correct_answer": "376", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 202, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-8 + 2 + -2 - 0 - 9) + (7 + 3 * -8 + 6 + -6)) + ((-1 - 2 - -4 - 3 - -6) + (-7 + 8 - 9 + -5 + 9))) + (((7 + -6 + -2 - 5 * 3) * (-3 - 4 - 8 - 7 * -4)) - ((9 + 2 * 6 + 6 + -9) * (5 * 4 + -9 + -5 + -2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C + D)) + ((E * F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (-8 + 2 + -2 - 0 - 9), B = (7 + 3 * -8 + 6 + -6), C = (-1 - 2 - -4 - 3 - -6), D = (-7 + 8 - 9 + -5 + 9), E = (7 + -6 + -2 - 5 * 3), F = (-3 - 4 - 8 - 7 * -4), G = (9 + 2 * 6 + 6 + -9) and H = (5 * 4 + -9 + -5 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + 2 + -2 - 0 - 9) = ((((-8 + 2) + -2) - 0) - 9) = (((-6 + -2) - 0) - 9) = ((-8 - 0) - 9) = (-8 - 9) = -17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 3 * -8 + 6 + -6) = (((7 + (3 * -8)) + 6) + -6) = (((7 + -24) + 6) + -6) = ((-17 + 6) + -6) = (-11 + -6) = -17.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 - 2 - -4 - 3 - -6) = ((((-1 - 2) - -4) - 3) - -6) = (((-3 - -4) - 3) - -6) = ((1 - 3) - -6) = (-2 - -6) = 4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + 8 - 9 + -5 + 9) = ((((-7 + 8) - 9) + -5) + 9) = (((1 - 9) + -5) + 9) = ((-8 + -5) + 9) = (-13 + 9) = -4.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (7 + -6 + -2 - 5 * 3) = (((7 + -6) + -2) - (5 * 3)) = ((1 + -2) - (5 * 3)) = ((1 + -2) - 15) = (-1 - 15) = -16.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-3 - 4 - 8 - 7 * -4) = (((-3 - 4) - 8) - (7 * -4)) = ((-7 - 8) - (7 * -4)) = ((-7 - 8) - -28) = (-15 - -28) = 13.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (9 + 2 * 6 + 6 + -9) = (((9 + (2 * 6)) + 6) + -9) = (((9 + 12) + 6) + -9) = ((21 + 6) + -9) = (27 + -9) = 18.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (5 * 4 + -9 + -5 + -2) = ((((5 * 4) + -9) + -5) + -2) = (((20 + -9) + -5) + -2) = ((11 + -5) + -2) = (6 + -2) = 4.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C + D)) + ((E * F) - (G * H))) = (((-17 + -17) + (4 + -4)) + ((-16 * 13) - (18 * 4))) = ((-34 + (4 + -4)) + ((-16 * 13) - (18 * 4))) = ((-34 + 0) + ((-16 * 13) - (18 * 4))) = ((-34 + 0) + (-208 - (18 * 4))) = ((-34 + 0) + (-208 - 72)) = (-34 + (-208 - 72)) = (-34 + -280) = -314.\n(Final response) So the answer is -314.", "correct_answer": "-314", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 311, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 * 2 - 3) - (8 + -9 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (4 * 2 - 3) and B = (8 + -9 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 2 - 3) = ((4 * 2) - 3) = (8 - 3) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + -9 * -2) = (8 + (-9 * -2)) = (8 + 18) = 26.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (5 - 26) = -21.\n(Final response) So the answer is -21.", "correct_answer": "-21", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 92, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 + -3 - 3) + (4 - 1 + 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-8 + -3 - 3) and B = (4 - 1 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + -3 - 3) = ((-8 + -3) - 3) = (-11 - 3) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 1 + 9) = ((4 - 1) + 9) = (3 + 9) = 12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-14 + 12) = -2.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2.", "correct_answer": "-2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 110, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-4 + -3 + -5) * (0 - -8 * -1)) - ((-7 - -8 * -8) * (4 * 8 + -9))) * (((-2 * -3 - 8) - (0 - -4 - 3)) - ((2 * -9 + 1) - (-8 - 6 * -9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C * D)) * ((E - F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (-4 + -3 + -5), B = (0 - -8 * -1), C = (-7 - -8 * -8), D = (4 * 8 + -9), E = (-2 * -3 - 8), F = (0 - -4 - 3), G = (2 * -9 + 1) and H = (-8 - 6 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -3 + -5) = ((-4 + -3) + -5) = (-7 + -5) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - -8 * -1) = (0 - (-8 * -1)) = (0 - 8) = -8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - -8 * -8) = (-7 - (-8 * -8)) = (-7 - 64) = -71.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * 8 + -9) = ((4 * 8) + -9) = (32 + -9) = 23.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-2 * -3 - 8) = ((-2 * -3) - 8) = (6 - 8) = -2.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (0 - -4 - 3) = ((0 - -4) - 3) = (4 - 3) = 1.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (2 * -9 + 1) = ((2 * -9) + 1) = (-18 + 1) = -17.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 - 6 * -9) = (-8 - (6 * -9)) = (-8 - -54) = 46.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C * D)) * ((E - F) - (G - H))) = (((-12 * -8) - (-71 * 23)) * ((-2 - 1) - (-17 - 46))) = ((96 - (-71 * 23)) * ((-2 - 1) - (-17 - 46))) = ((96 - -1633) * ((-2 - 1) - (-17 - 46))) = ((96 - -1633) * (-3 - (-17 - 46))) = ((96 - -1633) * (-3 - -63)) = (1729 * (-3 - -63)) = (1729 * 60) = 103740.\n(Final response) So the answer is 103740.", "correct_answer": "103740", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 268, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 + -9 - -6 * -7) - (-9 * -6 * -9 * 8)) - ((-4 + -9 * -5 * -8) + (6 + -8 - -6 * 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-6 + -9 - -6 * -7), B = (-9 * -6 * -9 * 8), C = (-4 + -9 * -5 * -8) and D = (6 + -8 - -6 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + -9 - -6 * -7) = ((-6 + -9) - (-6 * -7)) = (-15 - (-6 * -7)) = (-15 - 42) = -57.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -6 * -9 * 8) = (((-9 * -6) * -9) * 8) = ((54 * -9) * 8) = (-486 * 8) = -3888.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + -9 * -5 * -8) = (-4 + ((-9 * -5) * -8)) = (-4 + (45 * -8)) = (-4 + -360) = -364.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + -8 - -6 * 7) = ((6 + -8) - (-6 * 7)) = (-2 - (-6 * 7)) = (-2 - -42) = 40.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-57 - -3888) - (-364 + 40)) = (3831 - (-364 + 40)) = (3831 - -324) = 4155.\n(Final response) So the answer is 4155.", "correct_answer": "4155", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 496, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 + -8 + 5) * (1 * -4 - 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (2 + -8 + 5) and B = (1 * -4 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + -8 + 5) = ((2 + -8) + 5) = (-6 + 5) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -4 - 8) = ((1 * -4) - 8) = (-4 - 8) = -12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-1 * -12) = 12.\n(Final response) So the answer is 12.", "correct_answer": "12", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 26, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 + 4 * -2 + -6 + 2) * (3 * -4 * -6 * 1 + -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-3 + 4 * -2 + -6 + 2) and B = (3 * -4 * -6 * 1 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 4 * -2 + -6 + 2) = (((-3 + (4 * -2)) + -6) + 2) = (((-3 + -8) + -6) + 2) = ((-11 + -6) + 2) = (-17 + 2) = -15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * -4 * -6 * 1 + -3) = ((((3 * -4) * -6) * 1) + -3) = (((-12 * -6) * 1) + -3) = ((72 * 1) + -3) = (72 + -3) = 69.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-15 * 69) = -1035.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1035.", "correct_answer": "-1035", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 82, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 * 9 * 3) * (6 * -8 * -6)) + ((-9 + -5 - 2) - (-4 + 7 - 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (7 * 9 * 3), B = (6 * -8 * -6), C = (-9 + -5 - 2) and D = (-4 + 7 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 9 * 3) = ((7 * 9) * 3) = (63 * 3) = 189.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -8 * -6) = ((6 * -8) * -6) = (-48 * -6) = 288.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + -5 - 2) = ((-9 + -5) - 2) = (-14 - 2) = -16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + 7 - 3) = ((-4 + 7) - 3) = (3 - 3) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((189 * 288) + (-16 - 0)) = (54432 + (-16 - 0)) = (54432 + -16) = 54416.\n(Final response) So the answer is 54416.", "correct_answer": "54416", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 137, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 * -4 + 5) + (-1 - -5 - 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-7 * -4 + 5) and B = (-1 - -5 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * -4 + 5) = ((-7 * -4) + 5) = (28 + 5) = 33.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - -5 - 1) = ((-1 - -5) - 1) = (4 - 1) = 3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (33 + 3) = 36.\n(Final response) So the answer is 36.", "correct_answer": "36", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 129, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + -1 + 0 + 3) + (-6 * 8 - -1 * -3)) - ((5 - -1 * -1 * -6) - (7 - -4 * 0 - -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (7 + -1 + 0 + 3), B = (-6 * 8 - -1 * -3), C = (5 - -1 * -1 * -6) and D = (7 - -4 * 0 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -1 + 0 + 3) = (((7 + -1) + 0) + 3) = ((6 + 0) + 3) = (6 + 3) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 8 - -1 * -3) = ((-6 * 8) - (-1 * -3)) = (-48 - (-1 * -3)) = (-48 - 3) = -51.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 - -1 * -1 * -6) = (5 - ((-1 * -1) * -6)) = (5 - (1 * -6)) = (5 - -6) = 11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 - -4 * 0 - -4) = ((7 - (-4 * 0)) - -4) = ((7 - 0) - -4) = (7 - -4) = 11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((9 + -51) - (11 - 11)) = (-42 - (11 - 11)) = (-42 - 0) = -42.\n(Final response) So the answer is -42.", "correct_answer": "-42", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 156, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - -1 - 6 - 8 + 2 - -8) + (4 + 9 * -6 - 2 - -4 - -7)) * ((-8 + -9 - 8 - 4 + 3 * 5) + (-6 + -7 - 2 * -3 + 2 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (6 - -1 - 6 - 8 + 2 - -8), B = (4 + 9 * -6 - 2 - -4 - -7), C = (-8 + -9 - 8 - 4 + 3 * 5) and D = (-6 + -7 - 2 * -3 + 2 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -1 - 6 - 8 + 2 - -8) = (((((6 - -1) - 6) - 8) + 2) - -8) = ((((7 - 6) - 8) + 2) - -8) = (((1 - 8) + 2) - -8) = ((-7 + 2) - -8) = (-5 - -8) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 9 * -6 - 2 - -4 - -7) = ((((4 + (9 * -6)) - 2) - -4) - -7) = ((((4 + -54) - 2) - -4) - -7) = (((-50 - 2) - -4) - -7) = ((-52 - -4) - -7) = (-48 - -7) = -41.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 + -9 - 8 - 4 + 3 * 5) = ((((-8 + -9) - 8) - 4) + (3 * 5)) = (((-17 - 8) - 4) + (3 * 5)) = (((-17 - 8) - 4) + 15) = ((-25 - 4) + 15) = (-29 + 15) = -14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + -7 - 2 * -3 + 2 * 5) = (((-6 + -7) - (2 * -3)) + (2 * 5)) = ((-13 - (2 * -3)) + (2 * 5)) = ((-13 - -6) + (2 * 5)) = ((-13 - -6) + 10) = (-7 + 10) = 3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((3 + -41) * (-14 + 3)) = (-38 * (-14 + 3)) = (-38 * -11) = 418.\n(Final response) So the answer is 418.", "correct_answer": "418", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 212, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 * -2 + 3 + -3) + (-1 + -2 + 4 * 3)) * ((-6 + -9 * 6 * -3) - (-1 - -2 - 5 + -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-7 * -2 + 3 + -3), B = (-1 + -2 + 4 * 3), C = (-6 + -9 * 6 * -3) and D = (-1 - -2 - 5 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * -2 + 3 + -3) = (((-7 * -2) + 3) + -3) = ((14 + 3) + -3) = (17 + -3) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -2 + 4 * 3) = ((-1 + -2) + (4 * 3)) = (-3 + (4 * 3)) = (-3 + 12) = 9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -9 * 6 * -3) = (-6 + ((-9 * 6) * -3)) = (-6 + (-54 * -3)) = (-6 + 162) = 156.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 - -2 - 5 + -5) = (((-1 - -2) - 5) + -5) = ((1 - 5) + -5) = (-4 + -5) = -9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((14 + 9) * (156 - -9)) = (23 * (156 - -9)) = (23 * 165) = 3795.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3795.", "correct_answer": "3795", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 493, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 * 3 * -2) * (7 + 3 - 7)) * ((-7 + -4 - 0) - (3 - -4 - -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (2 * 3 * -2), B = (7 + 3 - 7), C = (-7 + -4 - 0) and D = (3 - -4 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 3 * -2) = ((2 * 3) * -2) = (6 * -2) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 3 - 7) = ((7 + 3) - 7) = (10 - 7) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + -4 - 0) = ((-7 + -4) - 0) = (-11 - 0) = -11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 - -4 - -5) = ((3 - -4) - -5) = (7 - -5) = 12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((-12 * 3) * (-11 - 12)) = (-36 * (-11 - 12)) = (-36 * -23) = 828.\n(Final response) So the answer is 828.", "correct_answer": "828", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 422, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 * -6 + -4) + (-9 + -5 * -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-3 * -6 + -4) and B = (-9 + -5 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * -6 + -4) = ((-3 * -6) + -4) = (18 + -4) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + -5 * -9) = (-9 + (-5 * -9)) = (-9 + 45) = 36.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (14 + 36) = 50.\n(Final response) So the answer is 50.", "correct_answer": "50", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 88, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * 4 * 4 - 7) + (-4 * -3 + -9 - -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-9 * 4 * 4 - 7) and B = (-4 * -3 + -9 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 4 * 4 - 7) = (((-9 * 4) * 4) - 7) = ((-36 * 4) - 7) = (-144 - 7) = -151.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * -3 + -9 - -5) = (((-4 * -3) + -9) - -5) = ((12 + -9) - -5) = (3 - -5) = 8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-151 + 8) = -143.\n(Final response) So the answer is -143.", "correct_answer": "-143", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 200, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-5 + 7 - 6 - -8 * 5 * -7) - (5 - 1 * -1 + -9 - 3 - -8)) + ((-1 * 1 - -6 + 5 - -5 - -2) - (-4 - 1 - 2 * 5 - -8 + 6))) + (((6 + 9 + 2 * -6 * 2 * -2) - (5 + 7 + -5 * 6 + 1 - -5)) * ((7 + 5 * 1 * 8 + -7 - -8) + (1 - -1 - 1 + 5 + 2 + -4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C - D)) + ((E - F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (-5 + 7 - 6 - -8 * 5 * -7), B = (5 - 1 * -1 + -9 - 3 - -8), C = (-1 * 1 - -6 + 5 - -5 - -2), D = (-4 - 1 - 2 * 5 - -8 + 6), E = (6 + 9 + 2 * -6 * 2 * -2), F = (5 + 7 + -5 * 6 + 1 - -5), G = (7 + 5 * 1 * 8 + -7 - -8) and H = (1 - -1 - 1 + 5 + 2 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + 7 - 6 - -8 * 5 * -7) = (((-5 + 7) - 6) - ((-8 * 5) * -7)) = ((2 - 6) - ((-8 * 5) * -7)) = ((2 - 6) - (-40 * -7)) = (-4 - (-40 * -7)) = (-4 - 280) = -284.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 1 * -1 + -9 - 3 - -8) = ((((5 - (1 * -1)) + -9) - 3) - -8) = ((((5 - -1) + -9) - 3) - -8) = (((6 + -9) - 3) - -8) = ((-3 - 3) - -8) = (-6 - -8) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * 1 - -6 + 5 - -5 - -2) = (((((-1 * 1) - -6) + 5) - -5) - -2) = ((((-1 - -6) + 5) - -5) - -2) = (((5 + 5) - -5) - -2) = ((10 - -5) - -2) = (15 - -2) = 17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - 1 - 2 * 5 - -8 + 6) = ((((-4 - 1) - (2 * 5)) - -8) + 6) = (((-5 - (2 * 5)) - -8) + 6) = (((-5 - 10) - -8) + 6) = ((-15 - -8) + 6) = (-7 + 6) = -1.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (6 + 9 + 2 * -6 * 2 * -2) = ((6 + 9) + (((2 * -6) * 2) * -2)) = (15 + (((2 * -6) * 2) * -2)) = (15 + ((-12 * 2) * -2)) = (15 + (-24 * -2)) = (15 + 48) = 63.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 + 7 + -5 * 6 + 1 - -5) = ((((5 + 7) + (-5 * 6)) + 1) - -5) = (((12 + (-5 * 6)) + 1) - -5) = (((12 + -30) + 1) - -5) = ((-18 + 1) - -5) = (-17 - -5) = -12.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 + 5 * 1 * 8 + -7 - -8) = (((7 + ((5 * 1) * 8)) + -7) - -8) = (((7 + (5 * 8)) + -7) - -8) = (((7 + 40) + -7) - -8) = ((47 + -7) - -8) = (40 - -8) = 48.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (1 - -1 - 1 + 5 + 2 + -4) = (((((1 - -1) - 1) + 5) + 2) + -4) = ((((2 - 1) + 5) + 2) + -4) = (((1 + 5) + 2) + -4) = ((6 + 2) + -4) = (8 + -4) = 4.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C - D)) + ((E - F) * (G + H))) = (((-284 - 2) + (17 - -1)) + ((63 - -12) * (48 + 4))) = ((-286 + (17 - -1)) + ((63 - -12) * (48 + 4))) = ((-286 + 18) + ((63 - -12) * (48 + 4))) = ((-286 + 18) + (75 * (48 + 4))) = ((-286 + 18) + (75 * 52)) = (-268 + (75 * 52)) = (-268 + 3900) = 3632.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3632.", "correct_answer": "3632", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 356, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((0 - 6 + -9 - -1 + 1 - -8) - (9 + -3 + -6 * -6 * 9 + 0)) + ((-1 - 3 + -6 - -6 - 1 - 9) - (3 + 1 - 9 - 9 - -5 * 1))) + (((0 - -8 * 8 - -1 + -3 * -6) + (6 - -9 + -5 * -6 * -9 - -8)) * ((9 * 6 - -9 + -7 + -2 - 9) - (0 * -6 + -1 + -5 * 4 - -2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C - D)) + ((E + F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (0 - 6 + -9 - -1 + 1 - -8), B = (9 + -3 + -6 * -6 * 9 + 0), C = (-1 - 3 + -6 - -6 - 1 - 9), D = (3 + 1 - 9 - 9 - -5 * 1), E = (0 - -8 * 8 - -1 + -3 * -6), F = (6 - -9 + -5 * -6 * -9 - -8), G = (9 * 6 - -9 + -7 + -2 - 9) and H = (0 * -6 + -1 + -5 * 4 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - 6 + -9 - -1 + 1 - -8) = (((((0 - 6) + -9) - -1) + 1) - -8) = ((((-6 + -9) - -1) + 1) - -8) = (((-15 - -1) + 1) - -8) = ((-14 + 1) - -8) = (-13 - -8) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + -3 + -6 * -6 * 9 + 0) = (((9 + -3) + ((-6 * -6) * 9)) + 0) = ((6 + ((-6 * -6) * 9)) + 0) = ((6 + (36 * 9)) + 0) = ((6 + 324) + 0) = (330 + 0) = 330.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 - 3 + -6 - -6 - 1 - 9) = (((((-1 - 3) + -6) - -6) - 1) - 9) = ((((-4 + -6) - -6) - 1) - 9) = (((-10 - -6) - 1) - 9) = ((-4 - 1) - 9) = (-5 - 9) = -14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + 1 - 9 - 9 - -5 * 1) = ((((3 + 1) - 9) - 9) - (-5 * 1)) = (((4 - 9) - 9) - (-5 * 1)) = (((4 - 9) - 9) - -5) = ((-5 - 9) - -5) = (-14 - -5) = -9.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 - -8 * 8 - -1 + -3 * -6) = (((0 - (-8 * 8)) - -1) + (-3 * -6)) = (((0 - -64) - -1) + (-3 * -6)) = (((0 - -64) - -1) + 18) = ((64 - -1) + 18) = (65 + 18) = 83.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (6 - -9 + -5 * -6 * -9 - -8) = (((6 - -9) + ((-5 * -6) * -9)) - -8) = ((15 + ((-5 * -6) * -9)) - -8) = ((15 + (30 * -9)) - -8) = ((15 + -270) - -8) = (-255 - -8) = -247.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (9 * 6 - -9 + -7 + -2 - 9) = (((((9 * 6) - -9) + -7) + -2) - 9) = ((((54 - -9) + -7) + -2) - 9) = (((63 + -7) + -2) - 9) = ((56 + -2) - 9) = (54 - 9) = 45.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (0 * -6 + -1 + -5 * 4 - -2) = ((((0 * -6) + -1) + (-5 * 4)) - -2) = (((0 + -1) + (-5 * 4)) - -2) = (((0 + -1) + -20) - -2) = ((-1 + -20) - -2) = (-21 - -2) = -19.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C - D)) + ((E + F) * (G - H))) = (((-5 - 330) + (-14 - -9)) + ((83 + -247) * (45 - -19))) = ((-335 + (-14 - -9)) + ((83 + -247) * (45 - -19))) = ((-335 + -5) + ((83 + -247) * (45 - -19))) = ((-335 + -5) + (-164 * (45 - -19))) = ((-335 + -5) + (-164 * 64)) = (-340 + (-164 * 64)) = (-340 + -10496) = -10836.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10836.", "correct_answer": "-10836", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 341, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 - -9 + -6 - -4) - (-7 * 7 + -1 * -5)) + ((-4 - -9 + 7 - 5) + (7 + 1 - 7 + -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (5 - -9 + -6 - -4), B = (-7 * 7 + -1 * -5), C = (-4 - -9 + 7 - 5) and D = (7 + 1 - 7 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - -9 + -6 - -4) = (((5 - -9) + -6) - -4) = ((14 + -6) - -4) = (8 - -4) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 7 + -1 * -5) = ((-7 * 7) + (-1 * -5)) = (-49 + (-1 * -5)) = (-49 + 5) = -44.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - -9 + 7 - 5) = (((-4 - -9) + 7) - 5) = ((5 + 7) - 5) = (12 - 5) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + 1 - 7 + -9) = (((7 + 1) - 7) + -9) = ((8 - 7) + -9) = (1 + -9) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((12 - -44) + (7 + -8)) = (56 + (7 + -8)) = (56 + -1) = 55.\n(Final response) So the answer is 55.", "correct_answer": "55", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 494, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 - -2 + -1) - (-9 + 5 - -6)) * ((-9 + 2 * 9) * (0 + -7 - 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (3 - -2 + -1), B = (-9 + 5 - -6), C = (-9 + 2 * 9) and D = (0 + -7 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - -2 + -1) = ((3 - -2) + -1) = (5 + -1) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 5 - -6) = ((-9 + 5) - -6) = (-4 - -6) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + 2 * 9) = (-9 + (2 * 9)) = (-9 + 18) = 9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + -7 - 5) = ((0 + -7) - 5) = (-7 - 5) = -12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((4 - 2) * (9 * -12)) = (2 * (9 * -12)) = (2 * -108) = -216.\n(Final response) So the answer is -216.", "correct_answer": "-216", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 143, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 + -9 * -9) + (6 * -6 * 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-8 + -9 * -9) and B = (6 * -6 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + -9 * -9) = (-8 + (-9 * -9)) = (-8 + 81) = 73.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -6 * 7) = ((6 * -6) * 7) = (-36 * 7) = -252.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (73 + -252) = -179.\n(Final response) So the answer is -179.", "correct_answer": "-179", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 26, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 + -3 * 6 + -5) - (-2 + -7 - 7 - -7)) + ((-8 * 4 + 7 - 5) + (9 + -6 + -2 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-9 + -3 * 6 + -5), B = (-2 + -7 - 7 - -7), C = (-8 * 4 + 7 - 5) and D = (9 + -6 + -2 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -3 * 6 + -5) = ((-9 + (-3 * 6)) + -5) = ((-9 + -18) + -5) = (-27 + -5) = -32.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + -7 - 7 - -7) = (((-2 + -7) - 7) - -7) = ((-9 - 7) - -7) = (-16 - -7) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * 4 + 7 - 5) = (((-8 * 4) + 7) - 5) = ((-32 + 7) - 5) = (-25 - 5) = -30.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -6 + -2 * 5) = ((9 + -6) + (-2 * 5)) = (3 + (-2 * 5)) = (3 + -10) = -7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-32 - -9) + (-30 + -7)) = (-23 + (-30 + -7)) = (-23 + -37) = -60.\n(Final response) So the answer is -60.", "correct_answer": "-60", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 585, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 - 3 + 5) - (2 - 3 - 1)) * ((0 * -4 + -4) + (-3 - 2 * -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (7 - 3 + 5), B = (2 - 3 - 1), C = (0 * -4 + -4) and D = (-3 - 2 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - 3 + 5) = ((7 - 3) + 5) = (4 + 5) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - 3 - 1) = ((2 - 3) - 1) = (-1 - 1) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * -4 + -4) = ((0 * -4) + -4) = (0 + -4) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 - 2 * -8) = (-3 - (2 * -8)) = (-3 - -16) = 13.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((9 - -2) * (-4 + 13)) = (11 * (-4 + 13)) = (11 * 9) = 99.\n(Final response) So the answer is 99.", "correct_answer": "99", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 404, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 + -7 * -5 * 2) + (-1 * -6 * 9 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (9 + -7 * -5 * 2) and B = (-1 * -6 * 9 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + -7 * -5 * 2) = (9 + ((-7 * -5) * 2)) = (9 + (35 * 2)) = (9 + 70) = 79.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * -6 * 9 - 3) = (((-1 * -6) * 9) - 3) = ((6 * 9) - 3) = (54 - 3) = 51.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (79 + 51) = 130.\n(Final response) So the answer is 130.", "correct_answer": "130", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 289, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 - -4 * 6 * -5) - (-3 - -9 - 4 * 6)) - ((-3 - 0 - 3 + -9) * (6 + -3 * -7 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-1 - -4 * 6 * -5), B = (-3 - -9 - 4 * 6), C = (-3 - 0 - 3 + -9) and D = (6 + -3 * -7 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - -4 * 6 * -5) = (-1 - ((-4 * 6) * -5)) = (-1 - (-24 * -5)) = (-1 - 120) = -121.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - -9 - 4 * 6) = ((-3 - -9) - (4 * 6)) = (6 - (4 * 6)) = (6 - 24) = -18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - 0 - 3 + -9) = (((-3 - 0) - 3) + -9) = ((-3 - 3) + -9) = (-6 + -9) = -15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + -3 * -7 + -8) = ((6 + (-3 * -7)) + -8) = ((6 + 21) + -8) = (27 + -8) = 19.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((-121 - -18) - (-15 * 19)) = (-103 - (-15 * 19)) = (-103 - -285) = 182.\n(Final response) So the answer is 182.", "correct_answer": "182", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 477, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * -3 + 3) - (9 + 2 - -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 * -3 + 3) and B = (9 + 2 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * -3 + 3) = ((7 * -3) + 3) = (-21 + 3) = -18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + 2 - -3) = ((9 + 2) - -3) = (11 - -3) = 14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-18 - 14) = -32.\n(Final response) So the answer is -32.", "correct_answer": "-32", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 50, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 + -2 * 8) * (-6 * 3 - -5)) - ((-2 + 9 * 7) + (-8 * 6 - 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (9 + -2 * 8), B = (-6 * 3 - -5), C = (-2 + 9 * 7) and D = (-8 * 6 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + -2 * 8) = (9 + (-2 * 8)) = (9 + -16) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 3 - -5) = ((-6 * 3) - -5) = (-18 - -5) = -13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + 9 * 7) = (-2 + (9 * 7)) = (-2 + 63) = 61.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 * 6 - 8) = ((-8 * 6) - 8) = (-48 - 8) = -56.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-7 * -13) - (61 + -56)) = (91 - (61 + -56)) = (91 - 5) = 86.\n(Final response) So the answer is 86.", "correct_answer": "86", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 449, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 * -6 * 9 * 5 - -9) - (9 - -7 + -1 - 1 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 * -6 * 9 * 5 - -9) and B = (9 - -7 + -1 - 1 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * -6 * 9 * 5 - -9) = ((((0 * -6) * 9) * 5) - -9) = (((0 * 9) * 5) - -9) = ((0 * 5) - -9) = (0 - -9) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - -7 + -1 - 1 - 2) = ((((9 - -7) + -1) - 1) - 2) = (((16 + -1) - 1) - 2) = ((15 - 1) - 2) = (14 - 2) = 12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (9 - 12) = -3.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3.", "correct_answer": "-3", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 76, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 + 8 - 8) - (5 * -4 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 + 8 - 8) and B = (5 * -4 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 8 - 8) = ((7 + 8) - 8) = (15 - 8) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * -4 * 3) = ((5 * -4) * 3) = (-20 * 3) = -60.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (7 - -60) = 67.\n(Final response) So the answer is 67.", "correct_answer": "67", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 147, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 + 2 - 8) - (-8 - -8 * -2)) * ((2 + 7 + 5) - (-3 - -6 - 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (6 + 2 - 8), B = (-8 - -8 * -2), C = (2 + 7 + 5) and D = (-3 - -6 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 2 - 8) = ((6 + 2) - 8) = (8 - 8) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - -8 * -2) = (-8 - (-8 * -2)) = (-8 - 16) = -24.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + 7 + 5) = ((2 + 7) + 5) = (9 + 5) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 - -6 - 4) = ((-3 - -6) - 4) = (3 - 4) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((0 - -24) * (14 - -1)) = (24 * (14 - -1)) = (24 * 15) = 360.\n(Final response) So the answer is 360.", "correct_answer": "360", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 435, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 - -8 * -3) * (-6 + -3 + 7)) + ((4 - 3 + 7) * (8 * -6 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (8 - -8 * -3), B = (-6 + -3 + 7), C = (4 - 3 + 7) and D = (8 * -6 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - -8 * -3) = (8 - (-8 * -3)) = (8 - 24) = -16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -3 + 7) = ((-6 + -3) + 7) = (-9 + 7) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - 3 + 7) = ((4 - 3) + 7) = (1 + 7) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * -6 * 0) = ((8 * -6) * 0) = (-48 * 0) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((-16 * -2) + (8 * 0)) = (32 + (8 * 0)) = (32 + 0) = 32.\n(Final response) So the answer is 32.", "correct_answer": "32", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 142, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 - -1 * 9) + (7 + 4 * 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-9 - -1 * 9) and B = (7 + 4 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - -1 * 9) = (-9 - (-1 * 9)) = (-9 - -9) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 4 * 6) = (7 + (4 * 6)) = (7 + 24) = 31.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (0 + 31) = 31.\n(Final response) So the answer is 31.", "correct_answer": "31", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 148, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 * 4 - 6 * 4 * -6 + -3) - (-1 * -1 - 7 + 5 * 7 + 0)) * ((9 * 4 + -9 + 8 * -3 * -6) * (-9 - -3 + -4 + 8 - 3 + -9))) + (((4 * 9 + -1 + 4 * -8 * 9) * (4 * -4 + -2 - -9 - 3 + -2)) - ((9 * -7 * 9 - 8 + 2 + 3) - (-1 * -4 + -3 * -5 - -8 + 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C * D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (2 * 4 - 6 * 4 * -6 + -3), B = (-1 * -1 - 7 + 5 * 7 + 0), C = (9 * 4 + -9 + 8 * -3 * -6), D = (-9 - -3 + -4 + 8 - 3 + -9), E = (4 * 9 + -1 + 4 * -8 * 9), F = (4 * -4 + -2 - -9 - 3 + -2), G = (9 * -7 * 9 - 8 + 2 + 3) and H = (-1 * -4 + -3 * -5 - -8 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 4 - 6 * 4 * -6 + -3) = (((2 * 4) - ((6 * 4) * -6)) + -3) = ((8 - ((6 * 4) * -6)) + -3) = ((8 - (24 * -6)) + -3) = ((8 - -144) + -3) = (152 + -3) = 149.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * -1 - 7 + 5 * 7 + 0) = ((((-1 * -1) - 7) + (5 * 7)) + 0) = (((1 - 7) + (5 * 7)) + 0) = (((1 - 7) + 35) + 0) = ((-6 + 35) + 0) = (29 + 0) = 29.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 * 4 + -9 + 8 * -3 * -6) = (((9 * 4) + -9) + ((8 * -3) * -6)) = ((36 + -9) + ((8 * -3) * -6)) = ((36 + -9) + (-24 * -6)) = (27 + (-24 * -6)) = (27 + 144) = 171.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 - -3 + -4 + 8 - 3 + -9) = (((((-9 - -3) + -4) + 8) - 3) + -9) = ((((-6 + -4) + 8) - 3) + -9) = (((-10 + 8) - 3) + -9) = ((-2 - 3) + -9) = (-5 + -9) = -14.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (4 * 9 + -1 + 4 * -8 * 9) = (((4 * 9) + -1) + ((4 * -8) * 9)) = ((36 + -1) + ((4 * -8) * 9)) = ((36 + -1) + (-32 * 9)) = (35 + (-32 * 9)) = (35 + -288) = -253.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (4 * -4 + -2 - -9 - 3 + -2) = (((((4 * -4) + -2) - -9) - 3) + -2) = ((((-16 + -2) - -9) - 3) + -2) = (((-18 - -9) - 3) + -2) = ((-9 - 3) + -2) = (-12 + -2) = -14.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (9 * -7 * 9 - 8 + 2 + 3) = (((((9 * -7) * 9) - 8) + 2) + 3) = ((((-63 * 9) - 8) + 2) + 3) = (((-567 - 8) + 2) + 3) = ((-575 + 2) + 3) = (-573 + 3) = -570.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-1 * -4 + -3 * -5 - -8 + 3) = ((((-1 * -4) + (-3 * -5)) - -8) + 3) = (((4 + (-3 * -5)) - -8) + 3) = (((4 + 15) - -8) + 3) = ((19 - -8) + 3) = (27 + 3) = 30.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C * D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H))) = (((149 - 29) * (171 * -14)) + ((-253 * -14) - (-570 - 30))) = ((120 * (171 * -14)) + ((-253 * -14) - (-570 - 30))) = ((120 * -2394) + ((-253 * -14) - (-570 - 30))) = ((120 * -2394) + (3542 - (-570 - 30))) = ((120 * -2394) + (3542 - -600)) = (-287280 + (3542 - -600)) = (-287280 + 4142) = -283138.\n(Final response) So the answer is -283138.", "correct_answer": "-283138", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 335, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 - -6 * -9) + (2 * -9 - 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-5 - -6 * -9) and B = (2 * -9 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -6 * -9) = (-5 - (-6 * -9)) = (-5 - 54) = -59.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * -9 - 4) = ((2 * -9) - 4) = (-18 - 4) = -22.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-59 + -22) = -81.\n(Final response) So the answer is -81.", "correct_answer": "-81", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 79, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 * 9 + 1 + 5 * -2 - 1) + (6 * -4 * -4 - -4 - -5 * -1)) * ((7 * 2 - 1 - 1 * 4 - -8) + (4 + 0 - 8 - -1 + -8 - -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (6 * 9 + 1 + 5 * -2 - 1), B = (6 * -4 * -4 - -4 - -5 * -1), C = (7 * 2 - 1 - 1 * 4 - -8) and D = (4 + 0 - 8 - -1 + -8 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * 9 + 1 + 5 * -2 - 1) = ((((6 * 9) + 1) + (5 * -2)) - 1) = (((54 + 1) + (5 * -2)) - 1) = (((54 + 1) + -10) - 1) = ((55 + -10) - 1) = (45 - 1) = 44.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -4 * -4 - -4 - -5 * -1) = ((((6 * -4) * -4) - -4) - (-5 * -1)) = (((-24 * -4) - -4) - (-5 * -1)) = (((-24 * -4) - -4) - 5) = ((96 - -4) - 5) = (100 - 5) = 95.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 * 2 - 1 - 1 * 4 - -8) = ((((7 * 2) - 1) - (1 * 4)) - -8) = (((14 - 1) - (1 * 4)) - -8) = (((14 - 1) - 4) - -8) = ((13 - 4) - -8) = (9 - -8) = 17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + 0 - 8 - -1 + -8 - -9) = (((((4 + 0) - 8) - -1) + -8) - -9) = ((((4 - 8) - -1) + -8) - -9) = (((-4 - -1) + -8) - -9) = ((-3 + -8) - -9) = (-11 - -9) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((44 + 95) * (17 + -2)) = (139 * (17 + -2)) = (139 * 15) = 2085.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2085.", "correct_answer": "2085", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 215, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 * 9 * 8 + 7) - (1 + 2 + -4 + -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (8 * 9 * 8 + 7) and B = (1 + 2 + -4 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 9 * 8 + 7) = (((8 * 9) * 8) + 7) = ((72 * 8) + 7) = (576 + 7) = 583.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + 2 + -4 + -5) = (((1 + 2) + -4) + -5) = ((3 + -4) + -5) = (-1 + -5) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (583 - -6) = 589.\n(Final response) So the answer is 589.", "correct_answer": "589", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 188, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 - 4 + 5 * 3 - 3) - (-3 * 6 - -4 - -6 * -9)) * ((9 + 4 * 9 - 3 - 6) - (6 - -1 + -7 * 8 - -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-6 - 4 + 5 * 3 - 3), B = (-3 * 6 - -4 - -6 * -9), C = (9 + 4 * 9 - 3 - 6) and D = (6 - -1 + -7 * 8 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 4 + 5 * 3 - 3) = (((-6 - 4) + (5 * 3)) - 3) = ((-10 + (5 * 3)) - 3) = ((-10 + 15) - 3) = (5 - 3) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * 6 - -4 - -6 * -9) = (((-3 * 6) - -4) - (-6 * -9)) = ((-18 - -4) - (-6 * -9)) = ((-18 - -4) - 54) = (-14 - 54) = -68.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 + 4 * 9 - 3 - 6) = (((9 + (4 * 9)) - 3) - 6) = (((9 + 36) - 3) - 6) = ((45 - 3) - 6) = (42 - 6) = 36.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 - -1 + -7 * 8 - -8) = (((6 - -1) + (-7 * 8)) - -8) = ((7 + (-7 * 8)) - -8) = ((7 + -56) - -8) = (-49 - -8) = -41.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((2 - -68) * (36 - -41)) = (70 * (36 - -41)) = (70 * 77) = 5390.\n(Final response) So the answer is 5390.", "correct_answer": "5390", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 201, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 - 0 - -1) + (-5 * 2 + 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (6 - 0 - -1) and B = (-5 * 2 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - 0 - -1) = ((6 - 0) - -1) = (6 - -1) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 2 + 1) = ((-5 * 2) + 1) = (-10 + 1) = -9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (7 + -9) = -2.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2.", "correct_answer": "-2", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 12, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 * -7 - -8 * 8 * 7) - (0 * -6 * 6 * 7 - 9)) - ((8 * -8 * -4 - -9 * 1) * (-6 + 9 + -4 - -1 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (6 * -7 - -8 * 8 * 7), B = (0 * -6 * 6 * 7 - 9), C = (8 * -8 * -4 - -9 * 1) and D = (-6 + 9 + -4 - -1 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * -7 - -8 * 8 * 7) = ((6 * -7) - ((-8 * 8) * 7)) = (-42 - ((-8 * 8) * 7)) = (-42 - (-64 * 7)) = (-42 - -448) = 406.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * -6 * 6 * 7 - 9) = ((((0 * -6) * 6) * 7) - 9) = (((0 * 6) * 7) - 9) = ((0 * 7) - 9) = (0 - 9) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -8 * -4 - -9 * 1) = (((8 * -8) * -4) - (-9 * 1)) = ((-64 * -4) - (-9 * 1)) = ((-64 * -4) - -9) = (256 - -9) = 265.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + 9 + -4 - -1 * 0) = (((-6 + 9) + -4) - (-1 * 0)) = ((3 + -4) - (-1 * 0)) = ((3 + -4) - 0) = (-1 - 0) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((406 - -9) - (265 * -1)) = (415 - (265 * -1)) = (415 - -265) = 680.\n(Final response) So the answer is 680.", "correct_answer": "680", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 189, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 * -2 + -6 - 1) + (-2 - -8 + -6 + -3)) - ((-5 - 2 + -4 + -7) * (-3 * 2 + -9 - -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-4 * -2 + -6 - 1), B = (-2 - -8 + -6 + -3), C = (-5 - 2 + -4 + -7) and D = (-3 * 2 + -9 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -2 + -6 - 1) = (((-4 * -2) + -6) - 1) = ((8 + -6) - 1) = (2 - 1) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - -8 + -6 + -3) = (((-2 - -8) + -6) + -3) = ((6 + -6) + -3) = (0 + -3) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - 2 + -4 + -7) = (((-5 - 2) + -4) + -7) = ((-7 + -4) + -7) = (-11 + -7) = -18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * 2 + -9 - -8) = (((-3 * 2) + -9) - -8) = ((-6 + -9) - -8) = (-15 - -8) = -7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((1 + -3) - (-18 * -7)) = (-2 - (-18 * -7)) = (-2 - 126) = -128.\n(Final response) So the answer is -128.", "correct_answer": "-128", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 560, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 - 0 - -6 - 2 + 1) * (1 * -6 + 3 * -4 * -2)) - ((-8 + 0 + 9 + 6 - -2) - (1 + -3 - -7 + -3 - -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (0 - 0 - -6 - 2 + 1), B = (1 * -6 + 3 * -4 * -2), C = (-8 + 0 + 9 + 6 - -2) and D = (1 + -3 - -7 + -3 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - 0 - -6 - 2 + 1) = ((((0 - 0) - -6) - 2) + 1) = (((0 - -6) - 2) + 1) = ((6 - 2) + 1) = (4 + 1) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -6 + 3 * -4 * -2) = ((1 * -6) + ((3 * -4) * -2)) = (-6 + ((3 * -4) * -2)) = (-6 + (-12 * -2)) = (-6 + 24) = 18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 + 0 + 9 + 6 - -2) = ((((-8 + 0) + 9) + 6) - -2) = (((-8 + 9) + 6) - -2) = ((1 + 6) - -2) = (7 - -2) = 9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + -3 - -7 + -3 - -7) = ((((1 + -3) - -7) + -3) - -7) = (((-2 - -7) + -3) - -7) = ((5 + -3) - -7) = (2 - -7) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((5 * 18) - (9 - 9)) = (90 - (9 - 9)) = (90 - 0) = 90.\n(Final response) So the answer is 90.", "correct_answer": "90", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 190, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 * -9 - 6 * 8) - (3 - -4 + 6 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 * -9 - 6 * 8) and B = (3 - -4 + 6 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * -9 - 6 * 8) = ((0 * -9) - (6 * 8)) = (0 - (6 * 8)) = (0 - 48) = -48.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - -4 + 6 * -3) = ((3 - -4) + (6 * -3)) = (7 + (6 * -3)) = (7 + -18) = -11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-48 - -11) = -37.\n(Final response) So the answer is -37.", "correct_answer": "-37", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 49, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 + 6 * 8) + (-6 + -8 + -1)) - ((1 + -4 + 6) - (-3 * -4 * 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (9 + 6 * 8), B = (-6 + -8 + -1), C = (1 + -4 + 6) and D = (-3 * -4 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + 6 * 8) = (9 + (6 * 8)) = (9 + 48) = 57.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -8 + -1) = ((-6 + -8) + -1) = (-14 + -1) = -15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 + -4 + 6) = ((1 + -4) + 6) = (-3 + 6) = 3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * -4 * 7) = ((-3 * -4) * 7) = (12 * 7) = 84.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((57 + -15) - (3 - 84)) = (42 - (3 - 84)) = (42 - -81) = 123.\n(Final response) So the answer is 123.", "correct_answer": "123", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 140, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 - -5 - -4 * 6 * -2 + -6) + (-7 + -3 + 7 * 7 - -5 + 1)) - ((-4 * -9 * -7 - 8 + -9 + -5) * (8 + 3 - 6 - -1 * 6 - 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (7 - -5 - -4 * 6 * -2 + -6), B = (-7 + -3 + 7 * 7 - -5 + 1), C = (-4 * -9 * -7 - 8 + -9 + -5) and D = (8 + 3 - 6 - -1 * 6 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -5 - -4 * 6 * -2 + -6) = (((7 - -5) - ((-4 * 6) * -2)) + -6) = ((12 - ((-4 * 6) * -2)) + -6) = ((12 - (-24 * -2)) + -6) = ((12 - 48) + -6) = (-36 + -6) = -42.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -3 + 7 * 7 - -5 + 1) = ((((-7 + -3) + (7 * 7)) - -5) + 1) = (((-10 + (7 * 7)) - -5) + 1) = (((-10 + 49) - -5) + 1) = ((39 - -5) + 1) = (44 + 1) = 45.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 * -9 * -7 - 8 + -9 + -5) = (((((-4 * -9) * -7) - 8) + -9) + -5) = ((((36 * -7) - 8) + -9) + -5) = (((-252 - 8) + -9) + -5) = ((-260 + -9) + -5) = (-269 + -5) = -274.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 + 3 - 6 - -1 * 6 - 2) = ((((8 + 3) - 6) - (-1 * 6)) - 2) = (((11 - 6) - (-1 * 6)) - 2) = (((11 - 6) - -6) - 2) = ((5 - -6) - 2) = (11 - 2) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-42 + 45) - (-274 * 9)) = (3 - (-274 * 9)) = (3 - -2466) = 2469.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2469.", "correct_answer": "2469", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 210, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 + 5 + -3) * (6 - -7 + -2)) - ((-7 * -8 * 9) + (-5 + 7 - -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-3 + 5 + -3), B = (6 - -7 + -2), C = (-7 * -8 * 9) and D = (-5 + 7 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 5 + -3) = ((-3 + 5) + -3) = (2 + -3) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - -7 + -2) = ((6 - -7) + -2) = (13 + -2) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * -8 * 9) = ((-7 * -8) * 9) = (56 * 9) = 504.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 + 7 - -1) = ((-5 + 7) - -1) = (2 - -1) = 3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-1 * 11) - (504 + 3)) = (-11 - (504 + 3)) = (-11 - 507) = -518.\n(Final response) So the answer is -518.", "correct_answer": "-518", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 316, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 - -8 * 0) - (7 + -1 * 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (5 - -8 * 0) and B = (7 + -1 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - -8 * 0) = (5 - (-8 * 0)) = (5 - 0) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + -1 * 6) = (7 + (-1 * 6)) = (7 + -6) = 1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (5 - 1) = 4.\n(Final response) So the answer is 4.", "correct_answer": "4", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 29, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + 0 + 2) - (4 + -9 + 6)) * ((-5 + 8 + -4) + (8 - 5 * 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (1 + 0 + 2), B = (4 + -9 + 6), C = (-5 + 8 + -4) and D = (8 - 5 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 0 + 2) = ((1 + 0) + 2) = (1 + 2) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + -9 + 6) = ((4 + -9) + 6) = (-5 + 6) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 + 8 + -4) = ((-5 + 8) + -4) = (3 + -4) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - 5 * 1) = (8 - (5 * 1)) = (8 - 5) = 3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((3 - 1) * (-1 + 3)) = (2 * (-1 + 3)) = (2 * 2) = 4.\n(Final response) So the answer is 4.", "correct_answer": "4", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 333, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 - 7 - 2 + -9) * (3 + -9 - 6 * 0)) + ((-1 - 5 * 0 + 6) + (9 + -6 - 6 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (9 - 7 - 2 + -9), B = (3 + -9 - 6 * 0), C = (-1 - 5 * 0 + 6) and D = (9 + -6 - 6 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - 7 - 2 + -9) = (((9 - 7) - 2) + -9) = ((2 - 2) + -9) = (0 + -9) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + -9 - 6 * 0) = ((3 + -9) - (6 * 0)) = (-6 - (6 * 0)) = (-6 - 0) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 - 5 * 0 + 6) = ((-1 - (5 * 0)) + 6) = ((-1 - 0) + 6) = (-1 + 6) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -6 - 6 * 5) = ((9 + -6) - (6 * 5)) = (3 - (6 * 5)) = (3 - 30) = -27.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((-9 * -6) + (5 + -27)) = (54 + (5 + -27)) = (54 + -22) = 32.\n(Final response) So the answer is 32.", "correct_answer": "32", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 508, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 * 5 + -9 + 1) + (-4 - -2 * 6 - 8)) * ((-6 + 6 * 1 - -3) * (7 * 0 - 7 - 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (6 * 5 + -9 + 1), B = (-4 - -2 * 6 - 8), C = (-6 + 6 * 1 - -3) and D = (7 * 0 - 7 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * 5 + -9 + 1) = (((6 * 5) + -9) + 1) = ((30 + -9) + 1) = (21 + 1) = 22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - -2 * 6 - 8) = ((-4 - (-2 * 6)) - 8) = ((-4 - -12) - 8) = (8 - 8) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + 6 * 1 - -3) = ((-6 + (6 * 1)) - -3) = ((-6 + 6) - -3) = (0 - -3) = 3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 * 0 - 7 - 1) = (((7 * 0) - 7) - 1) = ((0 - 7) - 1) = (-7 - 1) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((22 + 0) * (3 * -8)) = (22 * (3 * -8)) = (22 * -24) = -528.\n(Final response) So the answer is -528.", "correct_answer": "-528", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 534, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 + 4 + 4) + (9 + 3 - -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (9 + 4 + 4) and B = (9 + 3 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + 4 + 4) = ((9 + 4) + 4) = (13 + 4) = 17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + 3 - -9) = ((9 + 3) - -9) = (12 - -9) = 21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (17 + 21) = 38.\n(Final response) So the answer is 38.", "correct_answer": "38", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 61, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 * 3 + 8) * (8 * -3 + -2)) + ((6 + 0 + 4) * (-4 - -3 - 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-9 * 3 + 8), B = (8 * -3 + -2), C = (6 + 0 + 4) and D = (-4 - -3 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 3 + 8) = ((-9 * 3) + 8) = (-27 + 8) = -19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * -3 + -2) = ((8 * -3) + -2) = (-24 + -2) = -26.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + 0 + 4) = ((6 + 0) + 4) = (6 + 4) = 10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -3 - 7) = ((-4 - -3) - 7) = (-1 - 7) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((-19 * -26) + (10 * -8)) = (494 + (10 * -8)) = (494 + -80) = 414.\n(Final response) So the answer is 414.", "correct_answer": "414", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 426, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 * 0 * -2 + -2) * (1 * 6 * 3 - 7)) * ((-3 * 3 + 9 * -9) + (3 - -5 * -9 - 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-3 * 0 * -2 + -2), B = (1 * 6 * 3 - 7), C = (-3 * 3 + 9 * -9) and D = (3 - -5 * -9 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * 0 * -2 + -2) = (((-3 * 0) * -2) + -2) = ((0 * -2) + -2) = (0 + -2) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 6 * 3 - 7) = (((1 * 6) * 3) - 7) = ((6 * 3) - 7) = (18 - 7) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 * 3 + 9 * -9) = ((-3 * 3) + (9 * -9)) = (-9 + (9 * -9)) = (-9 + -81) = -90.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 - -5 * -9 - 8) = ((3 - (-5 * -9)) - 8) = ((3 - 45) - 8) = (-42 - 8) = -50.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((-2 * 11) * (-90 + -50)) = (-22 * (-90 + -50)) = (-22 * -140) = 3080.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3080.", "correct_answer": "3080", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 531, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 - -4 - 0) - (8 - 2 - 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-6 - -4 - 0) and B = (8 - 2 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - -4 - 0) = ((-6 - -4) - 0) = (-2 - 0) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 2 - 0) = ((8 - 2) - 0) = (6 - 0) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-2 - 6) = -8.\n(Final response) So the answer is -8.", "correct_answer": "-8", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 5, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 - -8 + -5) - (-9 * -7 - -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (8 - -8 + -5) and B = (-9 * -7 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - -8 + -5) = ((8 - -8) + -5) = (16 + -5) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -7 - -5) = ((-9 * -7) - -5) = (63 - -5) = 68.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (11 - 68) = -57.\n(Final response) So the answer is -57.", "correct_answer": "-57", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 14, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 * 3 * -4) - (-3 + -4 * 7)) * ((2 + 3 - -3) + (-5 + 6 - -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-1 * 3 * -4), B = (-3 + -4 * 7), C = (2 + 3 - -3) and D = (-5 + 6 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 3 * -4) = ((-1 * 3) * -4) = (-3 * -4) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + -4 * 7) = (-3 + (-4 * 7)) = (-3 + -28) = -31.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + 3 - -3) = ((2 + 3) - -3) = (5 - -3) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 + 6 - -6) = ((-5 + 6) - -6) = (1 - -6) = 7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((12 - -31) * (8 + 7)) = (43 * (8 + 7)) = (43 * 15) = 645.\n(Final response) So the answer is 645.", "correct_answer": "645", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 126, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 + -1 - 3 - -2 * -4 * -4) * (8 * -7 - 2 * -4 + -4 * 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-9 + -1 - 3 - -2 * -4 * -4) and B = (8 * -7 - 2 * -4 + -4 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -1 - 3 - -2 * -4 * -4) = (((-9 + -1) - 3) - ((-2 * -4) * -4)) = ((-10 - 3) - ((-2 * -4) * -4)) = ((-10 - 3) - (8 * -4)) = (-13 - (8 * -4)) = (-13 - -32) = 19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * -7 - 2 * -4 + -4 * 8) = (((8 * -7) - (2 * -4)) + (-4 * 8)) = ((-56 - (2 * -4)) + (-4 * 8)) = ((-56 - -8) + (-4 * 8)) = ((-56 - -8) + -32) = (-48 + -32) = -80.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (19 * -80) = -1520.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1520.", "correct_answer": "-1520", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 100, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * 5 - -8 - -7) - (5 * 0 + -9 - -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (9 * 5 - -8 - -7) and B = (5 * 0 + -9 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 5 - -8 - -7) = (((9 * 5) - -8) - -7) = ((45 - -8) - -7) = (53 - -7) = 60.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * 0 + -9 - -1) = (((5 * 0) + -9) - -1) = ((0 + -9) - -1) = (-9 - -1) = -8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (60 - -8) = 68.\n(Final response) So the answer is 68.", "correct_answer": "68", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 193, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-8 - -6 * 4) * (4 + -9 - 4)) + ((6 * 1 * 2) + (-7 * 1 + 5))) * (((6 * -2 - -6) - (5 * 5 + 0)) - ((-4 * 7 - -2) + (3 * 2 * 0)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C + D)) * ((E - F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (-8 - -6 * 4), B = (4 + -9 - 4), C = (6 * 1 * 2), D = (-7 * 1 + 5), E = (6 * -2 - -6), F = (5 * 5 + 0), G = (-4 * 7 - -2) and H = (3 * 2 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -6 * 4) = (-8 - (-6 * 4)) = (-8 - -24) = 16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + -9 - 4) = ((4 + -9) - 4) = (-5 - 4) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 * 1 * 2) = ((6 * 1) * 2) = (6 * 2) = 12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 * 1 + 5) = ((-7 * 1) + 5) = (-7 + 5) = -2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (6 * -2 - -6) = ((6 * -2) - -6) = (-12 - -6) = -6.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 * 5 + 0) = ((5 * 5) + 0) = (25 + 0) = 25.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-4 * 7 - -2) = ((-4 * 7) - -2) = (-28 - -2) = -26.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (3 * 2 * 0) = ((3 * 2) * 0) = (6 * 0) = 0.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C + D)) * ((E - F) - (G + H))) = (((16 * -9) + (12 + -2)) * ((-6 - 25) - (-26 + 0))) = ((-144 + (12 + -2)) * ((-6 - 25) - (-26 + 0))) = ((-144 + 10) * ((-6 - 25) - (-26 + 0))) = ((-144 + 10) * (-31 - (-26 + 0))) = ((-144 + 10) * (-31 - -26)) = (-134 * (-31 - -26)) = (-134 * -5) = 670.\n(Final response) So the answer is 670.", "correct_answer": "670", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 253, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + 2 - 5 - 8) * (-6 * 6 * 6 + -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-1 + 2 - 5 - 8) and B = (-6 * 6 * 6 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + 2 - 5 - 8) = (((-1 + 2) - 5) - 8) = ((1 - 5) - 8) = (-4 - 8) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 6 * 6 + -8) = (((-6 * 6) * 6) + -8) = ((-36 * 6) + -8) = (-216 + -8) = -224.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-12 * -224) = 2688.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2688.", "correct_answer": "2688", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 251, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 + 3 + -5 * 2) - (6 + -5 * 2 * -4)) + ((1 - 7 * -1 + 6) + (8 + 1 + 3 - 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-5 + 3 + -5 * 2), B = (6 + -5 * 2 * -4), C = (1 - 7 * -1 + 6) and D = (8 + 1 + 3 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + 3 + -5 * 2) = ((-5 + 3) + (-5 * 2)) = (-2 + (-5 * 2)) = (-2 + -10) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + -5 * 2 * -4) = (6 + ((-5 * 2) * -4)) = (6 + (-10 * -4)) = (6 + 40) = 46.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - 7 * -1 + 6) = ((1 - (7 * -1)) + 6) = ((1 - -7) + 6) = (8 + 6) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 + 1 + 3 - 3) = (((8 + 1) + 3) - 3) = ((9 + 3) - 3) = (12 - 3) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-12 - 46) + (14 + 9)) = (-58 + (14 + 9)) = (-58 + 23) = -35.\n(Final response) So the answer is -35.", "correct_answer": "-35", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 515, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 - -8 + 2) - (-4 * -6 * 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (9 - -8 + 2) and B = (-4 * -6 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - -8 + 2) = ((9 - -8) + 2) = (17 + 2) = 19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * -6 * 1) = ((-4 * -6) * 1) = (24 * 1) = 24.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (19 - 24) = -5.\n(Final response) So the answer is -5.", "correct_answer": "-5", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 17, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-2 - -3 - -5) - (4 * -7 - 7)) + ((-7 + 5 + 9) - (-2 + -5 * 2))) * (((9 + 6 * -9) * (7 + -7 + 7)) - ((8 - -2 * -1) + (8 + 7 - 2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E * F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (-2 - -3 - -5), B = (4 * -7 - 7), C = (-7 + 5 + 9), D = (-2 + -5 * 2), E = (9 + 6 * -9), F = (7 + -7 + 7), G = (8 - -2 * -1) and H = (8 + 7 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -3 - -5) = ((-2 - -3) - -5) = (1 - -5) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * -7 - 7) = ((4 * -7) - 7) = (-28 - 7) = -35.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + 5 + 9) = ((-7 + 5) + 9) = (-2 + 9) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 + -5 * 2) = (-2 + (-5 * 2)) = (-2 + -10) = -12.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (9 + 6 * -9) = (9 + (6 * -9)) = (9 + -54) = -45.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (7 + -7 + 7) = ((7 + -7) + 7) = (0 + 7) = 7.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 - -2 * -1) = (8 - (-2 * -1)) = (8 - 2) = 6.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 + 7 - 2) = ((8 + 7) - 2) = (15 - 2) = 13.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E * F) - (G + H))) = (((6 - -35) + (7 - -12)) * ((-45 * 7) - (6 + 13))) = ((41 + (7 - -12)) * ((-45 * 7) - (6 + 13))) = ((41 + 19) * ((-45 * 7) - (6 + 13))) = ((41 + 19) * (-315 - (6 + 13))) = ((41 + 19) * (-315 - 19)) = (60 * (-315 - 19)) = (60 * -334) = -20040.\n(Final response) So the answer is -20040.", "correct_answer": "-20040", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 266, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 - 4 * -7 * 6 * -8 + 1) * (-2 - 9 * 8 * 6 - -2 + -7)) - ((3 + -7 + -9 - 0 * -7 - -2) * (-5 - 8 - -7 - 7 - 4 - -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-2 - 4 * -7 * 6 * -8 + 1), B = (-2 - 9 * 8 * 6 - -2 + -7), C = (3 + -7 + -9 - 0 * -7 - -2) and D = (-5 - 8 - -7 - 7 - 4 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - 4 * -7 * 6 * -8 + 1) = ((-2 - (((4 * -7) * 6) * -8)) + 1) = ((-2 - ((-28 * 6) * -8)) + 1) = ((-2 - (-168 * -8)) + 1) = ((-2 - 1344) + 1) = (-1346 + 1) = -1345.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 9 * 8 * 6 - -2 + -7) = (((-2 - ((9 * 8) * 6)) - -2) + -7) = (((-2 - (72 * 6)) - -2) + -7) = (((-2 - 432) - -2) + -7) = ((-434 - -2) + -7) = (-432 + -7) = -439.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + -7 + -9 - 0 * -7 - -2) = ((((3 + -7) + -9) - (0 * -7)) - -2) = (((-4 + -9) - (0 * -7)) - -2) = (((-4 + -9) - 0) - -2) = ((-13 - 0) - -2) = (-13 - -2) = -11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - 8 - -7 - 7 - 4 - -4) = (((((-5 - 8) - -7) - 7) - 4) - -4) = ((((-13 - -7) - 7) - 4) - -4) = (((-6 - 7) - 4) - -4) = ((-13 - 4) - -4) = (-17 - -4) = -13.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-1345 * -439) - (-11 * -13)) = (590455 - (-11 * -13)) = (590455 - 143) = 590312.\n(Final response) So the answer is 590312.", "correct_answer": "590312", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 238, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 * -3 - 4) * (-5 - -6 * 5)) * ((-7 + 0 * -8) - (2 * 9 * -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (2 * -3 - 4), B = (-5 - -6 * 5), C = (-7 + 0 * -8) and D = (2 * 9 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * -3 - 4) = ((2 * -3) - 4) = (-6 - 4) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -6 * 5) = (-5 - (-6 * 5)) = (-5 - -30) = 25.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + 0 * -8) = (-7 + (0 * -8)) = (-7 + 0) = -7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * 9 * -7) = ((2 * 9) * -7) = (18 * -7) = -126.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((-10 * 25) * (-7 - -126)) = (-250 * (-7 - -126)) = (-250 * 119) = -29750.\n(Final response) So the answer is -29750.", "correct_answer": "-29750", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 384, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 + -4 - 1) - (-3 - -9 + 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 + -4 - 1) and B = (-3 - -9 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + -4 - 1) = ((0 + -4) - 1) = (-4 - 1) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - -9 + 3) = ((-3 - -9) + 3) = (6 + 3) = 9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-5 - 9) = -14.\n(Final response) So the answer is -14.", "correct_answer": "-14", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 13, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 * 5 - -5) + (-6 - -6 * 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-8 * 5 - -5) and B = (-6 - -6 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 5 - -5) = ((-8 * 5) - -5) = (-40 - -5) = -35.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - -6 * 7) = (-6 - (-6 * 7)) = (-6 - -42) = 36.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-35 + 36) = 1.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1.", "correct_answer": "1", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 138, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 - -4 - -5 - -1) + (8 - -1 + 7 * -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 - -4 - -5 - -1) and B = (8 - -1 + 7 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -4 - -5 - -1) = (((7 - -4) - -5) - -1) = ((11 - -5) - -1) = (16 - -1) = 17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - -1 + 7 * -7) = ((8 - -1) + (7 * -7)) = (9 + (7 * -7)) = (9 + -49) = -40.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (17 + -40) = -23.\n(Final response) So the answer is -23.", "correct_answer": "-23", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 191, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * 2 + -2) * (-7 - 7 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 * 2 + -2) and B = (-7 - 7 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 2 + -2) = ((5 * 2) + -2) = (10 + -2) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - 7 - -2) = ((-7 - 7) - -2) = (-14 - -2) = -12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (8 * -12) = -96.\n(Final response) So the answer is -96.", "correct_answer": "-96", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 4, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 - 2 * 9 + -5) - (6 + 3 + -6 * 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-4 - 2 * 9 + -5) and B = (6 + 3 + -6 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 2 * 9 + -5) = ((-4 - (2 * 9)) + -5) = ((-4 - 18) + -5) = (-22 + -5) = -27.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 3 + -6 * 7) = ((6 + 3) + (-6 * 7)) = (9 + (-6 * 7)) = (9 + -42) = -33.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-27 - -33) = 6.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6.", "correct_answer": "6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 293, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * 8 + 1) + (8 * 0 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-9 * 8 + 1) and B = (8 * 0 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 8 + 1) = ((-9 * 8) + 1) = (-72 + 1) = -71.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 0 * -3) = ((8 * 0) * -3) = (0 * -3) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-71 + 0) = -71.\n(Final response) So the answer is -71.", "correct_answer": "-71", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 20, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * -4 - -4) - (-8 - 5 * 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (9 * -4 - -4) and B = (-8 - 5 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * -4 - -4) = ((9 * -4) - -4) = (-36 - -4) = -32.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 5 * 9) = (-8 - (5 * 9)) = (-8 - 45) = -53.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-32 - -53) = 21.\n(Final response) So the answer is 21.", "correct_answer": "21", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 64, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 * 7 * 1) - (4 - -4 * -1)) - ((-7 + 2 * -6) + (0 - -3 - -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-7 * 7 * 1), B = (4 - -4 * -1), C = (-7 + 2 * -6) and D = (0 - -3 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * 7 * 1) = ((-7 * 7) * 1) = (-49 * 1) = -49.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - -4 * -1) = (4 - (-4 * -1)) = (4 - 4) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + 2 * -6) = (-7 + (2 * -6)) = (-7 + -12) = -19.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 - -3 - -3) = ((0 - -3) - -3) = (3 - -3) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-49 - 0) - (-19 + 6)) = (-49 - (-19 + 6)) = (-49 - -13) = -36.\n(Final response) So the answer is -36.", "correct_answer": "-36", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 374, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 * 0 * 7) * (-8 * 8 + -6)) + ((7 + 7 - 6) + (-2 * 5 + 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-3 * 0 * 7), B = (-8 * 8 + -6), C = (7 + 7 - 6) and D = (-2 * 5 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * 0 * 7) = ((-3 * 0) * 7) = (0 * 7) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * 8 + -6) = ((-8 * 8) + -6) = (-64 + -6) = -70.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + 7 - 6) = ((7 + 7) - 6) = (14 - 6) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * 5 + 9) = ((-2 * 5) + 9) = (-10 + 9) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((0 * -70) + (8 + -1)) = (0 + (8 + -1)) = (0 + 7) = 7.\n(Final response) So the answer is 7.", "correct_answer": "7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 417, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 - -7 - 0 - 1) * (-3 * 5 - -1 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (0 - -7 - 0 - 1) and B = (-3 * 5 - -1 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - -7 - 0 - 1) = (((0 - -7) - 0) - 1) = ((7 - 0) - 1) = (7 - 1) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * 5 - -1 - 2) = (((-3 * 5) - -1) - 2) = ((-15 - -1) - 2) = (-14 - 2) = -16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (6 * -16) = -96.\n(Final response) So the answer is -96.", "correct_answer": "-96", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 192, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-4 + 8 * -2 + 8) + (-3 + 6 - -3 * -9)) - ((-1 * -3 * 3 + -6) * (0 - -7 - -2 + -4))) + (((8 * 4 + 2 + -4) * (1 + -7 - 3 + -4)) - ((-3 * 5 * 8 - -9) - (4 * 2 + 8 + 4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) - (C * D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (-4 + 8 * -2 + 8), B = (-3 + 6 - -3 * -9), C = (-1 * -3 * 3 + -6), D = (0 - -7 - -2 + -4), E = (8 * 4 + 2 + -4), F = (1 + -7 - 3 + -4), G = (-3 * 5 * 8 - -9) and H = (4 * 2 + 8 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + 8 * -2 + 8) = ((-4 + (8 * -2)) + 8) = ((-4 + -16) + 8) = (-20 + 8) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 6 - -3 * -9) = ((-3 + 6) - (-3 * -9)) = (3 - (-3 * -9)) = (3 - 27) = -24.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * -3 * 3 + -6) = (((-1 * -3) * 3) + -6) = ((3 * 3) + -6) = (9 + -6) = 3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 - -7 - -2 + -4) = (((0 - -7) - -2) + -4) = ((7 - -2) + -4) = (9 + -4) = 5.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (8 * 4 + 2 + -4) = (((8 * 4) + 2) + -4) = ((32 + 2) + -4) = (34 + -4) = 30.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (1 + -7 - 3 + -4) = (((1 + -7) - 3) + -4) = ((-6 - 3) + -4) = (-9 + -4) = -13.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-3 * 5 * 8 - -9) = (((-3 * 5) * 8) - -9) = ((-15 * 8) - -9) = (-120 - -9) = -111.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (4 * 2 + 8 + 4) = (((4 * 2) + 8) + 4) = ((8 + 8) + 4) = (16 + 4) = 20.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) - (C * D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H))) = (((-12 + -24) - (3 * 5)) + ((30 * -13) - (-111 - 20))) = ((-36 - (3 * 5)) + ((30 * -13) - (-111 - 20))) = ((-36 - 15) + ((30 * -13) - (-111 - 20))) = ((-36 - 15) + (-390 - (-111 - 20))) = ((-36 - 15) + (-390 - -131)) = (-51 + (-390 - -131)) = (-51 + -259) = -310.\n(Final response) So the answer is -310.", "correct_answer": "-310", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 287, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 - -4 * 9) * (1 - 5 + -2)) + ((-8 * 3 * -1) * (-4 - -5 + -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (3 - -4 * 9), B = (1 - 5 + -2), C = (-8 * 3 * -1) and D = (-4 - -5 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - -4 * 9) = (3 - (-4 * 9)) = (3 - -36) = 39.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - 5 + -2) = ((1 - 5) + -2) = (-4 + -2) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * 3 * -1) = ((-8 * 3) * -1) = (-24 * -1) = 24.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -5 + -3) = ((-4 - -5) + -3) = (1 + -3) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((39 * -6) + (24 * -2)) = (-234 + (24 * -2)) = (-234 + -48) = -282.\n(Final response) So the answer is -282.", "correct_answer": "-282", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 372, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 + -6 * -1 - 2) + (8 - 3 * 4 * 0)) * ((-3 - 6 + -4 + 2) * (-7 - -7 - 1 - 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (4 + -6 * -1 - 2), B = (8 - 3 * 4 * 0), C = (-3 - 6 + -4 + 2) and D = (-7 - -7 - 1 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -6 * -1 - 2) = ((4 + (-6 * -1)) - 2) = ((4 + 6) - 2) = (10 - 2) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 3 * 4 * 0) = (8 - ((3 * 4) * 0)) = (8 - (12 * 0)) = (8 - 0) = 8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - 6 + -4 + 2) = (((-3 - 6) + -4) + 2) = ((-9 + -4) + 2) = (-13 + 2) = -11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -7 - 1 - 9) = (((-7 - -7) - 1) - 9) = ((0 - 1) - 9) = (-1 - 9) = -10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((8 + 8) * (-11 * -10)) = (16 * (-11 * -10)) = (16 * 110) = 1760.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1760.", "correct_answer": "1760", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 166, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * -6 - 9 * 1 + -5) * (8 * 2 - 5 - 8 - 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (7 * -6 - 9 * 1 + -5) and B = (8 * 2 - 5 - 8 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * -6 - 9 * 1 + -5) = (((7 * -6) - (9 * 1)) + -5) = ((-42 - (9 * 1)) + -5) = ((-42 - 9) + -5) = (-51 + -5) = -56.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 2 - 5 - 8 - 9) = ((((8 * 2) - 5) - 8) - 9) = (((16 - 5) - 8) - 9) = ((11 - 8) - 9) = (3 - 9) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-56 * -6) = 336.\n(Final response) So the answer is 336.", "correct_answer": "336", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 67, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 - -7 + 2 * -3 - 2) - (4 * 6 * -6 + 4 + -5)) - ((-5 * -7 - -2 - 0 + -8) - (-6 + 2 + 4 + 6 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-3 - -7 + 2 * -3 - 2), B = (4 * 6 * -6 + 4 + -5), C = (-5 * -7 - -2 - 0 + -8) and D = (-6 + 2 + 4 + 6 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - -7 + 2 * -3 - 2) = (((-3 - -7) + (2 * -3)) - 2) = ((4 + (2 * -3)) - 2) = ((4 + -6) - 2) = (-2 - 2) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 6 * -6 + 4 + -5) = ((((4 * 6) * -6) + 4) + -5) = (((24 * -6) + 4) + -5) = ((-144 + 4) + -5) = (-140 + -5) = -145.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * -7 - -2 - 0 + -8) = ((((-5 * -7) - -2) - 0) + -8) = (((35 - -2) - 0) + -8) = ((37 - 0) + -8) = (37 + -8) = 29.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + 2 + 4 + 6 * -6) = (((-6 + 2) + 4) + (6 * -6)) = ((-4 + 4) + (6 * -6)) = ((-4 + 4) + -36) = (0 + -36) = -36.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-4 - -145) - (29 - -36)) = (141 - (29 - -36)) = (141 - 65) = 76.\n(Final response) So the answer is 76.", "correct_answer": "76", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 206, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 + 4 * 5) * (-2 - -6 - 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (6 + 4 * 5) and B = (-2 - -6 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 4 * 5) = (6 + (4 * 5)) = (6 + 20) = 26.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - -6 - 8) = ((-2 - -6) - 8) = (4 - 8) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (26 * -4) = -104.\n(Final response) So the answer is -104.", "correct_answer": "-104", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 29, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 * 9 * -8 + 6) + (0 + 6 + -7 * -8)) + ((-6 - 8 - -4 * -7) * (-8 * 7 - -3 - -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-2 * 9 * -8 + 6), B = (0 + 6 + -7 * -8), C = (-6 - 8 - -4 * -7) and D = (-8 * 7 - -3 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * 9 * -8 + 6) = (((-2 * 9) * -8) + 6) = ((-18 * -8) + 6) = (144 + 6) = 150.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + 6 + -7 * -8) = ((0 + 6) + (-7 * -8)) = (6 + (-7 * -8)) = (6 + 56) = 62.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 - 8 - -4 * -7) = ((-6 - 8) - (-4 * -7)) = (-14 - (-4 * -7)) = (-14 - 28) = -42.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 * 7 - -3 - -4) = (((-8 * 7) - -3) - -4) = ((-56 - -3) - -4) = (-53 - -4) = -49.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((150 + 62) + (-42 * -49)) = (212 + (-42 * -49)) = (212 + 2058) = 2270.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2270.", "correct_answer": "2270", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 532, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 - 6 + 7 - 7) - (5 + 3 - 9 * -8)) + ((2 - -2 * -8 + -6) + (-3 - 0 - -9 + 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-6 - 6 + 7 - 7), B = (5 + 3 - 9 * -8), C = (2 - -2 * -8 + -6) and D = (-3 - 0 - -9 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 6 + 7 - 7) = (((-6 - 6) + 7) - 7) = ((-12 + 7) - 7) = (-5 - 7) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 3 - 9 * -8) = ((5 + 3) - (9 * -8)) = (8 - (9 * -8)) = (8 - -72) = 80.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - -2 * -8 + -6) = ((2 - (-2 * -8)) + -6) = ((2 - 16) + -6) = (-14 + -6) = -20.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 - 0 - -9 + 3) = (((-3 - 0) - -9) + 3) = ((-3 - -9) + 3) = (6 + 3) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-12 - 80) + (-20 + 9)) = (-92 + (-20 + 9)) = (-92 + -11) = -103.\n(Final response) So the answer is -103.", "correct_answer": "-103", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 506, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 * -7 - -9) - (5 + 7 + 1)) + ((0 + 7 * -9) + (-7 - -4 * -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (0 * -7 - -9), B = (5 + 7 + 1), C = (0 + 7 * -9) and D = (-7 - -4 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * -7 - -9) = ((0 * -7) - -9) = (0 - -9) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 7 + 1) = ((5 + 7) + 1) = (12 + 1) = 13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 + 7 * -9) = (0 + (7 * -9)) = (0 + -63) = -63.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -4 * -7) = (-7 - (-4 * -7)) = (-7 - 28) = -35.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((9 - 13) + (-63 + -35)) = (-4 + (-63 + -35)) = (-4 + -98) = -102.\n(Final response) So the answer is -102.", "correct_answer": "-102", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 425, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 + 0 + -5) - (-4 + -8 + 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 + 0 + -5) and B = (-4 + -8 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + 0 + -5) = ((0 + 0) + -5) = (0 + -5) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + -8 + 1) = ((-4 + -8) + 1) = (-12 + 1) = -11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-5 - -11) = 6.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6.", "correct_answer": "6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 66, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 * 2 + -8) + (5 - -7 + -6)) - ((-9 + 8 * 5) * (0 + 7 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-6 * 2 + -8), B = (5 - -7 + -6), C = (-9 + 8 * 5) and D = (0 + 7 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * 2 + -8) = ((-6 * 2) + -8) = (-12 + -8) = -20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - -7 + -6) = ((5 - -7) + -6) = (12 + -6) = 6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + 8 * 5) = (-9 + (8 * 5)) = (-9 + 40) = 31.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + 7 * 2) = (0 + (7 * 2)) = (0 + 14) = 14.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-20 + 6) - (31 * 14)) = (-14 - (31 * 14)) = (-14 - 434) = -448.\n(Final response) So the answer is -448.", "correct_answer": "-448", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 365, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((7 + -3 + 0 - 4) * (-1 * 2 + 7 * -9)) + ((8 + 7 + 7 * 7) + (4 + -2 - -6 - 3))) - (((1 * -2 + -9 - 6) - (-9 - 0 * 6 + -9)) * ((8 + -3 + -8 * -8) + (6 - 6 + -6 - 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C + D)) - ((E - F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (7 + -3 + 0 - 4), B = (-1 * 2 + 7 * -9), C = (8 + 7 + 7 * 7), D = (4 + -2 - -6 - 3), E = (1 * -2 + -9 - 6), F = (-9 - 0 * 6 + -9), G = (8 + -3 + -8 * -8) and H = (6 - 6 + -6 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -3 + 0 - 4) = (((7 + -3) + 0) - 4) = ((4 + 0) - 4) = (4 - 4) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * 2 + 7 * -9) = ((-1 * 2) + (7 * -9)) = (-2 + (7 * -9)) = (-2 + -63) = -65.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 + 7 + 7 * 7) = ((8 + 7) + (7 * 7)) = (15 + (7 * 7)) = (15 + 49) = 64.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + -2 - -6 - 3) = (((4 + -2) - -6) - 3) = ((2 - -6) - 3) = (8 - 3) = 5.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (1 * -2 + -9 - 6) = (((1 * -2) + -9) - 6) = ((-2 + -9) - 6) = (-11 - 6) = -17.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-9 - 0 * 6 + -9) = ((-9 - (0 * 6)) + -9) = ((-9 - 0) + -9) = (-9 + -9) = -18.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 + -3 + -8 * -8) = ((8 + -3) + (-8 * -8)) = (5 + (-8 * -8)) = (5 + 64) = 69.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (6 - 6 + -6 - 3) = (((6 - 6) + -6) - 3) = ((0 + -6) - 3) = (-6 - 3) = -9.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C + D)) - ((E - F) * (G + H))) = (((0 * -65) + (64 + 5)) - ((-17 - -18) * (69 + -9))) = ((0 + (64 + 5)) - ((-17 - -18) * (69 + -9))) = ((0 + 69) - ((-17 - -18) * (69 + -9))) = ((0 + 69) - (1 * (69 + -9))) = ((0 + 69) - (1 * 60)) = (69 - (1 * 60)) = (69 - 60) = 9.\n(Final response) So the answer is 9.", "correct_answer": "9", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 281, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * 7 * 0 * -2) - (-4 + -6 + 5 - 3)) - ((-9 + -1 - -5 * -6) - (6 + 8 - -2 - 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-5 * 7 * 0 * -2), B = (-4 + -6 + 5 - 3), C = (-9 + -1 - -5 * -6) and D = (6 + 8 - -2 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 7 * 0 * -2) = (((-5 * 7) * 0) * -2) = ((-35 * 0) * -2) = (0 * -2) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + -6 + 5 - 3) = (((-4 + -6) + 5) - 3) = ((-10 + 5) - 3) = (-5 - 3) = -8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + -1 - -5 * -6) = ((-9 + -1) - (-5 * -6)) = (-10 - (-5 * -6)) = (-10 - 30) = -40.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + 8 - -2 - 7) = (((6 + 8) - -2) - 7) = ((14 - -2) - 7) = (16 - 7) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((0 - -8) - (-40 - 9)) = (8 - (-40 - 9)) = (8 - -49) = 57.\n(Final response) So the answer is 57.", "correct_answer": "57", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 588, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 + -4 + -7 * -5) - (8 - 4 * -2 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-9 + -4 + -7 * -5) and B = (8 - 4 * -2 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -4 + -7 * -5) = ((-9 + -4) + (-7 * -5)) = (-13 + (-7 * -5)) = (-13 + 35) = 22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 4 * -2 * -3) = (8 - ((4 * -2) * -3)) = (8 - (-8 * -3)) = (8 - 24) = -16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (22 - -16) = 38.\n(Final response) So the answer is 38.", "correct_answer": "38", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 221, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 - 9 + 9) - (-5 - -1 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 - 9 + 9) and B = (-5 - -1 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - 9 + 9) = ((0 - 9) + 9) = (-9 + 9) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -1 + -9) = ((-5 - -1) + -9) = (-4 + -9) = -13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (0 - -13) = 13.\n(Final response) So the answer is 13.", "correct_answer": "13", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 34, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 + 5 + -3 + 0) - (4 + 8 - -8 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-8 + 5 + -3 + 0) and B = (4 + 8 - -8 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + 5 + -3 + 0) = (((-8 + 5) + -3) + 0) = ((-3 + -3) + 0) = (-6 + 0) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 8 - -8 - 2) = (((4 + 8) - -8) - 2) = ((12 - -8) - 2) = (20 - 2) = 18.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-6 - 18) = -24.\n(Final response) So the answer is -24.", "correct_answer": "-24", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 282, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 + 4 + -6) + (-7 + -9 - 9)) + ((0 - 2 - -8) - (5 * 2 - -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-9 + 4 + -6), B = (-7 + -9 - 9), C = (0 - 2 - -8) and D = (5 * 2 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + 4 + -6) = ((-9 + 4) + -6) = (-5 + -6) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -9 - 9) = ((-7 + -9) - 9) = (-16 - 9) = -25.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 - 2 - -8) = ((0 - 2) - -8) = (-2 - -8) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 * 2 - -6) = ((5 * 2) - -6) = (10 - -6) = 16.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((-11 + -25) + (6 - 16)) = (-36 + (6 - 16)) = (-36 + -10) = -46.\n(Final response) So the answer is -46.", "correct_answer": "-46", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 369, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-2 + -2 * 7 + 2) + (2 + 1 - 1 + 6)) + ((-1 * 0 * -7 + 1) * (-9 + 6 * 5 - 1))) + (((-5 * -2 - -3 - -3) + (-1 + -7 + 1 + -9)) + ((-5 - 9 * 6 - 1) + (0 - 0 * 2 - -2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C * D)) + ((E + F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-2 + -2 * 7 + 2), B = (2 + 1 - 1 + 6), C = (-1 * 0 * -7 + 1), D = (-9 + 6 * 5 - 1), E = (-5 * -2 - -3 - -3), F = (-1 + -7 + 1 + -9), G = (-5 - 9 * 6 - 1) and H = (0 - 0 * 2 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -2 * 7 + 2) = ((-2 + (-2 * 7)) + 2) = ((-2 + -14) + 2) = (-16 + 2) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + 1 - 1 + 6) = (((2 + 1) - 1) + 6) = ((3 - 1) + 6) = (2 + 6) = 8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * 0 * -7 + 1) = (((-1 * 0) * -7) + 1) = ((0 * -7) + 1) = (0 + 1) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 + 6 * 5 - 1) = ((-9 + (6 * 5)) - 1) = ((-9 + 30) - 1) = (21 - 1) = 20.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-5 * -2 - -3 - -3) = (((-5 * -2) - -3) - -3) = ((10 - -3) - -3) = (13 - -3) = 16.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-1 + -7 + 1 + -9) = (((-1 + -7) + 1) + -9) = ((-8 + 1) + -9) = (-7 + -9) = -16.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-5 - 9 * 6 - 1) = ((-5 - (9 * 6)) - 1) = ((-5 - 54) - 1) = (-59 - 1) = -60.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (0 - 0 * 2 - -2) = ((0 - (0 * 2)) - -2) = ((0 - 0) - -2) = (0 - -2) = 2.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C * D)) + ((E + F) + (G + H))) = (((-14 + 8) + (1 * 20)) + ((16 + -16) + (-60 + 2))) = ((-6 + (1 * 20)) + ((16 + -16) + (-60 + 2))) = ((-6 + 20) + ((16 + -16) + (-60 + 2))) = ((-6 + 20) + (0 + (-60 + 2))) = ((-6 + 20) + (0 + -58)) = (14 + (0 + -58)) = (14 + -58) = -44.\n(Final response) So the answer is -44.", "correct_answer": "-44", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 283, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + 7 - -2 - 3) * (4 * 5 * 3 * -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 + 7 - -2 - 3) and B = (4 * 5 * 3 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 7 - -2 - 3) = (((5 + 7) - -2) - 3) = ((12 - -2) - 3) = (14 - 3) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 5 * 3 * -5) = (((4 * 5) * 3) * -5) = ((20 * 3) * -5) = (60 * -5) = -300.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (11 * -300) = -3300.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3300.", "correct_answer": "-3300", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 241, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + -6 * 0 * 3 + 8 * 4) + (-1 - 7 + -5 * 6 * -1 + 8)) * ((-5 - 7 - -6 + -3 - -8 + 0) + (7 + -3 - -4 - -1 + -7 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (1 + -6 * 0 * 3 + 8 * 4), B = (-1 - 7 + -5 * 6 * -1 + 8), C = (-5 - 7 - -6 + -3 - -8 + 0) and D = (7 + -3 - -4 - -1 + -7 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + -6 * 0 * 3 + 8 * 4) = ((1 + ((-6 * 0) * 3)) + (8 * 4)) = ((1 + (0 * 3)) + (8 * 4)) = ((1 + (0 * 3)) + 32) = ((1 + 0) + 32) = (1 + 32) = 33.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 7 + -5 * 6 * -1 + 8) = (((-1 - 7) + ((-5 * 6) * -1)) + 8) = ((-8 + ((-5 * 6) * -1)) + 8) = ((-8 + (-30 * -1)) + 8) = ((-8 + 30) + 8) = (22 + 8) = 30.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - 7 - -6 + -3 - -8 + 0) = (((((-5 - 7) - -6) + -3) - -8) + 0) = ((((-12 - -6) + -3) - -8) + 0) = (((-6 + -3) - -8) + 0) = ((-9 - -8) + 0) = (-1 + 0) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + -3 - -4 - -1 + -7 * 0) = ((((7 + -3) - -4) - -1) + (-7 * 0)) = (((4 - -4) - -1) + (-7 * 0)) = (((4 - -4) - -1) + 0) = ((8 - -1) + 0) = (9 + 0) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((33 + 30) * (-1 + 9)) = (63 * (-1 + 9)) = (63 * 8) = 504.\n(Final response) So the answer is 504.", "correct_answer": "504", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 214, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 + 2 - 5) * (-2 - 7 + -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 + 2 - 5) and B = (-2 - 7 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 2 - 5) = ((-7 + 2) - 5) = (-5 - 5) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 7 + -2) = ((-2 - 7) + -2) = (-9 + -2) = -11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-10 * -11) = 110.\n(Final response) So the answer is 110.", "correct_answer": "110", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 144, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 + 9 - -8) + (3 * 1 * -7)) * ((6 - 4 - 0) * (1 - 1 + 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (8 + 9 - -8), B = (3 * 1 * -7), C = (6 - 4 - 0) and D = (1 - 1 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 9 - -8) = ((8 + 9) - -8) = (17 - -8) = 25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 1 * -7) = ((3 * 1) * -7) = (3 * -7) = -21.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 4 - 0) = ((6 - 4) - 0) = (2 - 0) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 - 1 + 9) = ((1 - 1) + 9) = (0 + 9) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((25 + -21) * (2 * 9)) = (4 * (2 * 9)) = (4 * 18) = 72.\n(Final response) So the answer is 72.", "correct_answer": "72", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 392, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 - 9 + 4) - (0 - 2 * -2)) + ((4 * -4 - -8) + (2 + -8 * -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (2 - 9 + 4), B = (0 - 2 * -2), C = (4 * -4 - -8) and D = (2 + -8 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - 9 + 4) = ((2 - 9) + 4) = (-7 + 4) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 2 * -2) = (0 - (2 * -2)) = (0 - -4) = 4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 * -4 - -8) = ((4 * -4) - -8) = (-16 - -8) = -8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 + -8 * -3) = (2 + (-8 * -3)) = (2 + 24) = 26.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-3 - 4) + (-8 + 26)) = (-7 + (-8 + 26)) = (-7 + 18) = 11.\n(Final response) So the answer is 11.", "correct_answer": "11", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 411, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 - -3 - -8 * 8) - (0 * -5 * -5 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-8 - -3 - -8 * 8) and B = (0 * -5 * -5 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -3 - -8 * 8) = ((-8 - -3) - (-8 * 8)) = (-5 - (-8 * 8)) = (-5 - -64) = 59.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * -5 * -5 - -2) = (((0 * -5) * -5) - -2) = ((0 * -5) - -2) = (0 - -2) = 2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (59 - 2) = 57.\n(Final response) So the answer is 57.", "correct_answer": "57", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 232, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-9 - -2 + -9 - 1 + 3) * (-7 - 4 + -9 + -1 - 4)) + ((-6 * -1 + 2 * -2 + 6) + (9 + 0 - -3 + -2 - -1))) + (((9 - -1 - 8 + 1 - 7) - (5 + -8 - -3 + 3 * -5)) + ((1 - 2 - 2 + -3 * 9) + (-8 - 3 + 6 * -8 - 2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C + D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-9 - -2 + -9 - 1 + 3), B = (-7 - 4 + -9 + -1 - 4), C = (-6 * -1 + 2 * -2 + 6), D = (9 + 0 - -3 + -2 - -1), E = (9 - -1 - 8 + 1 - 7), F = (5 + -8 - -3 + 3 * -5), G = (1 - 2 - 2 + -3 * 9) and H = (-8 - 3 + 6 * -8 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - -2 + -9 - 1 + 3) = ((((-9 - -2) + -9) - 1) + 3) = (((-7 + -9) - 1) + 3) = ((-16 - 1) + 3) = (-17 + 3) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - 4 + -9 + -1 - 4) = ((((-7 - 4) + -9) + -1) - 4) = (((-11 + -9) + -1) - 4) = ((-20 + -1) - 4) = (-21 - 4) = -25.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 * -1 + 2 * -2 + 6) = (((-6 * -1) + (2 * -2)) + 6) = ((6 + (2 * -2)) + 6) = ((6 + -4) + 6) = (2 + 6) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + 0 - -3 + -2 - -1) = ((((9 + 0) - -3) + -2) - -1) = (((9 - -3) + -2) - -1) = ((12 + -2) - -1) = (10 - -1) = 11.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (9 - -1 - 8 + 1 - 7) = ((((9 - -1) - 8) + 1) - 7) = (((10 - 8) + 1) - 7) = ((2 + 1) - 7) = (3 - 7) = -4.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 + -8 - -3 + 3 * -5) = (((5 + -8) - -3) + (3 * -5)) = ((-3 - -3) + (3 * -5)) = ((-3 - -3) + -15) = (0 + -15) = -15.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (1 - 2 - 2 + -3 * 9) = (((1 - 2) - 2) + (-3 * 9)) = ((-1 - 2) + (-3 * 9)) = ((-1 - 2) + -27) = (-3 + -27) = -30.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 - 3 + 6 * -8 - 2) = (((-8 - 3) + (6 * -8)) - 2) = ((-11 + (6 * -8)) - 2) = ((-11 + -48) - 2) = (-59 - 2) = -61.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C + D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((-14 * -25) + (8 + 11)) + ((-4 - -15) + (-30 + -61))) = ((350 + (8 + 11)) + ((-4 - -15) + (-30 + -61))) = ((350 + 19) + ((-4 - -15) + (-30 + -61))) = ((350 + 19) + (11 + (-30 + -61))) = ((350 + 19) + (11 + -91)) = (369 + (11 + -91)) = (369 + -80) = 289.\n(Final response) So the answer is 289.", "correct_answer": "289", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 321, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 - 9 + 0 + 6) - (-5 + -9 - -5 * 9)) * ((-9 * 8 * -1 * -6) + (-1 * 6 - -2 - -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (5 - 9 + 0 + 6), B = (-5 + -9 - -5 * 9), C = (-9 * 8 * -1 * -6) and D = (-1 * 6 - -2 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - 9 + 0 + 6) = (((5 - 9) + 0) + 6) = ((-4 + 0) + 6) = (-4 + 6) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + -9 - -5 * 9) = ((-5 + -9) - (-5 * 9)) = (-14 - (-5 * 9)) = (-14 - -45) = 31.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * 8 * -1 * -6) = (((-9 * 8) * -1) * -6) = ((-72 * -1) * -6) = (72 * -6) = -432.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * 6 - -2 - -3) = (((-1 * 6) - -2) - -3) = ((-6 - -2) - -3) = (-4 - -3) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((2 - 31) * (-432 + -1)) = (-29 * (-432 + -1)) = (-29 * -433) = 12557.\n(Final response) So the answer is 12557.", "correct_answer": "12557", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 485, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 - -5 - 6 + 1 - 2) + (-4 * -5 * -1 - 6 - 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-8 - -5 - 6 + 1 - 2) and B = (-4 * -5 * -1 - 6 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -5 - 6 + 1 - 2) = ((((-8 - -5) - 6) + 1) - 2) = (((-3 - 6) + 1) - 2) = ((-9 + 1) - 2) = (-8 - 2) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * -5 * -1 - 6 - 4) = ((((-4 * -5) * -1) - 6) - 4) = (((20 * -1) - 6) - 4) = ((-20 - 6) - 4) = (-26 - 4) = -30.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-10 + -30) = -40.\n(Final response) So the answer is -40.", "correct_answer": "-40", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 88, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-9 * -9 + 3 - 1 + -3 * -9) - (-1 - 6 + 8 * 7 + 3 - 2)) + ((0 - -4 + -4 + -1 + 0 - 6) * (2 - -9 * 9 * 0 - -9 - 3))) - (((-8 - -2 * 9 * 1 * -5 * 7) * (8 - 8 + 1 + 3 * 6 - 4)) + ((-4 * -1 + 3 - 8 + 6 * -1) + (3 - -9 * 4 + 8 + 3 - 7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C * D)) - ((E * F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-9 * -9 + 3 - 1 + -3 * -9), B = (-1 - 6 + 8 * 7 + 3 - 2), C = (0 - -4 + -4 + -1 + 0 - 6), D = (2 - -9 * 9 * 0 - -9 - 3), E = (-8 - -2 * 9 * 1 * -5 * 7), F = (8 - 8 + 1 + 3 * 6 - 4), G = (-4 * -1 + 3 - 8 + 6 * -1) and H = (3 - -9 * 4 + 8 + 3 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * -9 + 3 - 1 + -3 * -9) = ((((-9 * -9) + 3) - 1) + (-3 * -9)) = (((81 + 3) - 1) + (-3 * -9)) = (((81 + 3) - 1) + 27) = ((84 - 1) + 27) = (83 + 27) = 110.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 6 + 8 * 7 + 3 - 2) = ((((-1 - 6) + (8 * 7)) + 3) - 2) = (((-7 + (8 * 7)) + 3) - 2) = (((-7 + 56) + 3) - 2) = ((49 + 3) - 2) = (52 - 2) = 50.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 - -4 + -4 + -1 + 0 - 6) = (((((0 - -4) + -4) + -1) + 0) - 6) = ((((4 + -4) + -1) + 0) - 6) = (((0 + -1) + 0) - 6) = ((-1 + 0) - 6) = (-1 - 6) = -7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 - -9 * 9 * 0 - -9 - 3) = (((2 - ((-9 * 9) * 0)) - -9) - 3) = (((2 - (-81 * 0)) - -9) - 3) = (((2 - 0) - -9) - 3) = ((2 - -9) - 3) = (11 - 3) = 8.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-8 - -2 * 9 * 1 * -5 * 7) = (-8 - ((((-2 * 9) * 1) * -5) * 7)) = (-8 - (((-18 * 1) * -5) * 7)) = (-8 - ((-18 * -5) * 7)) = (-8 - (90 * 7)) = (-8 - 630) = -638.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (8 - 8 + 1 + 3 * 6 - 4) = ((((8 - 8) + 1) + (3 * 6)) - 4) = (((0 + 1) + (3 * 6)) - 4) = (((0 + 1) + 18) - 4) = ((1 + 18) - 4) = (19 - 4) = 15.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-4 * -1 + 3 - 8 + 6 * -1) = ((((-4 * -1) + 3) - 8) + (6 * -1)) = (((4 + 3) - 8) + (6 * -1)) = (((4 + 3) - 8) + -6) = ((7 - 8) + -6) = (-1 + -6) = -7.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (3 - -9 * 4 + 8 + 3 - 7) = ((((3 - (-9 * 4)) + 8) + 3) - 7) = ((((3 - -36) + 8) + 3) - 7) = (((39 + 8) + 3) - 7) = ((47 + 3) - 7) = (50 - 7) = 43.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C * D)) - ((E * F) + (G + H))) = (((110 - 50) + (-7 * 8)) - ((-638 * 15) + (-7 + 43))) = ((60 + (-7 * 8)) - ((-638 * 15) + (-7 + 43))) = ((60 + -56) - ((-638 * 15) + (-7 + 43))) = ((60 + -56) - (-9570 + (-7 + 43))) = ((60 + -56) - (-9570 + 36)) = (4 - (-9570 + 36)) = (4 - -9534) = 9538.\n(Final response) So the answer is 9538.", "correct_answer": "9538", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 355, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * -9 - -8 + 3) * (-1 * -9 * -2 * 4)) + ((-6 * 8 - -1 * -7) - (-6 * 8 - 5 - 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (3 * -9 - -8 + 3), B = (-1 * -9 * -2 * 4), C = (-6 * 8 - -1 * -7) and D = (-6 * 8 - 5 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -9 - -8 + 3) = (((3 * -9) - -8) + 3) = ((-27 - -8) + 3) = (-19 + 3) = -16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * -9 * -2 * 4) = (((-1 * -9) * -2) * 4) = ((9 * -2) * 4) = (-18 * 4) = -72.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 * 8 - -1 * -7) = ((-6 * 8) - (-1 * -7)) = (-48 - (-1 * -7)) = (-48 - 7) = -55.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * 8 - 5 - 2) = (((-6 * 8) - 5) - 2) = ((-48 - 5) - 2) = (-53 - 2) = -55.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((-16 * -72) + (-55 - -55)) = (1152 + (-55 - -55)) = (1152 + 0) = 1152.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1152.", "correct_answer": "1152", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 471, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 - 0 * 7) - (-7 + -8 * -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-7 - 0 * 7) and B = (-7 + -8 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - 0 * 7) = (-7 - (0 * 7)) = (-7 - 0) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -8 * -5) = (-7 + (-8 * -5)) = (-7 + 40) = 33.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-7 - 33) = -40.\n(Final response) So the answer is -40.", "correct_answer": "-40", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 119, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 - 6 - 5 + 6) - (0 * 3 + -5 + -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-5 - 6 - 5 + 6) and B = (0 * 3 + -5 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - 6 - 5 + 6) = (((-5 - 6) - 5) + 6) = ((-11 - 5) + 6) = (-16 + 6) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 3 + -5 + -7) = (((0 * 3) + -5) + -7) = ((0 + -5) + -7) = (-5 + -7) = -12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-10 - -12) = 2.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2.", "correct_answer": "2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 272, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 * 3 - -4 + 3 - -6) + (0 + -6 + -6 + -6 - -2)) * ((-6 + 1 + -1 - -6 + 3) + (0 + -7 - -6 + 3 - -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-9 * 3 - -4 + 3 - -6), B = (0 + -6 + -6 + -6 - -2), C = (-6 + 1 + -1 - -6 + 3) and D = (0 + -7 - -6 + 3 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 3 - -4 + 3 - -6) = ((((-9 * 3) - -4) + 3) - -6) = (((-27 - -4) + 3) - -6) = ((-23 + 3) - -6) = (-20 - -6) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -6 + -6 + -6 - -2) = ((((0 + -6) + -6) + -6) - -2) = (((-6 + -6) + -6) - -2) = ((-12 + -6) - -2) = (-18 - -2) = -16.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + 1 + -1 - -6 + 3) = ((((-6 + 1) + -1) - -6) + 3) = (((-5 + -1) - -6) + 3) = ((-6 - -6) + 3) = (0 + 3) = 3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + -7 - -6 + 3 - -4) = ((((0 + -7) - -6) + 3) - -4) = (((-7 - -6) + 3) - -4) = ((-1 + 3) - -4) = (2 - -4) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-14 + -16) * (3 + 6)) = (-30 * (3 + 6)) = (-30 * 9) = -270.\n(Final response) So the answer is -270.", "correct_answer": "-270", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 204, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * 5 - 7 * 1) * (-2 - -9 - -8 + -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (7 * 5 - 7 * 1) and B = (-2 - -9 - -8 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 5 - 7 * 1) = ((7 * 5) - (7 * 1)) = (35 - (7 * 1)) = (35 - 7) = 28.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - -9 - -8 + -6) = (((-2 - -9) - -8) + -6) = ((7 - -8) + -6) = (15 + -6) = 9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (28 * 9) = 252.\n(Final response) So the answer is 252.", "correct_answer": "252", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 185, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-5 * 2 * 8 * -9) - (2 * -2 + 6 - -4)) + ((7 - 9 + -7 - 0) + (-1 * 4 * 9 * 6))) - (((4 * -7 * 4 * 9) + (-6 * -2 + 5 * 6)) - ((-6 - -5 - 8 * -6) + (4 + -4 + -4 - 9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C + D)) - ((E + F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (-5 * 2 * 8 * -9), B = (2 * -2 + 6 - -4), C = (7 - 9 + -7 - 0), D = (-1 * 4 * 9 * 6), E = (4 * -7 * 4 * 9), F = (-6 * -2 + 5 * 6), G = (-6 - -5 - 8 * -6) and H = (4 + -4 + -4 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 2 * 8 * -9) = (((-5 * 2) * 8) * -9) = ((-10 * 8) * -9) = (-80 * -9) = 720.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * -2 + 6 - -4) = (((2 * -2) + 6) - -4) = ((-4 + 6) - -4) = (2 - -4) = 6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 - 9 + -7 - 0) = (((7 - 9) + -7) - 0) = ((-2 + -7) - 0) = (-9 - 0) = -9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * 4 * 9 * 6) = (((-1 * 4) * 9) * 6) = ((-4 * 9) * 6) = (-36 * 6) = -216.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (4 * -7 * 4 * 9) = (((4 * -7) * 4) * 9) = ((-28 * 4) * 9) = (-112 * 9) = -1008.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-6 * -2 + 5 * 6) = ((-6 * -2) + (5 * 6)) = (12 + (5 * 6)) = (12 + 30) = 42.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-6 - -5 - 8 * -6) = ((-6 - -5) - (8 * -6)) = (-1 - (8 * -6)) = (-1 - -48) = 47.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (4 + -4 + -4 - 9) = (((4 + -4) + -4) - 9) = ((0 + -4) - 9) = (-4 - 9) = -13.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C + D)) - ((E + F) - (G + H))) = (((720 - 6) + (-9 + -216)) - ((-1008 + 42) - (47 + -13))) = ((714 + (-9 + -216)) - ((-1008 + 42) - (47 + -13))) = ((714 + -225) - ((-1008 + 42) - (47 + -13))) = ((714 + -225) - (-966 - (47 + -13))) = ((714 + -225) - (-966 - 34)) = (489 - (-966 - 34)) = (489 - -1000) = 1489.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1489.", "correct_answer": "1489", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 273, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-8 - 4 + 7) + (-1 + -1 * -6)) - ((4 - -6 * 5) - (5 - -6 + -1))) * (((-3 - 2 - -3) * (-4 * 9 + 9)) - ((5 * 2 - 1) + (-6 + -9 + -8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) - (C - D)) * ((E * F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (-8 - 4 + 7), B = (-1 + -1 * -6), C = (4 - -6 * 5), D = (5 - -6 + -1), E = (-3 - 2 - -3), F = (-4 * 9 + 9), G = (5 * 2 - 1) and H = (-6 + -9 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 4 + 7) = ((-8 - 4) + 7) = (-12 + 7) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -1 * -6) = (-1 + (-1 * -6)) = (-1 + 6) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - -6 * 5) = (4 - (-6 * 5)) = (4 - -30) = 34.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - -6 + -1) = ((5 - -6) + -1) = (11 + -1) = 10.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-3 - 2 - -3) = ((-3 - 2) - -3) = (-5 - -3) = -2.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-4 * 9 + 9) = ((-4 * 9) + 9) = (-36 + 9) = -27.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (5 * 2 - 1) = ((5 * 2) - 1) = (10 - 1) = 9.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-6 + -9 + -8) = ((-6 + -9) + -8) = (-15 + -8) = -23.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) - (C - D)) * ((E * F) - (G + H))) = (((-5 + 5) - (34 - 10)) * ((-2 * -27) - (9 + -23))) = ((0 - (34 - 10)) * ((-2 * -27) - (9 + -23))) = ((0 - 24) * ((-2 * -27) - (9 + -23))) = ((0 - 24) * (54 - (9 + -23))) = ((0 - 24) * (54 - -14)) = (-24 * (54 - -14)) = (-24 * 68) = -1632.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1632.", "correct_answer": "-1632", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 241, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - -2 * -5 * -7) + (3 - -6 + -8 * -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-2 - -2 * -5 * -7) and B = (3 - -6 + -8 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -2 * -5 * -7) = (-2 - ((-2 * -5) * -7)) = (-2 - (10 * -7)) = (-2 - -70) = 68.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - -6 + -8 * -9) = ((3 - -6) + (-8 * -9)) = (9 + (-8 * -9)) = (9 + 72) = 81.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (68 + 81) = 149.\n(Final response) So the answer is 149.", "correct_answer": "149", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 173, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 - 8 + 7) - (3 + -7 * -3)) + ((2 * 1 - 8) * (-5 * -7 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C * D))\", where A = (3 - 8 + 7), B = (3 + -7 * -3), C = (2 * 1 - 8) and D = (-5 * -7 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - 8 + 7) = ((3 - 8) + 7) = (-5 + 7) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + -7 * -3) = (3 + (-7 * -3)) = (3 + 21) = 24.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 * 1 - 8) = ((2 * 1) - 8) = (2 - 8) = -6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 * -7 * 0) = ((-5 * -7) * 0) = (35 * 0) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C * D)) = ((2 - 24) + (-6 * 0)) = (-22 + (-6 * 0)) = (-22 + 0) = -22.\n(Final response) So the answer is -22.", "correct_answer": "-22", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 381, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - -7 - -8) + (6 - -9 - 0)) - ((-1 * -8 * 4) + (-1 * 4 * 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C + D))\", where A = (1 - -7 - -8), B = (6 - -9 - 0), C = (-1 * -8 * 4) and D = (-1 * 4 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -7 - -8) = ((1 - -7) - -8) = (8 - -8) = 16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - -9 - 0) = ((6 - -9) - 0) = (15 - 0) = 15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * -8 * 4) = ((-1 * -8) * 4) = (8 * 4) = 32.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * 4 * 6) = ((-1 * 4) * 6) = (-4 * 6) = -24.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C + D)) = ((16 + 15) - (32 + -24)) = (31 - (32 + -24)) = (31 - 8) = 23.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23.", "correct_answer": "23", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 361, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 * 3 * -5 - -4) - (4 + -4 - 8 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-8 * 3 * -5 - -4) and B = (4 + -4 - 8 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 3 * -5 - -4) = (((-8 * 3) * -5) - -4) = ((-24 * -5) - -4) = (120 - -4) = 124.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + -4 - 8 * -2) = ((4 + -4) - (8 * -2)) = (0 - (8 * -2)) = (0 - -16) = 16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (124 - 16) = 108.\n(Final response) So the answer is 108.", "correct_answer": "108", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 264, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 * -8 - 7 + -5) + (2 * -4 + 0 * 6)) - ((-6 + -5 + 1 * -7) + (-6 + 6 * -5 + 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C + D))\", where A = (2 * -8 - 7 + -5), B = (2 * -4 + 0 * 6), C = (-6 + -5 + 1 * -7) and D = (-6 + 6 * -5 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * -8 - 7 + -5) = (((2 * -8) - 7) + -5) = ((-16 - 7) + -5) = (-23 + -5) = -28.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * -4 + 0 * 6) = ((2 * -4) + (0 * 6)) = (-8 + (0 * 6)) = (-8 + 0) = -8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -5 + 1 * -7) = ((-6 + -5) + (1 * -7)) = (-11 + (1 * -7)) = (-11 + -7) = -18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + 6 * -5 + 1) = ((-6 + (6 * -5)) + 1) = ((-6 + -30) + 1) = (-36 + 1) = -35.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C + D)) = ((-28 + -8) - (-18 + -35)) = (-36 - (-18 + -35)) = (-36 - -53) = 17.\n(Final response) So the answer is 17.", "correct_answer": "17", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 172, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 + 7 * 6 - 6) * (-1 - 1 - 2 - -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-6 + 7 * 6 - 6) and B = (-1 - 1 - 2 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 7 * 6 - 6) = ((-6 + (7 * 6)) - 6) = ((-6 + 42) - 6) = (36 - 6) = 30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 1 - 2 - -6) = (((-1 - 1) - 2) - -6) = ((-2 - 2) - -6) = (-4 - -6) = 2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (30 * 2) = 60.\n(Final response) So the answer is 60.", "correct_answer": "60", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 299, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 + -1 + -1) + (-3 + -6 - -6)) + ((-6 - -7 + -2) + (8 - 2 + -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (3 + -1 + -1), B = (-3 + -6 - -6), C = (-6 - -7 + -2) and D = (8 - 2 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + -1 + -1) = ((3 + -1) + -1) = (2 + -1) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + -6 - -6) = ((-3 + -6) - -6) = (-9 - -6) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 - -7 + -2) = ((-6 - -7) + -2) = (1 + -2) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - 2 + -9) = ((8 - 2) + -9) = (6 + -9) = -3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((1 + -3) + (-1 + -3)) = (-2 + (-1 + -3)) = (-2 + -4) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 421, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 * 5 + 3) - (9 - 4 + -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 * 5 + 3) and B = (9 - 4 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * 5 + 3) = ((1 * 5) + 3) = (5 + 3) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - 4 + -6) = ((9 - 4) + -6) = (5 + -6) = -1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (8 - -1) = 9.\n(Final response) So the answer is 9.", "correct_answer": "9", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 28, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 - -6 + 3 - -7) - (-2 * 1 * -1 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 - -6 + 3 - -7) and B = (-2 * 1 * -1 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -6 + 3 - -7) = (((6 - -6) + 3) - -7) = ((12 + 3) - -7) = (15 - -7) = 22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * 1 * -1 * 3) = (((-2 * 1) * -1) * 3) = ((-2 * -1) * 3) = (2 * 3) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (22 - 6) = 16.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16.", "correct_answer": "16", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 262, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 + 2 - -6 - 2) * (-1 * 6 * 4 + -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (6 + 2 - -6 - 2) and B = (-1 * 6 * 4 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 2 - -6 - 2) = (((6 + 2) - -6) - 2) = ((8 - -6) - 2) = (14 - 2) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * 6 * 4 + -8) = (((-1 * 6) * 4) + -8) = ((-6 * 4) + -8) = (-24 + -8) = -32.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (12 * -32) = -384.\n(Final response) So the answer is -384.", "correct_answer": "-384", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 249, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 + 3 * -8) - (-8 - 2 + 2)) * ((-9 - 6 * -8) - (6 - 3 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (8 + 3 * -8), B = (-8 - 2 + 2), C = (-9 - 6 * -8) and D = (6 - 3 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 3 * -8) = (8 + (3 * -8)) = (8 + -24) = -16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 2 + 2) = ((-8 - 2) + 2) = (-10 + 2) = -8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 - 6 * -8) = (-9 - (6 * -8)) = (-9 - -48) = 39.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 - 3 * 0) = (6 - (3 * 0)) = (6 - 0) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((-16 - -8) * (39 - 6)) = (-8 * (39 - 6)) = (-8 * 33) = -264.\n(Final response) So the answer is -264.", "correct_answer": "-264", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 326, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((9 - -9 - -2) * (-6 * 0 + -1)) - ((-2 - 4 + -7) - (4 * 6 - -6))) - (((-6 - 1 * 1) * (-4 - 8 + 3)) + ((3 + -5 * 7) + (8 - 7 * 5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C - D)) - ((E * F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (9 - -9 - -2), B = (-6 * 0 + -1), C = (-2 - 4 + -7), D = (4 * 6 - -6), E = (-6 - 1 * 1), F = (-4 - 8 + 3), G = (3 + -5 * 7) and H = (8 - 7 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - -9 - -2) = ((9 - -9) - -2) = (18 - -2) = 20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 0 + -1) = ((-6 * 0) + -1) = (0 + -1) = -1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 - 4 + -7) = ((-2 - 4) + -7) = (-6 + -7) = -13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * 6 - -6) = ((4 * 6) - -6) = (24 - -6) = 30.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-6 - 1 * 1) = (-6 - (1 * 1)) = (-6 - 1) = -7.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-4 - 8 + 3) = ((-4 - 8) + 3) = (-12 + 3) = -9.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 + -5 * 7) = (3 + (-5 * 7)) = (3 + -35) = -32.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 - 7 * 5) = (8 - (7 * 5)) = (8 - 35) = -27.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C - D)) - ((E * F) + (G + H))) = (((20 * -1) - (-13 - 30)) - ((-7 * -9) + (-32 + -27))) = ((-20 - (-13 - 30)) - ((-7 * -9) + (-32 + -27))) = ((-20 - -43) - ((-7 * -9) + (-32 + -27))) = ((-20 - -43) - (63 + (-32 + -27))) = ((-20 - -43) - (63 + -59)) = (23 - (63 + -59)) = (23 - 4) = 19.\n(Final response) So the answer is 19.", "correct_answer": "19", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 263, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 + 1 * 0 - 4 + 0 - -1) + (-5 * -9 + 0 + -3 - -5 + -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-7 + 1 * 0 - 4 + 0 - -1) and B = (-5 * -9 + 0 + -3 - -5 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 1 * 0 - 4 + 0 - -1) = ((((-7 + (1 * 0)) - 4) + 0) - -1) = ((((-7 + 0) - 4) + 0) - -1) = (((-7 - 4) + 0) - -1) = ((-11 + 0) - -1) = (-11 - -1) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -9 + 0 + -3 - -5 + -4) = (((((-5 * -9) + 0) + -3) - -5) + -4) = ((((45 + 0) + -3) - -5) + -4) = (((45 + -3) - -5) + -4) = ((42 - -5) + -4) = (47 + -4) = 43.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-10 + 43) = 33.\n(Final response) So the answer is 33.", "correct_answer": "33", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 115, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 * 1 - 5 - -3) * (-1 * 7 + -1 + -1)) + ((2 + 9 * 5 - -2) + (-4 + -4 * -7 - -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-1 * 1 - 5 - -3), B = (-1 * 7 + -1 + -1), C = (2 + 9 * 5 - -2) and D = (-4 + -4 * -7 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 1 - 5 - -3) = (((-1 * 1) - 5) - -3) = ((-1 - 5) - -3) = (-6 - -3) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * 7 + -1 + -1) = (((-1 * 7) + -1) + -1) = ((-7 + -1) + -1) = (-8 + -1) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + 9 * 5 - -2) = ((2 + (9 * 5)) - -2) = ((2 + 45) - -2) = (47 - -2) = 49.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + -4 * -7 - -5) = ((-4 + (-4 * -7)) - -5) = ((-4 + 28) - -5) = (24 - -5) = 29.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((-3 * -9) + (49 + 29)) = (27 + (49 + 29)) = (27 + 78) = 105.\n(Final response) So the answer is 105.", "correct_answer": "105", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 527, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 + -7 * 5 - 9) * (-6 * -1 + 3 * 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-4 + -7 * 5 - 9) and B = (-6 * -1 + 3 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -7 * 5 - 9) = ((-4 + (-7 * 5)) - 9) = ((-4 + -35) - 9) = (-39 - 9) = -48.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * -1 + 3 * 8) = ((-6 * -1) + (3 * 8)) = (6 + (3 * 8)) = (6 + 24) = 30.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-48 * 30) = -1440.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1440.", "correct_answer": "-1440", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 180, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 - 9 + 0 - -6) * (-4 - -2 - 7 + -9)) - ((9 - 7 + 2 - -3) * (-2 * 7 + -2 * 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-6 - 9 + 0 - -6), B = (-4 - -2 - 7 + -9), C = (9 - 7 + 2 - -3) and D = (-2 * 7 + -2 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 9 + 0 - -6) = (((-6 - 9) + 0) - -6) = ((-15 + 0) - -6) = (-15 - -6) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - -2 - 7 + -9) = (((-4 - -2) - 7) + -9) = ((-2 - 7) + -9) = (-9 + -9) = -18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - 7 + 2 - -3) = (((9 - 7) + 2) - -3) = ((2 + 2) - -3) = (4 - -3) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * 7 + -2 * 1) = ((-2 * 7) + (-2 * 1)) = (-14 + (-2 * 1)) = (-14 + -2) = -16.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-9 * -18) - (7 * -16)) = (162 - (7 * -16)) = (162 - -112) = 274.\n(Final response) So the answer is 274.", "correct_answer": "274", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 537, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + 8 + -3 + 7) * (-3 - -5 - -2 + 2)) * ((-4 + 2 + 6 + -3) * (-4 + -7 - -7 - -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (1 + 8 + -3 + 7), B = (-3 - -5 - -2 + 2), C = (-4 + 2 + 6 + -3) and D = (-4 + -7 - -7 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 8 + -3 + 7) = (((1 + 8) + -3) + 7) = ((9 + -3) + 7) = (6 + 7) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - -5 - -2 + 2) = (((-3 - -5) - -2) + 2) = ((2 - -2) + 2) = (4 + 2) = 6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + 2 + 6 + -3) = (((-4 + 2) + 6) + -3) = ((-2 + 6) + -3) = (4 + -3) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + -7 - -7 - -1) = (((-4 + -7) - -7) - -1) = ((-11 - -7) - -1) = (-4 - -1) = -3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((13 * 6) * (1 * -3)) = (78 * (1 * -3)) = (78 * -3) = -234.\n(Final response) So the answer is -234.", "correct_answer": "-234", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 587, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 * 7 + -3) + (-7 - -3 + 7)) - ((6 - 5 * 1) - (-4 + -3 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-8 * 7 + -3), B = (-7 - -3 + 7), C = (6 - 5 * 1) and D = (-4 + -3 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 7 + -3) = ((-8 * 7) + -3) = (-56 + -3) = -59.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -3 + 7) = ((-7 - -3) + 7) = (-4 + 7) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 5 * 1) = (6 - (5 * 1)) = (6 - 5) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + -3 * 0) = (-4 + (-3 * 0)) = (-4 + 0) = -4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((-59 + 3) - (1 - -4)) = (-56 - (1 - -4)) = (-56 - 5) = -61.\n(Final response) So the answer is -61.", "correct_answer": "-61", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 386, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * -5 * 4) * (-9 + 4 * -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-9 * -5 * 4) and B = (-9 + 4 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * -5 * 4) = ((-9 * -5) * 4) = (45 * 4) = 180.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 4 * -1) = (-9 + (4 * -1)) = (-9 + -4) = -13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (180 * -13) = -2340.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2340.", "correct_answer": "-2340", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 10, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 - 6 * 0 - -4) * (9 * 3 - -7 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (8 - 6 * 0 - -4) and B = (9 * 3 - -7 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - 6 * 0 - -4) = ((8 - (6 * 0)) - -4) = ((8 - 0) - -4) = (8 - -4) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 3 - -7 - -4) = (((9 * 3) - -7) - -4) = ((27 - -7) - -4) = (34 - -4) = 38.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (12 * 38) = 456.\n(Final response) So the answer is 456.", "correct_answer": "456", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 199, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 + 9 + -5 - 1) * (-2 - -6 * 9 * -3)) - ((-6 - -9 + 1 - 5) - (3 * 8 - -3 + -8))) - (((-1 * -5 * 7 * -3) - (1 - -7 + -2 * -1)) - ((8 * 0 * 0 - 2) * (-4 + -9 + -1 + 6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C - D)) - ((E - F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (2 + 9 + -5 - 1), B = (-2 - -6 * 9 * -3), C = (-6 - -9 + 1 - 5), D = (3 * 8 - -3 + -8), E = (-1 * -5 * 7 * -3), F = (1 - -7 + -2 * -1), G = (8 * 0 * 0 - 2) and H = (-4 + -9 + -1 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + 9 + -5 - 1) = (((2 + 9) + -5) - 1) = ((11 + -5) - 1) = (6 - 1) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - -6 * 9 * -3) = (-2 - ((-6 * 9) * -3)) = (-2 - (-54 * -3)) = (-2 - 162) = -164.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 - -9 + 1 - 5) = (((-6 - -9) + 1) - 5) = ((3 + 1) - 5) = (4 - 5) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * 8 - -3 + -8) = (((3 * 8) - -3) + -8) = ((24 - -3) + -8) = (27 + -8) = 19.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-1 * -5 * 7 * -3) = (((-1 * -5) * 7) * -3) = ((5 * 7) * -3) = (35 * -3) = -105.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (1 - -7 + -2 * -1) = ((1 - -7) + (-2 * -1)) = (8 + (-2 * -1)) = (8 + 2) = 10.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 * 0 * 0 - 2) = (((8 * 0) * 0) - 2) = ((0 * 0) - 2) = (0 - 2) = -2.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-4 + -9 + -1 + 6) = (((-4 + -9) + -1) + 6) = ((-13 + -1) + 6) = (-14 + 6) = -8.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C - D)) - ((E - F) - (G * H))) = (((5 * -164) - (-1 - 19)) - ((-105 - 10) - (-2 * -8))) = ((-820 - (-1 - 19)) - ((-105 - 10) - (-2 * -8))) = ((-820 - -20) - ((-105 - 10) - (-2 * -8))) = ((-820 - -20) - (-115 - (-2 * -8))) = ((-820 - -20) - (-115 - 16)) = (-800 - (-115 - 16)) = (-800 - -131) = -669.\n(Final response) So the answer is -669.", "correct_answer": "-669", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 288, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 * -9 + 5) * (1 - -7 - 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 * -9 + 5) and B = (1 - -7 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * -9 + 5) = ((-5 * -9) + 5) = (45 + 5) = 50.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - -7 - 4) = ((1 - -7) - 4) = (8 - 4) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (50 * 4) = 200.\n(Final response) So the answer is 200.", "correct_answer": "200", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 11, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 + -2 - 6) - (2 * 5 - -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (3 + -2 - 6) and B = (2 * 5 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + -2 - 6) = ((3 + -2) - 6) = (1 - 6) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 5 - -8) = ((2 * 5) - -8) = (10 - -8) = 18.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-5 - 18) = -23.\n(Final response) So the answer is -23.", "correct_answer": "-23", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 31, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 * 2 + -7) + (-5 + -2 * 5)) * ((8 - -1 + -6) + (-9 - 3 + -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-4 * 2 + -7), B = (-5 + -2 * 5), C = (8 - -1 + -6) and D = (-9 - 3 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * 2 + -7) = ((-4 * 2) + -7) = (-8 + -7) = -15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + -2 * 5) = (-5 + (-2 * 5)) = (-5 + -10) = -15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 - -1 + -6) = ((8 - -1) + -6) = (9 + -6) = 3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 - 3 + -7) = ((-9 - 3) + -7) = (-12 + -7) = -19.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-15 + -15) * (3 + -19)) = (-30 * (3 + -19)) = (-30 * -16) = 480.\n(Final response) So the answer is 480.", "correct_answer": "480", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 308, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 - 9 * -5) * (-8 * -4 - -3)) - ((-8 * -7 + -2) - (1 - -9 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-8 - 9 * -5), B = (-8 * -4 - -3), C = (-8 * -7 + -2) and D = (1 - -9 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 9 * -5) = (-8 - (9 * -5)) = (-8 - -45) = 37.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * -4 - -3) = ((-8 * -4) - -3) = (32 - -3) = 35.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * -7 + -2) = ((-8 * -7) + -2) = (56 + -2) = 54.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 - -9 * -6) = (1 - (-9 * -6)) = (1 - 54) = -53.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((37 * 35) - (54 - -53)) = (1295 - (54 - -53)) = (1295 - 107) = 1188.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1188.", "correct_answer": "1188", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 401, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 - 7 - -3 + 1) + (1 * -6 * 5 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-8 - 7 - -3 + 1) and B = (1 * -6 * 5 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 7 - -3 + 1) = (((-8 - 7) - -3) + 1) = ((-15 - -3) + 1) = (-12 + 1) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -6 * 5 - 2) = (((1 * -6) * 5) - 2) = ((-6 * 5) - 2) = (-30 - 2) = -32.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-11 + -32) = -43.\n(Final response) So the answer is -43.", "correct_answer": "-43", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 277, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 + 6 * -4) - (-5 + 9 - 4)) + ((-7 - -5 * 7) - (2 + -1 + -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (6 + 6 * -4), B = (-5 + 9 - 4), C = (-7 - -5 * 7) and D = (2 + -1 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 6 * -4) = (6 + (6 * -4)) = (6 + -24) = -18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + 9 - 4) = ((-5 + 9) - 4) = (4 - 4) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - -5 * 7) = (-7 - (-5 * 7)) = (-7 - -35) = 28.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 + -1 + -7) = ((2 + -1) + -7) = (1 + -7) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-18 - 0) + (28 - -6)) = (-18 + (28 - -6)) = (-18 + 34) = 16.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16.", "correct_answer": "16", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 406, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 * 3 - 5 * 6) * (5 - 4 * -4 * -5)) * ((1 - -1 + 7 * -1) + (-6 - 8 + -7 - -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-9 * 3 - 5 * 6), B = (5 - 4 * -4 * -5), C = (1 - -1 + 7 * -1) and D = (-6 - 8 + -7 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 3 - 5 * 6) = ((-9 * 3) - (5 * 6)) = (-27 - (5 * 6)) = (-27 - 30) = -57.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 4 * -4 * -5) = (5 - ((4 * -4) * -5)) = (5 - (-16 * -5)) = (5 - 80) = -75.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - -1 + 7 * -1) = ((1 - -1) + (7 * -1)) = (2 + (7 * -1)) = (2 + -7) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - 8 + -7 - -1) = (((-6 - 8) + -7) - -1) = ((-14 + -7) - -1) = (-21 - -1) = -20.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((-57 * -75) * (-5 + -20)) = (4275 * (-5 + -20)) = (4275 * -25) = -106875.\n(Final response) So the answer is -106875.", "correct_answer": "-106875", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 547, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 + -4 + 9 * 7 - 1 * 8) * (1 - -2 * -1 * -3 + 3 + -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-2 + -4 + 9 * 7 - 1 * 8) and B = (1 - -2 * -1 * -3 + 3 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -4 + 9 * 7 - 1 * 8) = (((-2 + -4) + (9 * 7)) - (1 * 8)) = ((-6 + (9 * 7)) - (1 * 8)) = ((-6 + 63) - (1 * 8)) = ((-6 + 63) - 8) = (57 - 8) = 49.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - -2 * -1 * -3 + 3 + -6) = (((1 - ((-2 * -1) * -3)) + 3) + -6) = (((1 - (2 * -3)) + 3) + -6) = (((1 - -6) + 3) + -6) = ((7 + 3) + -6) = (10 + -6) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (49 * 4) = 196.\n(Final response) So the answer is 196.", "correct_answer": "196", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 93, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 + -8 - 5 * -4 * -3 - -7) - (-1 - -4 + 1 * 8 + -6 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-6 + -8 - 5 * -4 * -3 - -7) and B = (-1 - -4 + 1 * 8 + -6 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + -8 - 5 * -4 * -3 - -7) = (((-6 + -8) - ((5 * -4) * -3)) - -7) = ((-14 - ((5 * -4) * -3)) - -7) = ((-14 - (-20 * -3)) - -7) = ((-14 - 60) - -7) = (-74 - -7) = -67.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - -4 + 1 * 8 + -6 * 3) = (((-1 - -4) + (1 * 8)) + (-6 * 3)) = ((3 + (1 * 8)) + (-6 * 3)) = ((3 + 8) + (-6 * 3)) = ((3 + 8) + -18) = (11 + -18) = -7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-67 - -7) = -60.\n(Final response) So the answer is -60.", "correct_answer": "-60", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 94, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 * -4 - 6) + (-1 - 1 + 3)) * ((9 * 2 * -2) - (-1 + 7 - -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-6 * -4 - 6), B = (-1 - 1 + 3), C = (9 * 2 * -2) and D = (-1 + 7 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * -4 - 6) = ((-6 * -4) - 6) = (24 - 6) = 18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 1 + 3) = ((-1 - 1) + 3) = (-2 + 3) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 * 2 * -2) = ((9 * 2) * -2) = (18 * -2) = -36.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 + 7 - -6) = ((-1 + 7) - -6) = (6 - -6) = 12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((18 + 1) * (-36 - 12)) = (19 * (-36 - 12)) = (19 * -48) = -912.\n(Final response) So the answer is -912.", "correct_answer": "-912", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 364, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 - -4 * -8) * (1 - 9 + 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (7 - -4 * -8) and B = (1 - 9 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -4 * -8) = (7 - (-4 * -8)) = (7 - 32) = -25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - 9 + 2) = ((1 - 9) + 2) = (-8 + 2) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-25 * -6) = 150.\n(Final response) So the answer is 150.", "correct_answer": "150", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 78, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 + 3 * -7) * (2 + 5 - -2)) * ((7 + -2 - 0) * (9 * -6 - -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (9 + 3 * -7), B = (2 + 5 - -2), C = (7 + -2 - 0) and D = (9 * -6 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + 3 * -7) = (9 + (3 * -7)) = (9 + -21) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + 5 - -2) = ((2 + 5) - -2) = (7 - -2) = 9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + -2 - 0) = ((7 + -2) - 0) = (5 - 0) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 * -6 - -7) = ((9 * -6) - -7) = (-54 - -7) = -47.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((-12 * 9) * (5 * -47)) = (-108 * (5 * -47)) = (-108 * -235) = 25380.\n(Final response) So the answer is 25380.", "correct_answer": "25380", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 334, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 + 0 * 5 + 7) * (-7 + 1 - 0 + -1)) * ((1 - -5 + -9 + 0) - (0 + -6 - 9 - 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-4 + 0 * 5 + 7), B = (-7 + 1 - 0 + -1), C = (1 - -5 + -9 + 0) and D = (0 + -6 - 9 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + 0 * 5 + 7) = ((-4 + (0 * 5)) + 7) = ((-4 + 0) + 7) = (-4 + 7) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + 1 - 0 + -1) = (((-7 + 1) - 0) + -1) = ((-6 - 0) + -1) = (-6 + -1) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - -5 + -9 + 0) = (((1 - -5) + -9) + 0) = ((6 + -9) + 0) = (-3 + 0) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + -6 - 9 - 7) = (((0 + -6) - 9) - 7) = ((-6 - 9) - 7) = (-15 - 7) = -22.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((3 * -7) * (-3 - -22)) = (-21 * (-3 - -22)) = (-21 * 19) = -399.\n(Final response) So the answer is -399.", "correct_answer": "-399", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 554, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 - 6 + -4 - -7) + (-5 - -4 - -6 * 3)) * ((9 * -5 + -7 - -7) * (-3 * 5 * 6 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (2 - 6 + -4 - -7), B = (-5 - -4 - -6 * 3), C = (9 * -5 + -7 - -7) and D = (-3 * 5 * 6 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - 6 + -4 - -7) = (((2 - 6) + -4) - -7) = ((-4 + -4) - -7) = (-8 - -7) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -4 - -6 * 3) = ((-5 - -4) - (-6 * 3)) = (-1 - (-6 * 3)) = (-1 - -18) = 17.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 * -5 + -7 - -7) = (((9 * -5) + -7) - -7) = ((-45 + -7) - -7) = (-52 - -7) = -45.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * 5 * 6 + -8) = (((-3 * 5) * 6) + -8) = ((-15 * 6) + -8) = (-90 + -8) = -98.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((-1 + 17) * (-45 * -98)) = (16 * (-45 * -98)) = (16 * 4410) = 70560.\n(Final response) So the answer is 70560.", "correct_answer": "70560", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 528, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 * 4 + -6 + 1) - (-6 + 5 - 7 * 0)) + ((2 + 5 * -6 - 7) - (-4 - -5 - -8 + -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (2 * 4 + -6 + 1), B = (-6 + 5 - 7 * 0), C = (2 + 5 * -6 - 7) and D = (-4 - -5 - -8 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 4 + -6 + 1) = (((2 * 4) + -6) + 1) = ((8 + -6) + 1) = (2 + 1) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + 5 - 7 * 0) = ((-6 + 5) - (7 * 0)) = (-1 - (7 * 0)) = (-1 - 0) = -1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + 5 * -6 - 7) = ((2 + (5 * -6)) - 7) = ((2 + -30) - 7) = (-28 - 7) = -35.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -5 - -8 + -4) = (((-4 - -5) - -8) + -4) = ((1 - -8) + -4) = (9 + -4) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((3 - -1) + (-35 - 5)) = (4 + (-35 - 5)) = (4 + -40) = -36.\n(Final response) So the answer is -36.", "correct_answer": "-36", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 568, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 * 4 - 9) - (-7 * 7 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (2 * 4 - 9) and B = (-7 * 7 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 4 - 9) = ((2 * 4) - 9) = (8 - 9) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 7 - -2) = ((-7 * 7) - -2) = (-49 - -2) = -47.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-1 - -47) = 46.\n(Final response) So the answer is 46.", "correct_answer": "46", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 41, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-7 * -4 * 7) + (-5 * 1 + 3)) + ((1 - -6 - 0) * (1 - -9 + -8))) - (((2 * 6 * 3) - (1 * -2 + -2)) * ((7 + 3 - 5) * (3 * -2 * 2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C * D)) - ((E - F) * (G * H)))\", where A = (-7 * -4 * 7), B = (-5 * 1 + 3), C = (1 - -6 - 0), D = (1 - -9 + -8), E = (2 * 6 * 3), F = (1 * -2 + -2), G = (7 + 3 - 5) and H = (3 * -2 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * -4 * 7) = ((-7 * -4) * 7) = (28 * 7) = 196.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 1 + 3) = ((-5 * 1) + 3) = (-5 + 3) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - -6 - 0) = ((1 - -6) - 0) = (7 - 0) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 - -9 + -8) = ((1 - -9) + -8) = (10 + -8) = 2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (2 * 6 * 3) = ((2 * 6) * 3) = (12 * 3) = 36.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (1 * -2 + -2) = ((1 * -2) + -2) = (-2 + -2) = -4.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 + 3 - 5) = ((7 + 3) - 5) = (10 - 5) = 5.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (3 * -2 * 2) = ((3 * -2) * 2) = (-6 * 2) = -12.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C * D)) - ((E - F) * (G * H))) = (((196 + -2) + (7 * 2)) - ((36 - -4) * (5 * -12))) = ((194 + (7 * 2)) - ((36 - -4) * (5 * -12))) = ((194 + 14) - ((36 - -4) * (5 * -12))) = ((194 + 14) - (40 * (5 * -12))) = ((194 + 14) - (40 * -60)) = (208 - (40 * -60)) = (208 - -2400) = 2608.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2608.", "correct_answer": "2608", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 247, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 + -4 - 7 - -2 * -5) + (-6 - 1 - -5 + 4 - 0)) * ((-7 * -2 + -5 * 0 * -2) + (-1 + 5 + -5 * -6 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-4 + -4 - 7 - -2 * -5), B = (-6 - 1 - -5 + 4 - 0), C = (-7 * -2 + -5 * 0 * -2) and D = (-1 + 5 + -5 * -6 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -4 - 7 - -2 * -5) = (((-4 + -4) - 7) - (-2 * -5)) = ((-8 - 7) - (-2 * -5)) = ((-8 - 7) - 10) = (-15 - 10) = -25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - 1 - -5 + 4 - 0) = ((((-6 - 1) - -5) + 4) - 0) = (((-7 - -5) + 4) - 0) = ((-2 + 4) - 0) = (2 - 0) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * -2 + -5 * 0 * -2) = ((-7 * -2) + ((-5 * 0) * -2)) = (14 + ((-5 * 0) * -2)) = (14 + (0 * -2)) = (14 + 0) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 + 5 + -5 * -6 * 0) = ((-1 + 5) + ((-5 * -6) * 0)) = (4 + ((-5 * -6) * 0)) = (4 + (30 * 0)) = (4 + 0) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-25 + 2) * (14 + 4)) = (-23 * (14 + 4)) = (-23 * 18) = -414.\n(Final response) So the answer is -414.", "correct_answer": "-414", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 196, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * 8 + 3) + (3 * 0 - -3)) - ((-5 * 0 - 3) * (-4 * 1 - -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-5 * 8 + 3), B = (3 * 0 - -3), C = (-5 * 0 - 3) and D = (-4 * 1 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 8 + 3) = ((-5 * 8) + 3) = (-40 + 3) = -37.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 0 - -3) = ((3 * 0) - -3) = (0 - -3) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * 0 - 3) = ((-5 * 0) - 3) = (0 - 3) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * 1 - -9) = ((-4 * 1) - -9) = (-4 - -9) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-37 + 3) - (-3 * 5)) = (-34 - (-3 * 5)) = (-34 - -15) = -19.\n(Final response) So the answer is -19.", "correct_answer": "-19", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 353, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 - 7 - -9) - (8 - 4 * 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (2 - 7 - -9) and B = (8 - 4 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - 7 - -9) = ((2 - 7) - -9) = (-5 - -9) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 4 * 2) = (8 - (4 * 2)) = (8 - 8) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (4 - 0) = 4.\n(Final response) So the answer is 4.", "correct_answer": "4", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 139, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 - -1 * 2 * -5) - (0 - -3 * 1 * -2)) + ((-3 - 5 * -1 + -7) + (3 + -2 + -5 - -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (5 - -1 * 2 * -5), B = (0 - -3 * 1 * -2), C = (-3 - 5 * -1 + -7) and D = (3 + -2 + -5 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - -1 * 2 * -5) = (5 - ((-1 * 2) * -5)) = (5 - (-2 * -5)) = (5 - 10) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - -3 * 1 * -2) = (0 - ((-3 * 1) * -2)) = (0 - (-3 * -2)) = (0 - 6) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - 5 * -1 + -7) = ((-3 - (5 * -1)) + -7) = ((-3 - -5) + -7) = (2 + -7) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + -2 + -5 - -8) = (((3 + -2) + -5) - -8) = ((1 + -5) - -8) = (-4 - -8) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-5 - -6) + (-5 + 4)) = (1 + (-5 + 4)) = (1 + -1) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 165, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 + 8 + 1) + (7 - -1 + 6)) + ((-7 * -2 - -4) * (-4 + -5 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (8 + 8 + 1), B = (7 - -1 + 6), C = (-7 * -2 - -4) and D = (-4 + -5 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 8 + 1) = ((8 + 8) + 1) = (16 + 1) = 17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - -1 + 6) = ((7 - -1) + 6) = (8 + 6) = 14.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * -2 - -4) = ((-7 * -2) - -4) = (14 - -4) = 18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + -5 + -1) = ((-4 + -5) + -1) = (-9 + -1) = -10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((17 + 14) + (18 * -10)) = (31 + (18 * -10)) = (31 + -180) = -149.\n(Final response) So the answer is -149.", "correct_answer": "-149", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 375, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 * -8 + 2) - (-7 + -9 + 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-6 * -8 + 2) and B = (-7 + -9 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * -8 + 2) = ((-6 * -8) + 2) = (48 + 2) = 50.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -9 + 9) = ((-7 + -9) + 9) = (-16 + 9) = -7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (50 - -7) = 57.\n(Final response) So the answer is 57.", "correct_answer": "57", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 39, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((4 + 8 * 1) * (7 + -8 - 3)) - ((5 * -6 * 4) - (7 + 5 * 6))) - (((2 * 2 - -4) + (-9 - 7 + -5)) * ((-1 + -4 + 0) - (-9 + -9 + -7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C - D)) - ((E + F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (4 + 8 * 1), B = (7 + -8 - 3), C = (5 * -6 * 4), D = (7 + 5 * 6), E = (2 * 2 - -4), F = (-9 - 7 + -5), G = (-1 + -4 + 0) and H = (-9 + -9 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + 8 * 1) = (4 + (8 * 1)) = (4 + 8) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + -8 - 3) = ((7 + -8) - 3) = (-1 - 3) = -4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 * -6 * 4) = ((5 * -6) * 4) = (-30 * 4) = -120.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + 5 * 6) = (7 + (5 * 6)) = (7 + 30) = 37.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (2 * 2 - -4) = ((2 * 2) - -4) = (4 - -4) = 8.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-9 - 7 + -5) = ((-9 - 7) + -5) = (-16 + -5) = -21.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-1 + -4 + 0) = ((-1 + -4) + 0) = (-5 + 0) = -5.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-9 + -9 + -7) = ((-9 + -9) + -7) = (-18 + -7) = -25.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C - D)) - ((E + F) * (G - H))) = (((12 * -4) - (-120 - 37)) - ((8 + -21) * (-5 - -25))) = ((-48 - (-120 - 37)) - ((8 + -21) * (-5 - -25))) = ((-48 - -157) - ((8 + -21) * (-5 - -25))) = ((-48 - -157) - (-13 * (-5 - -25))) = ((-48 - -157) - (-13 * 20)) = (109 - (-13 * 20)) = (109 - -260) = 369.\n(Final response) So the answer is 369.", "correct_answer": "369", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 242, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 * -7 + 2) * (1 + -4 * 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-6 * -7 + 2) and B = (1 + -4 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * -7 + 2) = ((-6 * -7) + 2) = (42 + 2) = 44.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + -4 * 5) = (1 + (-4 * 5)) = (1 + -20) = -19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (44 * -19) = -836.\n(Final response) So the answer is -836.", "correct_answer": "-836", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 140, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 - -3 - -4) * (4 - 8 * -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (3 - -3 - -4) and B = (4 - 8 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - -3 - -4) = ((3 - -3) - -4) = (6 - -4) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 8 * -8) = (4 - (8 * -8)) = (4 - -64) = 68.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (10 * 68) = 680.\n(Final response) So the answer is 680.", "correct_answer": "680", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 0, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - 5 * 7 + 5 - 6) + (-1 + 7 + 3 + -5 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-2 - 5 * 7 + 5 - 6) and B = (-1 + 7 + 3 + -5 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - 5 * 7 + 5 - 6) = (((-2 - (5 * 7)) + 5) - 6) = (((-2 - 35) + 5) - 6) = ((-37 + 5) - 6) = (-32 - 6) = -38.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + 7 + 3 + -5 - -4) = ((((-1 + 7) + 3) + -5) - -4) = (((6 + 3) + -5) - -4) = ((9 + -5) - -4) = (4 - -4) = 8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-38 + 8) = -30.\n(Final response) So the answer is -30.", "correct_answer": "-30", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 80, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 - 9 + 6) + (0 + 4 * -6)) * ((-1 * -1 - -6) * (-6 + -9 + 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-8 - 9 + 6), B = (0 + 4 * -6), C = (-1 * -1 - -6) and D = (-6 + -9 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 9 + 6) = ((-8 - 9) + 6) = (-17 + 6) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + 4 * -6) = (0 + (4 * -6)) = (0 + -24) = -24.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * -1 - -6) = ((-1 * -1) - -6) = (1 - -6) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + -9 + 9) = ((-6 + -9) + 9) = (-15 + 9) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((-11 + -24) * (7 * -6)) = (-35 * (7 * -6)) = (-35 * -42) = 1470.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1470.", "correct_answer": "1470", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 419, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 - -3 * -4 + 3 - 5) - (6 + 5 - -3 + 5 - 9)) - ((-1 + 2 - -3 - -9 * -9) + (-8 * -6 - 2 + -6 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-7 - -3 * -4 + 3 - 5), B = (6 + 5 - -3 + 5 - 9), C = (-1 + 2 - -3 - -9 * -9) and D = (-8 * -6 - 2 + -6 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - -3 * -4 + 3 - 5) = (((-7 - (-3 * -4)) + 3) - 5) = (((-7 - 12) + 3) - 5) = ((-19 + 3) - 5) = (-16 - 5) = -21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 5 - -3 + 5 - 9) = ((((6 + 5) - -3) + 5) - 9) = (((11 - -3) + 5) - 9) = ((14 + 5) - 9) = (19 - 9) = 10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + 2 - -3 - -9 * -9) = (((-1 + 2) - -3) - (-9 * -9)) = ((1 - -3) - (-9 * -9)) = ((1 - -3) - 81) = (4 - 81) = -77.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 * -6 - 2 + -6 * 2) = (((-8 * -6) - 2) + (-6 * 2)) = ((48 - 2) + (-6 * 2)) = ((48 - 2) + -12) = (46 + -12) = 34.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-21 - 10) - (-77 + 34)) = (-31 - (-77 + 34)) = (-31 - -43) = 12.\n(Final response) So the answer is 12.", "correct_answer": "12", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 205, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - 3 - -3) * (-2 + 9 + 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (1 - 3 - -3) and B = (-2 + 9 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - 3 - -3) = ((1 - 3) - -3) = (-2 - -3) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 9 + 4) = ((-2 + 9) + 4) = (7 + 4) = 11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (1 * 11) = 11.\n(Final response) So the answer is 11.", "correct_answer": "11", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 126, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 + -5 + 7) - (-2 + 9 - -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 + -5 + 7) and B = (-2 + 9 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + -5 + 7) = ((6 + -5) + 7) = (1 + 7) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 9 - -7) = ((-2 + 9) - -7) = (7 - -7) = 14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (8 - 14) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 132, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 * -2 - 7 + 6 - -8 - -2) + (3 - 0 - -8 * 4 * 2 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (3 * -2 - 7 + 6 - -8 - -2) and B = (3 - 0 - -8 * 4 * 2 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -2 - 7 + 6 - -8 - -2) = (((((3 * -2) - 7) + 6) - -8) - -2) = ((((-6 - 7) + 6) - -8) - -2) = (((-13 + 6) - -8) - -2) = ((-7 - -8) - -2) = (1 - -2) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - 0 - -8 * 4 * 2 * 4) = ((3 - 0) - (((-8 * 4) * 2) * 4)) = (3 - (((-8 * 4) * 2) * 4)) = (3 - ((-32 * 2) * 4)) = (3 - (-64 * 4)) = (3 - -256) = 259.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (3 + 259) = 262.\n(Final response) So the answer is 262.", "correct_answer": "262", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 109, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * 4 + 1 * -8) - (-8 + -6 - -3 * 6)) - ((9 + -6 * 1 - 8) + (7 - 6 + 7 * 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-5 * 4 + 1 * -8), B = (-8 + -6 - -3 * 6), C = (9 + -6 * 1 - 8) and D = (7 - 6 + 7 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 4 + 1 * -8) = ((-5 * 4) + (1 * -8)) = (-20 + (1 * -8)) = (-20 + -8) = -28.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + -6 - -3 * 6) = ((-8 + -6) - (-3 * 6)) = (-14 - (-3 * 6)) = (-14 - -18) = 4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 + -6 * 1 - 8) = ((9 + (-6 * 1)) - 8) = ((9 + -6) - 8) = (3 - 8) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 - 6 + 7 * 8) = ((7 - 6) + (7 * 8)) = (1 + (7 * 8)) = (1 + 56) = 57.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-28 - 4) - (-5 + 57)) = (-32 - (-5 + 57)) = (-32 - 52) = -84.\n(Final response) So the answer is -84.", "correct_answer": "-84", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 490, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + 8 + -7 - 4 - 4) - (1 * 1 * 7 - -4 - -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (5 + 8 + -7 - 4 - 4) and B = (1 * 1 * 7 - -4 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 8 + -7 - 4 - 4) = ((((5 + 8) + -7) - 4) - 4) = (((13 + -7) - 4) - 4) = ((6 - 4) - 4) = (2 - 4) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 1 * 7 - -4 - -5) = ((((1 * 1) * 7) - -4) - -5) = (((1 * 7) - -4) - -5) = ((7 - -4) - -5) = (11 - -5) = 16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-2 - 16) = -18.\n(Final response) So the answer is -18.", "correct_answer": "-18", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 79, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-6 - -6 + -1 * 7 + -5 + 8) - (-8 - 7 + 0 - -5 * 5 + -8)) * ((3 + 0 + 8 - 6 + 4 - 1) - (-1 - -4 + 0 * -4 + -1 - 6))) + (((-6 * 2 * -4 + 5 + 8 - 5) * (-7 + -1 - 2 * 2 - 5 * 6)) - ((-5 + -1 * -8 - 0 - 6 + 4) * (7 + 8 * 6 + 1 * 5 * 8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C - D)) + ((E * F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (-6 - -6 + -1 * 7 + -5 + 8), B = (-8 - 7 + 0 - -5 * 5 + -8), C = (3 + 0 + 8 - 6 + 4 - 1), D = (-1 - -4 + 0 * -4 + -1 - 6), E = (-6 * 2 * -4 + 5 + 8 - 5), F = (-7 + -1 - 2 * 2 - 5 * 6), G = (-5 + -1 * -8 - 0 - 6 + 4) and H = (7 + 8 * 6 + 1 * 5 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - -6 + -1 * 7 + -5 + 8) = ((((-6 - -6) + (-1 * 7)) + -5) + 8) = (((0 + (-1 * 7)) + -5) + 8) = (((0 + -7) + -5) + 8) = ((-7 + -5) + 8) = (-12 + 8) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 7 + 0 - -5 * 5 + -8) = ((((-8 - 7) + 0) - (-5 * 5)) + -8) = (((-15 + 0) - (-5 * 5)) + -8) = (((-15 + 0) - -25) + -8) = ((-15 - -25) + -8) = (10 + -8) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + 0 + 8 - 6 + 4 - 1) = (((((3 + 0) + 8) - 6) + 4) - 1) = ((((3 + 8) - 6) + 4) - 1) = (((11 - 6) + 4) - 1) = ((5 + 4) - 1) = (9 - 1) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 - -4 + 0 * -4 + -1 - 6) = ((((-1 - -4) + (0 * -4)) + -1) - 6) = (((3 + (0 * -4)) + -1) - 6) = (((3 + 0) + -1) - 6) = ((3 + -1) - 6) = (2 - 6) = -4.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-6 * 2 * -4 + 5 + 8 - 5) = (((((-6 * 2) * -4) + 5) + 8) - 5) = ((((-12 * -4) + 5) + 8) - 5) = (((48 + 5) + 8) - 5) = ((53 + 8) - 5) = (61 - 5) = 56.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-7 + -1 - 2 * 2 - 5 * 6) = (((-7 + -1) - (2 * 2)) - (5 * 6)) = ((-8 - (2 * 2)) - (5 * 6)) = ((-8 - 4) - (5 * 6)) = ((-8 - 4) - 30) = (-12 - 30) = -42.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-5 + -1 * -8 - 0 - 6 + 4) = ((((-5 + (-1 * -8)) - 0) - 6) + 4) = ((((-5 + 8) - 0) - 6) + 4) = (((3 - 0) - 6) + 4) = ((3 - 6) + 4) = (-3 + 4) = 1.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (7 + 8 * 6 + 1 * 5 * 8) = ((7 + (8 * 6)) + ((1 * 5) * 8)) = ((7 + 48) + ((1 * 5) * 8)) = ((7 + 48) + (5 * 8)) = (55 + (5 * 8)) = (55 + 40) = 95.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C - D)) + ((E * F) - (G * H))) = (((-4 - 2) * (8 - -4)) + ((56 * -42) - (1 * 95))) = ((-6 * (8 - -4)) + ((56 * -42) - (1 * 95))) = ((-6 * 12) + ((56 * -42) - (1 * 95))) = ((-6 * 12) + (-2352 - (1 * 95))) = ((-6 * 12) + (-2352 - 95)) = (-72 + (-2352 - 95)) = (-72 + -2447) = -2519.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2519.", "correct_answer": "-2519", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 353, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 * -2 - 4 - -3) * (-4 + 4 - 2 * -3)) + ((2 + 1 - 2 - -3) * (-9 * 3 + 9 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-4 * -2 - 4 - -3), B = (-4 + 4 - 2 * -3), C = (2 + 1 - 2 - -3) and D = (-9 * 3 + 9 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -2 - 4 - -3) = (((-4 * -2) - 4) - -3) = ((8 - 4) - -3) = (4 - -3) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 4 - 2 * -3) = ((-4 + 4) - (2 * -3)) = (0 - (2 * -3)) = (0 - -6) = 6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + 1 - 2 - -3) = (((2 + 1) - 2) - -3) = ((3 - 2) - -3) = (1 - -3) = 4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 * 3 + 9 + -1) = (((-9 * 3) + 9) + -1) = ((-27 + 9) + -1) = (-18 + -1) = -19.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((7 * 6) + (4 * -19)) = (42 + (4 * -19)) = (42 + -76) = -34.\n(Final response) So the answer is -34.", "correct_answer": "-34", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 525, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * -6 + 9 * 9) * (6 - -2 - -5 + 9)) + ((-7 * 7 * 7 - 3) - (4 * 2 * -9 * -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-5 * -6 + 9 * 9), B = (6 - -2 - -5 + 9), C = (-7 * 7 * 7 - 3) and D = (4 * 2 * -9 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * -6 + 9 * 9) = ((-5 * -6) + (9 * 9)) = (30 + (9 * 9)) = (30 + 81) = 111.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - -2 - -5 + 9) = (((6 - -2) - -5) + 9) = ((8 - -5) + 9) = (13 + 9) = 22.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * 7 * 7 - 3) = (((-7 * 7) * 7) - 3) = ((-49 * 7) - 3) = (-343 - 3) = -346.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * 2 * -9 * -7) = (((4 * 2) * -9) * -7) = ((8 * -9) * -7) = (-72 * -7) = 504.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((111 * 22) + (-346 - 504)) = (2442 + (-346 - 504)) = (2442 + -850) = 1592.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1592.", "correct_answer": "1592", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 573, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 * 4 - 5 + 5) - (3 + -7 - -5 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-4 * 4 - 5 + 5) and B = (3 + -7 - -5 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * 4 - 5 + 5) = (((-4 * 4) - 5) + 5) = ((-16 - 5) + 5) = (-21 + 5) = -16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + -7 - -5 - 7) = (((3 + -7) - -5) - 7) = ((-4 - -5) - 7) = (1 - 7) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-16 - -6) = -10.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10.", "correct_answer": "-10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 258, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * 3 - -4) * (-4 * 3 * 3)) - ((3 + -2 + 7) + (3 + 3 + 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (3 * 3 - -4), B = (-4 * 3 * 3), C = (3 + -2 + 7) and D = (3 + 3 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 3 - -4) = ((3 * 3) - -4) = (9 - -4) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 3 * 3) = ((-4 * 3) * 3) = (-12 * 3) = -36.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + -2 + 7) = ((3 + -2) + 7) = (1 + 7) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + 3 + 4) = ((3 + 3) + 4) = (6 + 4) = 10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((13 * -36) - (8 + 10)) = (-468 - (8 + 10)) = (-468 - 18) = -486.\n(Final response) So the answer is -486.", "correct_answer": "-486", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 134, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * 6 * 7 - 2) * (0 * 5 - -1 - -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-9 * 6 * 7 - 2) and B = (0 * 5 - -1 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 6 * 7 - 2) = (((-9 * 6) * 7) - 2) = ((-54 * 7) - 2) = (-378 - 2) = -380.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 5 - -1 - -5) = (((0 * 5) - -1) - -5) = ((0 - -1) - -5) = (1 - -5) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-380 * 6) = -2280.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2280.", "correct_answer": "-2280", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 162, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 - -6 + -8) + (0 * 2 * -8)) * ((4 + 5 + -1) - (9 * 2 + -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (3 - -6 + -8), B = (0 * 2 * -8), C = (4 + 5 + -1) and D = (9 * 2 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - -6 + -8) = ((3 - -6) + -8) = (9 + -8) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 2 * -8) = ((0 * 2) * -8) = (0 * -8) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + 5 + -1) = ((4 + 5) + -1) = (9 + -1) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 * 2 + -9) = ((9 * 2) + -9) = (18 + -9) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((1 + 0) * (8 - 9)) = (1 * (8 - 9)) = (1 * -1) = -1.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1.", "correct_answer": "-1", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 304, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 * -2 * 4 * 1) + (-7 + 9 - -2 + -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (3 * -2 * 4 * 1) and B = (-7 + 9 - -2 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -2 * 4 * 1) = (((3 * -2) * 4) * 1) = ((-6 * 4) * 1) = (-24 * 1) = -24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + 9 - -2 + -7) = (((-7 + 9) - -2) + -7) = ((2 - -2) + -7) = (4 + -7) = -3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-24 + -3) = -27.\n(Final response) So the answer is -27.", "correct_answer": "-27", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 286, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 + 1 - 1 * -4) * (-8 + -7 * -5 + 1)) + ((2 - -7 + -7 - -4) - (7 + -2 - 5 - 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-6 + 1 - 1 * -4), B = (-8 + -7 * -5 + 1), C = (2 - -7 + -7 - -4) and D = (7 + -2 - 5 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 1 - 1 * -4) = ((-6 + 1) - (1 * -4)) = (-5 - (1 * -4)) = (-5 - -4) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + -7 * -5 + 1) = ((-8 + (-7 * -5)) + 1) = ((-8 + 35) + 1) = (27 + 1) = 28.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - -7 + -7 - -4) = (((2 - -7) + -7) - -4) = ((9 + -7) - -4) = (2 - -4) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + -2 - 5 - 3) = (((7 + -2) - 5) - 3) = ((5 - 5) - 3) = (0 - 3) = -3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((-1 * 28) + (6 - -3)) = (-28 + (6 - -3)) = (-28 + 9) = -19.\n(Final response) So the answer is -19.", "correct_answer": "-19", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 571, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 * 3 * 3 - -7) * (-3 * -1 + 8 + 4)) + ((-5 * 0 * 1 + -2) + (-2 - -6 - 6 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (9 * 3 * 3 - -7), B = (-3 * -1 + 8 + 4), C = (-5 * 0 * 1 + -2) and D = (-2 - -6 - 6 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 3 * 3 - -7) = (((9 * 3) * 3) - -7) = ((27 * 3) - -7) = (81 - -7) = 88.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * -1 + 8 + 4) = (((-3 * -1) + 8) + 4) = ((3 + 8) + 4) = (11 + 4) = 15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * 0 * 1 + -2) = (((-5 * 0) * 1) + -2) = ((0 * 1) + -2) = (0 + -2) = -2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - -6 - 6 + -1) = (((-2 - -6) - 6) + -1) = ((4 - 6) + -1) = (-2 + -1) = -3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((88 * 15) + (-2 + -3)) = (1320 + (-2 + -3)) = (1320 + -5) = 1315.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1315.", "correct_answer": "1315", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 581, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 * 8 + 9) * (-5 - 0 + -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 * 8 + 9) and B = (-5 - 0 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * 8 + 9) = ((-7 * 8) + 9) = (-56 + 9) = -47.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - 0 + -4) = ((-5 - 0) + -4) = (-5 + -4) = -9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-47 * -9) = 423.\n(Final response) So the answer is 423.", "correct_answer": "423", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 68, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 - -7 * -2) + (-4 + -4 - 9)) * ((1 * -6 * 6) * (-5 - -3 + 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (0 - -7 * -2), B = (-4 + -4 - 9), C = (1 * -6 * 6) and D = (-5 - -3 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - -7 * -2) = (0 - (-7 * -2)) = (0 - 14) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + -4 - 9) = ((-4 + -4) - 9) = (-8 - 9) = -17.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 * -6 * 6) = ((1 * -6) * 6) = (-6 * 6) = -36.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - -3 + 6) = ((-5 - -3) + 6) = (-2 + 6) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((-14 + -17) * (-36 * 4)) = (-31 * (-36 * 4)) = (-31 * -144) = 4464.\n(Final response) So the answer is 4464.", "correct_answer": "4464", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 393, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 - 0 * -2) - (-9 * -2 + -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 - 0 * -2) and B = (-9 * -2 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - 0 * -2) = (6 - (0 * -2)) = (6 - 0) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -2 + -4) = ((-9 * -2) + -4) = (18 + -4) = 14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (6 - 14) = -8.\n(Final response) So the answer is -8.", "correct_answer": "-8", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 17, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 - -9 * -6) + (-7 * 3 - 1)) - ((7 + -2 + 0) * (7 * 9 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-8 - -9 * -6), B = (-7 * 3 - 1), C = (7 + -2 + 0) and D = (7 * 9 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -9 * -6) = (-8 - (-9 * -6)) = (-8 - 54) = -62.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 3 - 1) = ((-7 * 3) - 1) = (-21 - 1) = -22.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + -2 + 0) = ((7 + -2) + 0) = (5 + 0) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 * 9 + -8) = ((7 * 9) + -8) = (63 + -8) = 55.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-62 + -22) - (5 * 55)) = (-84 - (5 * 55)) = (-84 - 275) = -359.\n(Final response) So the answer is -359.", "correct_answer": "-359", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 130, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 - -1 * -8 - -3) * (4 - 9 + 8 * 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 - -1 * -8 - -3) and B = (4 - 9 + 8 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -1 * -8 - -3) = ((-5 - (-1 * -8)) - -3) = ((-5 - 8) - -3) = (-13 - -3) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 9 + 8 * 7) = ((4 - 9) + (8 * 7)) = (-5 + (8 * 7)) = (-5 + 56) = 51.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-10 * 51) = -510.\n(Final response) So the answer is -510.", "correct_answer": "-510", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 53, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-3 + -7 + 9 + 9 - 8 + -3) + (4 + 8 - 2 - 9 * -4 - 9)) * ((-6 * -1 * 6 + 8 + 2 * 1) * (2 * -7 + -8 + 1 + 9 + -5))) - (((9 * -2 - -2 + 3 + -1 + -1) - (8 - -1 * -4 * 8 + -3 * 4)) + ((-7 - 0 - -5 + -1 - -2 + 5) - (-3 * -2 * -1 - 4 * 0 - 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (-3 + -7 + 9 + 9 - 8 + -3), B = (4 + 8 - 2 - 9 * -4 - 9), C = (-6 * -1 * 6 + 8 + 2 * 1), D = (2 * -7 + -8 + 1 + 9 + -5), E = (9 * -2 - -2 + 3 + -1 + -1), F = (8 - -1 * -4 * 8 + -3 * 4), G = (-7 - 0 - -5 + -1 - -2 + 5) and H = (-3 * -2 * -1 - 4 * 0 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + -7 + 9 + 9 - 8 + -3) = (((((-3 + -7) + 9) + 9) - 8) + -3) = ((((-10 + 9) + 9) - 8) + -3) = (((-1 + 9) - 8) + -3) = ((8 - 8) + -3) = (0 + -3) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 8 - 2 - 9 * -4 - 9) = ((((4 + 8) - 2) - (9 * -4)) - 9) = (((12 - 2) - (9 * -4)) - 9) = (((12 - 2) - -36) - 9) = ((10 - -36) - 9) = (46 - 9) = 37.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 * -1 * 6 + 8 + 2 * 1) = ((((-6 * -1) * 6) + 8) + (2 * 1)) = (((6 * 6) + 8) + (2 * 1)) = (((6 * 6) + 8) + 2) = ((36 + 8) + 2) = (44 + 2) = 46.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * -7 + -8 + 1 + 9 + -5) = (((((2 * -7) + -8) + 1) + 9) + -5) = ((((-14 + -8) + 1) + 9) + -5) = (((-22 + 1) + 9) + -5) = ((-21 + 9) + -5) = (-12 + -5) = -17.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (9 * -2 - -2 + 3 + -1 + -1) = (((((9 * -2) - -2) + 3) + -1) + -1) = ((((-18 - -2) + 3) + -1) + -1) = (((-16 + 3) + -1) + -1) = ((-13 + -1) + -1) = (-14 + -1) = -15.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (8 - -1 * -4 * 8 + -3 * 4) = ((8 - ((-1 * -4) * 8)) + (-3 * 4)) = ((8 - (4 * 8)) + (-3 * 4)) = ((8 - (4 * 8)) + -12) = ((8 - 32) + -12) = (-24 + -12) = -36.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-7 - 0 - -5 + -1 - -2 + 5) = (((((-7 - 0) - -5) + -1) - -2) + 5) = ((((-7 - -5) + -1) - -2) + 5) = (((-2 + -1) - -2) + 5) = ((-3 - -2) + 5) = (-1 + 5) = 4.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-3 * -2 * -1 - 4 * 0 - 3) = ((((-3 * -2) * -1) - (4 * 0)) - 3) = (((6 * -1) - (4 * 0)) - 3) = (((6 * -1) - 0) - 3) = ((-6 - 0) - 3) = (-6 - 3) = -9.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G - H))) = (((-3 + 37) * (46 * -17)) - ((-15 - -36) + (4 - -9))) = ((34 * (46 * -17)) - ((-15 - -36) + (4 - -9))) = ((34 * -782) - ((-15 - -36) + (4 - -9))) = ((34 * -782) - (21 + (4 - -9))) = ((34 * -782) - (21 + 13)) = (-26588 - (21 + 13)) = (-26588 - 34) = -26622.\n(Final response) So the answer is -26622.", "correct_answer": "-26622", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 357, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 * -2 + 3 + 7) + (-4 * 3 + 4 * -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-3 * -2 + 3 + 7) and B = (-4 * 3 + 4 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * -2 + 3 + 7) = (((-3 * -2) + 3) + 7) = ((6 + 3) + 7) = (9 + 7) = 16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 3 + 4 * -6) = ((-4 * 3) + (4 * -6)) = (-12 + (4 * -6)) = (-12 + -24) = -36.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (16 + -36) = -20.\n(Final response) So the answer is -20.", "correct_answer": "-20", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 237, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + 0 - 6 * -7) - (1 * 7 * -6 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 + 0 - 6 * -7) and B = (1 * 7 * -6 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + 0 - 6 * -7) = ((-1 + 0) - (6 * -7)) = (-1 - (6 * -7)) = (-1 - -42) = 41.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 7 * -6 + -1) = (((1 * 7) * -6) + -1) = ((7 * -6) + -1) = (-42 + -1) = -43.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (41 - -43) = 84.\n(Final response) So the answer is 84.", "correct_answer": "84", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 265, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 + 9 + -5 * 3) - (7 * 4 + 6 + 4)) - ((-4 - -2 + -9 + -7) - (7 - -4 + 0 - 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-1 + 9 + -5 * 3), B = (7 * 4 + 6 + 4), C = (-4 - -2 + -9 + -7) and D = (7 - -4 + 0 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + 9 + -5 * 3) = ((-1 + 9) + (-5 * 3)) = (8 + (-5 * 3)) = (8 + -15) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * 4 + 6 + 4) = (((7 * 4) + 6) + 4) = ((28 + 6) + 4) = (34 + 4) = 38.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - -2 + -9 + -7) = (((-4 - -2) + -9) + -7) = ((-2 + -9) + -7) = (-11 + -7) = -18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 - -4 + 0 - 4) = (((7 - -4) + 0) - 4) = ((11 + 0) - 4) = (11 - 4) = 7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-7 - 38) - (-18 - 7)) = (-45 - (-18 - 7)) = (-45 - -25) = -20.\n(Final response) So the answer is -20.", "correct_answer": "-20", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 502, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 * 6 - -9 * -9 + 4) - (-1 - 2 + 0 - 5 * -6)) + ((-1 + 0 - -7 * 6 + 4) - (6 + -5 + 5 + -6 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (0 * 6 - -9 * -9 + 4), B = (-1 - 2 + 0 - 5 * -6), C = (-1 + 0 - -7 * 6 + 4) and D = (6 + -5 + 5 + -6 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * 6 - -9 * -9 + 4) = (((0 * 6) - (-9 * -9)) + 4) = ((0 - (-9 * -9)) + 4) = ((0 - 81) + 4) = (-81 + 4) = -77.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 2 + 0 - 5 * -6) = (((-1 - 2) + 0) - (5 * -6)) = ((-3 + 0) - (5 * -6)) = ((-3 + 0) - -30) = (-3 - -30) = 27.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + 0 - -7 * 6 + 4) = (((-1 + 0) - (-7 * 6)) + 4) = ((-1 - (-7 * 6)) + 4) = ((-1 - -42) + 4) = (41 + 4) = 45.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + -5 + 5 + -6 * 4) = (((6 + -5) + 5) + (-6 * 4)) = ((1 + 5) + (-6 * 4)) = ((1 + 5) + -24) = (6 + -24) = -18.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-77 - 27) + (45 - -18)) = (-104 + (45 - -18)) = (-104 + 63) = -41.\n(Final response) So the answer is -41.", "correct_answer": "-41", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 199, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-7 + -9 + -1 - -7 - -5) - (-9 + 3 * 2 * 2 * -8)) + ((-7 * 4 - -1 * -7 - 3) - (-6 - -9 - -2 - 4 - -3))) * (((0 * 0 * 8 + -6 * -3) + (4 + 3 - 9 * -1 - -7)) - ((7 * 6 + -6 * 9 * 2) * (-1 - -2 - -9 - -2 + -3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E + F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (-7 + -9 + -1 - -7 - -5), B = (-9 + 3 * 2 * 2 * -8), C = (-7 * 4 - -1 * -7 - 3), D = (-6 - -9 - -2 - 4 - -3), E = (0 * 0 * 8 + -6 * -3), F = (4 + 3 - 9 * -1 - -7), G = (7 * 6 + -6 * 9 * 2) and H = (-1 - -2 - -9 - -2 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + -9 + -1 - -7 - -5) = ((((-7 + -9) + -1) - -7) - -5) = (((-16 + -1) - -7) - -5) = ((-17 - -7) - -5) = (-10 - -5) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 3 * 2 * 2 * -8) = (-9 + (((3 * 2) * 2) * -8)) = (-9 + ((6 * 2) * -8)) = (-9 + (12 * -8)) = (-9 + -96) = -105.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * 4 - -1 * -7 - 3) = (((-7 * 4) - (-1 * -7)) - 3) = ((-28 - (-1 * -7)) - 3) = ((-28 - 7) - 3) = (-35 - 3) = -38.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - -9 - -2 - 4 - -3) = ((((-6 - -9) - -2) - 4) - -3) = (((3 - -2) - 4) - -3) = ((5 - 4) - -3) = (1 - -3) = 4.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 * 0 * 8 + -6 * -3) = (((0 * 0) * 8) + (-6 * -3)) = ((0 * 8) + (-6 * -3)) = ((0 * 8) + 18) = (0 + 18) = 18.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (4 + 3 - 9 * -1 - -7) = (((4 + 3) - (9 * -1)) - -7) = ((7 - (9 * -1)) - -7) = ((7 - -9) - -7) = (16 - -7) = 23.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 * 6 + -6 * 9 * 2) = ((7 * 6) + ((-6 * 9) * 2)) = (42 + ((-6 * 9) * 2)) = (42 + (-54 * 2)) = (42 + -108) = -66.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-1 - -2 - -9 - -2 + -3) = ((((-1 - -2) - -9) - -2) + -3) = (((1 - -9) - -2) + -3) = ((10 - -2) + -3) = (12 + -3) = 9.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E + F) - (G * H))) = (((-5 - -105) + (-38 - 4)) * ((18 + 23) - (-66 * 9))) = ((100 + (-38 - 4)) * ((18 + 23) - (-66 * 9))) = ((100 + -42) * ((18 + 23) - (-66 * 9))) = ((100 + -42) * (41 - (-66 * 9))) = ((100 + -42) * (41 - -594)) = (58 * (41 - -594)) = (58 * 635) = 36830.\n(Final response) So the answer is 36830.", "correct_answer": "36830", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 300, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 * -1 + 4) * (-9 + -7 * 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (8 * -1 + 4) and B = (-9 + -7 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * -1 + 4) = ((8 * -1) + 4) = (-8 + 4) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + -7 * 1) = (-9 + (-7 * 1)) = (-9 + -7) = -16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-4 * -16) = 64.\n(Final response) So the answer is 64.", "correct_answer": "64", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 54, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 - 8 * -3 * 8) - (-5 - -9 * 1 * 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (2 - 8 * -3 * 8) and B = (-5 - -9 * 1 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - 8 * -3 * 8) = (2 - ((8 * -3) * 8)) = (2 - (-24 * 8)) = (2 - -192) = 194.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -9 * 1 * 8) = (-5 - ((-9 * 1) * 8)) = (-5 - (-9 * 8)) = (-5 - -72) = 67.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (194 - 67) = 127.\n(Final response) So the answer is 127.", "correct_answer": "127", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 32, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 - 3 * -1) + (4 * 1 - 6)) - ((6 - -8 + 6) - (8 - -4 * 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-4 - 3 * -1), B = (4 * 1 - 6), C = (6 - -8 + 6) and D = (8 - -4 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 3 * -1) = (-4 - (3 * -1)) = (-4 - -3) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 1 - 6) = ((4 * 1) - 6) = (4 - 6) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - -8 + 6) = ((6 - -8) + 6) = (14 + 6) = 20.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - -4 * 3) = (8 - (-4 * 3)) = (8 - -12) = 20.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((-1 + -2) - (20 - 20)) = (-3 - (20 - 20)) = (-3 - 0) = -3.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3.", "correct_answer": "-3", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 385, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 - 8 - -5) + (6 + 4 * -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (4 - 8 - -5) and B = (6 + 4 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - 8 - -5) = ((4 - 8) - -5) = (-4 - -5) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 4 * -1) = (6 + (4 * -1)) = (6 + -4) = 2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (1 + 2) = 3.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3.", "correct_answer": "3", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 124, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 - -1 * 3 + 3) - (-3 + -2 - -3 * -3)) * ((-6 - 3 - 9 - -3) + (-7 - -8 + 1 - 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-7 - -1 * 3 + 3), B = (-3 + -2 - -3 * -3), C = (-6 - 3 - 9 - -3) and D = (-7 - -8 + 1 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - -1 * 3 + 3) = ((-7 - (-1 * 3)) + 3) = ((-7 - -3) + 3) = (-4 + 3) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + -2 - -3 * -3) = ((-3 + -2) - (-3 * -3)) = (-5 - (-3 * -3)) = (-5 - 9) = -14.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 - 3 - 9 - -3) = (((-6 - 3) - 9) - -3) = ((-9 - 9) - -3) = (-18 - -3) = -15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -8 + 1 - 3) = (((-7 - -8) + 1) - 3) = ((1 + 1) - 3) = (2 - 3) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((-1 - -14) * (-15 + -1)) = (13 * (-15 + -1)) = (13 * -16) = -208.\n(Final response) So the answer is -208.", "correct_answer": "-208", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 450, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 - -6 - -7 + 7 * 6 - -5) * (-3 - -8 * 7 - 5 * -1 - 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-6 - -6 - -7 + 7 * 6 - -5) and B = (-3 - -8 * 7 - 5 * -1 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - -6 - -7 + 7 * 6 - -5) = ((((-6 - -6) - -7) + (7 * 6)) - -5) = (((0 - -7) + (7 * 6)) - -5) = (((0 - -7) + 42) - -5) = ((7 + 42) - -5) = (49 - -5) = 54.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - -8 * 7 - 5 * -1 - 8) = (((-3 - (-8 * 7)) - (5 * -1)) - 8) = (((-3 - -56) - (5 * -1)) - 8) = (((-3 - -56) - -5) - 8) = ((53 - -5) - 8) = (58 - 8) = 50.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (54 * 50) = 2700.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2700.", "correct_answer": "2700", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 110, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 + -5 - -9 - 6 - 2) + (3 - -3 + 4 - 6 * 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-7 + -5 - -9 - 6 - 2) and B = (3 - -3 + 4 - 6 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + -5 - -9 - 6 - 2) = ((((-7 + -5) - -9) - 6) - 2) = (((-12 - -9) - 6) - 2) = ((-3 - 6) - 2) = (-9 - 2) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - -3 + 4 - 6 * 2) = (((3 - -3) + 4) - (6 * 2)) = ((6 + 4) - (6 * 2)) = ((6 + 4) - 12) = (10 - 12) = -2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-11 + -2) = -13.\n(Final response) So the answer is -13.", "correct_answer": "-13", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 60, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 * -4 - 3) * (-8 - 0 - -5)) - ((-6 * -8 * 8) + (1 + 8 + 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (9 * -4 - 3), B = (-8 - 0 - -5), C = (-6 * -8 * 8) and D = (1 + 8 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * -4 - 3) = ((9 * -4) - 3) = (-36 - 3) = -39.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 0 - -5) = ((-8 - 0) - -5) = (-8 - -5) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 * -8 * 8) = ((-6 * -8) * 8) = (48 * 8) = 384.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + 8 + 2) = ((1 + 8) + 2) = (9 + 2) = 11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-39 * -3) - (384 + 11)) = (117 - (384 + 11)) = (117 - 395) = -278.\n(Final response) So the answer is -278.", "correct_answer": "-278", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 131, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 - 1 - -1 * 3) * (8 * 5 + 9 + -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-3 - 1 - -1 * 3) and B = (8 * 5 + 9 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - 1 - -1 * 3) = ((-3 - 1) - (-1 * 3)) = (-4 - (-1 * 3)) = (-4 - -3) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 5 + 9 + -6) = (((8 * 5) + 9) + -6) = ((40 + 9) + -6) = (49 + -6) = 43.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-1 * 43) = -43.\n(Final response) So the answer is -43.", "correct_answer": "-43", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 294, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 - -8 * 5 - 7 + -7 - -7) + (0 * -9 - -5 + -5 + 5 - -5)) - ((3 * -2 - 9 * -4 - 7 + 9) - (-8 + -3 - 4 - -2 - 1 + 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (2 - -8 * 5 - 7 + -7 - -7), B = (0 * -9 - -5 + -5 + 5 - -5), C = (3 * -2 - 9 * -4 - 7 + 9) and D = (-8 + -3 - 4 - -2 - 1 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - -8 * 5 - 7 + -7 - -7) = ((((2 - (-8 * 5)) - 7) + -7) - -7) = ((((2 - -40) - 7) + -7) - -7) = (((42 - 7) + -7) - -7) = ((35 + -7) - -7) = (28 - -7) = 35.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * -9 - -5 + -5 + 5 - -5) = (((((0 * -9) - -5) + -5) + 5) - -5) = ((((0 - -5) + -5) + 5) - -5) = (((5 + -5) + 5) - -5) = ((0 + 5) - -5) = (5 - -5) = 10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 * -2 - 9 * -4 - 7 + 9) = ((((3 * -2) - (9 * -4)) - 7) + 9) = (((-6 - (9 * -4)) - 7) + 9) = (((-6 - -36) - 7) + 9) = ((30 - 7) + 9) = (23 + 9) = 32.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + -3 - 4 - -2 - 1 + 0) = (((((-8 + -3) - 4) - -2) - 1) + 0) = ((((-11 - 4) - -2) - 1) + 0) = (((-15 - -2) - 1) + 0) = ((-13 - 1) + 0) = (-14 + 0) = -14.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((35 + 10) - (32 - -14)) = (45 - (32 - -14)) = (45 - 46) = -1.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1.", "correct_answer": "-1", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 227, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + 1 - 6 + -1) + (6 + 9 * -1 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (5 + 1 - 6 + -1) and B = (6 + 9 * -1 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 1 - 6 + -1) = (((5 + 1) - 6) + -1) = ((6 - 6) + -1) = (0 + -1) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 9 * -1 * 4) = (6 + ((9 * -1) * 4)) = (6 + (-9 * 4)) = (6 + -36) = -30.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-1 + -30) = -31.\n(Final response) So the answer is -31.", "correct_answer": "-31", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 212, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-8 - 6 * -6 - 4) - (-6 + 4 * -6 * 4)) - ((9 * -1 - -6 - 2) * (-3 - 0 - 3 + 8))) - (((0 - -7 + -3 + 1) - (5 * -2 * 3 - 2)) + ((7 * 3 - -2 + 3) + (-7 + -2 - -4 * 1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-8 - 6 * -6 - 4), B = (-6 + 4 * -6 * 4), C = (9 * -1 - -6 - 2), D = (-3 - 0 - 3 + 8), E = (0 - -7 + -3 + 1), F = (5 * -2 * 3 - 2), G = (7 * 3 - -2 + 3) and H = (-7 + -2 - -4 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 6 * -6 - 4) = ((-8 - (6 * -6)) - 4) = ((-8 - -36) - 4) = (28 - 4) = 24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + 4 * -6 * 4) = (-6 + ((4 * -6) * 4)) = (-6 + (-24 * 4)) = (-6 + -96) = -102.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 * -1 - -6 - 2) = (((9 * -1) - -6) - 2) = ((-9 - -6) - 2) = (-3 - 2) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 - 0 - 3 + 8) = (((-3 - 0) - 3) + 8) = ((-3 - 3) + 8) = (-6 + 8) = 2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 - -7 + -3 + 1) = (((0 - -7) + -3) + 1) = ((7 + -3) + 1) = (4 + 1) = 5.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 * -2 * 3 - 2) = (((5 * -2) * 3) - 2) = ((-10 * 3) - 2) = (-30 - 2) = -32.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 * 3 - -2 + 3) = (((7 * 3) - -2) + 3) = ((21 - -2) + 3) = (23 + 3) = 26.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-7 + -2 - -4 * 1) = ((-7 + -2) - (-4 * 1)) = (-9 - (-4 * 1)) = (-9 - -4) = -5.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((24 - -102) - (-5 * 2)) - ((5 - -32) + (26 + -5))) = ((126 - (-5 * 2)) - ((5 - -32) + (26 + -5))) = ((126 - -10) - ((5 - -32) + (26 + -5))) = ((126 - -10) - (37 + (26 + -5))) = ((126 - -10) - (37 + 21)) = (136 - (37 + 21)) = (136 - 58) = 78.\n(Final response) So the answer is 78.", "correct_answer": "78", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 279, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 - 4 - -5) - (6 + -3 + -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 - 4 - -5) and B = (6 + -3 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - 4 - -5) = ((7 - 4) - -5) = (3 - -5) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + -3 + -5) = ((6 + -3) + -5) = (3 + -5) = -2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (8 - -2) = 10.\n(Final response) So the answer is 10.", "correct_answer": "10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 37, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 + 7 - 6) - (-8 * 0 - 9)) + ((4 * 1 + -3) * (7 * 5 - -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-6 + 7 - 6), B = (-8 * 0 - 9), C = (4 * 1 + -3) and D = (7 * 5 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 7 - 6) = ((-6 + 7) - 6) = (1 - 6) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * 0 - 9) = ((-8 * 0) - 9) = (0 - 9) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 * 1 + -3) = ((4 * 1) + -3) = (4 + -3) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 * 5 - -2) = ((7 * 5) - -2) = (35 - -2) = 37.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C * D)) = ((-5 - -9) + (1 * 37)) = (4 + (1 * 37)) = (4 + 37) = 41.\n(Final response) So the answer is 41.", "correct_answer": "41", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 312, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 - -2 - -8 + 4 + -7 + -4) - (-2 - -4 * 9 * -7 + -9 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 - -2 - -8 + 4 + -7 + -4) and B = (-2 - -4 * 9 * -7 + -9 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -2 - -8 + 4 + -7 + -4) = (((((6 - -2) - -8) + 4) + -7) + -4) = ((((8 - -8) + 4) + -7) + -4) = (((16 + 4) + -7) + -4) = ((20 + -7) + -4) = (13 + -4) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - -4 * 9 * -7 + -9 - -4) = (((-2 - ((-4 * 9) * -7)) + -9) - -4) = (((-2 - (-36 * -7)) + -9) - -4) = (((-2 - 252) + -9) - -4) = ((-254 + -9) - -4) = (-263 - -4) = -259.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (9 - -259) = 268.\n(Final response) So the answer is 268.", "correct_answer": "268", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 90, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + -6 * -5) + (-5 * -4 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (5 + -6 * -5) and B = (-5 * -4 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + -6 * -5) = (5 + (-6 * -5)) = (5 + 30) = 35.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -4 * 4) = ((-5 * -4) * 4) = (20 * 4) = 80.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (35 + 80) = 115.\n(Final response) So the answer is 115.", "correct_answer": "115", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 125, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 - -7 + 8) - (8 - -7 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-7 - -7 + 8) and B = (8 - -7 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - -7 + 8) = ((-7 - -7) + 8) = (0 + 8) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - -7 + -1) = ((8 - -7) + -1) = (15 + -1) = 14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (8 - 14) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 23, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 * -2 + -5 * 8) + (-8 - 7 - -7 + 3)) - ((-2 + -4 - 7 + -7) * (2 + -4 + -3 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-2 * -2 + -5 * 8), B = (-8 - 7 - -7 + 3), C = (-2 + -4 - 7 + -7) and D = (2 + -4 + -3 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * -2 + -5 * 8) = ((-2 * -2) + (-5 * 8)) = (4 + (-5 * 8)) = (4 + -40) = -36.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 7 - -7 + 3) = (((-8 - 7) - -7) + 3) = ((-15 - -7) + 3) = (-8 + 3) = -5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + -4 - 7 + -7) = (((-2 + -4) - 7) + -7) = ((-6 - 7) + -7) = (-13 + -7) = -20.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 + -4 + -3 * -1) = ((2 + -4) + (-3 * -1)) = (-2 + (-3 * -1)) = (-2 + 3) = 1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-36 + -5) - (-20 * 1)) = (-41 - (-20 * 1)) = (-41 - -20) = -21.\n(Final response) So the answer is -21.", "correct_answer": "-21", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 463, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 + 9 - -8 + 6) - (-2 * -7 * 7 + 7)) + ((-9 * -6 * 5 + 7) - (3 * 5 + 6 - 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (6 + 9 - -8 + 6), B = (-2 * -7 * 7 + 7), C = (-9 * -6 * 5 + 7) and D = (3 * 5 + 6 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 9 - -8 + 6) = (((6 + 9) - -8) + 6) = ((15 - -8) + 6) = (23 + 6) = 29.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -7 * 7 + 7) = (((-2 * -7) * 7) + 7) = ((14 * 7) + 7) = (98 + 7) = 105.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * -6 * 5 + 7) = (((-9 * -6) * 5) + 7) = ((54 * 5) + 7) = (270 + 7) = 277.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * 5 + 6 - 1) = (((3 * 5) + 6) - 1) = ((15 + 6) - 1) = (21 - 1) = 20.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((29 - 105) + (277 - 20)) = (-76 + (277 - 20)) = (-76 + 257) = 181.\n(Final response) So the answer is 181.", "correct_answer": "181", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 575, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 * 4 - -9) * (8 * -2 + -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (0 * 4 - -9) and B = (8 * -2 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * 4 - -9) = ((0 * 4) - -9) = (0 - -9) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * -2 + -7) = ((8 * -2) + -7) = (-16 + -7) = -23.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (9 * -23) = -207.\n(Final response) So the answer is -207.", "correct_answer": "-207", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 101, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 + 2 * 7) + (7 - 7 * 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (9 + 2 * 7) and B = (7 - 7 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + 2 * 7) = (9 + (2 * 7)) = (9 + 14) = 23.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - 7 * 2) = (7 - (7 * 2)) = (7 - 14) = -7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (23 + -7) = 16.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16.", "correct_answer": "16", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 115, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 + 8 + 3) * (-3 + -5 + -9)) - ((-9 + 4 * 7) * (-3 * 9 * -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (8 + 8 + 3), B = (-3 + -5 + -9), C = (-9 + 4 * 7) and D = (-3 * 9 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 8 + 3) = ((8 + 8) + 3) = (16 + 3) = 19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + -5 + -9) = ((-3 + -5) + -9) = (-8 + -9) = -17.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + 4 * 7) = (-9 + (4 * 7)) = (-9 + 28) = 19.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * 9 * -7) = ((-3 * 9) * -7) = (-27 * -7) = 189.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((19 * -17) - (19 * 189)) = (-323 - (19 * 189)) = (-323 - 3591) = -3914.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3914.", "correct_answer": "-3914", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 398, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((8 * 3 + -9 - -9 * 4) + (-2 * -9 * 6 + -9 * 4)) * ((-4 * 9 * 2 + -4 + -9) * (-5 - -3 + 5 - 1 + -9))) * (((-8 - 2 + -3 + -8 * -4) * (-3 - 7 - -8 - -1 * 4)) + ((-9 - 1 + 4 + -9 - 8) * (-5 + 3 + -6 * -6 * -6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E * F) + (G * H)))\", where A = (8 * 3 + -9 - -9 * 4), B = (-2 * -9 * 6 + -9 * 4), C = (-4 * 9 * 2 + -4 + -9), D = (-5 - -3 + 5 - 1 + -9), E = (-8 - 2 + -3 + -8 * -4), F = (-3 - 7 - -8 - -1 * 4), G = (-9 - 1 + 4 + -9 - 8) and H = (-5 + 3 + -6 * -6 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 3 + -9 - -9 * 4) = (((8 * 3) + -9) - (-9 * 4)) = ((24 + -9) - (-9 * 4)) = ((24 + -9) - -36) = (15 - -36) = 51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -9 * 6 + -9 * 4) = (((-2 * -9) * 6) + (-9 * 4)) = ((18 * 6) + (-9 * 4)) = ((18 * 6) + -36) = (108 + -36) = 72.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 * 9 * 2 + -4 + -9) = ((((-4 * 9) * 2) + -4) + -9) = (((-36 * 2) + -4) + -9) = ((-72 + -4) + -9) = (-76 + -9) = -85.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - -3 + 5 - 1 + -9) = ((((-5 - -3) + 5) - 1) + -9) = (((-2 + 5) - 1) + -9) = ((3 - 1) + -9) = (2 + -9) = -7.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-8 - 2 + -3 + -8 * -4) = (((-8 - 2) + -3) + (-8 * -4)) = ((-10 + -3) + (-8 * -4)) = ((-10 + -3) + 32) = (-13 + 32) = 19.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-3 - 7 - -8 - -1 * 4) = (((-3 - 7) - -8) - (-1 * 4)) = ((-10 - -8) - (-1 * 4)) = ((-10 - -8) - -4) = (-2 - -4) = 2.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-9 - 1 + 4 + -9 - 8) = ((((-9 - 1) + 4) + -9) - 8) = (((-10 + 4) + -9) - 8) = ((-6 + -9) - 8) = (-15 - 8) = -23.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-5 + 3 + -6 * -6 * -6) = ((-5 + 3) + ((-6 * -6) * -6)) = (-2 + ((-6 * -6) * -6)) = (-2 + (36 * -6)) = (-2 + -216) = -218.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E * F) + (G * H))) = (((51 + 72) * (-85 * -7)) * ((19 * 2) + (-23 * -218))) = ((123 * (-85 * -7)) * ((19 * 2) + (-23 * -218))) = ((123 * 595) * ((19 * 2) + (-23 * -218))) = ((123 * 595) * (38 + (-23 * -218))) = ((123 * 595) * (38 + 5014)) = (73185 * (38 + 5014)) = (73185 * 5052) = 369730620.\n(Final response) So the answer is 369730620.", "correct_answer": "369730620", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 310, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - 2 * 5) + (-6 + 3 - -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (1 - 2 * 5) and B = (-6 + 3 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - 2 * 5) = (1 - (2 * 5)) = (1 - 10) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + 3 - -9) = ((-6 + 3) - -9) = (-3 - -9) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-9 + 6) = -3.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3.", "correct_answer": "-3", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 120, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 + -3 + 0) - (-3 - -5 * 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 + -3 + 0) and B = (-3 - -5 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + -3 + 0) = ((6 + -3) + 0) = (3 + 0) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - -5 * 1) = (-3 - (-5 * 1)) = (-3 - -5) = 2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (3 - 2) = 1.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1.", "correct_answer": "1", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 47, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 + 6 - -8 * -2) + (0 - -6 * -9 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (1 + 6 - -8 * -2) and B = (0 - -6 * -9 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 6 - -8 * -2) = ((1 + 6) - (-8 * -2)) = (7 - (-8 * -2)) = (7 - 16) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - -6 * -9 * -3) = (0 - ((-6 * -9) * -3)) = (0 - (54 * -3)) = (0 - -162) = 162.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-9 + 162) = 153.\n(Final response) So the answer is 153.", "correct_answer": "153", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 171, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 - 1 - 2) * (6 + 2 + 8)) + ((5 + -9 - 8) - (6 + 0 * 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-4 - 1 - 2), B = (6 + 2 + 8), C = (5 + -9 - 8) and D = (6 + 0 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 1 - 2) = ((-4 - 1) - 2) = (-5 - 2) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 2 + 8) = ((6 + 2) + 8) = (8 + 8) = 16.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 + -9 - 8) = ((5 + -9) - 8) = (-4 - 8) = -12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + 0 * 6) = (6 + (0 * 6)) = (6 + 0) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((-7 * 16) + (-12 - 6)) = (-112 + (-12 - 6)) = (-112 + -18) = -130.\n(Final response) So the answer is -130.", "correct_answer": "-130", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 317, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 + -5 + 0) * (3 * 2 - -7)) + ((-1 + -9 - -1) + (-1 - 9 * 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-4 + -5 + 0), B = (3 * 2 - -7), C = (-1 + -9 - -1) and D = (-1 - 9 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -5 + 0) = ((-4 + -5) + 0) = (-9 + 0) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 2 - -7) = ((3 * 2) - -7) = (6 - -7) = 13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + -9 - -1) = ((-1 + -9) - -1) = (-10 - -1) = -9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 - 9 * 6) = (-1 - (9 * 6)) = (-1 - 54) = -55.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((-9 * 13) + (-9 + -55)) = (-117 + (-9 + -55)) = (-117 + -64) = -181.\n(Final response) So the answer is -181.", "correct_answer": "-181", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 324, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 * 4 + 0 + 6) + (-9 + 5 + 1 - -5)) - ((-1 * 6 - 2 - -7) * (8 - 3 + -6 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-8 * 4 + 0 + 6), B = (-9 + 5 + 1 - -5), C = (-1 * 6 - 2 - -7) and D = (8 - 3 + -6 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 4 + 0 + 6) = (((-8 * 4) + 0) + 6) = ((-32 + 0) + 6) = (-32 + 6) = -26.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 5 + 1 - -5) = (((-9 + 5) + 1) - -5) = ((-4 + 1) - -5) = (-3 - -5) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * 6 - 2 - -7) = (((-1 * 6) - 2) - -7) = ((-6 - 2) - -7) = (-8 - -7) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - 3 + -6 * -5) = ((8 - 3) + (-6 * -5)) = (5 + (-6 * -5)) = (5 + 30) = 35.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-26 + 2) - (-1 * 35)) = (-24 - (-1 * 35)) = (-24 - -35) = 11.\n(Final response) So the answer is 11.", "correct_answer": "11", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 483, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 * 2 * -3 - 6) * (0 - 8 - -5 + -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-8 * 2 * -3 - 6) and B = (0 - 8 - -5 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 2 * -3 - 6) = (((-8 * 2) * -3) - 6) = ((-16 * -3) - 6) = (48 - 6) = 42.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 8 - -5 + -3) = (((0 - 8) - -5) + -3) = ((-8 - -5) + -3) = (-3 + -3) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (42 * -6) = -252.\n(Final response) So the answer is -252.", "correct_answer": "-252", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 263, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * 4 - -3) * (2 + -7 - 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 * 4 - -3) and B = (2 + -7 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 4 - -3) = ((5 * 4) - -3) = (20 - -3) = 23.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + -7 - 5) = ((2 + -7) - 5) = (-5 - 5) = -10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (23 * -10) = -230.\n(Final response) So the answer is -230.", "correct_answer": "-230", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 145, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 + -6 - -5) + (-7 + -7 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 + -6 - -5) and B = (-7 + -7 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + -6 - -5) = ((-6 + -6) - -5) = (-12 - -5) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -7 - 7) = ((-7 + -7) - 7) = (-14 - 7) = -21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-7 + -21) = -28.\n(Final response) So the answer is -28.", "correct_answer": "-28", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 43, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 + -8 * 1 - 9 + 1 * 7) + (3 - -9 - -2 + -2 * -4 * 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (6 + -8 * 1 - 9 + 1 * 7) and B = (3 - -9 - -2 + -2 * -4 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + -8 * 1 - 9 + 1 * 7) = (((6 + (-8 * 1)) - 9) + (1 * 7)) = (((6 + -8) - 9) + (1 * 7)) = (((6 + -8) - 9) + 7) = ((-2 - 9) + 7) = (-11 + 7) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - -9 - -2 + -2 * -4 * 6) = (((3 - -9) - -2) + ((-2 * -4) * 6)) = ((12 - -2) + ((-2 * -4) * 6)) = ((12 - -2) + (8 * 6)) = (14 + (8 * 6)) = (14 + 48) = 62.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-4 + 62) = 58.\n(Final response) So the answer is 58.", "correct_answer": "58", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 112, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 + 7 + 5) * (-8 - -2 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-9 + 7 + 5) and B = (-8 - -2 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + 7 + 5) = ((-9 + 7) + 5) = (-2 + 5) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - -2 * -3) = (-8 - (-2 * -3)) = (-8 - 6) = -14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (3 * -14) = -42.\n(Final response) So the answer is -42.", "correct_answer": "-42", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 86, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 + 8 * -4 + 0 * -1) + (8 + -3 - 6 - -8 - 7)) - ((0 - 5 + 2 * 1 + -2) - (-4 + 8 - -8 + -3 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-8 + 8 * -4 + 0 * -1), B = (8 + -3 - 6 - -8 - 7), C = (0 - 5 + 2 * 1 + -2) and D = (-4 + 8 - -8 + -3 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + 8 * -4 + 0 * -1) = ((-8 + (8 * -4)) + (0 * -1)) = ((-8 + -32) + (0 * -1)) = ((-8 + -32) + 0) = (-40 + 0) = -40.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + -3 - 6 - -8 - 7) = ((((8 + -3) - 6) - -8) - 7) = (((5 - 6) - -8) - 7) = ((-1 - -8) - 7) = (7 - 7) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 - 5 + 2 * 1 + -2) = (((0 - 5) + (2 * 1)) + -2) = ((-5 + (2 * 1)) + -2) = ((-5 + 2) + -2) = (-3 + -2) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + 8 - -8 + -3 * -1) = (((-4 + 8) - -8) + (-3 * -1)) = ((4 - -8) + (-3 * -1)) = ((4 - -8) + 3) = (12 + 3) = 15.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((-40 + 0) - (-5 - 15)) = (-40 - (-5 - 15)) = (-40 - -20) = -20.\n(Final response) So the answer is -20.", "correct_answer": "-20", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 197, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + -9 + -2 + -4) * (6 - -3 - -7 - 6)) * ((3 * -9 + -5 - 2) * (-1 * 4 - -7 - -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (7 + -9 + -2 + -4), B = (6 - -3 - -7 - 6), C = (3 * -9 + -5 - 2) and D = (-1 * 4 - -7 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -9 + -2 + -4) = (((7 + -9) + -2) + -4) = ((-2 + -2) + -4) = (-4 + -4) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - -3 - -7 - 6) = (((6 - -3) - -7) - 6) = ((9 - -7) - 6) = (16 - 6) = 10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 * -9 + -5 - 2) = (((3 * -9) + -5) - 2) = ((-27 + -5) - 2) = (-32 - 2) = -34.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * 4 - -7 - -3) = (((-1 * 4) - -7) - -3) = ((-4 - -7) - -3) = (3 - -3) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((-8 * 10) * (-34 * 6)) = (-80 * (-34 * 6)) = (-80 * -204) = 16320.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16320.", "correct_answer": "16320", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 594, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 - -3 - 6 * -4) * (-1 + 3 + -2 + 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 - -3 - 6 * -4) and B = (-1 + 3 + -2 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - -3 - 6 * -4) = ((9 - -3) - (6 * -4)) = (12 - (6 * -4)) = (12 - -24) = 36.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + 3 + -2 + 3) = (((-1 + 3) + -2) + 3) = ((2 + -2) + 3) = (0 + 3) = 3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (36 * 3) = 108.\n(Final response) So the answer is 108.", "correct_answer": "108", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 45, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 * -1 - -8) - (5 + 2 + 7)) - ((-9 * 6 * -1) - (-3 * 8 + -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (1 * -1 - -8), B = (5 + 2 + 7), C = (-9 * 6 * -1) and D = (-3 * 8 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * -1 - -8) = ((1 * -1) - -8) = (-1 - -8) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 2 + 7) = ((5 + 2) + 7) = (7 + 7) = 14.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * 6 * -1) = ((-9 * 6) * -1) = (-54 * -1) = 54.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * 8 + -3) = ((-3 * 8) + -3) = (-24 + -3) = -27.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((7 - 14) - (54 - -27)) = (-7 - (54 - -27)) = (-7 - 81) = -88.\n(Final response) So the answer is -88.", "correct_answer": "-88", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 345, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((4 + -1 + 3 - 7 * 9) + (-5 + -9 - 4 * -5 + 6)) - ((-4 * 9 + 4 * -8 + 5) + (-4 - -9 + 1 - 0 * 9))) - (((-7 - -4 * 2 * -4 * -2) + (9 - 2 * -3 + 7 + 7)) * ((-9 * 2 * -3 * -4 * 9) + (-1 + 6 + 3 + 5 * 4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) - (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (4 + -1 + 3 - 7 * 9), B = (-5 + -9 - 4 * -5 + 6), C = (-4 * 9 + 4 * -8 + 5), D = (-4 - -9 + 1 - 0 * 9), E = (-7 - -4 * 2 * -4 * -2), F = (9 - 2 * -3 + 7 + 7), G = (-9 * 2 * -3 * -4 * 9) and H = (-1 + 6 + 3 + 5 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -1 + 3 - 7 * 9) = (((4 + -1) + 3) - (7 * 9)) = ((3 + 3) - (7 * 9)) = ((3 + 3) - 63) = (6 - 63) = -57.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + -9 - 4 * -5 + 6) = (((-5 + -9) - (4 * -5)) + 6) = ((-14 - (4 * -5)) + 6) = ((-14 - -20) + 6) = (6 + 6) = 12.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 * 9 + 4 * -8 + 5) = (((-4 * 9) + (4 * -8)) + 5) = ((-36 + (4 * -8)) + 5) = ((-36 + -32) + 5) = (-68 + 5) = -63.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -9 + 1 - 0 * 9) = (((-4 - -9) + 1) - (0 * 9)) = ((5 + 1) - (0 * 9)) = ((5 + 1) - 0) = (6 - 0) = 6.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-7 - -4 * 2 * -4 * -2) = (-7 - (((-4 * 2) * -4) * -2)) = (-7 - ((-8 * -4) * -2)) = (-7 - (32 * -2)) = (-7 - -64) = 57.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (9 - 2 * -3 + 7 + 7) = (((9 - (2 * -3)) + 7) + 7) = (((9 - -6) + 7) + 7) = ((15 + 7) + 7) = (22 + 7) = 29.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-9 * 2 * -3 * -4 * 9) = ((((-9 * 2) * -3) * -4) * 9) = (((-18 * -3) * -4) * 9) = ((54 * -4) * 9) = (-216 * 9) = -1944.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-1 + 6 + 3 + 5 * 4) = (((-1 + 6) + 3) + (5 * 4)) = ((5 + 3) + (5 * 4)) = ((5 + 3) + 20) = (8 + 20) = 28.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) - (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G + H))) = (((-57 + 12) - (-63 + 6)) - ((57 + 29) * (-1944 + 28))) = ((-45 - (-63 + 6)) - ((57 + 29) * (-1944 + 28))) = ((-45 - -57) - ((57 + 29) * (-1944 + 28))) = ((-45 - -57) - (86 * (-1944 + 28))) = ((-45 - -57) - (86 * -1916)) = (12 - (86 * -1916)) = (12 - -164776) = 164788.\n(Final response) So the answer is 164788.", "correct_answer": "164788", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 305, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 + 2 - -6 - 7) - (-4 + 4 * 1 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (9 + 2 - -6 - 7) and B = (-4 + 4 * 1 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + 2 - -6 - 7) = (((9 + 2) - -6) - 7) = ((11 - -6) - 7) = (17 - 7) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 4 * 1 + 8) = ((-4 + (4 * 1)) + 8) = ((-4 + 4) + 8) = (0 + 8) = 8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (10 - 8) = 2.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2.", "correct_answer": "2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 226, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-2 + -2 + 3 + 4) - (5 + -3 - -8 * 3)) * ((-2 + -2 + -7 * 5) + (2 + 1 * -5 + -8))) + (((-7 + -2 * 3 * -1) - (-8 + 5 * -2 - -3)) + ((-3 * 1 * -8 * 9) + (7 + 3 - -5 + -8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C + D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-2 + -2 + 3 + 4), B = (5 + -3 - -8 * 3), C = (-2 + -2 + -7 * 5), D = (2 + 1 * -5 + -8), E = (-7 + -2 * 3 * -1), F = (-8 + 5 * -2 - -3), G = (-3 * 1 * -8 * 9) and H = (7 + 3 - -5 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -2 + 3 + 4) = (((-2 + -2) + 3) + 4) = ((-4 + 3) + 4) = (-1 + 4) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + -3 - -8 * 3) = ((5 + -3) - (-8 * 3)) = (2 - (-8 * 3)) = (2 - -24) = 26.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + -2 + -7 * 5) = ((-2 + -2) + (-7 * 5)) = (-4 + (-7 * 5)) = (-4 + -35) = -39.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 + 1 * -5 + -8) = ((2 + (1 * -5)) + -8) = ((2 + -5) + -8) = (-3 + -8) = -11.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-7 + -2 * 3 * -1) = (-7 + ((-2 * 3) * -1)) = (-7 + (-6 * -1)) = (-7 + 6) = -1.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-8 + 5 * -2 - -3) = ((-8 + (5 * -2)) - -3) = ((-8 + -10) - -3) = (-18 - -3) = -15.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-3 * 1 * -8 * 9) = (((-3 * 1) * -8) * 9) = ((-3 * -8) * 9) = (24 * 9) = 216.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (7 + 3 - -5 + -8) = (((7 + 3) - -5) + -8) = ((10 - -5) + -8) = (15 + -8) = 7.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C + D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((3 - 26) * (-39 + -11)) + ((-1 - -15) + (216 + 7))) = ((-23 * (-39 + -11)) + ((-1 - -15) + (216 + 7))) = ((-23 * -50) + ((-1 - -15) + (216 + 7))) = ((-23 * -50) + (14 + (216 + 7))) = ((-23 * -50) + (14 + 223)) = (1150 + (14 + 223)) = (1150 + 237) = 1387.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1387.", "correct_answer": "1387", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 274, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 + -2 + -6 * -1) + (-8 - 3 * 2 - -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-2 + -2 + -6 * -1) and B = (-8 - 3 * 2 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -2 + -6 * -1) = ((-2 + -2) + (-6 * -1)) = (-4 + (-6 * -1)) = (-4 + 6) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 3 * 2 - -6) = ((-8 - (3 * 2)) - -6) = ((-8 - 6) - -6) = (-14 - -6) = -8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (2 + -8) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 164, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 + 3 + 7) * (6 + 7 * -4)) * ((-6 + -9 + -8) * (0 * 9 + 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-6 + 3 + 7), B = (6 + 7 * -4), C = (-6 + -9 + -8) and D = (0 * 9 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 3 + 7) = ((-6 + 3) + 7) = (-3 + 7) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 7 * -4) = (6 + (7 * -4)) = (6 + -28) = -22.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -9 + -8) = ((-6 + -9) + -8) = (-15 + -8) = -23.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 * 9 + 3) = ((0 * 9) + 3) = (0 + 3) = 3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((4 * -22) * (-23 * 3)) = (-88 * (-23 * 3)) = (-88 * -69) = 6072.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6072.", "correct_answer": "6072", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 335, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 + 6 - 3) + (9 - 6 * -2)) - ((-6 - -3 * 4) * (3 + -5 + -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (3 + 6 - 3), B = (9 - 6 * -2), C = (-6 - -3 * 4) and D = (3 + -5 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + 6 - 3) = ((3 + 6) - 3) = (9 - 3) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - 6 * -2) = (9 - (6 * -2)) = (9 - -12) = 21.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 - -3 * 4) = (-6 - (-3 * 4)) = (-6 - -12) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + -5 + -7) = ((3 + -5) + -7) = (-2 + -7) = -9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((6 + 21) - (6 * -9)) = (27 - (6 * -9)) = (27 - -54) = 81.\n(Final response) So the answer is 81.", "correct_answer": "81", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 430, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((9 * -3 - -3 * 7) * (7 + 4 + -5 * 9)) * ((-9 + 9 + 7 - 5) + (-1 - -9 - 3 * 1))) + (((-4 + -4 * -1 + 6) + (-6 * 3 + -9 * 1)) + ((9 - 8 - -1 - -1) * (-5 * -1 + 7 * 0)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) * (C + D)) + ((E + F) + (G * H)))\", where A = (9 * -3 - -3 * 7), B = (7 + 4 + -5 * 9), C = (-9 + 9 + 7 - 5), D = (-1 - -9 - 3 * 1), E = (-4 + -4 * -1 + 6), F = (-6 * 3 + -9 * 1), G = (9 - 8 - -1 - -1) and H = (-5 * -1 + 7 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * -3 - -3 * 7) = ((9 * -3) - (-3 * 7)) = (-27 - (-3 * 7)) = (-27 - -21) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 4 + -5 * 9) = ((7 + 4) + (-5 * 9)) = (11 + (-5 * 9)) = (11 + -45) = -34.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + 9 + 7 - 5) = (((-9 + 9) + 7) - 5) = ((0 + 7) - 5) = (7 - 5) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 - -9 - 3 * 1) = ((-1 - -9) - (3 * 1)) = (8 - (3 * 1)) = (8 - 3) = 5.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-4 + -4 * -1 + 6) = ((-4 + (-4 * -1)) + 6) = ((-4 + 4) + 6) = (0 + 6) = 6.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-6 * 3 + -9 * 1) = ((-6 * 3) + (-9 * 1)) = (-18 + (-9 * 1)) = (-18 + -9) = -27.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (9 - 8 - -1 - -1) = (((9 - 8) - -1) - -1) = ((1 - -1) - -1) = (2 - -1) = 3.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-5 * -1 + 7 * 0) = ((-5 * -1) + (7 * 0)) = (5 + (7 * 0)) = (5 + 0) = 5.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) * (C + D)) + ((E + F) + (G * H))) = (((-6 * -34) * (2 + 5)) + ((6 + -27) + (3 * 5))) = ((204 * (2 + 5)) + ((6 + -27) + (3 * 5))) = ((204 * 7) + ((6 + -27) + (3 * 5))) = ((204 * 7) + (-21 + (3 * 5))) = ((204 * 7) + (-21 + 15)) = (1428 + (-21 + 15)) = (1428 + -6) = 1422.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1422.", "correct_answer": "1422", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 277, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 * -3 - 2 + -5) * (-9 * 3 + 7 * 0)) * ((-3 * 2 - 0 + 2) * (-4 * -5 + -8 + 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (4 * -3 - 2 + -5), B = (-9 * 3 + 7 * 0), C = (-3 * 2 - 0 + 2) and D = (-4 * -5 + -8 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * -3 - 2 + -5) = (((4 * -3) - 2) + -5) = ((-12 - 2) + -5) = (-14 + -5) = -19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * 3 + 7 * 0) = ((-9 * 3) + (7 * 0)) = (-27 + (7 * 0)) = (-27 + 0) = -27.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 * 2 - 0 + 2) = (((-3 * 2) - 0) + 2) = ((-6 - 0) + 2) = (-6 + 2) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * -5 + -8 + 9) = (((-4 * -5) + -8) + 9) = ((20 + -8) + 9) = (12 + 9) = 21.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((-19 * -27) * (-4 * 21)) = (513 * (-4 * 21)) = (513 * -84) = -43092.\n(Final response) So the answer is -43092.", "correct_answer": "-43092", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 504, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 - -1 - 3) + (-3 + 1 - -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 - -1 - 3) and B = (-3 + 1 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -1 - 3) = ((7 - -1) - 3) = (8 - 3) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 1 - -6) = ((-3 + 1) - -6) = (-2 - -6) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (5 + 4) = 9.\n(Final response) So the answer is 9.", "correct_answer": "9", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 107, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 - 6 - 7 * -1 - -7 + -5) - (7 * 4 * 4 + 6 * -9 - -8)) - ((-6 + -9 * 9 * -4 * 4 * 9) - (3 + 0 * 1 * -2 + -7 - 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (7 - 6 - 7 * -1 - -7 + -5), B = (7 * 4 * 4 + 6 * -9 - -8), C = (-6 + -9 * 9 * -4 * 4 * 9) and D = (3 + 0 * 1 * -2 + -7 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - 6 - 7 * -1 - -7 + -5) = ((((7 - 6) - (7 * -1)) - -7) + -5) = (((1 - (7 * -1)) - -7) + -5) = (((1 - -7) - -7) + -5) = ((8 - -7) + -5) = (15 + -5) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * 4 * 4 + 6 * -9 - -8) = ((((7 * 4) * 4) + (6 * -9)) - -8) = (((28 * 4) + (6 * -9)) - -8) = (((28 * 4) + -54) - -8) = ((112 + -54) - -8) = (58 - -8) = 66.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -9 * 9 * -4 * 4 * 9) = (-6 + ((((-9 * 9) * -4) * 4) * 9)) = (-6 + (((-81 * -4) * 4) * 9)) = (-6 + ((324 * 4) * 9)) = (-6 + (1296 * 9)) = (-6 + 11664) = 11658.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + 0 * 1 * -2 + -7 - 2) = (((3 + ((0 * 1) * -2)) + -7) - 2) = (((3 + (0 * -2)) + -7) - 2) = (((3 + 0) + -7) - 2) = ((3 + -7) - 2) = (-4 - 2) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((10 - 66) - (11658 - -6)) = (-56 - (11658 - -6)) = (-56 - 11664) = -11720.\n(Final response) So the answer is -11720.", "correct_answer": "-11720", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 220, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 - 5 * 3 * 7) - (6 * -5 + -9 * 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (2 - 5 * 3 * 7) and B = (6 * -5 + -9 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - 5 * 3 * 7) = (2 - ((5 * 3) * 7)) = (2 - (15 * 7)) = (2 - 105) = -103.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -5 + -9 * 0) = ((6 * -5) + (-9 * 0)) = (-30 + (-9 * 0)) = (-30 + 0) = -30.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-103 - -30) = -73.\n(Final response) So the answer is -73.", "correct_answer": "-73", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 155, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 - -7 - 5 - 6) * (0 - 2 + 9 + 3)) + ((-8 * -1 * -2 * -5) + (9 * 3 - 1 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-5 - -7 - 5 - 6), B = (0 - 2 + 9 + 3), C = (-8 * -1 * -2 * -5) and D = (9 * 3 - 1 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -7 - 5 - 6) = (((-5 - -7) - 5) - 6) = ((2 - 5) - 6) = (-3 - 6) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 2 + 9 + 3) = (((0 - 2) + 9) + 3) = ((-2 + 9) + 3) = (7 + 3) = 10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * -1 * -2 * -5) = (((-8 * -1) * -2) * -5) = ((8 * -2) * -5) = (-16 * -5) = 80.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 * 3 - 1 * -6) = ((9 * 3) - (1 * -6)) = (27 - (1 * -6)) = (27 - -6) = 33.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((-9 * 10) + (80 + 33)) = (-90 + (80 + 33)) = (-90 + 113) = 23.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23.", "correct_answer": "23", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 582, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 + 3 + 0 * -5) - (6 + 8 * -1 - -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 + 3 + 0 * -5) and B = (6 + 8 * -1 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + 3 + 0 * -5) = ((0 + 3) + (0 * -5)) = (3 + (0 * -5)) = (3 + 0) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 8 * -1 - -8) = ((6 + (8 * -1)) - -8) = ((6 + -8) - -8) = (-2 - -8) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (3 - 6) = -3.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3.", "correct_answer": "-3", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 280, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 * 6 * 3 + -2) + (-8 + -4 - -9 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (4 * 6 * 3 + -2) and B = (-8 + -4 - -9 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 6 * 3 + -2) = (((4 * 6) * 3) + -2) = ((24 * 3) + -2) = (72 + -2) = 70.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + -4 - -9 - 7) = (((-8 + -4) - -9) - 7) = ((-12 - -9) - 7) = (-3 - 7) = -10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (70 + -10) = 60.\n(Final response) So the answer is 60.", "correct_answer": "60", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 207, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * 8 + -4 + 2) + (1 + -9 * 9 + -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 * 8 + -4 + 2) and B = (1 + -9 * 9 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 8 + -4 + 2) = (((7 * 8) + -4) + 2) = ((56 + -4) + 2) = (52 + 2) = 54.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + -9 * 9 + -8) = ((1 + (-9 * 9)) + -8) = ((1 + -81) + -8) = (-80 + -8) = -88.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (54 + -88) = -34.\n(Final response) So the answer is -34.", "correct_answer": "-34", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 154, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((6 + 2 - -8 * -6) + (6 + -7 * -7 - 4)) * ((-9 * 4 + 1 + 1) * (5 - -6 * -4 - -8))) * (((-1 * -2 - 7 * -9) + (5 * -3 * 2 * -8)) - ((-2 * 1 * 1 - -5) + (0 - 5 - 2 - -3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (6 + 2 - -8 * -6), B = (6 + -7 * -7 - 4), C = (-9 * 4 + 1 + 1), D = (5 - -6 * -4 - -8), E = (-1 * -2 - 7 * -9), F = (5 * -3 * 2 * -8), G = (-2 * 1 * 1 - -5) and H = (0 - 5 - 2 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 2 - -8 * -6) = ((6 + 2) - (-8 * -6)) = (8 - (-8 * -6)) = (8 - 48) = -40.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + -7 * -7 - 4) = ((6 + (-7 * -7)) - 4) = ((6 + 49) - 4) = (55 - 4) = 51.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * 4 + 1 + 1) = (((-9 * 4) + 1) + 1) = ((-36 + 1) + 1) = (-35 + 1) = -34.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - -6 * -4 - -8) = ((5 - (-6 * -4)) - -8) = ((5 - 24) - -8) = (-19 - -8) = -11.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-1 * -2 - 7 * -9) = ((-1 * -2) - (7 * -9)) = (2 - (7 * -9)) = (2 - -63) = 65.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 * -3 * 2 * -8) = (((5 * -3) * 2) * -8) = ((-15 * 2) * -8) = (-30 * -8) = 240.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-2 * 1 * 1 - -5) = (((-2 * 1) * 1) - -5) = ((-2 * 1) - -5) = (-2 - -5) = 3.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (0 - 5 - 2 - -3) = (((0 - 5) - 2) - -3) = ((-5 - 2) - -3) = (-7 - -3) = -4.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) - (G + H))) = (((-40 + 51) * (-34 * -11)) * ((65 + 240) - (3 + -4))) = ((11 * (-34 * -11)) * ((65 + 240) - (3 + -4))) = ((11 * 374) * ((65 + 240) - (3 + -4))) = ((11 * 374) * (305 - (3 + -4))) = ((11 * 374) * (305 - -1)) = (4114 * (305 - -1)) = (4114 * 306) = 1258884.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1258884.", "correct_answer": "1258884", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 292, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 - -8 - 5) - (-6 - -3 - 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 - -8 - 5) and B = (-6 - -3 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - -8 - 5) = ((-1 - -8) - 5) = (7 - 5) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - -3 - 9) = ((-6 - -3) - 9) = (-3 - 9) = -12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (2 - -12) = 14.\n(Final response) So the answer is 14.", "correct_answer": "14", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 7, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((1 * 9 * 7 * 8 - -1 + 4) - (-6 * -6 - 7 - 2 * 4 + -5)) + ((8 * 2 - -2 + -6 - -9 - 6) - (-5 * 9 - 0 + 7 - 4 + 7))) - (((-6 * -3 - 4 + 5 * 4 - -2) - (-1 - 3 - -7 * -4 * -5 + 1)) - ((-3 * 3 + 6 * -2 - -6 + 8) * (-8 + -7 * -5 - 9 + -2 + -6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C - D)) - ((E - F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (1 * 9 * 7 * 8 - -1 + 4), B = (-6 * -6 - 7 - 2 * 4 + -5), C = (8 * 2 - -2 + -6 - -9 - 6), D = (-5 * 9 - 0 + 7 - 4 + 7), E = (-6 * -3 - 4 + 5 * 4 - -2), F = (-1 - 3 - -7 * -4 * -5 + 1), G = (-3 * 3 + 6 * -2 - -6 + 8) and H = (-8 + -7 * -5 - 9 + -2 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * 9 * 7 * 8 - -1 + 4) = (((((1 * 9) * 7) * 8) - -1) + 4) = ((((9 * 7) * 8) - -1) + 4) = (((63 * 8) - -1) + 4) = ((504 - -1) + 4) = (505 + 4) = 509.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * -6 - 7 - 2 * 4 + -5) = ((((-6 * -6) - 7) - (2 * 4)) + -5) = (((36 - 7) - (2 * 4)) + -5) = (((36 - 7) - 8) + -5) = ((29 - 8) + -5) = (21 + -5) = 16.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * 2 - -2 + -6 - -9 - 6) = (((((8 * 2) - -2) + -6) - -9) - 6) = ((((16 - -2) + -6) - -9) - 6) = (((18 + -6) - -9) - 6) = ((12 - -9) - 6) = (21 - 6) = 15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 * 9 - 0 + 7 - 4 + 7) = (((((-5 * 9) - 0) + 7) - 4) + 7) = ((((-45 - 0) + 7) - 4) + 7) = (((-45 + 7) - 4) + 7) = ((-38 - 4) + 7) = (-42 + 7) = -35.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-6 * -3 - 4 + 5 * 4 - -2) = ((((-6 * -3) - 4) + (5 * 4)) - -2) = (((18 - 4) + (5 * 4)) - -2) = (((18 - 4) + 20) - -2) = ((14 + 20) - -2) = (34 - -2) = 36.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-1 - 3 - -7 * -4 * -5 + 1) = (((-1 - 3) - ((-7 * -4) * -5)) + 1) = ((-4 - ((-7 * -4) * -5)) + 1) = ((-4 - (28 * -5)) + 1) = ((-4 - -140) + 1) = (136 + 1) = 137.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-3 * 3 + 6 * -2 - -6 + 8) = ((((-3 * 3) + (6 * -2)) - -6) + 8) = (((-9 + (6 * -2)) - -6) + 8) = (((-9 + -12) - -6) + 8) = ((-21 - -6) + 8) = (-15 + 8) = -7.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 + -7 * -5 - 9 + -2 + -6) = ((((-8 + (-7 * -5)) - 9) + -2) + -6) = ((((-8 + 35) - 9) + -2) + -6) = (((27 - 9) + -2) + -6) = ((18 + -2) + -6) = (16 + -6) = 10.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C - D)) - ((E - F) - (G * H))) = (((509 - 16) + (15 - -35)) - ((36 - 137) - (-7 * 10))) = ((493 + (15 - -35)) - ((36 - 137) - (-7 * 10))) = ((493 + 50) - ((36 - 137) - (-7 * 10))) = ((493 + 50) - (-101 - (-7 * 10))) = ((493 + 50) - (-101 - -70)) = (543 - (-101 - -70)) = (543 - -31) = 574.\n(Final response) So the answer is 574.", "correct_answer": "574", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 345, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * -6 - -8) * (2 - -9 * 6)) * ((4 + 5 - -3) + (8 * 5 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-5 * -6 - -8), B = (2 - -9 * 6), C = (4 + 5 - -3) and D = (8 * 5 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * -6 - -8) = ((-5 * -6) - -8) = (30 - -8) = 38.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -9 * 6) = (2 - (-9 * 6)) = (2 - -54) = 56.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + 5 - -3) = ((4 + 5) - -3) = (9 - -3) = 12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * 5 + -8) = ((8 * 5) + -8) = (40 + -8) = 32.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((38 * 56) * (12 + 32)) = (2128 * (12 + 32)) = (2128 * 44) = 93632.\n(Final response) So the answer is 93632.", "correct_answer": "93632", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 383, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 * 8 * -5 * -8 * 0 * -3) + (5 * 0 - 4 - 0 + 4 - 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (2 * 8 * -5 * -8 * 0 * -3) and B = (5 * 0 - 4 - 0 + 4 - 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 8 * -5 * -8 * 0 * -3) = (((((2 * 8) * -5) * -8) * 0) * -3) = ((((16 * -5) * -8) * 0) * -3) = (((-80 * -8) * 0) * -3) = ((640 * 0) * -3) = (0 * -3) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * 0 - 4 - 0 + 4 - 6) = (((((5 * 0) - 4) - 0) + 4) - 6) = ((((0 - 4) - 0) + 4) - 6) = (((-4 - 0) + 4) - 6) = ((-4 + 4) - 6) = (0 - 6) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (0 + -6) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 107, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 + 9 + -2 + -9) - (-2 * 2 - 6 * 1)) * ((-2 * -1 - -3 * 5) * (6 * -9 - 1 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-4 + 9 + -2 + -9), B = (-2 * 2 - 6 * 1), C = (-2 * -1 - -3 * 5) and D = (6 * -9 - 1 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + 9 + -2 + -9) = (((-4 + 9) + -2) + -9) = ((5 + -2) + -9) = (3 + -9) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * 2 - 6 * 1) = ((-2 * 2) - (6 * 1)) = (-4 - (6 * 1)) = (-4 - 6) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 * -1 - -3 * 5) = ((-2 * -1) - (-3 * 5)) = (2 - (-3 * 5)) = (2 - -15) = 17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 * -9 - 1 * -1) = ((6 * -9) - (1 * -1)) = (-54 - (1 * -1)) = (-54 - -1) = -53.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((-6 - -10) * (17 * -53)) = (4 * (17 * -53)) = (4 * -901) = -3604.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3604.", "correct_answer": "-3604", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 157, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 - 4 - 9 - -5) * (-1 - -5 * 4 + -5)) * ((-1 + -6 * -3 * 7) * (8 * 9 - 3 - 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-6 - 4 - 9 - -5), B = (-1 - -5 * 4 + -5), C = (-1 + -6 * -3 * 7) and D = (8 * 9 - 3 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 4 - 9 - -5) = (((-6 - 4) - 9) - -5) = ((-10 - 9) - -5) = (-19 - -5) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - -5 * 4 + -5) = ((-1 - (-5 * 4)) + -5) = ((-1 - -20) + -5) = (19 + -5) = 14.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + -6 * -3 * 7) = (-1 + ((-6 * -3) * 7)) = (-1 + (18 * 7)) = (-1 + 126) = 125.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * 9 - 3 - 1) = (((8 * 9) - 3) - 1) = ((72 - 3) - 1) = (69 - 1) = 68.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((-14 * 14) * (125 * 68)) = (-196 * (125 * 68)) = (-196 * 8500) = -1666000.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1666000.", "correct_answer": "-1666000", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 467, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 - -9 + -6 + 4) + (-7 - -7 + -7 - 4)) - ((2 - 0 + -6 * -9) + (1 - 6 * 9 * 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-1 - -9 + -6 + 4), B = (-7 - -7 + -7 - 4), C = (2 - 0 + -6 * -9) and D = (1 - 6 * 9 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - -9 + -6 + 4) = (((-1 - -9) + -6) + 4) = ((8 + -6) + 4) = (2 + 4) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -7 + -7 - 4) = (((-7 - -7) + -7) - 4) = ((0 + -7) - 4) = (-7 - 4) = -11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - 0 + -6 * -9) = ((2 - 0) + (-6 * -9)) = (2 + (-6 * -9)) = (2 + 54) = 56.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 - 6 * 9 * 8) = (1 - ((6 * 9) * 8)) = (1 - (54 * 8)) = (1 - 432) = -431.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C + D)) = ((6 + -11) - (56 + -431)) = (-5 - (56 + -431)) = (-5 - -375) = 370.\n(Final response) So the answer is 370.", "correct_answer": "370", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 516, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - 4 - 4 - -3) * (2 * 9 + -7 + 0)) - ((-4 - -2 * 0 - -5) + (-5 + -1 * -1 + 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-9 - 4 - 4 - -3), B = (2 * 9 + -7 + 0), C = (-4 - -2 * 0 - -5) and D = (-5 + -1 * -1 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 4 - 4 - -3) = (((-9 - 4) - 4) - -3) = ((-13 - 4) - -3) = (-17 - -3) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 9 + -7 + 0) = (((2 * 9) + -7) + 0) = ((18 + -7) + 0) = (11 + 0) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - -2 * 0 - -5) = ((-4 - (-2 * 0)) - -5) = ((-4 - 0) - -5) = (-4 - -5) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 + -1 * -1 + 4) = ((-5 + (-1 * -1)) + 4) = ((-5 + 1) + 4) = (-4 + 4) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-14 * 11) - (1 + 0)) = (-154 - (1 + 0)) = (-154 - 1) = -155.\n(Final response) So the answer is -155.", "correct_answer": "-155", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 461, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 * -1 * 6 - -1 - -3 + 7) * (1 * 9 * 2 * -2 * -4 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (3 * -1 * 6 - -1 - -3 + 7) and B = (1 * 9 * 2 * -2 * -4 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -1 * 6 - -1 - -3 + 7) = (((((3 * -1) * 6) - -1) - -3) + 7) = ((((-3 * 6) - -1) - -3) + 7) = (((-18 - -1) - -3) + 7) = ((-17 - -3) + 7) = (-14 + 7) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 9 * 2 * -2 * -4 + -1) = (((((1 * 9) * 2) * -2) * -4) + -1) = ((((9 * 2) * -2) * -4) + -1) = (((18 * -2) * -4) + -1) = ((-36 * -4) + -1) = (144 + -1) = 143.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-7 * 143) = -1001.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1001.", "correct_answer": "-1001", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 108, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 * -6 + 4 * 6) + (4 - -1 * -1 + -6)) - ((-7 + -1 * 6 + 8) - (9 - 5 * 1 - 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-1 * -6 + 4 * 6), B = (4 - -1 * -1 + -6), C = (-7 + -1 * 6 + 8) and D = (9 - 5 * 1 - 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * -6 + 4 * 6) = ((-1 * -6) + (4 * 6)) = (6 + (4 * 6)) = (6 + 24) = 30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - -1 * -1 + -6) = ((4 - (-1 * -1)) + -6) = ((4 - 1) + -6) = (3 + -6) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + -1 * 6 + 8) = ((-7 + (-1 * 6)) + 8) = ((-7 + -6) + 8) = (-13 + 8) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - 5 * 1 - 6) = ((9 - (5 * 1)) - 6) = ((9 - 5) - 6) = (4 - 6) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((30 + -3) - (-5 - -2)) = (27 - (-5 - -2)) = (27 - -3) = 30.\n(Final response) So the answer is 30.", "correct_answer": "30", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 539, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 * -1 + 5 * -4) + (-2 - 5 * 4 - 5)) * ((3 + -1 * 7 * -6) - (-7 * -1 + -5 - -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (1 * -1 + 5 * -4), B = (-2 - 5 * 4 - 5), C = (3 + -1 * 7 * -6) and D = (-7 * -1 + -5 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * -1 + 5 * -4) = ((1 * -1) + (5 * -4)) = (-1 + (5 * -4)) = (-1 + -20) = -21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 5 * 4 - 5) = ((-2 - (5 * 4)) - 5) = ((-2 - 20) - 5) = (-22 - 5) = -27.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + -1 * 7 * -6) = (3 + ((-1 * 7) * -6)) = (3 + (-7 * -6)) = (3 + 42) = 45.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 * -1 + -5 - -3) = (((-7 * -1) + -5) - -3) = ((7 + -5) - -3) = (2 - -3) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((-21 + -27) * (45 - 5)) = (-48 * (45 - 5)) = (-48 * 40) = -1920.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1920.", "correct_answer": "-1920", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 524, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + 0 - 6) * (8 - -6 * 2)) * ((-2 * -1 * 7) - (-7 + -2 - -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (1 + 0 - 6), B = (8 - -6 * 2), C = (-2 * -1 * 7) and D = (-7 + -2 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 0 - 6) = ((1 + 0) - 6) = (1 - 6) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - -6 * 2) = (8 - (-6 * 2)) = (8 - -12) = 20.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 * -1 * 7) = ((-2 * -1) * 7) = (2 * 7) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + -2 - -3) = ((-7 + -2) - -3) = (-9 - -3) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((-5 * 20) * (14 - -6)) = (-100 * (14 - -6)) = (-100 * 20) = -2000.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2000.", "correct_answer": "-2000", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 356, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 - -1 - -5 - 7) * (6 * -1 + 5 + 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-3 - -1 - -5 - 7) and B = (6 * -1 + 5 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - -1 - -5 - 7) = (((-3 - -1) - -5) - 7) = ((-2 - -5) - 7) = (3 - 7) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -1 + 5 + 3) = (((6 * -1) + 5) + 3) = ((-6 + 5) + 3) = (-1 + 3) = 2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-4 * 2) = -8.\n(Final response) So the answer is -8.", "correct_answer": "-8", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 206, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((5 * 1 - -7) - (-4 * 7 * 8)) * ((6 * -4 - 7) + (6 + 6 + -1))) * (((-5 + 0 + -9) * (-5 - -4 * 5)) + ((0 * -7 - 6) + (6 - -5 + 1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C + D)) * ((E * F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (5 * 1 - -7), B = (-4 * 7 * 8), C = (6 * -4 - 7), D = (6 + 6 + -1), E = (-5 + 0 + -9), F = (-5 - -4 * 5), G = (0 * -7 - 6) and H = (6 - -5 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 1 - -7) = ((5 * 1) - -7) = (5 - -7) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 7 * 8) = ((-4 * 7) * 8) = (-28 * 8) = -224.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 * -4 - 7) = ((6 * -4) - 7) = (-24 - 7) = -31.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + 6 + -1) = ((6 + 6) + -1) = (12 + -1) = 11.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-5 + 0 + -9) = ((-5 + 0) + -9) = (-5 + -9) = -14.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-5 - -4 * 5) = (-5 - (-4 * 5)) = (-5 - -20) = 15.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (0 * -7 - 6) = ((0 * -7) - 6) = (0 - 6) = -6.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (6 - -5 + 1) = ((6 - -5) + 1) = (11 + 1) = 12.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C + D)) * ((E * F) + (G + H))) = (((12 - -224) * (-31 + 11)) * ((-14 * 15) + (-6 + 12))) = ((236 * (-31 + 11)) * ((-14 * 15) + (-6 + 12))) = ((236 * -20) * ((-14 * 15) + (-6 + 12))) = ((236 * -20) * (-210 + (-6 + 12))) = ((236 * -20) * (-210 + 6)) = (-4720 * (-210 + 6)) = (-4720 * -204) = 962880.\n(Final response) So the answer is 962880.", "correct_answer": "962880", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 250, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 + 5 + -2 - -6) - (-7 - -6 + 3 * -2)) + ((4 - 6 - -9 - -9) * (-4 * 2 + 2 - 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C * D))\", where A = (0 + 5 + -2 - -6), B = (-7 - -6 + 3 * -2), C = (4 - 6 - -9 - -9) and D = (-4 * 2 + 2 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + 5 + -2 - -6) = (((0 + 5) + -2) - -6) = ((5 + -2) - -6) = (3 - -6) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -6 + 3 * -2) = ((-7 - -6) + (3 * -2)) = (-1 + (3 * -2)) = (-1 + -6) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - 6 - -9 - -9) = (((4 - 6) - -9) - -9) = ((-2 - -9) - -9) = (7 - -9) = 16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * 2 + 2 - 4) = (((-4 * 2) + 2) - 4) = ((-8 + 2) - 4) = (-6 - 4) = -10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C * D)) = ((9 - -7) + (16 * -10)) = (16 + (16 * -10)) = (16 + -160) = -144.\n(Final response) So the answer is -144.", "correct_answer": "-144", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 589, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 - -7 * -5 * 2) * (0 + -5 * -1 * 1)) + ((8 + -1 - -5 - 1) - (5 - 4 + -4 - 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-1 - -7 * -5 * 2), B = (0 + -5 * -1 * 1), C = (8 + -1 - -5 - 1) and D = (5 - 4 + -4 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - -7 * -5 * 2) = (-1 - ((-7 * -5) * 2)) = (-1 - (35 * 2)) = (-1 - 70) = -71.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -5 * -1 * 1) = (0 + ((-5 * -1) * 1)) = (0 + (5 * 1)) = (0 + 5) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 + -1 - -5 - 1) = (((8 + -1) - -5) - 1) = ((7 - -5) - 1) = (12 - 1) = 11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - 4 + -4 - 5) = (((5 - 4) + -4) - 5) = ((1 + -4) - 5) = (-3 - 5) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((-71 * 5) + (11 - -8)) = (-355 + (11 - -8)) = (-355 + 19) = -336.\n(Final response) So the answer is -336.", "correct_answer": "-336", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 536, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - -2 - -3 + 2 + 6 - 3) + (4 - 3 - 2 * 5 * 1 - 5)) - ((2 * 6 - -1 * 9 * 7 - -5) * (-8 + -6 * 8 + 6 - 2 - -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (1 - -2 - -3 + 2 + 6 - 3), B = (4 - 3 - 2 * 5 * 1 - 5), C = (2 * 6 - -1 * 9 * 7 - -5) and D = (-8 + -6 * 8 + 6 - 2 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -2 - -3 + 2 + 6 - 3) = (((((1 - -2) - -3) + 2) + 6) - 3) = ((((3 - -3) + 2) + 6) - 3) = (((6 + 2) + 6) - 3) = ((8 + 6) - 3) = (14 - 3) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 3 - 2 * 5 * 1 - 5) = (((4 - 3) - ((2 * 5) * 1)) - 5) = ((1 - ((2 * 5) * 1)) - 5) = ((1 - (10 * 1)) - 5) = ((1 - 10) - 5) = (-9 - 5) = -14.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 * 6 - -1 * 9 * 7 - -5) = (((2 * 6) - ((-1 * 9) * 7)) - -5) = ((12 - ((-1 * 9) * 7)) - -5) = ((12 - (-9 * 7)) - -5) = ((12 - -63) - -5) = (75 - -5) = 80.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + -6 * 8 + 6 - 2 - -9) = ((((-8 + (-6 * 8)) + 6) - 2) - -9) = ((((-8 + -48) + 6) - 2) - -9) = (((-56 + 6) - 2) - -9) = ((-50 - 2) - -9) = (-52 - -9) = -43.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((11 + -14) - (80 * -43)) = (-3 - (80 * -43)) = (-3 - -3440) = 3437.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3437.", "correct_answer": "3437", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 235, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 - 5 + -4 - 8) - (-6 + 4 - 3 * 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-8 - 5 + -4 - 8) and B = (-6 + 4 - 3 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 5 + -4 - 8) = (((-8 - 5) + -4) - 8) = ((-13 + -4) - 8) = (-17 - 8) = -25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + 4 - 3 * 2) = ((-6 + 4) - (3 * 2)) = (-2 - (3 * 2)) = (-2 - 6) = -8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-25 - -8) = -17.\n(Final response) So the answer is -17.", "correct_answer": "-17", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 259, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 - -8 * 1 + 2) + (5 + 7 - 8 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-8 - -8 * 1 + 2) and B = (5 + 7 - 8 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -8 * 1 + 2) = ((-8 - (-8 * 1)) + 2) = ((-8 - -8) + 2) = (0 + 2) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 7 - 8 - -4) = (((5 + 7) - 8) - -4) = ((12 - 8) - -4) = (4 - -4) = 8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (2 + 8) = 10.\n(Final response) So the answer is 10.", "correct_answer": "10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 153, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 + -6 * -2 + 6) - (-8 - -2 * -4 * 8)) + ((5 - 2 * 2 + 0) - (7 - 6 - -7 - -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-3 + -6 * -2 + 6), B = (-8 - -2 * -4 * 8), C = (5 - 2 * 2 + 0) and D = (7 - 6 - -7 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + -6 * -2 + 6) = ((-3 + (-6 * -2)) + 6) = ((-3 + 12) + 6) = (9 + 6) = 15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - -2 * -4 * 8) = (-8 - ((-2 * -4) * 8)) = (-8 - (8 * 8)) = (-8 - 64) = -72.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 - 2 * 2 + 0) = ((5 - (2 * 2)) + 0) = ((5 - 4) + 0) = (1 + 0) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 - 6 - -7 - -1) = (((7 - 6) - -7) - -1) = ((1 - -7) - -1) = (8 - -1) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((15 - -72) + (1 - 9)) = (87 + (1 - 9)) = (87 + -8) = 79.\n(Final response) So the answer is 79.", "correct_answer": "79", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 487, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 - 7 * 5) * (5 + 4 - 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 - 7 * 5) and B = (5 + 4 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - 7 * 5) = (-5 - (7 * 5)) = (-5 - 35) = -40.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 4 - 1) = ((5 + 4) - 1) = (9 - 1) = 8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-40 * 8) = -320.\n(Final response) So the answer is -320.", "correct_answer": "-320", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 63, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 + -5 + -7) - (-2 - 5 + 0)) * ((-1 - -5 * -1) - (9 + -9 * -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (2 + -5 + -7), B = (-2 - 5 + 0), C = (-1 - -5 * -1) and D = (9 + -9 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + -5 + -7) = ((2 + -5) + -7) = (-3 + -7) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 5 + 0) = ((-2 - 5) + 0) = (-7 + 0) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 - -5 * -1) = (-1 - (-5 * -1)) = (-1 - 5) = -6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -9 * -9) = (9 + (-9 * -9)) = (9 + 81) = 90.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((-10 - -7) * (-6 - 90)) = (-3 * (-6 - 90)) = (-3 * -96) = 288.\n(Final response) So the answer is 288.", "correct_answer": "288", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 339, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-5 - 1 - -4) - (1 + -5 - 1)) - ((3 * 1 - -8) * (-1 * 8 - 3))) + (((-3 + -1 - -1) - (-9 - -9 * 5)) + ((-2 - -7 * 2) * (8 + -5 - 7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C * D)) + ((E - F) + (G * H)))\", where A = (-5 - 1 - -4), B = (1 + -5 - 1), C = (3 * 1 - -8), D = (-1 * 8 - 3), E = (-3 + -1 - -1), F = (-9 - -9 * 5), G = (-2 - -7 * 2) and H = (8 + -5 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - 1 - -4) = ((-5 - 1) - -4) = (-6 - -4) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + -5 - 1) = ((1 + -5) - 1) = (-4 - 1) = -5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 * 1 - -8) = ((3 * 1) - -8) = (3 - -8) = 11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * 8 - 3) = ((-1 * 8) - 3) = (-8 - 3) = -11.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-3 + -1 - -1) = ((-3 + -1) - -1) = (-4 - -1) = -3.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-9 - -9 * 5) = (-9 - (-9 * 5)) = (-9 - -45) = 36.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-2 - -7 * 2) = (-2 - (-7 * 2)) = (-2 - -14) = 12.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 + -5 - 7) = ((8 + -5) - 7) = (3 - 7) = -4.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C * D)) + ((E - F) + (G * H))) = (((-2 - -5) - (11 * -11)) + ((-3 - 36) + (12 * -4))) = ((3 - (11 * -11)) + ((-3 - 36) + (12 * -4))) = ((3 - -121) + ((-3 - 36) + (12 * -4))) = ((3 - -121) + (-39 + (12 * -4))) = ((3 - -121) + (-39 + -48)) = (124 + (-39 + -48)) = (124 + -87) = 37.\n(Final response) So the answer is 37.", "correct_answer": "37", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 246, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 * 8 + -1 - -5 * -2 + 1) + (7 - -6 * 9 - -8 + 2 + 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (4 * 8 + -1 - -5 * -2 + 1) and B = (7 - -6 * 9 - -8 + 2 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 8 + -1 - -5 * -2 + 1) = ((((4 * 8) + -1) - (-5 * -2)) + 1) = (((32 + -1) - (-5 * -2)) + 1) = (((32 + -1) - 10) + 1) = ((31 - 10) + 1) = (21 + 1) = 22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - -6 * 9 - -8 + 2 + 7) = ((((7 - (-6 * 9)) - -8) + 2) + 7) = ((((7 - -54) - -8) + 2) + 7) = (((61 - -8) + 2) + 7) = ((69 + 2) + 7) = (71 + 7) = 78.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (22 + 78) = 100.\n(Final response) So the answer is 100.", "correct_answer": "100", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 119, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + 3 + -4 * 0) + (-3 * -1 + 0 * -7)) + ((-2 + -3 * 3 - 8) + (4 * -7 + 2 * -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (7 + 3 + -4 * 0), B = (-3 * -1 + 0 * -7), C = (-2 + -3 * 3 - 8) and D = (4 * -7 + 2 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 3 + -4 * 0) = ((7 + 3) + (-4 * 0)) = (10 + (-4 * 0)) = (10 + 0) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * -1 + 0 * -7) = ((-3 * -1) + (0 * -7)) = (3 + (0 * -7)) = (3 + 0) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + -3 * 3 - 8) = ((-2 + (-3 * 3)) - 8) = ((-2 + -9) - 8) = (-11 - 8) = -19.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * -7 + 2 * -8) = ((4 * -7) + (2 * -8)) = (-28 + (2 * -8)) = (-28 + -16) = -44.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((10 + 3) + (-19 + -44)) = (13 + (-19 + -44)) = (13 + -63) = -50.\n(Final response) So the answer is -50.", "correct_answer": "-50", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 466, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 * 1 + -3) - (5 - 5 - -2)) + ((0 * -7 - -1) + (-4 * -2 - -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (4 * 1 + -3), B = (5 - 5 - -2), C = (0 * -7 - -1) and D = (-4 * -2 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 1 + -3) = ((4 * 1) + -3) = (4 + -3) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 5 - -2) = ((5 - 5) - -2) = (0 - -2) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * -7 - -1) = ((0 * -7) - -1) = (0 - -1) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * -2 - -6) = ((-4 * -2) - -6) = (8 - -6) = 14.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((1 - 2) + (1 + 14)) = (-1 + (1 + 14)) = (-1 + 15) = 14.\n(Final response) So the answer is 14.", "correct_answer": "14", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 340, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 * -8 + -6 * -9) * (-7 + 8 + 0 * -3)) + ((-2 + 8 - 2 + -8) - (-6 + 5 * 7 * -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-1 * -8 + -6 * -9), B = (-7 + 8 + 0 * -3), C = (-2 + 8 - 2 + -8) and D = (-6 + 5 * 7 * -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * -8 + -6 * -9) = ((-1 * -8) + (-6 * -9)) = (8 + (-6 * -9)) = (8 + 54) = 62.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + 8 + 0 * -3) = ((-7 + 8) + (0 * -3)) = (1 + (0 * -3)) = (1 + 0) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + 8 - 2 + -8) = (((-2 + 8) - 2) + -8) = ((6 - 2) + -8) = (4 + -8) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + 5 * 7 * -4) = (-6 + ((5 * 7) * -4)) = (-6 + (35 * -4)) = (-6 + -140) = -146.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((62 * 1) + (-4 - -146)) = (62 + (-4 - -146)) = (62 + 142) = 204.\n(Final response) So the answer is 204.", "correct_answer": "204", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 456, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-9 * 8 + 4 * 0 - 0) - (9 + -1 + -2 + -3 + -8)) * ((-9 * -9 * 7 * -2 + 5) - (-2 * 7 + 8 * 1 - 6))) * (((3 + 3 * 7 - 4 - 6) - (6 * -4 * 1 + 0 - -5)) - ((3 - -7 * 1 - -7 + -4) - (-2 - -7 + 7 - -7 * 5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C - D)) * ((E - F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (-9 * 8 + 4 * 0 - 0), B = (9 + -1 + -2 + -3 + -8), C = (-9 * -9 * 7 * -2 + 5), D = (-2 * 7 + 8 * 1 - 6), E = (3 + 3 * 7 - 4 - 6), F = (6 * -4 * 1 + 0 - -5), G = (3 - -7 * 1 - -7 + -4) and H = (-2 - -7 + 7 - -7 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 8 + 4 * 0 - 0) = (((-9 * 8) + (4 * 0)) - 0) = ((-72 + (4 * 0)) - 0) = ((-72 + 0) - 0) = (-72 - 0) = -72.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + -1 + -2 + -3 + -8) = ((((9 + -1) + -2) + -3) + -8) = (((8 + -2) + -3) + -8) = ((6 + -3) + -8) = (3 + -8) = -5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * -9 * 7 * -2 + 5) = ((((-9 * -9) * 7) * -2) + 5) = (((81 * 7) * -2) + 5) = ((567 * -2) + 5) = (-1134 + 5) = -1129.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * 7 + 8 * 1 - 6) = (((-2 * 7) + (8 * 1)) - 6) = ((-14 + (8 * 1)) - 6) = ((-14 + 8) - 6) = (-6 - 6) = -12.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (3 + 3 * 7 - 4 - 6) = (((3 + (3 * 7)) - 4) - 6) = (((3 + 21) - 4) - 6) = ((24 - 4) - 6) = (20 - 6) = 14.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (6 * -4 * 1 + 0 - -5) = ((((6 * -4) * 1) + 0) - -5) = (((-24 * 1) + 0) - -5) = ((-24 + 0) - -5) = (-24 - -5) = -19.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 - -7 * 1 - -7 + -4) = (((3 - (-7 * 1)) - -7) + -4) = (((3 - -7) - -7) + -4) = ((10 - -7) + -4) = (17 + -4) = 13.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-2 - -7 + 7 - -7 * 5) = (((-2 - -7) + 7) - (-7 * 5)) = ((5 + 7) - (-7 * 5)) = ((5 + 7) - -35) = (12 - -35) = 47.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C - D)) * ((E - F) - (G - H))) = (((-72 - -5) * (-1129 - -12)) * ((14 - -19) - (13 - 47))) = ((-67 * (-1129 - -12)) * ((14 - -19) - (13 - 47))) = ((-67 * -1117) * ((14 - -19) - (13 - 47))) = ((-67 * -1117) * (33 - (13 - 47))) = ((-67 * -1117) * (33 - -34)) = (74839 * (33 - -34)) = (74839 * 67) = 5014213.\n(Final response) So the answer is 5014213.", "correct_answer": "5014213", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 312, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 - -9 + -2 * -9) + (6 - -2 + 6 - -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (9 - -9 + -2 * -9) and B = (6 - -2 + 6 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - -9 + -2 * -9) = ((9 - -9) + (-2 * -9)) = (18 + (-2 * -9)) = (18 + 18) = 36.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - -2 + 6 - -7) = (((6 - -2) + 6) - -7) = ((8 + 6) - -7) = (14 - -7) = 21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (36 + 21) = 57.\n(Final response) So the answer is 57.", "correct_answer": "57", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 186, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - -8 * -7 + 9) - (7 + 3 * -9 + 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 - -8 * -7 + 9) and B = (7 + 3 * -9 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -8 * -7 + 9) = ((1 - (-8 * -7)) + 9) = ((1 - 56) + 9) = (-55 + 9) = -46.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 3 * -9 + 3) = ((7 + (3 * -9)) + 3) = ((7 + -27) + 3) = (-20 + 3) = -17.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-46 - -17) = -29.\n(Final response) So the answer is -29.", "correct_answer": "-29", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 47, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + 8 + -6) - (-3 + -5 * -1)) * ((9 + 7 * -7) - (9 + -4 - 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (7 + 8 + -6), B = (-3 + -5 * -1), C = (9 + 7 * -7) and D = (9 + -4 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 8 + -6) = ((7 + 8) + -6) = (15 + -6) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + -5 * -1) = (-3 + (-5 * -1)) = (-3 + 5) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 + 7 * -7) = (9 + (7 * -7)) = (9 + -49) = -40.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -4 - 9) = ((9 + -4) - 9) = (5 - 9) = -4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((9 - 2) * (-40 - -4)) = (7 * (-40 - -4)) = (7 * -36) = -252.\n(Final response) So the answer is -252.", "correct_answer": "-252", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 343, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 * 4 - 9 * 5) + (-2 + -6 - -8 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (3 * 4 - 9 * 5) and B = (-2 + -6 - -8 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 4 - 9 * 5) = ((3 * 4) - (9 * 5)) = (12 - (9 * 5)) = (12 - 45) = -33.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + -6 - -8 * -2) = ((-2 + -6) - (-8 * -2)) = (-8 - (-8 * -2)) = (-8 - 16) = -24.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-33 + -24) = -57.\n(Final response) So the answer is -57.", "correct_answer": "-57", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 39, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-7 * 3 * 7) + (6 * -1 + 2)) * ((-1 + 9 - 3) - (9 - 2 - -5))) - (((-2 - 6 - -8) + (-9 + 2 + 1)) - ((-2 + -1 - -3) * (4 * 8 + 8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C - D)) - ((E + F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (-7 * 3 * 7), B = (6 * -1 + 2), C = (-1 + 9 - 3), D = (9 - 2 - -5), E = (-2 - 6 - -8), F = (-9 + 2 + 1), G = (-2 + -1 - -3) and H = (4 * 8 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * 3 * 7) = ((-7 * 3) * 7) = (-21 * 7) = -147.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -1 + 2) = ((6 * -1) + 2) = (-6 + 2) = -4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + 9 - 3) = ((-1 + 9) - 3) = (8 - 3) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - 2 - -5) = ((9 - 2) - -5) = (7 - -5) = 12.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-2 - 6 - -8) = ((-2 - 6) - -8) = (-8 - -8) = 0.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-9 + 2 + 1) = ((-9 + 2) + 1) = (-7 + 1) = -6.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-2 + -1 - -3) = ((-2 + -1) - -3) = (-3 - -3) = 0.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (4 * 8 + 8) = ((4 * 8) + 8) = (32 + 8) = 40.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C - D)) - ((E + F) - (G * H))) = (((-147 + -4) * (5 - 12)) - ((0 + -6) - (0 * 40))) = ((-151 * (5 - 12)) - ((0 + -6) - (0 * 40))) = ((-151 * -7) - ((0 + -6) - (0 * 40))) = ((-151 * -7) - (-6 - (0 * 40))) = ((-151 * -7) - (-6 - 0)) = (1057 - (-6 - 0)) = (1057 - -6) = 1063.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1063.", "correct_answer": "1063", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 265, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 + -6 * -3) - (-6 + 1 * 1)) * ((4 + -8 - 6) - (6 * -2 * -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-3 + -6 * -3), B = (-6 + 1 * 1), C = (4 + -8 - 6) and D = (6 * -2 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + -6 * -3) = (-3 + (-6 * -3)) = (-3 + 18) = 15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + 1 * 1) = (-6 + (1 * 1)) = (-6 + 1) = -5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + -8 - 6) = ((4 + -8) - 6) = (-4 - 6) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 * -2 * -8) = ((6 * -2) * -8) = (-12 * -8) = 96.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((15 - -5) * (-10 - 96)) = (20 * (-10 - 96)) = (20 * -106) = -2120.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2120.", "correct_answer": "-2120", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 368, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 + -6 + -3 * -2) * (-9 * -1 + 2 - 3)) + ((-5 + 9 - -9 - 8) - (-2 - 5 * 0 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-1 + -6 + -3 * -2), B = (-9 * -1 + 2 - 3), C = (-5 + 9 - -9 - 8) and D = (-2 - 5 * 0 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + -6 + -3 * -2) = ((-1 + -6) + (-3 * -2)) = (-7 + (-3 * -2)) = (-7 + 6) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -1 + 2 - 3) = (((-9 * -1) + 2) - 3) = ((9 + 2) - 3) = (11 - 3) = 8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 + 9 - -9 - 8) = (((-5 + 9) - -9) - 8) = ((4 - -9) - 8) = (13 - 8) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - 5 * 0 * 2) = (-2 - ((5 * 0) * 2)) = (-2 - (0 * 2)) = (-2 - 0) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((-1 * 8) + (5 - -2)) = (-8 + (5 - -2)) = (-8 + 7) = -1.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1.", "correct_answer": "-1", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 548, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 - 5 * -1 - 8) + (1 + -6 + 2 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-4 - 5 * -1 - 8) and B = (1 + -6 + 2 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 5 * -1 - 8) = ((-4 - (5 * -1)) - 8) = ((-4 - -5) - 8) = (1 - 8) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + -6 + 2 - 3) = (((1 + -6) + 2) - 3) = ((-5 + 2) - 3) = (-3 - 3) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-7 + -6) = -13.\n(Final response) So the answer is -13.", "correct_answer": "-13", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 275, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * 6 * 6 - 2 * 7) + (8 * -6 + -1 - -8 + -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 * 6 * 6 - 2 * 7) and B = (8 * -6 + -1 - -8 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 6 * 6 - 2 * 7) = (((7 * 6) * 6) - (2 * 7)) = ((42 * 6) - (2 * 7)) = ((42 * 6) - 14) = (252 - 14) = 238.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * -6 + -1 - -8 + -4) = ((((8 * -6) + -1) - -8) + -4) = (((-48 + -1) - -8) + -4) = ((-49 - -8) + -4) = (-41 + -4) = -45.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (238 + -45) = 193.\n(Final response) So the answer is 193.", "correct_answer": "193", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 64, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 + -4 * -9 - 6) * (1 + 0 * -1 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 + -4 * -9 - 6) and B = (1 + 0 * -1 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + -4 * -9 - 6) = ((9 + (-4 * -9)) - 6) = ((9 + 36) - 6) = (45 - 6) = 39.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + 0 * -1 * 4) = (1 + ((0 * -1) * 4)) = (1 + (0 * 4)) = (1 + 0) = 1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (39 * 1) = 39.\n(Final response) So the answer is 39.", "correct_answer": "39", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 266, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 + -7 - 5 * -4) + (-6 * 8 + -6 - -5)) + ((-4 - 9 * 5 - -1) * (4 * 6 * -6 - -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (6 + -7 - 5 * -4), B = (-6 * 8 + -6 - -5), C = (-4 - 9 * 5 - -1) and D = (4 * 6 * -6 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + -7 - 5 * -4) = ((6 + -7) - (5 * -4)) = (-1 - (5 * -4)) = (-1 - -20) = 19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 8 + -6 - -5) = (((-6 * 8) + -6) - -5) = ((-48 + -6) - -5) = (-54 - -5) = -49.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - 9 * 5 - -1) = ((-4 - (9 * 5)) - -1) = ((-4 - 45) - -1) = (-49 - -1) = -48.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * 6 * -6 - -2) = (((4 * 6) * -6) - -2) = ((24 * -6) - -2) = (-144 - -2) = -142.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((19 + -49) + (-48 * -142)) = (-30 + (-48 * -142)) = (-30 + 6816) = 6786.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6786.", "correct_answer": "6786", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 150, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 - 1 - 6 - 9) * (9 + 6 - 9 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (7 - 1 - 6 - 9) and B = (9 + 6 - 9 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - 1 - 6 - 9) = (((7 - 1) - 6) - 9) = ((6 - 6) - 9) = (0 - 9) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + 6 - 9 + -9) = (((9 + 6) - 9) + -9) = ((15 - 9) + -9) = (6 + -9) = -3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-9 * -3) = 27.\n(Final response) So the answer is 27.", "correct_answer": "27", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 48, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 + -4 - -1 - 9) * (3 - -5 + 9 * -4)) + ((-9 + -1 * -8 * -5) + (7 + 5 - 2 - 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-5 + -4 - -1 - 9), B = (3 - -5 + 9 * -4), C = (-9 + -1 * -8 * -5) and D = (7 + 5 - 2 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + -4 - -1 - 9) = (((-5 + -4) - -1) - 9) = ((-9 - -1) - 9) = (-8 - 9) = -17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - -5 + 9 * -4) = ((3 - -5) + (9 * -4)) = (8 + (9 * -4)) = (8 + -36) = -28.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + -1 * -8 * -5) = (-9 + ((-1 * -8) * -5)) = (-9 + (8 * -5)) = (-9 + -40) = -49.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + 5 - 2 - 3) = (((7 + 5) - 2) - 3) = ((12 - 2) - 3) = (10 - 3) = 7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((-17 * -28) + (-49 + 7)) = (476 + (-49 + 7)) = (476 + -42) = 434.\n(Final response) So the answer is 434.", "correct_answer": "434", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 513, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + -7 * 6) * (-9 * 7 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-1 + -7 * 6) and B = (-9 * 7 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + -7 * 6) = (-1 + (-7 * 6)) = (-1 + -42) = -43.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * 7 - -2) = ((-9 * 7) - -2) = (-63 - -2) = -61.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-43 * -61) = 2623.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2623.", "correct_answer": "2623", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 22, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 + 8 - -4 * 2) - (1 - 9 + -6 * 3)) * ((9 - -1 + 4 - -1) + (8 - -7 - 0 - -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-3 + 8 - -4 * 2), B = (1 - 9 + -6 * 3), C = (9 - -1 + 4 - -1) and D = (8 - -7 - 0 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 8 - -4 * 2) = ((-3 + 8) - (-4 * 2)) = (5 - (-4 * 2)) = (5 - -8) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - 9 + -6 * 3) = ((1 - 9) + (-6 * 3)) = (-8 + (-6 * 3)) = (-8 + -18) = -26.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - -1 + 4 - -1) = (((9 - -1) + 4) - -1) = ((10 + 4) - -1) = (14 - -1) = 15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - -7 - 0 - -1) = (((8 - -7) - 0) - -1) = ((15 - 0) - -1) = (15 - -1) = 16.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((13 - -26) * (15 + 16)) = (39 * (15 + 16)) = (39 * 31) = 1209.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1209.", "correct_answer": "1209", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 522, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 + -9 + 1) - (8 + 7 * 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-4 + -9 + 1) and B = (8 + 7 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -9 + 1) = ((-4 + -9) + 1) = (-13 + 1) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + 7 * 7) = (8 + (7 * 7)) = (8 + 49) = 57.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-12 - 57) = -69.\n(Final response) So the answer is -69.", "correct_answer": "-69", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 97, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 - -7 - 7 * 6) - (3 * 4 + 9 - 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (4 - -7 - 7 * 6) and B = (3 * 4 + 9 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - -7 - 7 * 6) = ((4 - -7) - (7 * 6)) = (11 - (7 * 6)) = (11 - 42) = -31.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 4 + 9 - 0) = (((3 * 4) + 9) - 0) = ((12 + 9) - 0) = (21 - 0) = 21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-31 - 21) = -52.\n(Final response) So the answer is -52.", "correct_answer": "-52", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 295, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 * 9 + 1 + -1) - (8 + -2 * 7 + 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 * 9 + 1 + -1) and B = (8 + -2 * 7 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 9 + 1 + -1) = (((-1 * 9) + 1) + -1) = ((-9 + 1) + -1) = (-8 + -1) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + -2 * 7 + 5) = ((8 + (-2 * 7)) + 5) = ((8 + -14) + 5) = (-6 + 5) = -1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-9 - -1) = -8.\n(Final response) So the answer is -8.", "correct_answer": "-8", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 197, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - 3 + -1) - (4 - 1 - -7)) + ((6 - 7 + -3) + (1 + -8 * 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-9 - 3 + -1), B = (4 - 1 - -7), C = (6 - 7 + -3) and D = (1 + -8 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 3 + -1) = ((-9 - 3) + -1) = (-12 + -1) = -13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 1 - -7) = ((4 - 1) - -7) = (3 - -7) = 10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 7 + -3) = ((6 - 7) + -3) = (-1 + -3) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + -8 * 9) = (1 + (-8 * 9)) = (1 + -72) = -71.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-13 - 10) + (-4 + -71)) = (-23 + (-4 + -71)) = (-23 + -75) = -98.\n(Final response) So the answer is -98.", "correct_answer": "-98", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 444, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 + -7 + -4 - 4) + (6 * 5 - -6 * 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (8 + -7 + -4 - 4) and B = (6 * 5 - -6 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + -7 + -4 - 4) = (((8 + -7) + -4) - 4) = ((1 + -4) - 4) = (-3 - 4) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * 5 - -6 * 6) = ((6 * 5) - (-6 * 6)) = (30 - (-6 * 6)) = (30 - -36) = 66.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-7 + 66) = 59.\n(Final response) So the answer is 59.", "correct_answer": "59", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 261, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 - 6 * 1) - (-4 * 6 + -7)) + ((-7 - 7 * -8) - (0 * 6 * 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-8 - 6 * 1), B = (-4 * 6 + -7), C = (-7 - 7 * -8) and D = (0 * 6 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 6 * 1) = (-8 - (6 * 1)) = (-8 - 6) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 6 + -7) = ((-4 * 6) + -7) = (-24 + -7) = -31.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - 7 * -8) = (-7 - (7 * -8)) = (-7 - -56) = 49.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 * 6 * 6) = ((0 * 6) * 6) = (0 * 6) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-14 - -31) + (49 - 0)) = (17 + (49 - 0)) = (17 + 49) = 66.\n(Final response) So the answer is 66.", "correct_answer": "66", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 310, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-8 * -1 + 4 - -1 * -1 * -3) + (-6 * 1 * 7 * 7 - 7 * 2)) + ((-2 * 9 + -2 * 8 + -8 * -9) + (-2 * 4 - 1 * 4 - 0 - 9))) * (((7 + 1 - 6 + -2 * 0 * 1) + (-6 * 1 + -6 * 6 * -2 - 7)) - ((6 - -3 - 3 * 4 + -8 * -2) * (-6 * -6 + -2 - 7 - -7 + 0)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C + D)) * ((E + F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (-8 * -1 + 4 - -1 * -1 * -3), B = (-6 * 1 * 7 * 7 - 7 * 2), C = (-2 * 9 + -2 * 8 + -8 * -9), D = (-2 * 4 - 1 * 4 - 0 - 9), E = (7 + 1 - 6 + -2 * 0 * 1), F = (-6 * 1 + -6 * 6 * -2 - 7), G = (6 - -3 - 3 * 4 + -8 * -2) and H = (-6 * -6 + -2 - 7 - -7 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * -1 + 4 - -1 * -1 * -3) = (((-8 * -1) + 4) - ((-1 * -1) * -3)) = ((8 + 4) - ((-1 * -1) * -3)) = ((8 + 4) - (1 * -3)) = (12 - (1 * -3)) = (12 - -3) = 15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 1 * 7 * 7 - 7 * 2) = ((((-6 * 1) * 7) * 7) - (7 * 2)) = (((-6 * 7) * 7) - (7 * 2)) = (((-6 * 7) * 7) - 14) = ((-42 * 7) - 14) = (-294 - 14) = -308.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 * 9 + -2 * 8 + -8 * -9) = (((-2 * 9) + (-2 * 8)) + (-8 * -9)) = ((-18 + (-2 * 8)) + (-8 * -9)) = ((-18 + -16) + (-8 * -9)) = ((-18 + -16) + 72) = (-34 + 72) = 38.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * 4 - 1 * 4 - 0 - 9) = ((((-2 * 4) - (1 * 4)) - 0) - 9) = (((-8 - (1 * 4)) - 0) - 9) = (((-8 - 4) - 0) - 9) = ((-12 - 0) - 9) = (-12 - 9) = -21.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (7 + 1 - 6 + -2 * 0 * 1) = (((7 + 1) - 6) + ((-2 * 0) * 1)) = ((8 - 6) + ((-2 * 0) * 1)) = ((8 - 6) + (0 * 1)) = (2 + (0 * 1)) = (2 + 0) = 2.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-6 * 1 + -6 * 6 * -2 - 7) = (((-6 * 1) + ((-6 * 6) * -2)) - 7) = ((-6 + ((-6 * 6) * -2)) - 7) = ((-6 + (-36 * -2)) - 7) = ((-6 + 72) - 7) = (66 - 7) = 59.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (6 - -3 - 3 * 4 + -8 * -2) = (((6 - -3) - (3 * 4)) + (-8 * -2)) = ((9 - (3 * 4)) + (-8 * -2)) = ((9 - 12) + (-8 * -2)) = ((9 - 12) + 16) = (-3 + 16) = 13.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-6 * -6 + -2 - 7 - -7 + 0) = (((((-6 * -6) + -2) - 7) - -7) + 0) = ((((36 + -2) - 7) - -7) + 0) = (((34 - 7) - -7) + 0) = ((27 - -7) + 0) = (34 + 0) = 34.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C + D)) * ((E + F) - (G * H))) = (((15 + -308) + (38 + -21)) * ((2 + 59) - (13 * 34))) = ((-293 + (38 + -21)) * ((2 + 59) - (13 * 34))) = ((-293 + 17) * ((2 + 59) - (13 * 34))) = ((-293 + 17) * (61 - (13 * 34))) = ((-293 + 17) * (61 - 442)) = (-276 * (61 - 442)) = (-276 * -381) = 105156.\n(Final response) So the answer is 105156.", "correct_answer": "105156", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 339, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 + 7 - 0 + 2) * (0 - 3 + -4 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 + 7 - 0 + 2) and B = (0 - 3 + -4 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 7 - 0 + 2) = (((-7 + 7) - 0) + 2) = ((0 - 0) + 2) = (0 + 2) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 3 + -4 - 7) = (((0 - 3) + -4) - 7) = ((-3 + -4) - 7) = (-7 - 7) = -14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (2 * -14) = -28.\n(Final response) So the answer is -28.", "correct_answer": "-28", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 160, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 - 1 - 5) * (-3 * 7 - 6)) * ((5 + 0 - -3) * (4 * 5 * 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-6 - 1 - 5), B = (-3 * 7 - 6), C = (5 + 0 - -3) and D = (4 * 5 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 1 - 5) = ((-6 - 1) - 5) = (-7 - 5) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * 7 - 6) = ((-3 * 7) - 6) = (-21 - 6) = -27.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 + 0 - -3) = ((5 + 0) - -3) = (5 - -3) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * 5 * 3) = ((4 * 5) * 3) = (20 * 3) = 60.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((-12 * -27) * (8 * 60)) = (324 * (8 * 60)) = (324 * 480) = 155520.\n(Final response) So the answer is 155520.", "correct_answer": "155520", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 402, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-9 - -2 - -1 * 0 * -4 - 9) * (3 + 0 * 5 + 4 * -1 - -2)) + ((-3 - -6 + 7 + -8 + 1 - 1) + (-4 * -1 - -9 + 3 - -6 * 8))) - (((7 - 1 + 6 * 1 * -6 - 5) - (3 - 6 + 1 - -8 + 1 + -1)) + ((5 - 3 * 8 * 9 * -4 - 9) - (2 * 2 * -9 - -3 * 6 + 1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C + D)) - ((E - F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (-9 - -2 - -1 * 0 * -4 - 9), B = (3 + 0 * 5 + 4 * -1 - -2), C = (-3 - -6 + 7 + -8 + 1 - 1), D = (-4 * -1 - -9 + 3 - -6 * 8), E = (7 - 1 + 6 * 1 * -6 - 5), F = (3 - 6 + 1 - -8 + 1 + -1), G = (5 - 3 * 8 * 9 * -4 - 9) and H = (2 * 2 * -9 - -3 * 6 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - -2 - -1 * 0 * -4 - 9) = (((-9 - -2) - ((-1 * 0) * -4)) - 9) = ((-7 - ((-1 * 0) * -4)) - 9) = ((-7 - (0 * -4)) - 9) = ((-7 - 0) - 9) = (-7 - 9) = -16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + 0 * 5 + 4 * -1 - -2) = (((3 + (0 * 5)) + (4 * -1)) - -2) = (((3 + 0) + (4 * -1)) - -2) = (((3 + 0) + -4) - -2) = ((3 + -4) - -2) = (-1 - -2) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - -6 + 7 + -8 + 1 - 1) = (((((-3 - -6) + 7) + -8) + 1) - 1) = ((((3 + 7) + -8) + 1) - 1) = (((10 + -8) + 1) - 1) = ((2 + 1) - 1) = (3 - 1) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * -1 - -9 + 3 - -6 * 8) = ((((-4 * -1) - -9) + 3) - (-6 * 8)) = (((4 - -9) + 3) - (-6 * 8)) = (((4 - -9) + 3) - -48) = ((13 + 3) - -48) = (16 - -48) = 64.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (7 - 1 + 6 * 1 * -6 - 5) = (((7 - 1) + ((6 * 1) * -6)) - 5) = ((6 + ((6 * 1) * -6)) - 5) = ((6 + (6 * -6)) - 5) = ((6 + -36) - 5) = (-30 - 5) = -35.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (3 - 6 + 1 - -8 + 1 + -1) = (((((3 - 6) + 1) - -8) + 1) + -1) = ((((-3 + 1) - -8) + 1) + -1) = (((-2 - -8) + 1) + -1) = ((6 + 1) + -1) = (7 + -1) = 6.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (5 - 3 * 8 * 9 * -4 - 9) = ((5 - (((3 * 8) * 9) * -4)) - 9) = ((5 - ((24 * 9) * -4)) - 9) = ((5 - (216 * -4)) - 9) = ((5 - -864) - 9) = (869 - 9) = 860.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (2 * 2 * -9 - -3 * 6 + 1) = ((((2 * 2) * -9) - (-3 * 6)) + 1) = (((4 * -9) - (-3 * 6)) + 1) = (((4 * -9) - -18) + 1) = ((-36 - -18) + 1) = (-18 + 1) = -17.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C + D)) - ((E - F) + (G - H))) = (((-16 * 1) + (2 + 64)) - ((-35 - 6) + (860 - -17))) = ((-16 + (2 + 64)) - ((-35 - 6) + (860 - -17))) = ((-16 + 66) - ((-35 - 6) + (860 - -17))) = ((-16 + 66) - (-41 + (860 - -17))) = ((-16 + 66) - (-41 + 877)) = (50 - (-41 + 877)) = (50 - 836) = -786.\n(Final response) So the answer is -786.", "correct_answer": "-786", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 348, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 + 1 * -7 - 9) * (3 * 5 * -3 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-6 + 1 * -7 - 9) and B = (3 * 5 * -3 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 1 * -7 - 9) = ((-6 + (1 * -7)) - 9) = ((-6 + -7) - 9) = (-13 - 9) = -22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 5 * -3 - -2) = (((3 * 5) * -3) - -2) = ((15 * -3) - -2) = (-45 - -2) = -43.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-22 * -43) = 946.\n(Final response) So the answer is 946.", "correct_answer": "946", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 176, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 - -6 * -4) + (1 + -1 * -1)) + ((2 * 7 + 2) + (8 - 8 - -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (9 - -6 * -4), B = (1 + -1 * -1), C = (2 * 7 + 2) and D = (8 - 8 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - -6 * -4) = (9 - (-6 * -4)) = (9 - 24) = -15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + -1 * -1) = (1 + (-1 * -1)) = (1 + 1) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 * 7 + 2) = ((2 * 7) + 2) = (14 + 2) = 16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - 8 - -2) = ((8 - 8) - -2) = (0 - -2) = 2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((-15 + 2) + (16 + 2)) = (-13 + (16 + 2)) = (-13 + 18) = 5.\n(Final response) So the answer is 5.", "correct_answer": "5", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 125, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 * -4 + 0 * -3) - (0 + 5 - -8 + 5)) + ((8 + -6 - 9 - 3) + (0 - -4 + 1 - 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (6 * -4 + 0 * -3), B = (0 + 5 - -8 + 5), C = (8 + -6 - 9 - 3) and D = (0 - -4 + 1 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * -4 + 0 * -3) = ((6 * -4) + (0 * -3)) = (-24 + (0 * -3)) = (-24 + 0) = -24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + 5 - -8 + 5) = (((0 + 5) - -8) + 5) = ((5 - -8) + 5) = (13 + 5) = 18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 + -6 - 9 - 3) = (((8 + -6) - 9) - 3) = ((2 - 9) - 3) = (-7 - 3) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 - -4 + 1 - 5) = (((0 - -4) + 1) - 5) = ((4 + 1) - 5) = (5 - 5) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-24 - 18) + (-10 + 0)) = (-42 + (-10 + 0)) = (-42 + -10) = -52.\n(Final response) So the answer is -52.", "correct_answer": "-52", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 160, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 - -6 + 1 - -8) - (6 * 6 * -3 * 2)) - ((6 - 6 * 3 + -9) + (4 * -8 + 8 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (5 - -6 + 1 - -8), B = (6 * 6 * -3 * 2), C = (6 - 6 * 3 + -9) and D = (4 * -8 + 8 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - -6 + 1 - -8) = (((5 - -6) + 1) - -8) = ((11 + 1) - -8) = (12 - -8) = 20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * 6 * -3 * 2) = (((6 * 6) * -3) * 2) = ((36 * -3) * 2) = (-108 * 2) = -216.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 6 * 3 + -9) = ((6 - (6 * 3)) + -9) = ((6 - 18) + -9) = (-12 + -9) = -21.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * -8 + 8 * 4) = ((4 * -8) + (8 * 4)) = (-32 + (8 * 4)) = (-32 + 32) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((20 - -216) - (-21 + 0)) = (236 - (-21 + 0)) = (236 - -21) = 257.\n(Final response) So the answer is 257.", "correct_answer": "257", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 481, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 * -3 + 0 * 5 * 6) - (2 - 3 + -6 - -2 + 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (4 * -3 + 0 * 5 * 6) and B = (2 - 3 + -6 - -2 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * -3 + 0 * 5 * 6) = ((4 * -3) + ((0 * 5) * 6)) = (-12 + ((0 * 5) * 6)) = (-12 + (0 * 6)) = (-12 + 0) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - 3 + -6 - -2 + 9) = ((((2 - 3) + -6) - -2) + 9) = (((-1 + -6) - -2) + 9) = ((-7 - -2) + 9) = (-5 + 9) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-12 - 4) = -16.\n(Final response) So the answer is -16.", "correct_answer": "-16", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 69, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-2 * -4 * -3) - (3 + -5 - 0)) * ((0 + 6 - -7) + (-9 + -7 - 9))) + (((-2 - 9 + -5) - (-4 - -3 * 0)) - ((9 * -1 * -9) + (8 - 5 - 7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C + D)) + ((E - F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (-2 * -4 * -3), B = (3 + -5 - 0), C = (0 + 6 - -7), D = (-9 + -7 - 9), E = (-2 - 9 + -5), F = (-4 - -3 * 0), G = (9 * -1 * -9) and H = (8 - 5 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * -4 * -3) = ((-2 * -4) * -3) = (8 * -3) = -24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + -5 - 0) = ((3 + -5) - 0) = (-2 - 0) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 + 6 - -7) = ((0 + 6) - -7) = (6 - -7) = 13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 + -7 - 9) = ((-9 + -7) - 9) = (-16 - 9) = -25.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-2 - 9 + -5) = ((-2 - 9) + -5) = (-11 + -5) = -16.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-4 - -3 * 0) = (-4 - (-3 * 0)) = (-4 - 0) = -4.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (9 * -1 * -9) = ((9 * -1) * -9) = (-9 * -9) = 81.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 - 5 - 7) = ((8 - 5) - 7) = (3 - 7) = -4.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C + D)) + ((E - F) - (G + H))) = (((-24 - -2) * (13 + -25)) + ((-16 - -4) - (81 + -4))) = ((-22 * (13 + -25)) + ((-16 - -4) - (81 + -4))) = ((-22 * -12) + ((-16 - -4) - (81 + -4))) = ((-22 * -12) + (-12 - (81 + -4))) = ((-22 * -12) + (-12 - 77)) = (264 + (-12 - 77)) = (264 + -89) = 175.\n(Final response) So the answer is 175.", "correct_answer": "175", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 244, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 * -9 + 2 + -8) + (-6 * -6 + -3 - 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-4 * -9 + 2 + -8) and B = (-6 * -6 + -3 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -9 + 2 + -8) = (((-4 * -9) + 2) + -8) = ((36 + 2) + -8) = (38 + -8) = 30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * -6 + -3 - 8) = (((-6 * -6) + -3) - 8) = ((36 + -3) - 8) = (33 - 8) = 25.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (30 + 25) = 55.\n(Final response) So the answer is 55.", "correct_answer": "55", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 297, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 - 4 - -8) - (-1 * -2 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-7 - 4 - -8) and B = (-1 * -2 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - 4 - -8) = ((-7 - 4) - -8) = (-11 - -8) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * -2 - -4) = ((-1 * -2) - -4) = (2 - -4) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-3 - 6) = -9.\n(Final response) So the answer is -9.", "correct_answer": "-9", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 25, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 + -9 * 7 - -9 + -5) + (3 + 6 - 7 + -6 * 7)) - ((6 * -8 * 1 + -6 + 5) + (-1 * -7 - 4 - 3 + 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C + D))\", where A = (8 + -9 * 7 - -9 + -5), B = (3 + 6 - 7 + -6 * 7), C = (6 * -8 * 1 + -6 + 5) and D = (-1 * -7 - 4 - 3 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + -9 * 7 - -9 + -5) = (((8 + (-9 * 7)) - -9) + -5) = (((8 + -63) - -9) + -5) = ((-55 - -9) + -5) = (-46 + -5) = -51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + 6 - 7 + -6 * 7) = (((3 + 6) - 7) + (-6 * 7)) = ((9 - 7) + (-6 * 7)) = ((9 - 7) + -42) = (2 + -42) = -40.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 * -8 * 1 + -6 + 5) = ((((6 * -8) * 1) + -6) + 5) = (((-48 * 1) + -6) + 5) = ((-48 + -6) + 5) = (-54 + 5) = -49.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * -7 - 4 - 3 + 9) = ((((-1 * -7) - 4) - 3) + 9) = (((7 - 4) - 3) + 9) = ((3 - 3) + 9) = (0 + 9) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C + D)) = ((-51 + -40) - (-49 + 9)) = (-91 - (-49 + 9)) = (-91 - -40) = -51.\n(Final response) So the answer is -51.", "correct_answer": "-51", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 209, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * 6 - 6) + (-1 - -8 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (9 * 6 - 6) and B = (-1 - -8 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 6 - 6) = ((9 * 6) - 6) = (54 - 6) = 48.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - -8 - -4) = ((-1 - -8) - -4) = (7 - -4) = 11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (48 + 11) = 59.\n(Final response) So the answer is 59.", "correct_answer": "59", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 20, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 * -3 - -2) * (-1 - -5 + 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-1 * -3 - -2) and B = (-1 - -5 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * -3 - -2) = ((-1 * -3) - -2) = (3 - -2) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - -5 + 9) = ((-1 - -5) + 9) = (4 + 9) = 13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (5 * 13) = 65.\n(Final response) So the answer is 65.", "correct_answer": "65", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 14, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 * 7 * -8) * (8 - 2 + 1)) + ((-3 + -9 + -5) - (3 * -2 - 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-6 * 7 * -8), B = (8 - 2 + 1), C = (-3 + -9 + -5) and D = (3 * -2 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * 7 * -8) = ((-6 * 7) * -8) = (-42 * -8) = 336.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 2 + 1) = ((8 - 2) + 1) = (6 + 1) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -9 + -5) = ((-3 + -9) + -5) = (-12 + -5) = -17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * -2 - 5) = ((3 * -2) - 5) = (-6 - 5) = -11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((336 * 7) + (-17 - -11)) = (2352 + (-17 - -11)) = (2352 + -6) = 2346.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2346.", "correct_answer": "2346", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 128, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 * 4 - 1 + 6 + 6 + 7) * (0 + 8 - 0 * -9 - -7 * -4)) + ((2 * 7 * -1 - -4 * -4 * 1) * (3 + -3 - -8 * -6 + -9 + 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-4 * 4 - 1 + 6 + 6 + 7), B = (0 + 8 - 0 * -9 - -7 * -4), C = (2 * 7 * -1 - -4 * -4 * 1) and D = (3 + -3 - -8 * -6 + -9 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * 4 - 1 + 6 + 6 + 7) = (((((-4 * 4) - 1) + 6) + 6) + 7) = ((((-16 - 1) + 6) + 6) + 7) = (((-17 + 6) + 6) + 7) = ((-11 + 6) + 7) = (-5 + 7) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + 8 - 0 * -9 - -7 * -4) = (((0 + 8) - (0 * -9)) - (-7 * -4)) = ((8 - (0 * -9)) - (-7 * -4)) = ((8 - 0) - (-7 * -4)) = ((8 - 0) - 28) = (8 - 28) = -20.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 * 7 * -1 - -4 * -4 * 1) = (((2 * 7) * -1) - ((-4 * -4) * 1)) = ((14 * -1) - ((-4 * -4) * 1)) = ((14 * -1) - (16 * 1)) = (-14 - (16 * 1)) = (-14 - 16) = -30.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + -3 - -8 * -6 + -9 + 7) = ((((3 + -3) - (-8 * -6)) + -9) + 7) = (((0 - (-8 * -6)) + -9) + 7) = (((0 - 48) + -9) + 7) = ((-48 + -9) + 7) = (-57 + 7) = -50.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((2 * -20) + (-30 * -50)) = (-40 + (-30 * -50)) = (-40 + 1500) = 1460.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1460.", "correct_answer": "1460", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 232, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 * 7 * -4) + (-7 - -5 + -9)) + ((-7 - 9 + 2) * (1 + 6 - 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (0 * 7 * -4), B = (-7 - -5 + -9), C = (-7 - 9 + 2) and D = (1 + 6 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * 7 * -4) = ((0 * 7) * -4) = (0 * -4) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -5 + -9) = ((-7 - -5) + -9) = (-2 + -9) = -11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - 9 + 2) = ((-7 - 9) + 2) = (-16 + 2) = -14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + 6 - 4) = ((1 + 6) - 4) = (7 - 4) = 3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((0 + -11) + (-14 * 3)) = (-11 + (-14 * 3)) = (-11 + -42) = -53.\n(Final response) So the answer is -53.", "correct_answer": "-53", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 431, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((3 + 3 + -9) - (-4 + 8 * 6)) * ((-2 - 3 + 3) - (-4 - 8 * 3))) * (((5 - 1 - 3) - (-8 + -5 * 0)) - ((2 - -1 - -6) - (-4 * 9 - 9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C - D)) * ((E - F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (3 + 3 + -9), B = (-4 + 8 * 6), C = (-2 - 3 + 3), D = (-4 - 8 * 3), E = (5 - 1 - 3), F = (-8 + -5 * 0), G = (2 - -1 - -6) and H = (-4 * 9 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + 3 + -9) = ((3 + 3) + -9) = (6 + -9) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 8 * 6) = (-4 + (8 * 6)) = (-4 + 48) = 44.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 - 3 + 3) = ((-2 - 3) + 3) = (-5 + 3) = -2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - 8 * 3) = (-4 - (8 * 3)) = (-4 - 24) = -28.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (5 - 1 - 3) = ((5 - 1) - 3) = (4 - 3) = 1.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-8 + -5 * 0) = (-8 + (-5 * 0)) = (-8 + 0) = -8.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (2 - -1 - -6) = ((2 - -1) - -6) = (3 - -6) = 9.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-4 * 9 - 9) = ((-4 * 9) - 9) = (-36 - 9) = -45.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C - D)) * ((E - F) - (G - H))) = (((-3 - 44) * (-2 - -28)) * ((1 - -8) - (9 - -45))) = ((-47 * (-2 - -28)) * ((1 - -8) - (9 - -45))) = ((-47 * 26) * ((1 - -8) - (9 - -45))) = ((-47 * 26) * (9 - (9 - -45))) = ((-47 * 26) * (9 - 54)) = (-1222 * (9 - 54)) = (-1222 * -45) = 54990.\n(Final response) So the answer is 54990.", "correct_answer": "54990", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 258, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 - 4 - 8 - -4) + (4 + 1 + 0 + 2)) - ((-9 * 8 - -9 + -9) - (2 * -6 + -6 - 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-7 - 4 - 8 - -4), B = (4 + 1 + 0 + 2), C = (-9 * 8 - -9 + -9) and D = (2 * -6 + -6 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - 4 - 8 - -4) = (((-7 - 4) - 8) - -4) = ((-11 - 8) - -4) = (-19 - -4) = -15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 1 + 0 + 2) = (((4 + 1) + 0) + 2) = ((5 + 0) + 2) = (5 + 2) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * 8 - -9 + -9) = (((-9 * 8) - -9) + -9) = ((-72 - -9) + -9) = (-63 + -9) = -72.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * -6 + -6 - 5) = (((2 * -6) + -6) - 5) = ((-12 + -6) - 5) = (-18 - 5) = -23.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((-15 + 7) - (-72 - -23)) = (-8 - (-72 - -23)) = (-8 - -49) = 41.\n(Final response) So the answer is 41.", "correct_answer": "41", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 460, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * 1 * 2 * 7) * (9 * 6 + 7 * 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 * 1 * 2 * 7) and B = (9 * 6 + 7 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 1 * 2 * 7) = (((5 * 1) * 2) * 7) = ((5 * 2) * 7) = (10 * 7) = 70.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 6 + 7 * 1) = ((9 * 6) + (7 * 1)) = (54 + (7 * 1)) = (54 + 7) = 61.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (70 * 61) = 4270.\n(Final response) So the answer is 4270.", "correct_answer": "4270", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 260, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 + 8 - 0) - (-7 + -7 + -5)) * ((-7 + -7 * -6) * (-8 - -5 * -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (5 + 8 - 0), B = (-7 + -7 + -5), C = (-7 + -7 * -6) and D = (-8 - -5 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 8 - 0) = ((5 + 8) - 0) = (13 - 0) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -7 + -5) = ((-7 + -7) + -5) = (-14 + -5) = -19.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + -7 * -6) = (-7 + (-7 * -6)) = (-7 + 42) = 35.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - -5 * -8) = (-8 - (-5 * -8)) = (-8 - 40) = -48.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((13 - -19) * (35 * -48)) = (32 * (35 * -48)) = (32 * -1680) = -53760.\n(Final response) So the answer is -53760.", "correct_answer": "-53760", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 328, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 + -1 + 4 + -1) + (6 * -3 - -8 - 8)) + ((1 - 4 * -8 + 4) * (-1 + -3 * 7 - 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-1 + -1 + 4 + -1), B = (6 * -3 - -8 - 8), C = (1 - 4 * -8 + 4) and D = (-1 + -3 * 7 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + -1 + 4 + -1) = (((-1 + -1) + 4) + -1) = ((-2 + 4) + -1) = (2 + -1) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -3 - -8 - 8) = (((6 * -3) - -8) - 8) = ((-18 - -8) - 8) = (-10 - 8) = -18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - 4 * -8 + 4) = ((1 - (4 * -8)) + 4) = ((1 - -32) + 4) = (33 + 4) = 37.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 + -3 * 7 - 3) = ((-1 + (-3 * 7)) - 3) = ((-1 + -21) - 3) = (-22 - 3) = -25.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((1 + -18) + (37 * -25)) = (-17 + (37 * -25)) = (-17 + -925) = -942.\n(Final response) So the answer is -942.", "correct_answer": "-942", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 472, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - 5 - 3 - -3) + (6 * -1 - 4 + -3)) * ((4 * 1 + 3 - -3) + (6 + 3 - 1 - -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-9 - 5 - 3 - -3), B = (6 * -1 - 4 + -3), C = (4 * 1 + 3 - -3) and D = (6 + 3 - 1 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 5 - 3 - -3) = (((-9 - 5) - 3) - -3) = ((-14 - 3) - -3) = (-17 - -3) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -1 - 4 + -3) = (((6 * -1) - 4) + -3) = ((-6 - 4) + -3) = (-10 + -3) = -13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 * 1 + 3 - -3) = (((4 * 1) + 3) - -3) = ((4 + 3) - -3) = (7 - -3) = 10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + 3 - 1 - -5) = (((6 + 3) - 1) - -5) = ((9 - 1) - -5) = (8 - -5) = 13.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-14 + -13) * (10 + 13)) = (-27 * (10 + 13)) = (-27 * 23) = -621.\n(Final response) So the answer is -621.", "correct_answer": "-621", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 458, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 - -2 * -2) + (5 * 4 * 7)) - ((-5 - 9 - 0) * (-8 - -7 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (9 - -2 * -2), B = (5 * 4 * 7), C = (-5 - 9 - 0) and D = (-8 - -7 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - -2 * -2) = (9 - (-2 * -2)) = (9 - 4) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * 4 * 7) = ((5 * 4) * 7) = (20 * 7) = 140.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - 9 - 0) = ((-5 - 9) - 0) = (-14 - 0) = -14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - -7 * -5) = (-8 - (-7 * -5)) = (-8 - 35) = -43.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((5 + 140) - (-14 * -43)) = (145 - (-14 * -43)) = (145 - 602) = -457.\n(Final response) So the answer is -457.", "correct_answer": "-457", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 395, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * -8 - 6) + (-2 + -9 + -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-9 * -8 - 6) and B = (-2 + -9 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * -8 - 6) = ((-9 * -8) - 6) = (72 - 6) = 66.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + -9 + -3) = ((-2 + -9) + -3) = (-11 + -3) = -14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (66 + -14) = 52.\n(Final response) So the answer is 52.", "correct_answer": "52", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 35, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 * -1 + -9 - -7) + (5 - 0 * -4 + 9)) - ((7 + -7 - -6 - -4) - (5 * 7 * -5 + -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-3 * -1 + -9 - -7), B = (5 - 0 * -4 + 9), C = (7 + -7 - -6 - -4) and D = (5 * 7 * -5 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * -1 + -9 - -7) = (((-3 * -1) + -9) - -7) = ((3 + -9) - -7) = (-6 - -7) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 0 * -4 + 9) = ((5 - (0 * -4)) + 9) = ((5 - 0) + 9) = (5 + 9) = 14.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + -7 - -6 - -4) = (((7 + -7) - -6) - -4) = ((0 - -6) - -4) = (6 - -4) = 10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 * 7 * -5 + -4) = (((5 * 7) * -5) + -4) = ((35 * -5) + -4) = (-175 + -4) = -179.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((1 + 14) - (10 - -179)) = (15 - (10 - -179)) = (15 - 189) = -174.\n(Final response) So the answer is -174.", "correct_answer": "-174", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 489, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 - 3 * -5 + -1 - 1 - 7) - (1 + -9 - 8 * -5 * 6 - -1)) - ((-5 * 7 - 9 - -2 * 3 + -1) + (8 + 4 - 6 + 3 + 8 * -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (4 - 3 * -5 + -1 - 1 - 7), B = (1 + -9 - 8 * -5 * 6 - -1), C = (-5 * 7 - 9 - -2 * 3 + -1) and D = (8 + 4 - 6 + 3 + 8 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - 3 * -5 + -1 - 1 - 7) = ((((4 - (3 * -5)) + -1) - 1) - 7) = ((((4 - -15) + -1) - 1) - 7) = (((19 + -1) - 1) - 7) = ((18 - 1) - 7) = (17 - 7) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + -9 - 8 * -5 * 6 - -1) = (((1 + -9) - ((8 * -5) * 6)) - -1) = ((-8 - ((8 * -5) * 6)) - -1) = ((-8 - (-40 * 6)) - -1) = ((-8 - -240) - -1) = (232 - -1) = 233.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * 7 - 9 - -2 * 3 + -1) = ((((-5 * 7) - 9) - (-2 * 3)) + -1) = (((-35 - 9) - (-2 * 3)) + -1) = (((-35 - 9) - -6) + -1) = ((-44 - -6) + -1) = (-38 + -1) = -39.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 + 4 - 6 + 3 + 8 * -9) = ((((8 + 4) - 6) + 3) + (8 * -9)) = (((12 - 6) + 3) + (8 * -9)) = (((12 - 6) + 3) + -72) = ((6 + 3) + -72) = (9 + -72) = -63.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((10 - 233) - (-39 + -63)) = (-223 - (-39 + -63)) = (-223 - -102) = -121.\n(Final response) So the answer is -121.", "correct_answer": "-121", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 218, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 - 3 - -5 * -5) - (0 * -3 - 5 * 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 - 3 - -5 * -5) and B = (0 * -3 - 5 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - 3 - -5 * -5) = ((-1 - 3) - (-5 * -5)) = (-4 - (-5 * -5)) = (-4 - 25) = -29.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * -3 - 5 * 5) = ((0 * -3) - (5 * 5)) = (0 - (5 * 5)) = (0 - 25) = -25.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-29 - -25) = -4.\n(Final response) So the answer is -4.", "correct_answer": "-4", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 34, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 * 9 * -6 + -9) * (0 * 3 * 4 * -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (3 * 9 * -6 + -9) and B = (0 * 3 * 4 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 9 * -6 + -9) = (((3 * 9) * -6) + -9) = ((27 * -6) + -9) = (-162 + -9) = -171.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 3 * 4 * -5) = (((0 * 3) * 4) * -5) = ((0 * 4) * -5) = (0 * -5) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-171 * 0) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 204, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + -2 + -3) + (3 - 9 * 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-1 + -2 + -3) and B = (3 - 9 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + -2 + -3) = ((-1 + -2) + -3) = (-3 + -3) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - 9 * 9) = (3 - (9 * 9)) = (3 - 81) = -78.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-6 + -78) = -84.\n(Final response) So the answer is -84.", "correct_answer": "-84", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 98, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 - 8 + 8) * (1 * 9 + -4)) + ((0 + 4 * 2) * (0 * -1 * -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (9 - 8 + 8), B = (1 * 9 + -4), C = (0 + 4 * 2) and D = (0 * -1 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - 8 + 8) = ((9 - 8) + 8) = (1 + 8) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 9 + -4) = ((1 * 9) + -4) = (9 + -4) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 + 4 * 2) = (0 + (4 * 2)) = (0 + 8) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 * -1 * -8) = ((0 * -1) * -8) = (0 * -8) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((9 * 5) + (8 * 0)) = (45 + (8 * 0)) = (45 + 0) = 45.\n(Final response) So the answer is 45.", "correct_answer": "45", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 337, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 * 0 + 6 * -6 + -4) - (-6 * 2 - 2 + 9 + 9)) - ((-9 + -2 - 4 - -2 + -9) + (-3 - 0 * 2 + -9 + -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (0 * 0 + 6 * -6 + -4), B = (-6 * 2 - 2 + 9 + 9), C = (-9 + -2 - 4 - -2 + -9) and D = (-3 - 0 * 2 + -9 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * 0 + 6 * -6 + -4) = (((0 * 0) + (6 * -6)) + -4) = ((0 + (6 * -6)) + -4) = ((0 + -36) + -4) = (-36 + -4) = -40.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 2 - 2 + 9 + 9) = ((((-6 * 2) - 2) + 9) + 9) = (((-12 - 2) + 9) + 9) = ((-14 + 9) + 9) = (-5 + 9) = 4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + -2 - 4 - -2 + -9) = ((((-9 + -2) - 4) - -2) + -9) = (((-11 - 4) - -2) + -9) = ((-15 - -2) + -9) = (-13 + -9) = -22.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 - 0 * 2 + -9 + -4) = (((-3 - (0 * 2)) + -9) + -4) = (((-3 - 0) + -9) + -4) = ((-3 + -9) + -4) = (-12 + -4) = -16.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-40 - 4) - (-22 + -16)) = (-44 - (-22 + -16)) = (-44 - -38) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 203, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + 0 - 0 + 6 + 7 - 4) * (7 - -2 + -1 + 7 * -3 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-1 + 0 - 0 + 6 + 7 - 4) and B = (7 - -2 + -1 + 7 * -3 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + 0 - 0 + 6 + 7 - 4) = (((((-1 + 0) - 0) + 6) + 7) - 4) = ((((-1 - 0) + 6) + 7) - 4) = (((-1 + 6) + 7) - 4) = ((5 + 7) - 4) = (12 - 4) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - -2 + -1 + 7 * -3 + -9) = ((((7 - -2) + -1) + (7 * -3)) + -9) = (((9 + -1) + (7 * -3)) + -9) = (((9 + -1) + -21) + -9) = ((8 + -21) + -9) = (-13 + -9) = -22.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (8 * -22) = -176.\n(Final response) So the answer is -176.", "correct_answer": "-176", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 113, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 * -2 * 7) * (-5 - 6 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (6 * -2 * 7) and B = (-5 - 6 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * -2 * 7) = ((6 * -2) * 7) = (-12 * 7) = -84.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - 6 - -2) = ((-5 - 6) - -2) = (-11 - -2) = -9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-84 * -9) = 756.\n(Final response) So the answer is 756.", "correct_answer": "756", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 116, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 + -7 * 7 - 9 - 2) + (2 * -8 * 6 - 2 - -9)) - ((-1 * -5 + 0 * 0 + 8) * (8 + 1 - -1 * 4 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (9 + -7 * 7 - 9 - 2), B = (2 * -8 * 6 - 2 - -9), C = (-1 * -5 + 0 * 0 + 8) and D = (8 + 1 - -1 * 4 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + -7 * 7 - 9 - 2) = (((9 + (-7 * 7)) - 9) - 2) = (((9 + -49) - 9) - 2) = ((-40 - 9) - 2) = (-49 - 2) = -51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * -8 * 6 - 2 - -9) = ((((2 * -8) * 6) - 2) - -9) = (((-16 * 6) - 2) - -9) = ((-96 - 2) - -9) = (-98 - -9) = -89.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * -5 + 0 * 0 + 8) = (((-1 * -5) + (0 * 0)) + 8) = ((5 + (0 * 0)) + 8) = ((5 + 0) + 8) = (5 + 8) = 13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 + 1 - -1 * 4 * 4) = ((8 + 1) - ((-1 * 4) * 4)) = (9 - ((-1 * 4) * 4)) = (9 - (-4 * 4)) = (9 - -16) = 25.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-51 + -89) - (13 * 25)) = (-140 - (13 * 25)) = (-140 - 325) = -465.\n(Final response) So the answer is -465.", "correct_answer": "-465", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 188, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - 5 - 4) * (-6 - -5 * 7)) + ((-4 - -5 * 7) + (-4 - -9 - 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-9 - 5 - 4), B = (-6 - -5 * 7), C = (-4 - -5 * 7) and D = (-4 - -9 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 5 - 4) = ((-9 - 5) - 4) = (-14 - 4) = -18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - -5 * 7) = (-6 - (-5 * 7)) = (-6 - -35) = 29.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - -5 * 7) = (-4 - (-5 * 7)) = (-4 - -35) = 31.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -9 - 0) = ((-4 - -9) - 0) = (5 - 0) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((-18 * 29) + (31 + 5)) = (-522 + (31 + 5)) = (-522 + 36) = -486.\n(Final response) So the answer is -486.", "correct_answer": "-486", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 407, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 + 8 + -2 * 7 + 1) * (-8 - 4 * 2 + -8 - 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 + 8 + -2 * 7 + 1) and B = (-8 - 4 * 2 + -8 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 8 + -2 * 7 + 1) = (((-7 + 8) + (-2 * 7)) + 1) = ((1 + (-2 * 7)) + 1) = ((1 + -14) + 1) = (-13 + 1) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 4 * 2 + -8 - 5) = (((-8 - (4 * 2)) + -8) - 5) = (((-8 - 8) + -8) - 5) = ((-16 + -8) - 5) = (-24 - 5) = -29.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-12 * -29) = 348.\n(Final response) So the answer is 348.", "correct_answer": "348", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 70, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 * -2 - -5 + -7) - (0 - 3 * 2 * 4)) * ((0 + 2 * 3 - -4) + (9 + -3 - -5 + 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (9 * -2 - -5 + -7), B = (0 - 3 * 2 * 4), C = (0 + 2 * 3 - -4) and D = (9 + -3 - -5 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * -2 - -5 + -7) = (((9 * -2) - -5) + -7) = ((-18 - -5) + -7) = (-13 + -7) = -20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 3 * 2 * 4) = (0 - ((3 * 2) * 4)) = (0 - (6 * 4)) = (0 - 24) = -24.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 + 2 * 3 - -4) = ((0 + (2 * 3)) - -4) = ((0 + 6) - -4) = (6 - -4) = 10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -3 - -5 + 8) = (((9 + -3) - -5) + 8) = ((6 - -5) + 8) = (11 + 8) = 19.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((-20 - -24) * (10 + 19)) = (4 * (10 + 19)) = (4 * 29) = 116.\n(Final response) So the answer is 116.", "correct_answer": "116", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 155, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 * -8 + 7 * 3) + (-1 + -4 + 0 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 * -8 + 7 * 3) and B = (-1 + -4 + 0 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * -8 + 7 * 3) = ((-6 * -8) + (7 * 3)) = (48 + (7 * 3)) = (48 + 21) = 69.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -4 + 0 * -3) = ((-1 + -4) + (0 * -3)) = (-5 + (0 * -3)) = (-5 + 0) = -5.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (69 + -5) = 64.\n(Final response) So the answer is 64.", "correct_answer": "64", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 179, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 + 4 * 4 - -9 * -2 + -8) + (3 + 0 + -4 * 5 * -4 * -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 + 4 * 4 - -9 * -2 + -8) and B = (3 + 0 + -4 * 5 * -4 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 4 * 4 - -9 * -2 + -8) = (((-6 + (4 * 4)) - (-9 * -2)) + -8) = (((-6 + 16) - (-9 * -2)) + -8) = (((-6 + 16) - 18) + -8) = ((10 - 18) + -8) = (-8 + -8) = -16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + 0 + -4 * 5 * -4 * -5) = ((3 + 0) + (((-4 * 5) * -4) * -5)) = (3 + (((-4 * 5) * -4) * -5)) = (3 + ((-20 * -4) * -5)) = (3 + (80 * -5)) = (3 + -400) = -397.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-16 + -397) = -413.\n(Final response) So the answer is -413.", "correct_answer": "-413", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 103, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 * -9 * 3 * 0) - (-6 * -2 - 8 + 4)) + ((5 + 7 * 3 * -1) + (-7 + 1 - -5 - 8))) * (((-5 + 2 * -4 + 4) * (-9 * 3 - 0 * 9)) * ((7 * -2 * 6 + 3) - (-1 + 8 - 0 + 2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C + D)) * ((E * F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (2 * -9 * 3 * 0), B = (-6 * -2 - 8 + 4), C = (5 + 7 * 3 * -1), D = (-7 + 1 - -5 - 8), E = (-5 + 2 * -4 + 4), F = (-9 * 3 - 0 * 9), G = (7 * -2 * 6 + 3) and H = (-1 + 8 - 0 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * -9 * 3 * 0) = (((2 * -9) * 3) * 0) = ((-18 * 3) * 0) = (-54 * 0) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * -2 - 8 + 4) = (((-6 * -2) - 8) + 4) = ((12 - 8) + 4) = (4 + 4) = 8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 + 7 * 3 * -1) = (5 + ((7 * 3) * -1)) = (5 + (21 * -1)) = (5 + -21) = -16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + 1 - -5 - 8) = (((-7 + 1) - -5) - 8) = ((-6 - -5) - 8) = (-1 - 8) = -9.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-5 + 2 * -4 + 4) = ((-5 + (2 * -4)) + 4) = ((-5 + -8) + 4) = (-13 + 4) = -9.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-9 * 3 - 0 * 9) = ((-9 * 3) - (0 * 9)) = (-27 - (0 * 9)) = (-27 - 0) = -27.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 * -2 * 6 + 3) = (((7 * -2) * 6) + 3) = ((-14 * 6) + 3) = (-84 + 3) = -81.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-1 + 8 - 0 + 2) = (((-1 + 8) - 0) + 2) = ((7 - 0) + 2) = (7 + 2) = 9.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C + D)) * ((E * F) * (G - H))) = (((0 - 8) + (-16 + -9)) * ((-9 * -27) * (-81 - 9))) = ((-8 + (-16 + -9)) * ((-9 * -27) * (-81 - 9))) = ((-8 + -25) * ((-9 * -27) * (-81 - 9))) = ((-8 + -25) * (243 * (-81 - 9))) = ((-8 + -25) * (243 * -90)) = (-33 * (243 * -90)) = (-33 * -21870) = 721710.\n(Final response) So the answer is 721710.", "correct_answer": "721710", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 297, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 + -5 + 6) - (1 + -4 - 7)) + ((7 + -5 + -3) - (-4 - 3 - 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (5 + -5 + 6), B = (1 + -4 - 7), C = (7 + -5 + -3) and D = (-4 - 3 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + -5 + 6) = ((5 + -5) + 6) = (0 + 6) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + -4 - 7) = ((1 + -4) - 7) = (-3 - 7) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + -5 + -3) = ((7 + -5) + -3) = (2 + -3) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - 3 - 1) = ((-4 - 3) - 1) = (-7 - 1) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((6 - -10) + (-1 - -8)) = (16 + (-1 - -8)) = (16 + 7) = 23.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23.", "correct_answer": "23", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 418, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 + 8 * 9 * 0) - (-1 - -9 - -7 + -4)) - ((8 * -5 + -7 + -7) * (3 * 7 * -5 - 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-5 + 8 * 9 * 0), B = (-1 - -9 - -7 + -4), C = (8 * -5 + -7 + -7) and D = (3 * 7 * -5 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + 8 * 9 * 0) = (-5 + ((8 * 9) * 0)) = (-5 + (72 * 0)) = (-5 + 0) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - -9 - -7 + -4) = (((-1 - -9) - -7) + -4) = ((8 - -7) + -4) = (15 + -4) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -5 + -7 + -7) = (((8 * -5) + -7) + -7) = ((-40 + -7) + -7) = (-47 + -7) = -54.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * 7 * -5 - 4) = (((3 * 7) * -5) - 4) = ((21 * -5) - 4) = (-105 - 4) = -109.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((-5 - 11) - (-54 * -109)) = (-16 - (-54 * -109)) = (-16 - 5886) = -5902.\n(Final response) So the answer is -5902.", "correct_answer": "-5902", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 577, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 - -8 + -1) + (-2 + -9 + 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-1 - -8 + -1) and B = (-2 + -9 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - -8 + -1) = ((-1 - -8) + -1) = (7 + -1) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + -9 + 1) = ((-2 + -9) + 1) = (-11 + 1) = -10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (6 + -10) = -4.\n(Final response) So the answer is -4.", "correct_answer": "-4", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 113, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 * 4 - -9 * 8 * -4 - 3) + (-1 + 5 + 6 - 4 * -4 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 * 4 - -9 * 8 * -4 - 3) and B = (-1 + 5 + 6 - 4 * -4 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * 4 - -9 * 8 * -4 - 3) = (((-6 * 4) - ((-9 * 8) * -4)) - 3) = ((-24 - ((-9 * 8) * -4)) - 3) = ((-24 - (-72 * -4)) - 3) = ((-24 - 288) - 3) = (-312 - 3) = -315.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + 5 + 6 - 4 * -4 - -2) = ((((-1 + 5) + 6) - (4 * -4)) - -2) = (((4 + 6) - (4 * -4)) - -2) = (((4 + 6) - -16) - -2) = ((10 - -16) - -2) = (26 - -2) = 28.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-315 + 28) = -287.\n(Final response) So the answer is -287.", "correct_answer": "-287", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 102, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 + -4 + 8) * (1 * -1 * 7)) + ((7 * 9 + 7) * (8 * 5 + 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (3 + -4 + 8), B = (1 * -1 * 7), C = (7 * 9 + 7) and D = (8 * 5 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + -4 + 8) = ((3 + -4) + 8) = (-1 + 8) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -1 * 7) = ((1 * -1) * 7) = (-1 * 7) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 * 9 + 7) = ((7 * 9) + 7) = (63 + 7) = 70.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * 5 + 0) = ((8 * 5) + 0) = (40 + 0) = 40.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((7 * -7) + (70 * 40)) = (-49 + (70 * 40)) = (-49 + 2800) = 2751.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2751.", "correct_answer": "2751", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 439, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((4 * 5 * -4) + (4 + 6 + 2)) + ((1 - 1 - -4) * (-4 - -4 + 3))) + (((2 + -7 * -5) * (7 + -4 - -4)) - ((0 * 4 + 8) - (5 * 0 + 5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C * D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (4 * 5 * -4), B = (4 + 6 + 2), C = (1 - 1 - -4), D = (-4 - -4 + 3), E = (2 + -7 * -5), F = (7 + -4 - -4), G = (0 * 4 + 8) and H = (5 * 0 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 5 * -4) = ((4 * 5) * -4) = (20 * -4) = -80.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 6 + 2) = ((4 + 6) + 2) = (10 + 2) = 12.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - 1 - -4) = ((1 - 1) - -4) = (0 - -4) = 4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -4 + 3) = ((-4 - -4) + 3) = (0 + 3) = 3.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (2 + -7 * -5) = (2 + (-7 * -5)) = (2 + 35) = 37.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (7 + -4 - -4) = ((7 + -4) - -4) = (3 - -4) = 7.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (0 * 4 + 8) = ((0 * 4) + 8) = (0 + 8) = 8.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (5 * 0 + 5) = ((5 * 0) + 5) = (0 + 5) = 5.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C * D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H))) = (((-80 + 12) + (4 * 3)) + ((37 * 7) - (8 - 5))) = ((-68 + (4 * 3)) + ((37 * 7) - (8 - 5))) = ((-68 + 12) + ((37 * 7) - (8 - 5))) = ((-68 + 12) + (259 - (8 - 5))) = ((-68 + 12) + (259 - 3)) = (-56 + (259 - 3)) = (-56 + 256) = 200.\n(Final response) So the answer is 200.", "correct_answer": "200", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 252, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - -6 * 2) - (0 - 6 * -2)) * ((-2 + -4 * -2) + (0 + 1 + -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (1 - -6 * 2), B = (0 - 6 * -2), C = (-2 + -4 * -2) and D = (0 + 1 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -6 * 2) = (1 - (-6 * 2)) = (1 - -12) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 6 * -2) = (0 - (6 * -2)) = (0 - -12) = 12.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + -4 * -2) = (-2 + (-4 * -2)) = (-2 + 8) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + 1 + -7) = ((0 + 1) + -7) = (1 + -7) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((13 - 12) * (6 + -6)) = (1 * (6 + -6)) = (1 * 0) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 446, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 - 3 + 7 + -6) * (7 + -6 * -9 - -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-8 - 3 + 7 + -6) and B = (7 + -6 * -9 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 3 + 7 + -6) = (((-8 - 3) + 7) + -6) = ((-11 + 7) + -6) = (-4 + -6) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + -6 * -9 - -6) = ((7 + (-6 * -9)) - -6) = ((7 + 54) - -6) = (61 - -6) = 67.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-10 * 67) = -670.\n(Final response) So the answer is -670.", "correct_answer": "-670", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 195, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - -2 + 1 + 8 * 8) - (0 * -1 * 1 * 2 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 - -2 + 1 + 8 * 8) and B = (0 * -1 * 1 * 2 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -2 + 1 + 8 * 8) = (((1 - -2) + 1) + (8 * 8)) = ((3 + 1) + (8 * 8)) = ((3 + 1) + 64) = (4 + 64) = 68.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * -1 * 1 * 2 * -3) = ((((0 * -1) * 1) * 2) * -3) = (((0 * 1) * 2) * -3) = ((0 * 2) * -3) = (0 * -3) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (68 - 0) = 68.\n(Final response) So the answer is 68.", "correct_answer": "68", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 68, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 - 0 + 9) - (2 * -3 - 9)) * ((-3 - -3 - 0) + (-5 - -1 - 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-7 - 0 + 9), B = (2 * -3 - 9), C = (-3 - -3 - 0) and D = (-5 - -1 - 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - 0 + 9) = ((-7 - 0) + 9) = (-7 + 9) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * -3 - 9) = ((2 * -3) - 9) = (-6 - 9) = -15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - -3 - 0) = ((-3 - -3) - 0) = (0 - 0) = 0.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - -1 - 6) = ((-5 - -1) - 6) = (-4 - 6) = -10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((2 - -15) * (0 + -10)) = (17 * (0 + -10)) = (17 * -10) = -170.\n(Final response) So the answer is -170.", "correct_answer": "-170", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 359, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 + -1 - 2) - (4 * -3 - -2)) - ((4 - 8 - 8) + (-5 * 0 + 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (0 + -1 - 2), B = (4 * -3 - -2), C = (4 - 8 - 8) and D = (-5 * 0 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + -1 - 2) = ((0 + -1) - 2) = (-1 - 2) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * -3 - -2) = ((4 * -3) - -2) = (-12 - -2) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - 8 - 8) = ((4 - 8) - 8) = (-4 - 8) = -12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 * 0 + 3) = ((-5 * 0) + 3) = (0 + 3) = 3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-3 - -10) - (-12 + 3)) = (7 - (-12 + 3)) = (7 - -9) = 16.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16.", "correct_answer": "16", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 403, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-6 + 5 - 8 - -2) + (-8 - -8 + -1 + 0)) * ((3 + 2 + -1 - -2) - (0 * -9 + 0 + 8))) - (((9 + -4 + 4 - 6) + (-6 - -5 + 5 - 2)) - ((3 * -7 - -3 * -1) - (-7 * -9 + -1 - 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C - D)) - ((E + F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (-6 + 5 - 8 - -2), B = (-8 - -8 + -1 + 0), C = (3 + 2 + -1 - -2), D = (0 * -9 + 0 + 8), E = (9 + -4 + 4 - 6), F = (-6 - -5 + 5 - 2), G = (3 * -7 - -3 * -1) and H = (-7 * -9 + -1 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 5 - 8 - -2) = (((-6 + 5) - 8) - -2) = ((-1 - 8) - -2) = (-9 - -2) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - -8 + -1 + 0) = (((-8 - -8) + -1) + 0) = ((0 + -1) + 0) = (-1 + 0) = -1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + 2 + -1 - -2) = (((3 + 2) + -1) - -2) = ((5 + -1) - -2) = (4 - -2) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 * -9 + 0 + 8) = (((0 * -9) + 0) + 8) = ((0 + 0) + 8) = (0 + 8) = 8.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (9 + -4 + 4 - 6) = (((9 + -4) + 4) - 6) = ((5 + 4) - 6) = (9 - 6) = 3.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-6 - -5 + 5 - 2) = (((-6 - -5) + 5) - 2) = ((-1 + 5) - 2) = (4 - 2) = 2.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 * -7 - -3 * -1) = ((3 * -7) - (-3 * -1)) = (-21 - (-3 * -1)) = (-21 - 3) = -24.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-7 * -9 + -1 - 3) = (((-7 * -9) + -1) - 3) = ((63 + -1) - 3) = (62 - 3) = 59.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C - D)) - ((E + F) - (G - H))) = (((-7 + -1) * (6 - 8)) - ((3 + 2) - (-24 - 59))) = ((-8 * (6 - 8)) - ((3 + 2) - (-24 - 59))) = ((-8 * -2) - ((3 + 2) - (-24 - 59))) = ((-8 * -2) - (5 - (-24 - 59))) = ((-8 * -2) - (5 - -83)) = (16 - (5 - -83)) = (16 - 88) = -72.\n(Final response) So the answer is -72.", "correct_answer": "-72", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 276, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 + 2 * -8) + (4 * 7 + 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (3 + 2 * -8) and B = (4 * 7 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + 2 * -8) = (3 + (2 * -8)) = (3 + -16) = -13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 7 + 7) = ((4 * 7) + 7) = (28 + 7) = 35.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-13 + 35) = 22.\n(Final response) So the answer is 22.", "correct_answer": "22", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 136, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-9 + -7 + -3 - 2) + (-4 + 1 * 3 + 9)) - ((-5 - 3 + -5 * -7) + (0 + -4 - -1 + -5))) * (((-2 * 6 * -8 + 0) * (-6 + -8 * -4 * 4)) + ((7 - -9 - -6 - 0) - (7 + -5 * -6 * -1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) - (C + D)) * ((E * F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (-9 + -7 + -3 - 2), B = (-4 + 1 * 3 + 9), C = (-5 - 3 + -5 * -7), D = (0 + -4 - -1 + -5), E = (-2 * 6 * -8 + 0), F = (-6 + -8 * -4 * 4), G = (7 - -9 - -6 - 0) and H = (7 + -5 * -6 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -7 + -3 - 2) = (((-9 + -7) + -3) - 2) = ((-16 + -3) - 2) = (-19 - 2) = -21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 1 * 3 + 9) = ((-4 + (1 * 3)) + 9) = ((-4 + 3) + 9) = (-1 + 9) = 8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - 3 + -5 * -7) = ((-5 - 3) + (-5 * -7)) = (-8 + (-5 * -7)) = (-8 + 35) = 27.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + -4 - -1 + -5) = (((0 + -4) - -1) + -5) = ((-4 - -1) + -5) = (-3 + -5) = -8.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-2 * 6 * -8 + 0) = (((-2 * 6) * -8) + 0) = ((-12 * -8) + 0) = (96 + 0) = 96.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-6 + -8 * -4 * 4) = (-6 + ((-8 * -4) * 4)) = (-6 + (32 * 4)) = (-6 + 128) = 122.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 - -9 - -6 - 0) = (((7 - -9) - -6) - 0) = ((16 - -6) - 0) = (22 - 0) = 22.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (7 + -5 * -6 * -1) = (7 + ((-5 * -6) * -1)) = (7 + (30 * -1)) = (7 + -30) = -23.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) - (C + D)) * ((E * F) + (G - H))) = (((-21 + 8) - (27 + -8)) * ((96 * 122) + (22 - -23))) = ((-13 - (27 + -8)) * ((96 * 122) + (22 - -23))) = ((-13 - 19) * ((96 * 122) + (22 - -23))) = ((-13 - 19) * (11712 + (22 - -23))) = ((-13 - 19) * (11712 + 45)) = (-32 * (11712 + 45)) = (-32 * 11757) = -376224.\n(Final response) So the answer is -376224.", "correct_answer": "-376224", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 295, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 + 4 - 8 * -8) * (-3 * 3 * -4 + 8)) + ((-9 * 3 - 9 - 3) - (4 + 1 * -2 * -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-5 + 4 - 8 * -8), B = (-3 * 3 * -4 + 8), C = (-9 * 3 - 9 - 3) and D = (4 + 1 * -2 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + 4 - 8 * -8) = ((-5 + 4) - (8 * -8)) = (-1 - (8 * -8)) = (-1 - -64) = 63.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * 3 * -4 + 8) = (((-3 * 3) * -4) + 8) = ((-9 * -4) + 8) = (36 + 8) = 44.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * 3 - 9 - 3) = (((-9 * 3) - 9) - 3) = ((-27 - 9) - 3) = (-36 - 3) = -39.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + 1 * -2 * -3) = (4 + ((1 * -2) * -3)) = (4 + (-2 * -3)) = (4 + 6) = 10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((63 * 44) + (-39 - 10)) = (2772 + (-39 - 10)) = (2772 + -49) = 2723.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2723.", "correct_answer": "2723", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 503, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 * 7 - 6) * (4 + 6 + 2)) - ((-8 + 6 - 5) - (5 - 1 * -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (7 * 7 - 6), B = (4 + 6 + 2), C = (-8 + 6 - 5) and D = (5 - 1 * -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 7 - 6) = ((7 * 7) - 6) = (49 - 6) = 43.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 6 + 2) = ((4 + 6) + 2) = (10 + 2) = 12.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 + 6 - 5) = ((-8 + 6) - 5) = (-2 - 5) = -7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - 1 * -4) = (5 - (1 * -4)) = (5 - -4) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((43 * 12) - (-7 - 9)) = (516 - (-7 - 9)) = (516 - -16) = 532.\n(Final response) So the answer is 532.", "correct_answer": "532", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 376, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 - 7 * -3 + -8) - (-3 + 6 - 9 + 2)) - ((-3 - 7 * 8 + 2) * (4 * 9 - -1 - -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-4 - 7 * -3 + -8), B = (-3 + 6 - 9 + 2), C = (-3 - 7 * 8 + 2) and D = (4 * 9 - -1 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 7 * -3 + -8) = ((-4 - (7 * -3)) + -8) = ((-4 - -21) + -8) = (17 + -8) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 6 - 9 + 2) = (((-3 + 6) - 9) + 2) = ((3 - 9) + 2) = (-6 + 2) = -4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - 7 * 8 + 2) = ((-3 - (7 * 8)) + 2) = ((-3 - 56) + 2) = (-59 + 2) = -57.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * 9 - -1 - -6) = (((4 * 9) - -1) - -6) = ((36 - -1) - -6) = (37 - -6) = 43.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((9 - -4) - (-57 * 43)) = (13 - (-57 * 43)) = (13 - -2451) = 2464.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2464.", "correct_answer": "2464", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 507, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 - -1 * -6) - (-5 * 0 - 5)) + ((-9 + -5 - 5) + (9 + 3 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-3 - -1 * -6), B = (-5 * 0 - 5), C = (-9 + -5 - 5) and D = (9 + 3 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - -1 * -6) = (-3 - (-1 * -6)) = (-3 - 6) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 0 - 5) = ((-5 * 0) - 5) = (0 - 5) = -5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + -5 - 5) = ((-9 + -5) - 5) = (-14 - 5) = -19.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + 3 * 0) = (9 + (3 * 0)) = (9 + 0) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-9 - -5) + (-19 + 9)) = (-4 + (-19 + 9)) = (-4 + -10) = -14.\n(Final response) So the answer is -14.", "correct_answer": "-14", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 342, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 * -7 + -2 * 6) + (-7 + 4 + -3 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 * -7 + -2 * 6) and B = (-7 + 4 + -3 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * -7 + -2 * 6) = ((-6 * -7) + (-2 * 6)) = (42 + (-2 * 6)) = (42 + -12) = 30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + 4 + -3 * -3) = ((-7 + 4) + (-3 * -3)) = (-3 + (-3 * -3)) = (-3 + 9) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (30 + 6) = 36.\n(Final response) So the answer is 36.", "correct_answer": "36", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 36, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 - -9 + 8 - 9) + (-9 - 6 * 3 + -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (5 - -9 + 8 - 9) and B = (-9 - 6 * 3 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - -9 + 8 - 9) = (((5 - -9) + 8) - 9) = ((14 + 8) - 9) = (22 - 9) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 6 * 3 + -3) = ((-9 - (6 * 3)) + -3) = ((-9 - 18) + -3) = (-27 + -3) = -30.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (13 + -30) = -17.\n(Final response) So the answer is -17.", "correct_answer": "-17", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 210, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 * 1 * 7 + 3) - (-5 - -7 - 7 - 2)) + ((-4 + -8 - -4 + -9) + (-3 + 4 * -1 + 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (1 * 1 * 7 + 3), B = (-5 - -7 - 7 - 2), C = (-4 + -8 - -4 + -9) and D = (-3 + 4 * -1 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * 1 * 7 + 3) = (((1 * 1) * 7) + 3) = ((1 * 7) + 3) = (7 + 3) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -7 - 7 - 2) = (((-5 - -7) - 7) - 2) = ((2 - 7) - 2) = (-5 - 2) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + -8 - -4 + -9) = (((-4 + -8) - -4) + -9) = ((-12 - -4) + -9) = (-8 + -9) = -17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 + 4 * -1 + 5) = ((-3 + (4 * -1)) + 5) = ((-3 + -4) + 5) = (-7 + 5) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((10 - -7) + (-17 + -2)) = (17 + (-17 + -2)) = (17 + -19) = -2.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2.", "correct_answer": "-2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 509, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * 7 * -9) * (6 * 3 * -6)) * ((8 - 0 + 3) - (4 - -3 - -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (3 * 7 * -9), B = (6 * 3 * -6), C = (8 - 0 + 3) and D = (4 - -3 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 7 * -9) = ((3 * 7) * -9) = (21 * -9) = -189.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * 3 * -6) = ((6 * 3) * -6) = (18 * -6) = -108.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 - 0 + 3) = ((8 - 0) + 3) = (8 + 3) = 11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 - -3 - -7) = ((4 - -3) - -7) = (7 - -7) = 14.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((-189 * -108) * (11 - 14)) = (20412 * (11 - 14)) = (20412 * -3) = -61236.\n(Final response) So the answer is -61236.", "correct_answer": "-61236", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 400, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 * 3 - 5 + 1) * (-7 * 4 - 3 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (2 * 3 - 5 + 1) and B = (-7 * 4 - 3 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 3 - 5 + 1) = (((2 * 3) - 5) + 1) = ((6 - 5) + 1) = (1 + 1) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 4 - 3 + -9) = (((-7 * 4) - 3) + -9) = ((-28 - 3) + -9) = (-31 + -9) = -40.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (2 * -40) = -80.\n(Final response) So the answer is -80.", "correct_answer": "-80", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 41, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 * 4 + 9 - -7) - (6 * -8 - 0 * -7)) + ((8 * 1 * 9 + -3) * (-8 - -5 - 8 + -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-6 * 4 + 9 - -7), B = (6 * -8 - 0 * -7), C = (8 * 1 * 9 + -3) and D = (-8 - -5 - 8 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * 4 + 9 - -7) = (((-6 * 4) + 9) - -7) = ((-24 + 9) - -7) = (-15 - -7) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -8 - 0 * -7) = ((6 * -8) - (0 * -7)) = (-48 - (0 * -7)) = (-48 - 0) = -48.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * 1 * 9 + -3) = (((8 * 1) * 9) + -3) = ((8 * 9) + -3) = (72 + -3) = 69.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - -5 - 8 + -9) = (((-8 - -5) - 8) + -9) = ((-3 - 8) + -9) = (-11 + -9) = -20.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C * D)) = ((-8 - -48) + (69 * -20)) = (40 + (69 * -20)) = (40 + -1380) = -1340.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1340.", "correct_answer": "-1340", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 510, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 + -1 * -5) * (-1 - -7 - 2)) + ((0 * 4 - 3) - (-2 - 7 - 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-6 + -1 * -5), B = (-1 - -7 - 2), C = (0 * 4 - 3) and D = (-2 - 7 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + -1 * -5) = (-6 + (-1 * -5)) = (-6 + 5) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - -7 - 2) = ((-1 - -7) - 2) = (6 - 2) = 4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * 4 - 3) = ((0 * 4) - 3) = (0 - 3) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - 7 - 7) = ((-2 - 7) - 7) = (-9 - 7) = -16.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((-1 * 4) + (-3 - -16)) = (-4 + (-3 - -16)) = (-4 + 13) = 9.\n(Final response) So the answer is 9.", "correct_answer": "9", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 377, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 - 1 * -5) * (0 - -4 * 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 - 1 * -5) and B = (0 - -4 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - 1 * -5) = (9 - (1 * -5)) = (9 - -5) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - -4 * 5) = (0 - (-4 * 5)) = (0 - -20) = 20.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (14 * 20) = 280.\n(Final response) So the answer is 280.", "correct_answer": "280", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 91, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 + 5 * -6) + (-3 * 9 - -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-3 + 5 * -6) and B = (-3 * 9 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 5 * -6) = (-3 + (5 * -6)) = (-3 + -30) = -33.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * 9 - -8) = ((-3 * 9) - -8) = (-27 - -8) = -19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-33 + -19) = -52.\n(Final response) So the answer is -52.", "correct_answer": "-52", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 12, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * 3 + 7 * -3) - (7 * -9 + 7 * -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 * 3 + 7 * -3) and B = (7 * -9 + 7 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 3 + 7 * -3) = ((7 * 3) + (7 * -3)) = (21 + (7 * -3)) = (21 + -21) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * -9 + 7 * -7) = ((7 * -9) + (7 * -7)) = (-63 + (7 * -7)) = (-63 + -49) = -112.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (0 - -112) = 112.\n(Final response) So the answer is 112.", "correct_answer": "112", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 211, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 - -6 * 6 - -1) + (-3 - 4 - -5 - 3)) * ((9 + -4 * 4 + 0) + (7 + 7 * 3 + -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-3 - -6 * 6 - -1), B = (-3 - 4 - -5 - 3), C = (9 + -4 * 4 + 0) and D = (7 + 7 * 3 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - -6 * 6 - -1) = ((-3 - (-6 * 6)) - -1) = ((-3 - -36) - -1) = (33 - -1) = 34.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - 4 - -5 - 3) = (((-3 - 4) - -5) - 3) = ((-7 - -5) - 3) = (-2 - 3) = -5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 + -4 * 4 + 0) = ((9 + (-4 * 4)) + 0) = ((9 + -16) + 0) = (-7 + 0) = -7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + 7 * 3 + -9) = ((7 + (7 * 3)) + -9) = ((7 + 21) + -9) = (28 + -9) = 19.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((34 + -5) * (-7 + 19)) = (29 * (-7 + 19)) = (29 * 12) = 348.\n(Final response) So the answer is 348.", "correct_answer": "348", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 451, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 + 5 + -2) + (5 + -8 * 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 + 5 + -2) and B = (5 + -8 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 5 + -2) = ((-6 + 5) + -2) = (-1 + -2) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + -8 * 9) = (5 + (-8 * 9)) = (5 + -72) = -67.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-3 + -67) = -70.\n(Final response) So the answer is -70.", "correct_answer": "-70", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 90, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 + -2 - 8) * (-6 * 5 - -9)) - ((1 * 3 + 8) - (4 + -3 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-1 + -2 - 8), B = (-6 * 5 - -9), C = (1 * 3 + 8) and D = (4 + -3 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + -2 - 8) = ((-1 + -2) - 8) = (-3 - 8) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 5 - -9) = ((-6 * 5) - -9) = (-30 - -9) = -21.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 * 3 + 8) = ((1 * 3) + 8) = (3 + 8) = 11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + -3 * 4) = (4 + (-3 * 4)) = (4 + -12) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((-11 * -21) - (11 - -8)) = (231 - (11 - -8)) = (231 - 19) = 212.\n(Final response) So the answer is 212.", "correct_answer": "212", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 415, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 * -4 + 0) - (-3 + 7 * 2)) - ((-3 + 9 + 4) - (-6 * 6 - 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (8 * -4 + 0), B = (-3 + 7 * 2), C = (-3 + 9 + 4) and D = (-6 * 6 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * -4 + 0) = ((8 * -4) + 0) = (-32 + 0) = -32.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 7 * 2) = (-3 + (7 * 2)) = (-3 + 14) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + 9 + 4) = ((-3 + 9) + 4) = (6 + 4) = 10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * 6 - 7) = ((-6 * 6) - 7) = (-36 - 7) = -43.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-32 - 11) - (10 - -43)) = (-43 - (10 - -43)) = (-43 - 53) = -96.\n(Final response) So the answer is -96.", "correct_answer": "-96", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 409, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 * 0 + -4 + -7) + (4 + -6 + 7 - 5)) * ((-6 + -4 * 2 * 2) * (7 + -1 * -7 * -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-9 * 0 + -4 + -7), B = (4 + -6 + 7 - 5), C = (-6 + -4 * 2 * 2) and D = (7 + -1 * -7 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 0 + -4 + -7) = (((-9 * 0) + -4) + -7) = ((0 + -4) + -7) = (-4 + -7) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + -6 + 7 - 5) = (((4 + -6) + 7) - 5) = ((-2 + 7) - 5) = (5 - 5) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -4 * 2 * 2) = (-6 + ((-4 * 2) * 2)) = (-6 + (-8 * 2)) = (-6 + -16) = -22.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + -1 * -7 * -7) = (7 + ((-1 * -7) * -7)) = (7 + (7 * -7)) = (7 + -49) = -42.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((-11 + 0) * (-22 * -42)) = (-11 * (-22 * -42)) = (-11 * 924) = -10164.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10164.", "correct_answer": "-10164", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 499, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - -4 * 0 - 9) - (4 * 0 + 9 - 5)) + ((9 - -6 + 9 - 8) + (9 - -5 - 1 + -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-9 - -4 * 0 - 9), B = (4 * 0 + 9 - 5), C = (9 - -6 + 9 - 8) and D = (9 - -5 - 1 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - -4 * 0 - 9) = ((-9 - (-4 * 0)) - 9) = ((-9 - 0) - 9) = (-9 - 9) = -18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 0 + 9 - 5) = (((4 * 0) + 9) - 5) = ((0 + 9) - 5) = (9 - 5) = 4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - -6 + 9 - 8) = (((9 - -6) + 9) - 8) = ((15 + 9) - 8) = (24 - 8) = 16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - -5 - 1 + -2) = (((9 - -5) - 1) + -2) = ((14 - 1) + -2) = (13 + -2) = 11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-18 - 4) + (16 + 11)) = (-22 + (16 + 11)) = (-22 + 27) = 5.\n(Final response) So the answer is 5.", "correct_answer": "5", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 595, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 * 9 * 5) - (7 * -7 + 6)) * ((-3 + -9 * -2) - (8 * -3 + -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (0 * 9 * 5), B = (7 * -7 + 6), C = (-3 + -9 * -2) and D = (8 * -3 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * 9 * 5) = ((0 * 9) * 5) = (0 * 5) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * -7 + 6) = ((7 * -7) + 6) = (-49 + 6) = -43.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -9 * -2) = (-3 + (-9 * -2)) = (-3 + 18) = 15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * -3 + -4) = ((8 * -3) + -4) = (-24 + -4) = -28.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((0 - -43) * (15 - -28)) = (43 * (15 - -28)) = (43 * 43) = 1849.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1849.", "correct_answer": "1849", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 442, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 + 0 - -8) * (-7 - -8 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (6 + 0 - -8) and B = (-7 - -8 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 0 - -8) = ((6 + 0) - -8) = (6 - -8) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -8 - 3) = ((-7 - -8) - 3) = (1 - 3) = -2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (14 * -2) = -28.\n(Final response) So the answer is -28.", "correct_answer": "-28", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 121, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 - -7 + -2 - -2) - (8 + -1 - -6 * 4)) - ((6 + 5 + -1 * 3) + (-2 - -4 + -9 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-8 - -7 + -2 - -2), B = (8 + -1 - -6 * 4), C = (6 + 5 + -1 * 3) and D = (-2 - -4 + -9 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -7 + -2 - -2) = (((-8 - -7) + -2) - -2) = ((-1 + -2) - -2) = (-3 - -2) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + -1 - -6 * 4) = ((8 + -1) - (-6 * 4)) = (7 - (-6 * 4)) = (7 - -24) = 31.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + 5 + -1 * 3) = ((6 + 5) + (-1 * 3)) = (11 + (-1 * 3)) = (11 + -3) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - -4 + -9 * 4) = ((-2 - -4) + (-9 * 4)) = (2 + (-9 * 4)) = (2 + -36) = -34.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-1 - 31) - (8 + -34)) = (-32 - (8 + -34)) = (-32 - -26) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 476, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 * 6 * 4 + 1) * (-5 + 0 + -6 + 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-2 * 6 * 4 + 1) and B = (-5 + 0 + -6 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * 6 * 4 + 1) = (((-2 * 6) * 4) + 1) = ((-12 * 4) + 1) = (-48 + 1) = -47.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + 0 + -6 + 2) = (((-5 + 0) + -6) + 2) = ((-5 + -6) + 2) = (-11 + 2) = -9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-47 * -9) = 423.\n(Final response) So the answer is 423.", "correct_answer": "423", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 52, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 * 9 + -9) + (7 * 2 - 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-3 * 9 + -9) and B = (7 * 2 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * 9 + -9) = ((-3 * 9) + -9) = (-27 + -9) = -36.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * 2 - 1) = ((7 * 2) - 1) = (14 - 1) = 13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-36 + 13) = -23.\n(Final response) So the answer is -23.", "correct_answer": "-23", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 24, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 - 5 * 7 - -4) * (7 - -1 - -5 - -2)) - ((7 + -7 + -3 - 2) + (-7 + 4 * 8 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-8 - 5 * 7 - -4), B = (7 - -1 - -5 - -2), C = (7 + -7 + -3 - 2) and D = (-7 + 4 * 8 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 5 * 7 - -4) = ((-8 - (5 * 7)) - -4) = ((-8 - 35) - -4) = (-43 - -4) = -39.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - -1 - -5 - -2) = (((7 - -1) - -5) - -2) = ((8 - -5) - -2) = (13 - -2) = 15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + -7 + -3 - 2) = (((7 + -7) + -3) - 2) = ((0 + -3) - 2) = (-3 - 2) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + 4 * 8 * -6) = (-7 + ((4 * 8) * -6)) = (-7 + (32 * -6)) = (-7 + -192) = -199.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-39 * 15) - (-5 + -199)) = (-585 - (-5 + -199)) = (-585 - -204) = -381.\n(Final response) So the answer is -381.", "correct_answer": "-381", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 161, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 + 1 * -8 * 0 * 0) * (8 - 8 - 3 + -2 * -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (8 + 1 * -8 * 0 * 0) and B = (8 - 8 - 3 + -2 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 1 * -8 * 0 * 0) = (8 + (((1 * -8) * 0) * 0)) = (8 + ((-8 * 0) * 0)) = (8 + (0 * 0)) = (8 + 0) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 8 - 3 + -2 * -6) = (((8 - 8) - 3) + (-2 * -6)) = ((0 - 3) + (-2 * -6)) = ((0 - 3) + 12) = (-3 + 12) = 9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (8 * 9) = 72.\n(Final response) So the answer is 72.", "correct_answer": "72", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 72, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - -8 * 2) + (-5 - -1 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (1 - -8 * 2) and B = (-5 - -1 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -8 * 2) = (1 - (-8 * 2)) = (1 - -16) = 17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -1 - 2) = ((-5 - -1) - 2) = (-4 - 2) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (17 + -6) = 11.\n(Final response) So the answer is 11.", "correct_answer": "11", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 105, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * -5 * -5 * 8) * (-8 + 3 - 3 - -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 * -5 * -5 * 8) and B = (-8 + 3 - 3 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * -5 * -5 * 8) = (((5 * -5) * -5) * 8) = ((-25 * -5) * 8) = (125 * 8) = 1000.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 3 - 3 - -1) = (((-8 + 3) - 3) - -1) = ((-5 - 3) - -1) = (-8 - -1) = -7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (1000 * -7) = -7000.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7000.", "correct_answer": "-7000", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 51, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 * -3 - -4 + 6 * -8 * -8) - (-1 * 2 * -5 + -7 - -8 + 7)) + ((9 - 3 + 8 * 1 - 9 + -3) - (9 - -7 + 0 * -8 + -2 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (6 * -3 - -4 + 6 * -8 * -8), B = (-1 * 2 * -5 + -7 - -8 + 7), C = (9 - 3 + 8 * 1 - 9 + -3) and D = (9 - -7 + 0 * -8 + -2 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * -3 - -4 + 6 * -8 * -8) = (((6 * -3) - -4) + ((6 * -8) * -8)) = ((-18 - -4) + ((6 * -8) * -8)) = ((-18 - -4) + (-48 * -8)) = (-14 + (-48 * -8)) = (-14 + 384) = 370.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * 2 * -5 + -7 - -8 + 7) = (((((-1 * 2) * -5) + -7) - -8) + 7) = ((((-2 * -5) + -7) - -8) + 7) = (((10 + -7) - -8) + 7) = ((3 - -8) + 7) = (11 + 7) = 18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - 3 + 8 * 1 - 9 + -3) = ((((9 - 3) + (8 * 1)) - 9) + -3) = (((6 + (8 * 1)) - 9) + -3) = (((6 + 8) - 9) + -3) = ((14 - 9) + -3) = (5 + -3) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - -7 + 0 * -8 + -2 + -1) = ((((9 - -7) + (0 * -8)) + -2) + -1) = (((16 + (0 * -8)) + -2) + -1) = (((16 + 0) + -2) + -1) = ((16 + -2) + -1) = (14 + -1) = 13.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((370 - 18) + (2 - 13)) = (352 + (2 - 13)) = (352 + -11) = 341.\n(Final response) So the answer is 341.", "correct_answer": "341", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 222, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 + 6 + 5) + (-2 * -8 - -3)) - ((-6 * -1 * 1) * (8 - 9 - 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (2 + 6 + 5), B = (-2 * -8 - -3), C = (-6 * -1 * 1) and D = (8 - 9 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + 6 + 5) = ((2 + 6) + 5) = (8 + 5) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -8 - -3) = ((-2 * -8) - -3) = (16 - -3) = 19.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 * -1 * 1) = ((-6 * -1) * 1) = (6 * 1) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - 9 - 1) = ((8 - 9) - 1) = (-1 - 1) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((13 + 19) - (6 * -2)) = (32 - (6 * -2)) = (32 - -12) = 44.\n(Final response) So the answer is 44.", "correct_answer": "44", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 366, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * 3 - -5 - 0) - (4 * 5 * -7 * 5)) * ((0 * 8 + 4 + -4) - (6 - 9 + 1 * 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-5 * 3 - -5 - 0), B = (4 * 5 * -7 * 5), C = (0 * 8 + 4 + -4) and D = (6 - 9 + 1 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 3 - -5 - 0) = (((-5 * 3) - -5) - 0) = ((-15 - -5) - 0) = (-10 - 0) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 5 * -7 * 5) = (((4 * 5) * -7) * 5) = ((20 * -7) * 5) = (-140 * 5) = -700.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * 8 + 4 + -4) = (((0 * 8) + 4) + -4) = ((0 + 4) + -4) = (4 + -4) = 0.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 - 9 + 1 * 9) = ((6 - 9) + (1 * 9)) = (-3 + (1 * 9)) = (-3 + 9) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((-10 - -700) * (0 - 6)) = (690 * (0 - 6)) = (690 * -6) = -4140.\n(Final response) So the answer is -4140.", "correct_answer": "-4140", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 596, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-2 + 7 * 8 * 0 - -9) + (-2 - 3 - 7 - -8 * 8)) * ((-7 - -7 - 0 - 1 - -6) * (-6 * 6 * -9 + 3 + -2))) - (((-4 * 8 * -2 - 9 - -1) + (8 - 3 - 8 + -9 - 4)) - ((8 * -3 - -6 * 8 * -1) + (6 - 5 - 3 - -3 - -6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C * D)) - ((E + F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (-2 + 7 * 8 * 0 - -9), B = (-2 - 3 - 7 - -8 * 8), C = (-7 - -7 - 0 - 1 - -6), D = (-6 * 6 * -9 + 3 + -2), E = (-4 * 8 * -2 - 9 - -1), F = (8 - 3 - 8 + -9 - 4), G = (8 * -3 - -6 * 8 * -1) and H = (6 - 5 - 3 - -3 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + 7 * 8 * 0 - -9) = ((-2 + ((7 * 8) * 0)) - -9) = ((-2 + (56 * 0)) - -9) = ((-2 + 0) - -9) = (-2 - -9) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 3 - 7 - -8 * 8) = (((-2 - 3) - 7) - (-8 * 8)) = ((-5 - 7) - (-8 * 8)) = ((-5 - 7) - -64) = (-12 - -64) = 52.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - -7 - 0 - 1 - -6) = ((((-7 - -7) - 0) - 1) - -6) = (((0 - 0) - 1) - -6) = ((0 - 1) - -6) = (-1 - -6) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * 6 * -9 + 3 + -2) = ((((-6 * 6) * -9) + 3) + -2) = (((-36 * -9) + 3) + -2) = ((324 + 3) + -2) = (327 + -2) = 325.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-4 * 8 * -2 - 9 - -1) = ((((-4 * 8) * -2) - 9) - -1) = (((-32 * -2) - 9) - -1) = ((64 - 9) - -1) = (55 - -1) = 56.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (8 - 3 - 8 + -9 - 4) = ((((8 - 3) - 8) + -9) - 4) = (((5 - 8) + -9) - 4) = ((-3 + -9) - 4) = (-12 - 4) = -16.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 * -3 - -6 * 8 * -1) = ((8 * -3) - ((-6 * 8) * -1)) = (-24 - ((-6 * 8) * -1)) = (-24 - (-48 * -1)) = (-24 - 48) = -72.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (6 - 5 - 3 - -3 - -6) = ((((6 - 5) - 3) - -3) - -6) = (((1 - 3) - -3) - -6) = ((-2 - -3) - -6) = (1 - -6) = 7.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C * D)) - ((E + F) - (G + H))) = (((7 + 52) * (5 * 325)) - ((56 + -16) - (-72 + 7))) = ((59 * (5 * 325)) - ((56 + -16) - (-72 + 7))) = ((59 * 1625) - ((56 + -16) - (-72 + 7))) = ((59 * 1625) - (40 - (-72 + 7))) = ((59 * 1625) - (40 - -65)) = (95875 - (40 - -65)) = (95875 - 105) = 95770.\n(Final response) So the answer is 95770.", "correct_answer": "95770", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 304, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 - -4 * 4) * (2 - -5 + 5)) - ((-9 + -1 * -6) * (4 + 8 - 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (7 - -4 * 4), B = (2 - -5 + 5), C = (-9 + -1 * -6) and D = (4 + 8 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -4 * 4) = (7 - (-4 * 4)) = (7 - -16) = 23.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -5 + 5) = ((2 - -5) + 5) = (7 + 5) = 12.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + -1 * -6) = (-9 + (-1 * -6)) = (-9 + 6) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + 8 - 0) = ((4 + 8) - 0) = (12 - 0) = 12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((23 * 12) - (-3 * 12)) = (276 - (-3 * 12)) = (276 - -36) = 312.\n(Final response) So the answer is 312.", "correct_answer": "312", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 315, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 - -8 * -1) * (-6 - 8 + 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (0 - -8 * -1) and B = (-6 - 8 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - -8 * -1) = (0 - (-8 * -1)) = (0 - 8) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - 8 + 1) = ((-6 - 8) + 1) = (-14 + 1) = -13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-8 * -13) = 104.\n(Final response) So the answer is 104.", "correct_answer": "104", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 42, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 * -1 * -8) - (-1 * -2 + -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 * -1 * -8) and B = (-1 * -2 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * -1 * -8) = ((-1 * -1) * -8) = (1 * -8) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * -2 + -5) = ((-1 * -2) + -5) = (2 + -5) = -3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-8 - -3) = -5.\n(Final response) So the answer is -5.", "correct_answer": "-5", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 130, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 - -8 * 4) * (-9 + 5 - -5)) * ((7 + 0 + 1) - (-6 * 9 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-2 - -8 * 4), B = (-9 + 5 - -5), C = (7 + 0 + 1) and D = (-6 * 9 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -8 * 4) = (-2 - (-8 * 4)) = (-2 - -32) = 30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 5 - -5) = ((-9 + 5) - -5) = (-4 - -5) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + 0 + 1) = ((7 + 0) + 1) = (7 + 1) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * 9 * 4) = ((-6 * 9) * 4) = (-54 * 4) = -216.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((30 * 1) * (8 - -216)) = (30 * (8 - -216)) = (30 * 224) = 6720.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6720.", "correct_answer": "6720", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 440, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 + -1 - 3 + 9) + (9 + 7 * 0 - -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-9 + -1 - 3 + 9) and B = (9 + 7 * 0 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -1 - 3 + 9) = (((-9 + -1) - 3) + 9) = ((-10 - 3) + 9) = (-13 + 9) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + 7 * 0 - -6) = ((9 + (7 * 0)) - -6) = ((9 + 0) - -6) = (9 - -6) = 15.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-4 + 15) = 11.\n(Final response) So the answer is 11.", "correct_answer": "11", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 151, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 + -2 + -2 + 2 - 7) + (4 + -1 + -4 - 2 - -5)) - ((-3 * 3 + -4 + -2 + -3) - (-2 - -8 - 5 - 4 + 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (4 + -2 + -2 + 2 - 7), B = (4 + -1 + -4 - 2 - -5), C = (-3 * 3 + -4 + -2 + -3) and D = (-2 - -8 - 5 - 4 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -2 + -2 + 2 - 7) = ((((4 + -2) + -2) + 2) - 7) = (((2 + -2) + 2) - 7) = ((0 + 2) - 7) = (2 - 7) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + -1 + -4 - 2 - -5) = ((((4 + -1) + -4) - 2) - -5) = (((3 + -4) - 2) - -5) = ((-1 - 2) - -5) = (-3 - -5) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 * 3 + -4 + -2 + -3) = ((((-3 * 3) + -4) + -2) + -3) = (((-9 + -4) + -2) + -3) = ((-13 + -2) + -3) = (-15 + -3) = -18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - -8 - 5 - 4 + 8) = ((((-2 - -8) - 5) - 4) + 8) = (((6 - 5) - 4) + 8) = ((1 - 4) + 8) = (-3 + 8) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((-5 + 2) - (-18 - 5)) = (-3 - (-18 - 5)) = (-3 - -23) = 20.\n(Final response) So the answer is 20.", "correct_answer": "20", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 185, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 - -7 - 6) * (-5 - 4 + 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 - -7 - 6) and B = (-5 - 4 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -7 - 6) = ((-5 - -7) - 6) = (2 - 6) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - 4 + 5) = ((-5 - 4) + 5) = (-9 + 5) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-4 * -4) = 16.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16.", "correct_answer": "16", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 36, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - 8 - 8 - 5) - (-6 + -2 - 2 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-2 - 8 - 8 - 5) and B = (-6 + -2 - 2 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - 8 - 8 - 5) = (((-2 - 8) - 8) - 5) = ((-10 - 8) - 5) = (-18 - 5) = -23.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -2 - 2 * 4) = ((-6 + -2) - (2 * 4)) = (-8 - (2 * 4)) = (-8 - 8) = -16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-23 - -16) = -7.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7.", "correct_answer": "-7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 152, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-3 + -7 * -3) * (4 - 6 + 0)) - ((-3 - 0 - 3) - (-8 - 4 + 9))) + (((-4 - 5 * 6) * (3 + 9 + -9)) - ((-9 + 0 - -9) + (-8 * 4 + -4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C - D)) + ((E * F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (-3 + -7 * -3), B = (4 - 6 + 0), C = (-3 - 0 - 3), D = (-8 - 4 + 9), E = (-4 - 5 * 6), F = (3 + 9 + -9), G = (-9 + 0 - -9) and H = (-8 * 4 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + -7 * -3) = (-3 + (-7 * -3)) = (-3 + 21) = 18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 6 + 0) = ((4 - 6) + 0) = (-2 + 0) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - 0 - 3) = ((-3 - 0) - 3) = (-3 - 3) = -6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - 4 + 9) = ((-8 - 4) + 9) = (-12 + 9) = -3.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-4 - 5 * 6) = (-4 - (5 * 6)) = (-4 - 30) = -34.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (3 + 9 + -9) = ((3 + 9) + -9) = (12 + -9) = 3.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-9 + 0 - -9) = ((-9 + 0) - -9) = (-9 - -9) = 0.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 * 4 + -4) = ((-8 * 4) + -4) = (-32 + -4) = -36.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C - D)) + ((E * F) - (G + H))) = (((18 * -2) - (-6 - -3)) + ((-34 * 3) - (0 + -36))) = ((-36 - (-6 - -3)) + ((-34 * 3) - (0 + -36))) = ((-36 - -3) + ((-34 * 3) - (0 + -36))) = ((-36 - -3) + (-102 - (0 + -36))) = ((-36 - -3) + (-102 - -36)) = (-33 + (-102 - -36)) = (-33 + -66) = -99.\n(Final response) So the answer is -99.", "correct_answer": "-99", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 255, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 + 5 - -3) * (0 * 4 - -7)) + ((-9 * -6 - -8) + (1 + 6 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-2 + 5 - -3), B = (0 * 4 - -7), C = (-9 * -6 - -8) and D = (1 + 6 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + 5 - -3) = ((-2 + 5) - -3) = (3 - -3) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 4 - -7) = ((0 * 4) - -7) = (0 - -7) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * -6 - -8) = ((-9 * -6) - -8) = (54 - -8) = 62.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + 6 * -1) = (1 + (6 * -1)) = (1 + -6) = -5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((6 * 7) + (62 + -5)) = (42 + (62 + -5)) = (42 + 57) = 99.\n(Final response) So the answer is 99.", "correct_answer": "99", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 145, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 * 8 + -3 * -4) * (2 + 7 - -3 - -3)) * ((1 + -2 + -5 * -6) - (9 - 6 * 0 * -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (6 * 8 + -3 * -4), B = (2 + 7 - -3 - -3), C = (1 + -2 + -5 * -6) and D = (9 - 6 * 0 * -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * 8 + -3 * -4) = ((6 * 8) + (-3 * -4)) = (48 + (-3 * -4)) = (48 + 12) = 60.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + 7 - -3 - -3) = (((2 + 7) - -3) - -3) = ((9 - -3) - -3) = (12 - -3) = 15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 + -2 + -5 * -6) = ((1 + -2) + (-5 * -6)) = (-1 + (-5 * -6)) = (-1 + 30) = 29.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - 6 * 0 * -4) = (9 - ((6 * 0) * -4)) = (9 - (0 * -4)) = (9 - 0) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((60 * 15) * (29 - 9)) = (900 * (29 - 9)) = (900 * 20) = 18000.\n(Final response) So the answer is 18000.", "correct_answer": "18000", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 579, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 * -7 - 0) + (-1 + -7 + -2)) - ((7 * 6 - 1) - (-1 * 5 * 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-4 * -7 - 0), B = (-1 + -7 + -2), C = (7 * 6 - 1) and D = (-1 * 5 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -7 - 0) = ((-4 * -7) - 0) = (28 - 0) = 28.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -7 + -2) = ((-1 + -7) + -2) = (-8 + -2) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 * 6 - 1) = ((7 * 6) - 1) = (42 - 1) = 41.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * 5 * 8) = ((-1 * 5) * 8) = (-5 * 8) = -40.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((28 + -10) - (41 - -40)) = (18 - (41 - -40)) = (18 - 81) = -63.\n(Final response) So the answer is -63.", "correct_answer": "-63", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 437, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 + -2 - -6 * -9) * (-6 + -1 - 0 * -7)) - ((-5 * -9 * 2 - -7) * (6 - 4 - 6 + -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-9 + -2 - -6 * -9), B = (-6 + -1 - 0 * -7), C = (-5 * -9 * 2 - -7) and D = (6 - 4 - 6 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -2 - -6 * -9) = ((-9 + -2) - (-6 * -9)) = (-11 - (-6 * -9)) = (-11 - 54) = -65.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -1 - 0 * -7) = ((-6 + -1) - (0 * -7)) = (-7 - (0 * -7)) = (-7 - 0) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * -9 * 2 - -7) = (((-5 * -9) * 2) - -7) = ((45 * 2) - -7) = (90 - -7) = 97.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 - 4 - 6 + -2) = (((6 - 4) - 6) + -2) = ((2 - 6) + -2) = (-4 + -2) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-65 * -7) - (97 * -6)) = (455 - (97 * -6)) = (455 - -582) = 1037.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1037.", "correct_answer": "1037", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 452, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 + 3 - 0 * -8) + (7 + -6 - -4 + 3)) - ((7 * 0 * -5 + 2) - (-1 * -6 - -9 - -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-4 + 3 - 0 * -8), B = (7 + -6 - -4 + 3), C = (7 * 0 * -5 + 2) and D = (-1 * -6 - -9 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + 3 - 0 * -8) = ((-4 + 3) - (0 * -8)) = (-1 - (0 * -8)) = (-1 - 0) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + -6 - -4 + 3) = (((7 + -6) - -4) + 3) = ((1 - -4) + 3) = (5 + 3) = 8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 * 0 * -5 + 2) = (((7 * 0) * -5) + 2) = ((0 * -5) + 2) = (0 + 2) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * -6 - -9 - -1) = (((-1 * -6) - -9) - -1) = ((6 - -9) - -1) = (15 - -1) = 16.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((-1 + 8) - (2 - 16)) = (7 - (2 - 16)) = (7 - -14) = 21.\n(Final response) So the answer is 21.", "correct_answer": "21", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 153, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + 0 - 0 + 4) - (-1 + 4 * 6 - 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (5 + 0 - 0 + 4) and B = (-1 + 4 * 6 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 0 - 0 + 4) = (((5 + 0) - 0) + 4) = ((5 - 0) + 4) = (5 + 4) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + 4 * 6 - 0) = ((-1 + (4 * 6)) - 0) = ((-1 + 24) - 0) = (23 - 0) = 23.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (9 - 23) = -14.\n(Final response) So the answer is -14.", "correct_answer": "-14", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 268, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - -2 * 3) + (-9 - 9 + 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-2 - -2 * 3) and B = (-9 - 9 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -2 * 3) = (-2 - (-2 * 3)) = (-2 - -6) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 9 + 6) = ((-9 - 9) + 6) = (-18 + 6) = -12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (4 + -12) = -8.\n(Final response) So the answer is -8.", "correct_answer": "-8", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 133, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - -1 * -5) + (-4 + 7 + 3)) + ((4 - 9 - -7) - (-8 - -3 + -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (6 - -1 * -5), B = (-4 + 7 + 3), C = (4 - 9 - -7) and D = (-8 - -3 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -1 * -5) = (6 - (-1 * -5)) = (6 - 5) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 7 + 3) = ((-4 + 7) + 3) = (3 + 3) = 6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - 9 - -7) = ((4 - 9) - -7) = (-5 - -7) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - -3 + -4) = ((-8 - -3) + -4) = (-5 + -4) = -9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((1 + 6) + (2 - -9)) = (7 + (2 - -9)) = (7 + 11) = 18.\n(Final response) So the answer is 18.", "correct_answer": "18", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 341, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 - 4 + -3 * 8) * (5 + 5 - -1 * -3)) - ((-2 - 6 * -7 + 3) - (2 * -1 - -1 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (3 - 4 + -3 * 8), B = (5 + 5 - -1 * -3), C = (-2 - 6 * -7 + 3) and D = (2 * -1 - -1 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - 4 + -3 * 8) = ((3 - 4) + (-3 * 8)) = (-1 + (-3 * 8)) = (-1 + -24) = -25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 5 - -1 * -3) = ((5 + 5) - (-1 * -3)) = (10 - (-1 * -3)) = (10 - 3) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 - 6 * -7 + 3) = ((-2 - (6 * -7)) + 3) = ((-2 - -42) + 3) = (40 + 3) = 43.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * -1 - -1 * -5) = ((2 * -1) - (-1 * -5)) = (-2 - (-1 * -5)) = (-2 - 5) = -7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((-25 * 7) - (43 - -7)) = (-175 - (43 - -7)) = (-175 - 50) = -225.\n(Final response) So the answer is -225.", "correct_answer": "-225", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 169, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 * 9 + -6) + (-1 * 2 + -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (3 * 9 + -6) and B = (-1 * 2 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 9 + -6) = ((3 * 9) + -6) = (27 + -6) = 21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * 2 + -3) = ((-1 * 2) + -3) = (-2 + -3) = -5.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (21 + -5) = 16.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16.", "correct_answer": "16", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 45, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 + -6 - 4 * 6) + (-6 + -9 + -6 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-4 + -6 - 4 * 6) and B = (-6 + -9 + -6 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -6 - 4 * 6) = ((-4 + -6) - (4 * 6)) = (-10 - (4 * 6)) = (-10 - 24) = -34.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -9 + -6 - -4) = (((-6 + -9) + -6) - -4) = ((-15 + -6) - -4) = (-21 - -4) = -17.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-34 + -17) = -51.\n(Final response) So the answer is -51.", "correct_answer": "-51", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 283, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 * 1 + 1) * (6 * 5 + -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (2 * 1 + 1) and B = (6 * 5 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 1 + 1) = ((2 * 1) + 1) = (2 + 1) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * 5 + -6) = ((6 * 5) + -6) = (30 + -6) = 24.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (3 * 24) = 72.\n(Final response) So the answer is 72.", "correct_answer": "72", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 27, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-3 + -9 + -3 - 6 * 6) + (3 - -1 - -5 + 7 * 5)) * ((-4 * 8 * 6 + -7 - -5) * (3 - 1 + -9 + -6 * 0))) * (((-5 * 5 + -5 + -4 + -4) + (1 * 6 + -9 + -3 * -3)) + ((-9 * -6 - -5 - 5 + 8) - (1 - 5 - -5 * 1 - 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (-3 + -9 + -3 - 6 * 6), B = (3 - -1 - -5 + 7 * 5), C = (-4 * 8 * 6 + -7 - -5), D = (3 - 1 + -9 + -6 * 0), E = (-5 * 5 + -5 + -4 + -4), F = (1 * 6 + -9 + -3 * -3), G = (-9 * -6 - -5 - 5 + 8) and H = (1 - 5 - -5 * 1 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + -9 + -3 - 6 * 6) = (((-3 + -9) + -3) - (6 * 6)) = ((-12 + -3) - (6 * 6)) = ((-12 + -3) - 36) = (-15 - 36) = -51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - -1 - -5 + 7 * 5) = (((3 - -1) - -5) + (7 * 5)) = ((4 - -5) + (7 * 5)) = ((4 - -5) + 35) = (9 + 35) = 44.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 * 8 * 6 + -7 - -5) = ((((-4 * 8) * 6) + -7) - -5) = (((-32 * 6) + -7) - -5) = ((-192 + -7) - -5) = (-199 - -5) = -194.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 - 1 + -9 + -6 * 0) = (((3 - 1) + -9) + (-6 * 0)) = ((2 + -9) + (-6 * 0)) = ((2 + -9) + 0) = (-7 + 0) = -7.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-5 * 5 + -5 + -4 + -4) = ((((-5 * 5) + -5) + -4) + -4) = (((-25 + -5) + -4) + -4) = ((-30 + -4) + -4) = (-34 + -4) = -38.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (1 * 6 + -9 + -3 * -3) = (((1 * 6) + -9) + (-3 * -3)) = ((6 + -9) + (-3 * -3)) = ((6 + -9) + 9) = (-3 + 9) = 6.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-9 * -6 - -5 - 5 + 8) = ((((-9 * -6) - -5) - 5) + 8) = (((54 - -5) - 5) + 8) = ((59 - 5) + 8) = (54 + 8) = 62.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (1 - 5 - -5 * 1 - 3) = (((1 - 5) - (-5 * 1)) - 3) = ((-4 - (-5 * 1)) - 3) = ((-4 - -5) - 3) = (1 - 3) = -2.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G - H))) = (((-51 + 44) * (-194 * -7)) * ((-38 + 6) + (62 - -2))) = ((-7 * (-194 * -7)) * ((-38 + 6) + (62 - -2))) = ((-7 * 1358) * ((-38 + 6) + (62 - -2))) = ((-7 * 1358) * (-32 + (62 - -2))) = ((-7 * 1358) * (-32 + 64)) = (-9506 * (-32 + 64)) = (-9506 * 32) = -304192.\n(Final response) So the answer is -304192.", "correct_answer": "-304192", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 308, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 + -7 + 7) + (-9 - -4 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-3 + -7 + 7) and B = (-9 - -4 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + -7 + 7) = ((-3 + -7) + 7) = (-10 + 7) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - -4 - 2) = ((-9 - -4) - 2) = (-5 - 2) = -7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-3 + -7) = -10.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10.", "correct_answer": "-10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 52, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-8 - -8 + 9) * (-1 - -1 + 1)) + ((9 + -4 + 8) + (-9 - 8 + 9))) * (((4 - -3 + -1) * (1 * -4 * -1)) + ((-4 + 7 - 4) + (8 - 1 - -7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C + D)) * ((E * F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-8 - -8 + 9), B = (-1 - -1 + 1), C = (9 + -4 + 8), D = (-9 - 8 + 9), E = (4 - -3 + -1), F = (1 * -4 * -1), G = (-4 + 7 - 4) and H = (8 - 1 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -8 + 9) = ((-8 - -8) + 9) = (0 + 9) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - -1 + 1) = ((-1 - -1) + 1) = (0 + 1) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 + -4 + 8) = ((9 + -4) + 8) = (5 + 8) = 13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 - 8 + 9) = ((-9 - 8) + 9) = (-17 + 9) = -8.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (4 - -3 + -1) = ((4 - -3) + -1) = (7 + -1) = 6.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (1 * -4 * -1) = ((1 * -4) * -1) = (-4 * -1) = 4.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-4 + 7 - 4) = ((-4 + 7) - 4) = (3 - 4) = -1.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 - 1 - -7) = ((8 - 1) - -7) = (7 - -7) = 14.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C + D)) * ((E * F) + (G + H))) = (((9 * 1) + (13 + -8)) * ((6 * 4) + (-1 + 14))) = ((9 + (13 + -8)) * ((6 * 4) + (-1 + 14))) = ((9 + 5) * ((6 * 4) + (-1 + 14))) = ((9 + 5) * (24 + (-1 + 14))) = ((9 + 5) * (24 + 13)) = (14 * (24 + 13)) = (14 * 37) = 518.\n(Final response) So the answer is 518.", "correct_answer": "518", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 240, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-8 - -4 * 4 * 4) - (-9 + 7 + 0 * 0)) - ((-9 - 8 * -6 + -7) * (-6 - -3 * -4 + -2))) - (((7 * -9 - 3 - 0) - (-2 + -6 * -1 + -2)) + ((-9 - 1 + -8 + 1) + (2 * 7 * -2 - -6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (-8 - -4 * 4 * 4), B = (-9 + 7 + 0 * 0), C = (-9 - 8 * -6 + -7), D = (-6 - -3 * -4 + -2), E = (7 * -9 - 3 - 0), F = (-2 + -6 * -1 + -2), G = (-9 - 1 + -8 + 1) and H = (2 * 7 * -2 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -4 * 4 * 4) = (-8 - ((-4 * 4) * 4)) = (-8 - (-16 * 4)) = (-8 - -64) = 56.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 7 + 0 * 0) = ((-9 + 7) + (0 * 0)) = (-2 + (0 * 0)) = (-2 + 0) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 - 8 * -6 + -7) = ((-9 - (8 * -6)) + -7) = ((-9 - -48) + -7) = (39 + -7) = 32.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - -3 * -4 + -2) = ((-6 - (-3 * -4)) + -2) = ((-6 - 12) + -2) = (-18 + -2) = -20.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (7 * -9 - 3 - 0) = (((7 * -9) - 3) - 0) = ((-63 - 3) - 0) = (-66 - 0) = -66.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-2 + -6 * -1 + -2) = ((-2 + (-6 * -1)) + -2) = ((-2 + 6) + -2) = (4 + -2) = 2.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-9 - 1 + -8 + 1) = (((-9 - 1) + -8) + 1) = ((-10 + -8) + 1) = (-18 + 1) = -17.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (2 * 7 * -2 - -6) = (((2 * 7) * -2) - -6) = ((14 * -2) - -6) = (-28 - -6) = -22.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((56 - -2) - (32 * -20)) - ((-66 - 2) + (-17 + -22))) = ((58 - (32 * -20)) - ((-66 - 2) + (-17 + -22))) = ((58 - -640) - ((-66 - 2) + (-17 + -22))) = ((58 - -640) - (-68 + (-17 + -22))) = ((58 - -640) - (-68 + -39)) = (698 - (-68 + -39)) = (698 - -107) = 805.\n(Final response) So the answer is 805.", "correct_answer": "805", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 298, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((9 + 0 * -1 - 7 * -4 * -9) + (4 - -6 + -5 - 4 * 5 + 8)) - ((6 + -1 + 8 - -6 + -2 - -3) * (0 * 7 * 0 * 1 * 7 + 0))) + (((1 - 9 + 1 - -2 + 4 - -2) - (1 + 5 * 7 - 5 - 3 - -7)) - ((5 - 3 * 2 + 3 + 8 - 3) * (8 + -1 * 1 - -2 + 8 - 9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) - (C * D)) + ((E - F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (9 + 0 * -1 - 7 * -4 * -9), B = (4 - -6 + -5 - 4 * 5 + 8), C = (6 + -1 + 8 - -6 + -2 - -3), D = (0 * 7 * 0 * 1 * 7 + 0), E = (1 - 9 + 1 - -2 + 4 - -2), F = (1 + 5 * 7 - 5 - 3 - -7), G = (5 - 3 * 2 + 3 + 8 - 3) and H = (8 + -1 * 1 - -2 + 8 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + 0 * -1 - 7 * -4 * -9) = ((9 + (0 * -1)) - ((7 * -4) * -9)) = ((9 + 0) - ((7 * -4) * -9)) = ((9 + 0) - (-28 * -9)) = (9 - (-28 * -9)) = (9 - 252) = -243.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - -6 + -5 - 4 * 5 + 8) = ((((4 - -6) + -5) - (4 * 5)) + 8) = (((10 + -5) - (4 * 5)) + 8) = (((10 + -5) - 20) + 8) = ((5 - 20) + 8) = (-15 + 8) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + -1 + 8 - -6 + -2 - -3) = (((((6 + -1) + 8) - -6) + -2) - -3) = ((((5 + 8) - -6) + -2) - -3) = (((13 - -6) + -2) - -3) = ((19 + -2) - -3) = (17 - -3) = 20.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 * 7 * 0 * 1 * 7 + 0) = (((((0 * 7) * 0) * 1) * 7) + 0) = ((((0 * 0) * 1) * 7) + 0) = (((0 * 1) * 7) + 0) = ((0 * 7) + 0) = (0 + 0) = 0.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (1 - 9 + 1 - -2 + 4 - -2) = (((((1 - 9) + 1) - -2) + 4) - -2) = ((((-8 + 1) - -2) + 4) - -2) = (((-7 - -2) + 4) - -2) = ((-5 + 4) - -2) = (-1 - -2) = 1.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (1 + 5 * 7 - 5 - 3 - -7) = ((((1 + (5 * 7)) - 5) - 3) - -7) = ((((1 + 35) - 5) - 3) - -7) = (((36 - 5) - 3) - -7) = ((31 - 3) - -7) = (28 - -7) = 35.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (5 - 3 * 2 + 3 + 8 - 3) = ((((5 - (3 * 2)) + 3) + 8) - 3) = ((((5 - 6) + 3) + 8) - 3) = (((-1 + 3) + 8) - 3) = ((2 + 8) - 3) = (10 - 3) = 7.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 + -1 * 1 - -2 + 8 - 9) = ((((8 + (-1 * 1)) - -2) + 8) - 9) = ((((8 + -1) - -2) + 8) - 9) = (((7 - -2) + 8) - 9) = ((9 + 8) - 9) = (17 - 9) = 8.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) - (C * D)) + ((E - F) - (G * H))) = (((-243 + -7) - (20 * 0)) + ((1 - 35) - (7 * 8))) = ((-250 - (20 * 0)) + ((1 - 35) - (7 * 8))) = ((-250 - 0) + ((1 - 35) - (7 * 8))) = ((-250 - 0) + (-34 - (7 * 8))) = ((-250 - 0) + (-34 - 56)) = (-250 + (-34 - 56)) = (-250 + -90) = -340.\n(Final response) So the answer is -340.", "correct_answer": "-340", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 337, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((9 - 0 - -1 - 0 + 6) * (-6 - 0 - -8 + 9 - 2)) - ((-3 + 1 * 3 - 3 * 7) - (6 - 9 - 8 - 0 - -4))) + (((-3 * -9 - 3 + 5 * 8) * (-8 - -5 - 9 * -3 - -7)) + ((3 * -8 * -6 + 1 - -8) - (8 * -8 * -4 * 0 + -4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C - D)) + ((E * F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (9 - 0 - -1 - 0 + 6), B = (-6 - 0 - -8 + 9 - 2), C = (-3 + 1 * 3 - 3 * 7), D = (6 - 9 - 8 - 0 - -4), E = (-3 * -9 - 3 + 5 * 8), F = (-8 - -5 - 9 * -3 - -7), G = (3 * -8 * -6 + 1 - -8) and H = (8 * -8 * -4 * 0 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - 0 - -1 - 0 + 6) = ((((9 - 0) - -1) - 0) + 6) = (((9 - -1) - 0) + 6) = ((10 - 0) + 6) = (10 + 6) = 16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - 0 - -8 + 9 - 2) = ((((-6 - 0) - -8) + 9) - 2) = (((-6 - -8) + 9) - 2) = ((2 + 9) - 2) = (11 - 2) = 9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + 1 * 3 - 3 * 7) = ((-3 + (1 * 3)) - (3 * 7)) = ((-3 + 3) - (3 * 7)) = ((-3 + 3) - 21) = (0 - 21) = -21.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 - 9 - 8 - 0 - -4) = ((((6 - 9) - 8) - 0) - -4) = (((-3 - 8) - 0) - -4) = ((-11 - 0) - -4) = (-11 - -4) = -7.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-3 * -9 - 3 + 5 * 8) = (((-3 * -9) - 3) + (5 * 8)) = ((27 - 3) + (5 * 8)) = ((27 - 3) + 40) = (24 + 40) = 64.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-8 - -5 - 9 * -3 - -7) = (((-8 - -5) - (9 * -3)) - -7) = ((-3 - (9 * -3)) - -7) = ((-3 - -27) - -7) = (24 - -7) = 31.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 * -8 * -6 + 1 - -8) = ((((3 * -8) * -6) + 1) - -8) = (((-24 * -6) + 1) - -8) = ((144 + 1) - -8) = (145 - -8) = 153.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 * -8 * -4 * 0 + -4) = ((((8 * -8) * -4) * 0) + -4) = (((-64 * -4) * 0) + -4) = ((256 * 0) + -4) = (0 + -4) = -4.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C - D)) + ((E * F) + (G - H))) = (((16 * 9) - (-21 - -7)) + ((64 * 31) + (153 - -4))) = ((144 - (-21 - -7)) + ((64 * 31) + (153 - -4))) = ((144 - -14) + ((64 * 31) + (153 - -4))) = ((144 - -14) + (1984 + (153 - -4))) = ((144 - -14) + (1984 + 157)) = (158 + (1984 + 157)) = (158 + 2141) = 2299.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2299.", "correct_answer": "2299", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 302, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - 9 - 0 * 9) - (-1 - 1 - -3 * 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 - 9 - 0 * 9) and B = (-1 - 1 - -3 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - 9 - 0 * 9) = ((1 - 9) - (0 * 9)) = (-8 - (0 * 9)) = (-8 - 0) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 1 - -3 * 5) = ((-1 - 1) - (-3 * 5)) = (-2 - (-3 * 5)) = (-2 - -15) = 13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-8 - 13) = -21.\n(Final response) So the answer is -21.", "correct_answer": "-21", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 208, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 + -6 * 4) - (-2 * 5 * 9)) + ((8 - 7 - 5) + (8 * 3 + 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-4 + -6 * 4), B = (-2 * 5 * 9), C = (8 - 7 - 5) and D = (8 * 3 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -6 * 4) = (-4 + (-6 * 4)) = (-4 + -24) = -28.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * 5 * 9) = ((-2 * 5) * 9) = (-10 * 9) = -90.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 - 7 - 5) = ((8 - 7) - 5) = (1 - 5) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * 3 + 8) = ((8 * 3) + 8) = (24 + 8) = 32.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-28 - -90) + (-4 + 32)) = (62 + (-4 + 32)) = (62 + 28) = 90.\n(Final response) So the answer is 90.", "correct_answer": "90", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 351, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * 4 * -6 * 1) - (1 * 1 - 7 + -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (9 * 4 * -6 * 1) and B = (1 * 1 - 7 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 4 * -6 * 1) = (((9 * 4) * -6) * 1) = ((36 * -6) * 1) = (-216 * 1) = -216.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 1 - 7 + -8) = (((1 * 1) - 7) + -8) = ((1 - 7) + -8) = (-6 + -8) = -14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-216 - -14) = -202.\n(Final response) So the answer is -202.", "correct_answer": "-202", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 215, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 + 6 * 4 * -9) * (5 + 7 - -4 + 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (1 + 6 * 4 * -9) and B = (5 + 7 - -4 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 6 * 4 * -9) = (1 + ((6 * 4) * -9)) = (1 + (24 * -9)) = (1 + -216) = -215.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 7 - -4 + 6) = (((5 + 7) - -4) + 6) = ((12 - -4) + 6) = (16 + 6) = 22.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-215 * 22) = -4730.\n(Final response) So the answer is -4730.", "correct_answer": "-4730", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 288, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 + 1 + 5 + 0) * (-8 - -6 * 1 - 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (7 + 1 + 5 + 0) and B = (-8 - -6 * 1 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 1 + 5 + 0) = (((7 + 1) + 5) + 0) = ((8 + 5) + 0) = (13 + 0) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - -6 * 1 - 1) = ((-8 - (-6 * 1)) - 1) = ((-8 - -6) - 1) = (-2 - 1) = -3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (13 * -3) = -39.\n(Final response) So the answer is -39.", "correct_answer": "-39", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 278, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-1 * 4 + 9 * 1 * -8 + -5) * (2 - -8 * 2 + 6 * -9 - 5)) + ((-9 + 6 * 0 + 5 * 8 + 6) * (-3 * -3 - 4 + -8 + -9 * 9))) * (((7 * -4 - -6 - -4 + -7 - -1) + (-5 + 3 - -4 - -7 * 8 + 7)) * ((5 - 2 * 0 * -9 + -4 + 7) + (1 * 5 + 3 + -4 - 7 - -8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C * D)) * ((E + F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (-1 * 4 + 9 * 1 * -8 + -5), B = (2 - -8 * 2 + 6 * -9 - 5), C = (-9 + 6 * 0 + 5 * 8 + 6), D = (-3 * -3 - 4 + -8 + -9 * 9), E = (7 * -4 - -6 - -4 + -7 - -1), F = (-5 + 3 - -4 - -7 * 8 + 7), G = (5 - 2 * 0 * -9 + -4 + 7) and H = (1 * 5 + 3 + -4 - 7 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 4 + 9 * 1 * -8 + -5) = (((-1 * 4) + ((9 * 1) * -8)) + -5) = ((-4 + ((9 * 1) * -8)) + -5) = ((-4 + (9 * -8)) + -5) = ((-4 + -72) + -5) = (-76 + -5) = -81.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -8 * 2 + 6 * -9 - 5) = (((2 - (-8 * 2)) + (6 * -9)) - 5) = (((2 - -16) + (6 * -9)) - 5) = (((2 - -16) + -54) - 5) = ((18 + -54) - 5) = (-36 - 5) = -41.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + 6 * 0 + 5 * 8 + 6) = (((-9 + (6 * 0)) + (5 * 8)) + 6) = (((-9 + 0) + (5 * 8)) + 6) = (((-9 + 0) + 40) + 6) = ((-9 + 40) + 6) = (31 + 6) = 37.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * -3 - 4 + -8 + -9 * 9) = ((((-3 * -3) - 4) + -8) + (-9 * 9)) = (((9 - 4) + -8) + (-9 * 9)) = (((9 - 4) + -8) + -81) = ((5 + -8) + -81) = (-3 + -81) = -84.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (7 * -4 - -6 - -4 + -7 - -1) = (((((7 * -4) - -6) - -4) + -7) - -1) = ((((-28 - -6) - -4) + -7) - -1) = (((-22 - -4) + -7) - -1) = ((-18 + -7) - -1) = (-25 - -1) = -24.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-5 + 3 - -4 - -7 * 8 + 7) = ((((-5 + 3) - -4) - (-7 * 8)) + 7) = (((-2 - -4) - (-7 * 8)) + 7) = (((-2 - -4) - -56) + 7) = ((2 - -56) + 7) = (58 + 7) = 65.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (5 - 2 * 0 * -9 + -4 + 7) = (((5 - ((2 * 0) * -9)) + -4) + 7) = (((5 - (0 * -9)) + -4) + 7) = (((5 - 0) + -4) + 7) = ((5 + -4) + 7) = (1 + 7) = 8.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (1 * 5 + 3 + -4 - 7 - -8) = (((((1 * 5) + 3) + -4) - 7) - -8) = ((((5 + 3) + -4) - 7) - -8) = (((8 + -4) - 7) - -8) = ((4 - 7) - -8) = (-3 - -8) = 5.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C * D)) * ((E + F) * (G + H))) = (((-81 * -41) + (37 * -84)) * ((-24 + 65) * (8 + 5))) = ((3321 + (37 * -84)) * ((-24 + 65) * (8 + 5))) = ((3321 + -3108) * ((-24 + 65) * (8 + 5))) = ((3321 + -3108) * (41 * (8 + 5))) = ((3321 + -3108) * (41 * 13)) = (213 * (41 * 13)) = (213 * 533) = 113529.\n(Final response) So the answer is 113529.", "correct_answer": "113529", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 347, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 + -4 - 2) * (0 - -4 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 + -4 - 2) and B = (0 - -4 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + -4 - 2) = ((-5 + -4) - 2) = (-9 - 2) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - -4 * -2) = (0 - (-4 * -2)) = (0 - 8) = -8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-11 * -8) = 88.\n(Final response) So the answer is 88.", "correct_answer": "88", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 109, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 - 5 + -3) + (9 - 8 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-3 - 5 + -3) and B = (9 - 8 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - 5 + -3) = ((-3 - 5) + -3) = (-8 + -3) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - 8 * -3) = (9 - (8 * -3)) = (9 - -24) = 33.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-11 + 33) = 22.\n(Final response) So the answer is 22.", "correct_answer": "22", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 118, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((4 * 7 - -8 * 9 * 2) - (-6 + -7 * -5 * 9 * -5)) - ((-8 * 6 * -6 - 5 * 5) - (6 + -5 - -6 - 0 - -9))) - (((0 + 3 - -8 - 1 + 1) * (3 - 4 - 5 + 0 + -1)) - ((-4 + -7 + 2 - -6 - -2) - (-8 - -6 - -4 * 5 * -5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C - D)) - ((E * F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (4 * 7 - -8 * 9 * 2), B = (-6 + -7 * -5 * 9 * -5), C = (-8 * 6 * -6 - 5 * 5), D = (6 + -5 - -6 - 0 - -9), E = (0 + 3 - -8 - 1 + 1), F = (3 - 4 - 5 + 0 + -1), G = (-4 + -7 + 2 - -6 - -2) and H = (-8 - -6 - -4 * 5 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 7 - -8 * 9 * 2) = ((4 * 7) - ((-8 * 9) * 2)) = (28 - ((-8 * 9) * 2)) = (28 - (-72 * 2)) = (28 - -144) = 172.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -7 * -5 * 9 * -5) = (-6 + (((-7 * -5) * 9) * -5)) = (-6 + ((35 * 9) * -5)) = (-6 + (315 * -5)) = (-6 + -1575) = -1581.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * 6 * -6 - 5 * 5) = (((-8 * 6) * -6) - (5 * 5)) = ((-48 * -6) - (5 * 5)) = ((-48 * -6) - 25) = (288 - 25) = 263.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + -5 - -6 - 0 - -9) = ((((6 + -5) - -6) - 0) - -9) = (((1 - -6) - 0) - -9) = ((7 - 0) - -9) = (7 - -9) = 16.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 + 3 - -8 - 1 + 1) = ((((0 + 3) - -8) - 1) + 1) = (((3 - -8) - 1) + 1) = ((11 - 1) + 1) = (10 + 1) = 11.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (3 - 4 - 5 + 0 + -1) = ((((3 - 4) - 5) + 0) + -1) = (((-1 - 5) + 0) + -1) = ((-6 + 0) + -1) = (-6 + -1) = -7.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-4 + -7 + 2 - -6 - -2) = ((((-4 + -7) + 2) - -6) - -2) = (((-11 + 2) - -6) - -2) = ((-9 - -6) - -2) = (-3 - -2) = -1.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 - -6 - -4 * 5 * -5) = ((-8 - -6) - ((-4 * 5) * -5)) = (-2 - ((-4 * 5) * -5)) = (-2 - (-20 * -5)) = (-2 - 100) = -102.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C - D)) - ((E * F) - (G - H))) = (((172 - -1581) - (263 - 16)) - ((11 * -7) - (-1 - -102))) = ((1753 - (263 - 16)) - ((11 * -7) - (-1 - -102))) = ((1753 - 247) - ((11 * -7) - (-1 - -102))) = ((1753 - 247) - (-77 - (-1 - -102))) = ((1753 - 247) - (-77 - 101)) = (1506 - (-77 - 101)) = (1506 - -178) = 1684.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1684.", "correct_answer": "1684", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 301, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 * -8 + -7) - (9 - -3 - -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-2 * -8 + -7) and B = (9 - -3 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * -8 + -7) = ((-2 * -8) + -7) = (16 + -7) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - -3 - -1) = ((9 - -3) - -1) = (12 - -1) = 13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (9 - 13) = -4.\n(Final response) So the answer is -4.", "correct_answer": "-4", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 137, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 - 2 + 0) - (4 * 7 - 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-7 - 2 + 0) and B = (4 * 7 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - 2 + 0) = ((-7 - 2) + 0) = (-9 + 0) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 7 - 9) = ((4 * 7) - 9) = (28 - 9) = 19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-9 - 19) = -28.\n(Final response) So the answer is -28.", "correct_answer": "-28", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 106, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 + 2 * -5) * (0 - 9 + -6)) - ((8 * -7 + 6) + (1 - 3 * -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (8 + 2 * -5), B = (0 - 9 + -6), C = (8 * -7 + 6) and D = (1 - 3 * -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 2 * -5) = (8 + (2 * -5)) = (8 + -10) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 9 + -6) = ((0 - 9) + -6) = (-9 + -6) = -15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -7 + 6) = ((8 * -7) + 6) = (-56 + 6) = -50.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 - 3 * -4) = (1 - (3 * -4)) = (1 - -12) = 13.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-2 * -15) - (-50 + 13)) = (30 - (-50 + 13)) = (30 - -37) = 67.\n(Final response) So the answer is 67.", "correct_answer": "67", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 306, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 * 1 * 7) * (-7 + -5 - -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (2 * 1 * 7) and B = (-7 + -5 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 1 * 7) = ((2 * 1) * 7) = (2 * 7) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -5 - -3) = ((-7 + -5) - -3) = (-12 - -3) = -9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (14 * -9) = -126.\n(Final response) So the answer is -126.", "correct_answer": "-126", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 8, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 - 1 + -2 - -5 - -5) * (2 * -3 * -6 * 4 * 8)) - ((-3 * -9 - 9 * -4 - 3) * (-4 + 5 + 6 + 3 + 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-6 - 1 + -2 - -5 - -5), B = (2 * -3 * -6 * 4 * 8), C = (-3 * -9 - 9 * -4 - 3) and D = (-4 + 5 + 6 + 3 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 1 + -2 - -5 - -5) = ((((-6 - 1) + -2) - -5) - -5) = (((-7 + -2) - -5) - -5) = ((-9 - -5) - -5) = (-4 - -5) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * -3 * -6 * 4 * 8) = ((((2 * -3) * -6) * 4) * 8) = (((-6 * -6) * 4) * 8) = ((36 * 4) * 8) = (144 * 8) = 1152.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 * -9 - 9 * -4 - 3) = (((-3 * -9) - (9 * -4)) - 3) = ((27 - (9 * -4)) - 3) = ((27 - -36) - 3) = (63 - 3) = 60.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + 5 + 6 + 3 + 2) = ((((-4 + 5) + 6) + 3) + 2) = (((1 + 6) + 3) + 2) = ((7 + 3) + 2) = (10 + 2) = 12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((1 * 1152) - (60 * 12)) = (1152 - (60 * 12)) = (1152 - 720) = 432.\n(Final response) So the answer is 432.", "correct_answer": "432", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 187, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 - 6 * 6) - (7 - -3 * 0)) * ((-1 - 7 + -1) + (-3 * -2 + 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-2 - 6 * 6), B = (7 - -3 * 0), C = (-1 - 7 + -1) and D = (-3 * -2 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - 6 * 6) = (-2 - (6 * 6)) = (-2 - 36) = -38.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - -3 * 0) = (7 - (-3 * 0)) = (7 - 0) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 - 7 + -1) = ((-1 - 7) + -1) = (-8 + -1) = -9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * -2 + 4) = ((-3 * -2) + 4) = (6 + 4) = 10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((-38 - 7) * (-9 + 10)) = (-45 * (-9 + 10)) = (-45 * 1) = -45.\n(Final response) So the answer is -45.", "correct_answer": "-45", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 309, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 + -5 * 5 - 2) + (-9 - 8 - -4 + 7)) - ((5 + -8 * 9 * -2) - (-9 + 1 - -1 - -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (6 + -5 * 5 - 2), B = (-9 - 8 - -4 + 7), C = (5 + -8 * 9 * -2) and D = (-9 + 1 - -1 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + -5 * 5 - 2) = ((6 + (-5 * 5)) - 2) = ((6 + -25) - 2) = (-19 - 2) = -21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 8 - -4 + 7) = (((-9 - 8) - -4) + 7) = ((-17 - -4) + 7) = (-13 + 7) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 + -8 * 9 * -2) = (5 + ((-8 * 9) * -2)) = (5 + (-72 * -2)) = (5 + 144) = 149.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 + 1 - -1 - -7) = (((-9 + 1) - -1) - -7) = ((-8 - -1) - -7) = (-7 - -7) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((-21 + -6) - (149 - 0)) = (-27 - (149 - 0)) = (-27 - 149) = -176.\n(Final response) So the answer is -176.", "correct_answer": "-176", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 556, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((0 - -4 - 0 + -7 + 7) + (0 + -9 * 0 - 6 * 8)) * ((4 - -2 * 7 + -5 * 6) - (7 * 5 - -2 + -1 * -1))) - (((1 * -6 * -1 * 9 + 6) - (-7 - 1 + 7 * 2 + 1)) * ((-4 + 5 - 9 - 5 * 7) + (-9 - 9 - 6 - -8 + -3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C - D)) - ((E - F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (0 - -4 - 0 + -7 + 7), B = (0 + -9 * 0 - 6 * 8), C = (4 - -2 * 7 + -5 * 6), D = (7 * 5 - -2 + -1 * -1), E = (1 * -6 * -1 * 9 + 6), F = (-7 - 1 + 7 * 2 + 1), G = (-4 + 5 - 9 - 5 * 7) and H = (-9 - 9 - 6 - -8 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - -4 - 0 + -7 + 7) = ((((0 - -4) - 0) + -7) + 7) = (((4 - 0) + -7) + 7) = ((4 + -7) + 7) = (-3 + 7) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -9 * 0 - 6 * 8) = ((0 + (-9 * 0)) - (6 * 8)) = ((0 + 0) - (6 * 8)) = ((0 + 0) - 48) = (0 - 48) = -48.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - -2 * 7 + -5 * 6) = ((4 - (-2 * 7)) + (-5 * 6)) = ((4 - -14) + (-5 * 6)) = ((4 - -14) + -30) = (18 + -30) = -12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 * 5 - -2 + -1 * -1) = (((7 * 5) - -2) + (-1 * -1)) = ((35 - -2) + (-1 * -1)) = ((35 - -2) + 1) = (37 + 1) = 38.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (1 * -6 * -1 * 9 + 6) = ((((1 * -6) * -1) * 9) + 6) = (((-6 * -1) * 9) + 6) = ((6 * 9) + 6) = (54 + 6) = 60.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-7 - 1 + 7 * 2 + 1) = (((-7 - 1) + (7 * 2)) + 1) = ((-8 + (7 * 2)) + 1) = ((-8 + 14) + 1) = (6 + 1) = 7.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-4 + 5 - 9 - 5 * 7) = (((-4 + 5) - 9) - (5 * 7)) = ((1 - 9) - (5 * 7)) = ((1 - 9) - 35) = (-8 - 35) = -43.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-9 - 9 - 6 - -8 + -3) = ((((-9 - 9) - 6) - -8) + -3) = (((-18 - 6) - -8) + -3) = ((-24 - -8) + -3) = (-16 + -3) = -19.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C - D)) - ((E - F) * (G + H))) = (((4 + -48) * (-12 - 38)) - ((60 - 7) * (-43 + -19))) = ((-44 * (-12 - 38)) - ((60 - 7) * (-43 + -19))) = ((-44 * -50) - ((60 - 7) * (-43 + -19))) = ((-44 * -50) - (53 * (-43 + -19))) = ((-44 * -50) - (53 * -62)) = (2200 - (53 * -62)) = (2200 - -3286) = 5486.\n(Final response) So the answer is 5486.", "correct_answer": "5486", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 317, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - 0 - 4) - (-5 + -4 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-2 - 0 - 4) and B = (-5 + -4 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - 0 - 4) = ((-2 - 0) - 4) = (-2 - 4) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + -4 + -1) = ((-5 + -4) + -1) = (-9 + -1) = -10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-6 - -10) = 4.\n(Final response) So the answer is 4.", "correct_answer": "4", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 9, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 + 9 * 9 * 4) * (0 * 1 - -8 * 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (3 + 9 * 9 * 4) and B = (0 * 1 - -8 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + 9 * 9 * 4) = (3 + ((9 * 9) * 4)) = (3 + (81 * 4)) = (3 + 324) = 327.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 1 - -8 * 9) = ((0 * 1) - (-8 * 9)) = (0 - (-8 * 9)) = (0 - -72) = 72.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (327 * 72) = 23544.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23544.", "correct_answer": "23544", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 291, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + 7 - 6) + (-8 + 4 * 9)) + ((7 * 0 - -3) + (-4 + -8 - 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-7 + 7 - 6), B = (-8 + 4 * 9), C = (7 * 0 - -3) and D = (-4 + -8 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 7 - 6) = ((-7 + 7) - 6) = (0 - 6) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 4 * 9) = (-8 + (4 * 9)) = (-8 + 36) = 28.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 * 0 - -3) = ((7 * 0) - -3) = (0 - -3) = 3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + -8 - 7) = ((-4 + -8) - 7) = (-12 - 7) = -19.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((-6 + 28) + (3 + -19)) = (22 + (3 + -19)) = (22 + -16) = 6.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6.", "correct_answer": "6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 378, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((8 * -2 + 4) + (2 - -9 * -4)) * ((8 * 7 + -8) * (0 - 2 + 4))) * (((0 * -2 + 3) - (-2 * -5 + 1)) + ((-9 * -4 - 7) + (8 + -3 * 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (8 * -2 + 4), B = (2 - -9 * -4), C = (8 * 7 + -8), D = (0 - 2 + 4), E = (0 * -2 + 3), F = (-2 * -5 + 1), G = (-9 * -4 - 7) and H = (8 + -3 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * -2 + 4) = ((8 * -2) + 4) = (-16 + 4) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -9 * -4) = (2 - (-9 * -4)) = (2 - 36) = -34.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * 7 + -8) = ((8 * 7) + -8) = (56 + -8) = 48.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 - 2 + 4) = ((0 - 2) + 4) = (-2 + 4) = 2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 * -2 + 3) = ((0 * -2) + 3) = (0 + 3) = 3.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-2 * -5 + 1) = ((-2 * -5) + 1) = (10 + 1) = 11.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-9 * -4 - 7) = ((-9 * -4) - 7) = (36 - 7) = 29.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 + -3 * 3) = (8 + (-3 * 3)) = (8 + -9) = -1.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((-12 + -34) * (48 * 2)) * ((3 - 11) + (29 + -1))) = ((-46 * (48 * 2)) * ((3 - 11) + (29 + -1))) = ((-46 * 96) * ((3 - 11) + (29 + -1))) = ((-46 * 96) * (-8 + (29 + -1))) = ((-46 * 96) * (-8 + 28)) = (-4416 * (-8 + 28)) = (-4416 * 20) = -88320.\n(Final response) So the answer is -88320.", "correct_answer": "-88320", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 251, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-2 + 2 * -9 - -3 * -2 + -9) - (1 - -1 * 5 - -1 - 3 * 3)) * ((9 + 8 + 3 + 7 - 5 - 4) - (6 * 7 + 4 * 0 + 1 + -6))) + (((9 + 1 - 2 + 7 + -4 + 0) * (6 * 3 * 6 - -1 + 6 - 0)) * ((-1 * 3 - -5 - 0 - 0 + 6) * (-3 * -2 - -2 - -7 * 3 - -6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C - D)) + ((E * F) * (G * H)))\", where A = (-2 + 2 * -9 - -3 * -2 + -9), B = (1 - -1 * 5 - -1 - 3 * 3), C = (9 + 8 + 3 + 7 - 5 - 4), D = (6 * 7 + 4 * 0 + 1 + -6), E = (9 + 1 - 2 + 7 + -4 + 0), F = (6 * 3 * 6 - -1 + 6 - 0), G = (-1 * 3 - -5 - 0 - 0 + 6) and H = (-3 * -2 - -2 - -7 * 3 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + 2 * -9 - -3 * -2 + -9) = (((-2 + (2 * -9)) - (-3 * -2)) + -9) = (((-2 + -18) - (-3 * -2)) + -9) = (((-2 + -18) - 6) + -9) = ((-20 - 6) + -9) = (-26 + -9) = -35.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - -1 * 5 - -1 - 3 * 3) = (((1 - (-1 * 5)) - -1) - (3 * 3)) = (((1 - -5) - -1) - (3 * 3)) = (((1 - -5) - -1) - 9) = ((6 - -1) - 9) = (7 - 9) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 + 8 + 3 + 7 - 5 - 4) = (((((9 + 8) + 3) + 7) - 5) - 4) = ((((17 + 3) + 7) - 5) - 4) = (((20 + 7) - 5) - 4) = ((27 - 5) - 4) = (22 - 4) = 18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 * 7 + 4 * 0 + 1 + -6) = ((((6 * 7) + (4 * 0)) + 1) + -6) = (((42 + (4 * 0)) + 1) + -6) = (((42 + 0) + 1) + -6) = ((42 + 1) + -6) = (43 + -6) = 37.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (9 + 1 - 2 + 7 + -4 + 0) = (((((9 + 1) - 2) + 7) + -4) + 0) = ((((10 - 2) + 7) + -4) + 0) = (((8 + 7) + -4) + 0) = ((15 + -4) + 0) = (11 + 0) = 11.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (6 * 3 * 6 - -1 + 6 - 0) = (((((6 * 3) * 6) - -1) + 6) - 0) = ((((18 * 6) - -1) + 6) - 0) = (((108 - -1) + 6) - 0) = ((109 + 6) - 0) = (115 - 0) = 115.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-1 * 3 - -5 - 0 - 0 + 6) = (((((-1 * 3) - -5) - 0) - 0) + 6) = ((((-3 - -5) - 0) - 0) + 6) = (((2 - 0) - 0) + 6) = ((2 - 0) + 6) = (2 + 6) = 8.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-3 * -2 - -2 - -7 * 3 - -6) = ((((-3 * -2) - -2) - (-7 * 3)) - -6) = (((6 - -2) - (-7 * 3)) - -6) = (((6 - -2) - -21) - -6) = ((8 - -21) - -6) = (29 - -6) = 35.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C - D)) + ((E * F) * (G * H))) = (((-35 - -2) * (18 - 37)) + ((11 * 115) * (8 * 35))) = ((-33 * (18 - 37)) + ((11 * 115) * (8 * 35))) = ((-33 * -19) + ((11 * 115) * (8 * 35))) = ((-33 * -19) + (1265 * (8 * 35))) = ((-33 * -19) + (1265 * 280)) = (627 + (1265 * 280)) = (627 + 354200) = 354827.\n(Final response) So the answer is 354827.", "correct_answer": "354827", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 344, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - 1 - 4) + (3 * 1 - -9)) - ((-3 + -6 - 5) * (-7 * -4 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (6 - 1 - 4), B = (3 * 1 - -9), C = (-3 + -6 - 5) and D = (-7 * -4 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - 1 - 4) = ((6 - 1) - 4) = (5 - 4) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 1 - -9) = ((3 * 1) - -9) = (3 - -9) = 12.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -6 - 5) = ((-3 + -6) - 5) = (-9 - 5) = -14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 * -4 * 5) = ((-7 * -4) * 5) = (28 * 5) = 140.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((1 + 12) - (-14 * 140)) = (13 - (-14 * 140)) = (13 - -1960) = 1973.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1973.", "correct_answer": "1973", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 357, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * -2 * -9 - 2 + -1) * (-2 - 3 * 3 * -5 - 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 * -2 * -9 - 2 + -1) and B = (-2 - 3 * 3 * -5 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * -2 * -9 - 2 + -1) = ((((5 * -2) * -9) - 2) + -1) = (((-10 * -9) - 2) + -1) = ((90 - 2) + -1) = (88 + -1) = 87.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 3 * 3 * -5 - 1) = ((-2 - ((3 * 3) * -5)) - 1) = ((-2 - (9 * -5)) - 1) = ((-2 - -45) - 1) = (43 - 1) = 42.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (87 * 42) = 3654.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3654.", "correct_answer": "3654", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 84, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 * 7 - 3 * 1) * (5 - -1 - 5 + 2)) - ((-9 - 9 - 3 - 7) + (-1 * 5 - -8 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (4 * 7 - 3 * 1), B = (5 - -1 - 5 + 2), C = (-9 - 9 - 3 - 7) and D = (-1 * 5 - -8 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 7 - 3 * 1) = ((4 * 7) - (3 * 1)) = (28 - (3 * 1)) = (28 - 3) = 25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - -1 - 5 + 2) = (((5 - -1) - 5) + 2) = ((6 - 5) + 2) = (1 + 2) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 - 9 - 3 - 7) = (((-9 - 9) - 3) - 7) = ((-18 - 3) - 7) = (-21 - 7) = -28.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * 5 - -8 + -8) = (((-1 * 5) - -8) + -8) = ((-5 - -8) + -8) = (3 + -8) = -5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((25 * 3) - (-28 + -5)) = (75 - (-28 + -5)) = (75 - -33) = 108.\n(Final response) So the answer is 108.", "correct_answer": "108", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 586, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 * -9 * -9 - -5) + (1 * 3 * -4 * 5)) + ((3 - -9 + -4 + 2) + (8 - -2 + 4 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (8 * -9 * -9 - -5), B = (1 * 3 * -4 * 5), C = (3 - -9 + -4 + 2) and D = (8 - -2 + 4 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * -9 * -9 - -5) = (((8 * -9) * -9) - -5) = ((-72 * -9) - -5) = (648 - -5) = 653.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 3 * -4 * 5) = (((1 * 3) * -4) * 5) = ((3 * -4) * 5) = (-12 * 5) = -60.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 - -9 + -4 + 2) = (((3 - -9) + -4) + 2) = ((12 + -4) + 2) = (8 + 2) = 10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - -2 + 4 + -8) = (((8 - -2) + 4) + -8) = ((10 + 4) + -8) = (14 + -8) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((653 + -60) + (10 + 6)) = (593 + (10 + 6)) = (593 + 16) = 609.\n(Final response) So the answer is 609.", "correct_answer": "609", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 518, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 - -1 - 7 + 2) + (0 * 6 - -2 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-4 - -1 - 7 + 2) and B = (0 * 6 - -2 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - -1 - 7 + 2) = (((-4 - -1) - 7) + 2) = ((-3 - 7) + 2) = (-10 + 2) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 6 - -2 + 8) = (((0 * 6) - -2) + 8) = ((0 - -2) + 8) = (2 + 8) = 10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-8 + 10) = 2.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2.", "correct_answer": "2", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 37, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + 2 * -1 - -8) - (-8 - 2 - -1 + 6)) - ((5 - -6 * 8 * -5) - (-8 * 1 * 7 * -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (1 + 2 * -1 - -8), B = (-8 - 2 - -1 + 6), C = (5 - -6 * 8 * -5) and D = (-8 * 1 * 7 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 2 * -1 - -8) = ((1 + (2 * -1)) - -8) = ((1 + -2) - -8) = (-1 - -8) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 2 - -1 + 6) = (((-8 - 2) - -1) + 6) = ((-10 - -1) + 6) = (-9 + 6) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 - -6 * 8 * -5) = (5 - ((-6 * 8) * -5)) = (5 - (-48 * -5)) = (5 - 240) = -235.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 * 1 * 7 * -7) = (((-8 * 1) * 7) * -7) = ((-8 * 7) * -7) = (-56 * -7) = 392.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((7 - -3) - (-235 - 392)) = (10 - (-235 - 392)) = (10 - -627) = 637.\n(Final response) So the answer is 637.", "correct_answer": "637", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 550, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + 2 * 0) + (-5 - -8 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (5 + 2 * 0) and B = (-5 - -8 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 2 * 0) = (5 + (2 * 0)) = (5 + 0) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -8 * 3) = (-5 - (-8 * 3)) = (-5 - -24) = 19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (5 + 19) = 24.\n(Final response) So the answer is 24.", "correct_answer": "24", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 75, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - 5 + -7) * (-9 * -2 - -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-2 - 5 + -7) and B = (-9 * -2 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - 5 + -7) = ((-2 - 5) + -7) = (-7 + -7) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -2 - -7) = ((-9 * -2) - -7) = (18 - -7) = 25.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-14 * 25) = -350.\n(Final response) So the answer is -350.", "correct_answer": "-350", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 102, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 + -7 - -8 + 5) - (-4 + 6 - -6 * 4)) - ((3 + -5 - 9 + -1) * (-5 + 0 - 5 + -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (5 + -7 - -8 + 5), B = (-4 + 6 - -6 * 4), C = (3 + -5 - 9 + -1) and D = (-5 + 0 - 5 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + -7 - -8 + 5) = (((5 + -7) - -8) + 5) = ((-2 - -8) + 5) = (6 + 5) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 6 - -6 * 4) = ((-4 + 6) - (-6 * 4)) = (2 - (-6 * 4)) = (2 - -24) = 26.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + -5 - 9 + -1) = (((3 + -5) - 9) + -1) = ((-2 - 9) + -1) = (-11 + -1) = -12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 + 0 - 5 + -2) = (((-5 + 0) - 5) + -2) = ((-5 - 5) + -2) = (-10 + -2) = -12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((11 - 26) - (-12 * -12)) = (-15 - (-12 * -12)) = (-15 - 144) = -159.\n(Final response) So the answer is -159.", "correct_answer": "-159", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 576, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 * -3 * -4 * 2 * -6 + -1) + (-8 + 0 - -4 + -5 + -2 + -7)) * ((4 + 5 - -1 * 9 * 1 * -6) + (0 * 0 - -2 + -8 - -8 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (5 * -3 * -4 * 2 * -6 + -1), B = (-8 + 0 - -4 + -5 + -2 + -7), C = (4 + 5 - -1 * 9 * 1 * -6) and D = (0 * 0 - -2 + -8 - -8 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * -3 * -4 * 2 * -6 + -1) = (((((5 * -3) * -4) * 2) * -6) + -1) = ((((-15 * -4) * 2) * -6) + -1) = (((60 * 2) * -6) + -1) = ((120 * -6) + -1) = (-720 + -1) = -721.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 0 - -4 + -5 + -2 + -7) = (((((-8 + 0) - -4) + -5) + -2) + -7) = ((((-8 - -4) + -5) + -2) + -7) = (((-4 + -5) + -2) + -7) = ((-9 + -2) + -7) = (-11 + -7) = -18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + 5 - -1 * 9 * 1 * -6) = ((4 + 5) - (((-1 * 9) * 1) * -6)) = (9 - (((-1 * 9) * 1) * -6)) = (9 - ((-9 * 1) * -6)) = (9 - (-9 * -6)) = (9 - 54) = -45.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 * 0 - -2 + -8 - -8 * 4) = ((((0 * 0) - -2) + -8) - (-8 * 4)) = (((0 - -2) + -8) - (-8 * 4)) = (((0 - -2) + -8) - -32) = ((2 + -8) - -32) = (-6 - -32) = 26.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-721 + -18) * (-45 + 26)) = (-739 * (-45 + 26)) = (-739 * -19) = 14041.\n(Final response) So the answer is 14041.", "correct_answer": "14041", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 221, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 * -1 - -9) * (-5 * 2 - -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-1 * -1 - -9) and B = (-5 * 2 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * -1 - -9) = ((-1 * -1) - -9) = (1 - -9) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 2 - -7) = ((-5 * 2) - -7) = (-10 - -7) = -3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (10 * -3) = -30.\n(Final response) So the answer is -30.", "correct_answer": "-30", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 9, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 + -6 - -7) + (3 - 5 * -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 + -6 - -7) and B = (3 - 5 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -6 - -7) = ((7 + -6) - -7) = (1 - -7) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - 5 * -8) = (3 - (5 * -8)) = (3 - -40) = 43.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (8 + 43) = 51.\n(Final response) So the answer is 51.", "correct_answer": "51", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 74, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-2 - -8 + 0 + -9) * (-8 + 0 - -3 + 6)) * ((-1 + -1 * 7 - 1) * (-1 * -2 + -4 * 1))) * (((-8 + -7 - 3 * 1) - (3 - 9 - 3 + 3)) * ((-4 - 9 - 4 - 7) - (6 - -5 * -4 - -5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) * (C * D)) * ((E - F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (-2 - -8 + 0 + -9), B = (-8 + 0 - -3 + 6), C = (-1 + -1 * 7 - 1), D = (-1 * -2 + -4 * 1), E = (-8 + -7 - 3 * 1), F = (3 - 9 - 3 + 3), G = (-4 - 9 - 4 - 7) and H = (6 - -5 * -4 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -8 + 0 + -9) = (((-2 - -8) + 0) + -9) = ((6 + 0) + -9) = (6 + -9) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 0 - -3 + 6) = (((-8 + 0) - -3) + 6) = ((-8 - -3) + 6) = (-5 + 6) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + -1 * 7 - 1) = ((-1 + (-1 * 7)) - 1) = ((-1 + -7) - 1) = (-8 - 1) = -9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * -2 + -4 * 1) = ((-1 * -2) + (-4 * 1)) = (2 + (-4 * 1)) = (2 + -4) = -2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-8 + -7 - 3 * 1) = ((-8 + -7) - (3 * 1)) = (-15 - (3 * 1)) = (-15 - 3) = -18.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (3 - 9 - 3 + 3) = (((3 - 9) - 3) + 3) = ((-6 - 3) + 3) = (-9 + 3) = -6.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-4 - 9 - 4 - 7) = (((-4 - 9) - 4) - 7) = ((-13 - 4) - 7) = (-17 - 7) = -24.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (6 - -5 * -4 - -5) = ((6 - (-5 * -4)) - -5) = ((6 - 20) - -5) = (-14 - -5) = -9.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) * (C * D)) * ((E - F) * (G - H))) = (((-3 * 1) * (-9 * -2)) * ((-18 - -6) * (-24 - -9))) = ((-3 * (-9 * -2)) * ((-18 - -6) * (-24 - -9))) = ((-3 * 18) * ((-18 - -6) * (-24 - -9))) = ((-3 * 18) * (-12 * (-24 - -9))) = ((-3 * 18) * (-12 * -15)) = (-54 * (-12 * -15)) = (-54 * 180) = -9720.\n(Final response) So the answer is -9720.", "correct_answer": "-9720", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 285, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * -4 * -9 * -7) - (-6 * 5 * 8 * -4)) - ((9 - 8 * -7 + -9) - (9 + -1 * 5 + -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-5 * -4 * -9 * -7), B = (-6 * 5 * 8 * -4), C = (9 - 8 * -7 + -9) and D = (9 + -1 * 5 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * -4 * -9 * -7) = (((-5 * -4) * -9) * -7) = ((20 * -9) * -7) = (-180 * -7) = 1260.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 5 * 8 * -4) = (((-6 * 5) * 8) * -4) = ((-30 * 8) * -4) = (-240 * -4) = 960.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - 8 * -7 + -9) = ((9 - (8 * -7)) + -9) = ((9 - -56) + -9) = (65 + -9) = 56.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -1 * 5 + -3) = ((9 + (-1 * 5)) + -3) = ((9 + -5) + -3) = (4 + -3) = 1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((1260 - 960) - (56 - 1)) = (300 - (56 - 1)) = (300 - 55) = 245.\n(Final response) So the answer is 245.", "correct_answer": "245", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 468, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 + -5 * -5) + (4 * -6 - 9)) - ((-9 * 6 + 8) * (7 * 9 * 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (3 + -5 * -5), B = (4 * -6 - 9), C = (-9 * 6 + 8) and D = (7 * 9 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + -5 * -5) = (3 + (-5 * -5)) = (3 + 25) = 28.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * -6 - 9) = ((4 * -6) - 9) = (-24 - 9) = -33.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * 6 + 8) = ((-9 * 6) + 8) = (-54 + 8) = -46.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 * 9 * 8) = ((7 * 9) * 8) = (63 * 8) = 504.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((28 + -33) - (-46 * 504)) = (-5 - (-46 * 504)) = (-5 - -23184) = 23179.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23179.", "correct_answer": "23179", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 307, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + 1 + 0) * (-4 * -5 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-1 + 1 + 0) and B = (-4 * -5 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + 1 + 0) = ((-1 + 1) + 0) = (0 + 0) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * -5 * 3) = ((-4 * -5) * 3) = (20 * 3) = 60.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (0 * 60) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 134, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 + 3 + 5 + -5 + -6 * 6) - (0 + -7 - 3 * -7 + 4 - 7)) + ((-3 - -8 - -2 - -4 * -8 - 1) - (-6 - -6 - -5 - -1 - 6 * 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (2 + 3 + 5 + -5 + -6 * 6), B = (0 + -7 - 3 * -7 + 4 - 7), C = (-3 - -8 - -2 - -4 * -8 - 1) and D = (-6 - -6 - -5 - -1 - 6 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + 3 + 5 + -5 + -6 * 6) = ((((2 + 3) + 5) + -5) + (-6 * 6)) = (((5 + 5) + -5) + (-6 * 6)) = (((5 + 5) + -5) + -36) = ((10 + -5) + -36) = (5 + -36) = -31.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -7 - 3 * -7 + 4 - 7) = ((((0 + -7) - (3 * -7)) + 4) - 7) = (((-7 - (3 * -7)) + 4) - 7) = (((-7 - -21) + 4) - 7) = ((14 + 4) - 7) = (18 - 7) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - -8 - -2 - -4 * -8 - 1) = ((((-3 - -8) - -2) - (-4 * -8)) - 1) = (((5 - -2) - (-4 * -8)) - 1) = (((5 - -2) - 32) - 1) = ((7 - 32) - 1) = (-25 - 1) = -26.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - -6 - -5 - -1 - 6 * 1) = ((((-6 - -6) - -5) - -1) - (6 * 1)) = (((0 - -5) - -1) - (6 * 1)) = (((0 - -5) - -1) - 6) = ((5 - -1) - 6) = (6 - 6) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-31 - 11) + (-26 - 0)) = (-42 + (-26 - 0)) = (-42 + -26) = -68.\n(Final response) So the answer is -68.", "correct_answer": "-68", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 223, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 - -3 + -9 * 3) - (-4 - 9 + 8 * -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (8 - -3 + -9 * 3) and B = (-4 - 9 + 8 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - -3 + -9 * 3) = ((8 - -3) + (-9 * 3)) = (11 + (-9 * 3)) = (11 + -27) = -16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - 9 + 8 * -5) = ((-4 - 9) + (8 * -5)) = (-13 + (8 * -5)) = (-13 + -40) = -53.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-16 - -53) = 37.\n(Final response) So the answer is 37.", "correct_answer": "37", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 30, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + 2 * 1 - 6) + (5 + 3 - -2 * 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (5 + 2 * 1 - 6) and B = (5 + 3 - -2 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 2 * 1 - 6) = ((5 + (2 * 1)) - 6) = ((5 + 2) - 6) = (7 - 6) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 3 - -2 * 2) = ((5 + 3) - (-2 * 2)) = (8 - (-2 * 2)) = (8 - -4) = 12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (1 + 12) = 13.\n(Final response) So the answer is 13.", "correct_answer": "13", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 244, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((3 * -9 - -9 * 6 * 2 + 6) - (2 * -8 * 2 * 7 * -1 + -3)) * ((5 - -4 - 2 - -6 - -7 * -2) * (-9 + -3 * -7 + 9 * 8 * 5))) - (((2 + 5 + 1 * 5 - -8 + -6) - (-1 - 6 + 2 * -8 * 4 * -9)) * ((3 - -8 + 7 - 4 - -6 - 6) + (1 * -2 * 4 * -3 * 1 + 9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C * D)) - ((E - F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (3 * -9 - -9 * 6 * 2 + 6), B = (2 * -8 * 2 * 7 * -1 + -3), C = (5 - -4 - 2 - -6 - -7 * -2), D = (-9 + -3 * -7 + 9 * 8 * 5), E = (2 + 5 + 1 * 5 - -8 + -6), F = (-1 - 6 + 2 * -8 * 4 * -9), G = (3 - -8 + 7 - 4 - -6 - 6) and H = (1 * -2 * 4 * -3 * 1 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -9 - -9 * 6 * 2 + 6) = (((3 * -9) - ((-9 * 6) * 2)) + 6) = ((-27 - ((-9 * 6) * 2)) + 6) = ((-27 - (-54 * 2)) + 6) = ((-27 - -108) + 6) = (81 + 6) = 87.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * -8 * 2 * 7 * -1 + -3) = (((((2 * -8) * 2) * 7) * -1) + -3) = ((((-16 * 2) * 7) * -1) + -3) = (((-32 * 7) * -1) + -3) = ((-224 * -1) + -3) = (224 + -3) = 221.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 - -4 - 2 - -6 - -7 * -2) = ((((5 - -4) - 2) - -6) - (-7 * -2)) = (((9 - 2) - -6) - (-7 * -2)) = (((9 - 2) - -6) - 14) = ((7 - -6) - 14) = (13 - 14) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 + -3 * -7 + 9 * 8 * 5) = ((-9 + (-3 * -7)) + ((9 * 8) * 5)) = ((-9 + 21) + ((9 * 8) * 5)) = ((-9 + 21) + (72 * 5)) = (12 + (72 * 5)) = (12 + 360) = 372.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (2 + 5 + 1 * 5 - -8 + -6) = ((((2 + 5) + (1 * 5)) - -8) + -6) = (((7 + (1 * 5)) - -8) + -6) = (((7 + 5) - -8) + -6) = ((12 - -8) + -6) = (20 + -6) = 14.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-1 - 6 + 2 * -8 * 4 * -9) = ((-1 - 6) + (((2 * -8) * 4) * -9)) = (-7 + (((2 * -8) * 4) * -9)) = (-7 + ((-16 * 4) * -9)) = (-7 + (-64 * -9)) = (-7 + 576) = 569.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 - -8 + 7 - 4 - -6 - 6) = (((((3 - -8) + 7) - 4) - -6) - 6) = ((((11 + 7) - 4) - -6) - 6) = (((18 - 4) - -6) - 6) = ((14 - -6) - 6) = (20 - 6) = 14.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (1 * -2 * 4 * -3 * 1 + 9) = (((((1 * -2) * 4) * -3) * 1) + 9) = ((((-2 * 4) * -3) * 1) + 9) = (((-8 * -3) * 1) + 9) = ((24 * 1) + 9) = (24 + 9) = 33.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C * D)) - ((E - F) * (G + H))) = (((87 - 221) * (-1 * 372)) - ((14 - 569) * (14 + 33))) = ((-134 * (-1 * 372)) - ((14 - 569) * (14 + 33))) = ((-134 * -372) - ((14 - 569) * (14 + 33))) = ((-134 * -372) - (-555 * (14 + 33))) = ((-134 * -372) - (-555 * 47)) = (49848 - (-555 * 47)) = (49848 - -26085) = 75933.\n(Final response) So the answer is 75933.", "correct_answer": "75933", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 336, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 - 5 - -2 * -1) * (-9 - -9 * -7 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 - 5 - -2 * -1) and B = (-9 - -9 * -7 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - 5 - -2 * -1) = ((9 - 5) - (-2 * -1)) = (4 - (-2 * -1)) = (4 - 2) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - -9 * -7 - -2) = ((-9 - (-9 * -7)) - -2) = ((-9 - 63) - -2) = (-72 - -2) = -70.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (2 * -70) = -140.\n(Final response) So the answer is -140.", "correct_answer": "-140", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 209, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 - 7 * -1 + 0) * (5 + 5 * -8 + 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-9 - 7 * -1 + 0) and B = (5 + 5 * -8 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 7 * -1 + 0) = ((-9 - (7 * -1)) + 0) = ((-9 - -7) + 0) = (-2 + 0) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 5 * -8 + 6) = ((5 + (5 * -8)) + 6) = ((5 + -40) + 6) = (-35 + 6) = -29.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-2 * -29) = 58.\n(Final response) So the answer is 58.", "correct_answer": "58", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 267, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * 8 - 4 + 0 * 4 + 9) - (-5 * -7 + -2 + -5 + 7 + 4)) + ((-1 * -7 * 3 + -4 - -4 - 7) + (-6 * 5 - 8 * 8 * 5 + -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (3 * 8 - 4 + 0 * 4 + 9), B = (-5 * -7 + -2 + -5 + 7 + 4), C = (-1 * -7 * 3 + -4 - -4 - 7) and D = (-6 * 5 - 8 * 8 * 5 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 8 - 4 + 0 * 4 + 9) = ((((3 * 8) - 4) + (0 * 4)) + 9) = (((24 - 4) + (0 * 4)) + 9) = (((24 - 4) + 0) + 9) = ((20 + 0) + 9) = (20 + 9) = 29.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -7 + -2 + -5 + 7 + 4) = (((((-5 * -7) + -2) + -5) + 7) + 4) = ((((35 + -2) + -5) + 7) + 4) = (((33 + -5) + 7) + 4) = ((28 + 7) + 4) = (35 + 4) = 39.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * -7 * 3 + -4 - -4 - 7) = (((((-1 * -7) * 3) + -4) - -4) - 7) = ((((7 * 3) + -4) - -4) - 7) = (((21 + -4) - -4) - 7) = ((17 - -4) - 7) = (21 - 7) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * 5 - 8 * 8 * 5 + -5) = (((-6 * 5) - ((8 * 8) * 5)) + -5) = ((-30 - ((8 * 8) * 5)) + -5) = ((-30 - (64 * 5)) + -5) = ((-30 - 320) + -5) = (-350 + -5) = -355.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((29 - 39) + (14 + -355)) = (-10 + (14 + -355)) = (-10 + -341) = -351.\n(Final response) So the answer is -351.", "correct_answer": "-351", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 234, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 + 0 - 8 - -5) - (3 * 4 * 1 * -6)) + ((-2 * 3 * 0 + 3) + (-4 - 7 - -4 + -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-6 + 0 - 8 - -5), B = (3 * 4 * 1 * -6), C = (-2 * 3 * 0 + 3) and D = (-4 - 7 - -4 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 0 - 8 - -5) = (((-6 + 0) - 8) - -5) = ((-6 - 8) - -5) = (-14 - -5) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 4 * 1 * -6) = (((3 * 4) * 1) * -6) = ((12 * 1) * -6) = (12 * -6) = -72.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 * 3 * 0 + 3) = (((-2 * 3) * 0) + 3) = ((-6 * 0) + 3) = (0 + 3) = 3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - 7 - -4 + -5) = (((-4 - 7) - -4) + -5) = ((-11 - -4) + -5) = (-7 + -5) = -12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-9 - -72) + (3 + -12)) = (63 + (3 + -12)) = (63 + -9) = 54.\n(Final response) So the answer is 54.", "correct_answer": "54", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 535, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - -3 * 0 * -4) + (3 * 9 + -5 + -1)) + ((5 * -7 * -3 - 4) + (-7 * -1 + -6 + -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (1 - -3 * 0 * -4), B = (3 * 9 + -5 + -1), C = (5 * -7 * -3 - 4) and D = (-7 * -1 + -6 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -3 * 0 * -4) = (1 - ((-3 * 0) * -4)) = (1 - (0 * -4)) = (1 - 0) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 9 + -5 + -1) = (((3 * 9) + -5) + -1) = ((27 + -5) + -1) = (22 + -1) = 21.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 * -7 * -3 - 4) = (((5 * -7) * -3) - 4) = ((-35 * -3) - 4) = (105 - 4) = 101.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 * -1 + -6 + -4) = (((-7 * -1) + -6) + -4) = ((7 + -6) + -4) = (1 + -4) = -3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((1 + 21) + (101 + -3)) = (22 + (101 + -3)) = (22 + 98) = 120.\n(Final response) So the answer is 120.", "correct_answer": "120", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 578, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-7 - -7 + 5 - 7 * -1) - (-8 + 4 + 1 + -9 * -8)) + ((0 - -8 + -1 - 1 * -9) * (6 * 3 - -8 + -9 + 0))) * (((-8 - 9 - -7 * -1 * -8) * (-2 + -8 * -4 - -6 + -9)) + ((5 + 5 - 3 * 6 - 5) - (2 * 2 + -9 + -2 + -5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C * D)) * ((E * F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (-7 - -7 + 5 - 7 * -1), B = (-8 + 4 + 1 + -9 * -8), C = (0 - -8 + -1 - 1 * -9), D = (6 * 3 - -8 + -9 + 0), E = (-8 - 9 - -7 * -1 * -8), F = (-2 + -8 * -4 - -6 + -9), G = (5 + 5 - 3 * 6 - 5) and H = (2 * 2 + -9 + -2 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - -7 + 5 - 7 * -1) = (((-7 - -7) + 5) - (7 * -1)) = ((0 + 5) - (7 * -1)) = ((0 + 5) - -7) = (5 - -7) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 4 + 1 + -9 * -8) = (((-8 + 4) + 1) + (-9 * -8)) = ((-4 + 1) + (-9 * -8)) = ((-4 + 1) + 72) = (-3 + 72) = 69.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 - -8 + -1 - 1 * -9) = (((0 - -8) + -1) - (1 * -9)) = ((8 + -1) - (1 * -9)) = ((8 + -1) - -9) = (7 - -9) = 16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 * 3 - -8 + -9 + 0) = ((((6 * 3) - -8) + -9) + 0) = (((18 - -8) + -9) + 0) = ((26 + -9) + 0) = (17 + 0) = 17.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-8 - 9 - -7 * -1 * -8) = ((-8 - 9) - ((-7 * -1) * -8)) = (-17 - ((-7 * -1) * -8)) = (-17 - (7 * -8)) = (-17 - -56) = 39.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-2 + -8 * -4 - -6 + -9) = (((-2 + (-8 * -4)) - -6) + -9) = (((-2 + 32) - -6) + -9) = ((30 - -6) + -9) = (36 + -9) = 27.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (5 + 5 - 3 * 6 - 5) = (((5 + 5) - (3 * 6)) - 5) = ((10 - (3 * 6)) - 5) = ((10 - 18) - 5) = (-8 - 5) = -13.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (2 * 2 + -9 + -2 + -5) = ((((2 * 2) + -9) + -2) + -5) = (((4 + -9) + -2) + -5) = ((-5 + -2) + -5) = (-7 + -5) = -12.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C * D)) * ((E * F) + (G - H))) = (((12 - 69) + (16 * 17)) * ((39 * 27) + (-13 - -12))) = ((-57 + (16 * 17)) * ((39 * 27) + (-13 - -12))) = ((-57 + 272) * ((39 * 27) + (-13 - -12))) = ((-57 + 272) * (1053 + (-13 - -12))) = ((-57 + 272) * (1053 + -1)) = (215 * (1053 + -1)) = (215 * 1052) = 226180.\n(Final response) So the answer is 226180.", "correct_answer": "226180", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 328, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 + -8 * -7) + (-2 - -2 * -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (1 + -8 * -7) and B = (-2 - -2 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + -8 * -7) = (1 + (-8 * -7)) = (1 + 56) = 57.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - -2 * -1) = (-2 - (-2 * -1)) = (-2 - 2) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (57 + -4) = 53.\n(Final response) So the answer is 53.", "correct_answer": "53", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 83, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 + 2 * -9) + (-2 - 1 + 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (1 + 2 * -9) and B = (-2 - 1 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 2 * -9) = (1 + (2 * -9)) = (1 + -18) = -17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 1 + 3) = ((-2 - 1) + 3) = (-3 + 3) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-17 + 0) = -17.\n(Final response) So the answer is -17.", "correct_answer": "-17", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 40, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 - 8 + -7 * 8) * (-4 + 5 * 0 - -8)) + ((6 - -5 * -7 + -8) * (7 + 1 + 9 * 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-8 - 8 + -7 * 8), B = (-4 + 5 * 0 - -8), C = (6 - -5 * -7 + -8) and D = (7 + 1 + 9 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - 8 + -7 * 8) = ((-8 - 8) + (-7 * 8)) = (-16 + (-7 * 8)) = (-16 + -56) = -72.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 5 * 0 - -8) = ((-4 + (5 * 0)) - -8) = ((-4 + 0) - -8) = (-4 - -8) = 4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - -5 * -7 + -8) = ((6 - (-5 * -7)) + -8) = ((6 - 35) + -8) = (-29 + -8) = -37.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + 1 + 9 * 1) = ((7 + 1) + (9 * 1)) = (8 + (9 * 1)) = (8 + 9) = 17.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((-72 * 4) + (-37 * 17)) = (-288 + (-37 * 17)) = (-288 + -629) = -917.\n(Final response) So the answer is -917.", "correct_answer": "-917", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 592, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 + -3 - -8 * -9 * -9 * 5) - (-4 - -9 * -5 - 7 * -6 * 2)) * ((5 + 2 + -2 * -3 * 3 * -9) * (3 - 9 * -9 + -2 + -2 - -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-5 + -3 - -8 * -9 * -9 * 5), B = (-4 - -9 * -5 - 7 * -6 * 2), C = (5 + 2 + -2 * -3 * 3 * -9) and D = (3 - 9 * -9 + -2 + -2 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + -3 - -8 * -9 * -9 * 5) = ((-5 + -3) - (((-8 * -9) * -9) * 5)) = (-8 - (((-8 * -9) * -9) * 5)) = (-8 - ((72 * -9) * 5)) = (-8 - (-648 * 5)) = (-8 - -3240) = 3232.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - -9 * -5 - 7 * -6 * 2) = ((-4 - (-9 * -5)) - ((7 * -6) * 2)) = ((-4 - 45) - ((7 * -6) * 2)) = ((-4 - 45) - (-42 * 2)) = (-49 - (-42 * 2)) = (-49 - -84) = 35.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 + 2 + -2 * -3 * 3 * -9) = ((5 + 2) + (((-2 * -3) * 3) * -9)) = (7 + (((-2 * -3) * 3) * -9)) = (7 + ((6 * 3) * -9)) = (7 + (18 * -9)) = (7 + -162) = -155.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 - 9 * -9 + -2 + -2 - -2) = ((((3 - (9 * -9)) + -2) + -2) - -2) = ((((3 - -81) + -2) + -2) - -2) = (((84 + -2) + -2) - -2) = ((82 + -2) - -2) = (80 - -2) = 82.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((3232 - 35) * (-155 * 82)) = (3197 * (-155 * 82)) = (3197 * -12710) = -40633870.\n(Final response) So the answer is -40633870.", "correct_answer": "-40633870", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 217, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + 5 * 1 * 3) - (9 * -7 + 4 - -7)) * ((-3 * -7 + -9 + -4) * (-8 - 5 * 0 + 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-7 + 5 * 1 * 3), B = (9 * -7 + 4 - -7), C = (-3 * -7 + -9 + -4) and D = (-8 - 5 * 0 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 5 * 1 * 3) = (-7 + ((5 * 1) * 3)) = (-7 + (5 * 3)) = (-7 + 15) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * -7 + 4 - -7) = (((9 * -7) + 4) - -7) = ((-63 + 4) - -7) = (-59 - -7) = -52.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 * -7 + -9 + -4) = (((-3 * -7) + -9) + -4) = ((21 + -9) + -4) = (12 + -4) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - 5 * 0 + 8) = ((-8 - (5 * 0)) + 8) = ((-8 - 0) + 8) = (-8 + 8) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((8 - -52) * (8 * 0)) = (60 * (8 * 0)) = (60 * 0) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 583, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 - -7 * -3) - (7 + 2 + 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (3 - -7 * -3) and B = (7 + 2 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - -7 * -3) = (3 - (-7 * -3)) = (3 - 21) = -18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 2 + 6) = ((7 + 2) + 6) = (9 + 6) = 15.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-18 - 15) = -33.\n(Final response) So the answer is -33.", "correct_answer": "-33", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 122, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 - -9 + 4) - (0 * 6 + 6)) * ((-2 * 1 + -4) * (9 - 5 - 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-2 - -9 + 4), B = (0 * 6 + 6), C = (-2 * 1 + -4) and D = (9 - 5 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -9 + 4) = ((-2 - -9) + 4) = (7 + 4) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 6 + 6) = ((0 * 6) + 6) = (0 + 6) = 6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 * 1 + -4) = ((-2 * 1) + -4) = (-2 + -4) = -6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - 5 - 0) = ((9 - 5) - 0) = (4 - 0) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((11 - 6) * (-6 * 4)) = (5 * (-6 * 4)) = (5 * -24) = -120.\n(Final response) So the answer is -120.", "correct_answer": "-120", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 413, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 * -6 + 3 * 0) - (7 + 7 - -6 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-3 * -6 + 3 * 0) and B = (7 + 7 - -6 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * -6 + 3 * 0) = ((-3 * -6) + (3 * 0)) = (18 + (3 * 0)) = (18 + 0) = 18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 7 - -6 + -9) = (((7 + 7) - -6) + -9) = ((14 - -6) + -9) = (20 + -9) = 11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (18 - 11) = 7.\n(Final response) So the answer is 7.", "correct_answer": "7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 240, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 + 4 * -8 - 4 * -3 - 1) * (6 - -4 * -4 - -2 - -3 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (6 + 4 * -8 - 4 * -3 - 1) and B = (6 - -4 * -4 - -2 - -3 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 4 * -8 - 4 * -3 - 1) = (((6 + (4 * -8)) - (4 * -3)) - 1) = (((6 + -32) - (4 * -3)) - 1) = (((6 + -32) - -12) - 1) = ((-26 - -12) - 1) = (-14 - 1) = -15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - -4 * -4 - -2 - -3 * 4) = (((6 - (-4 * -4)) - -2) - (-3 * 4)) = (((6 - 16) - -2) - (-3 * 4)) = (((6 - 16) - -2) - -12) = ((-10 - -2) - -12) = (-8 - -12) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-15 * 4) = -60.\n(Final response) So the answer is -60.", "correct_answer": "-60", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 95, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((9 * 0 * -3 * 2 * 8) * (6 * -9 * 0 + 5 + 6)) + ((0 * 6 + -9 + -2 - -8) - (-2 * 3 * -5 + 8 - -7))) * (((-5 + 8 * -7 * -1 * -7) + (3 * -3 * 1 - -9 - -8)) + ((-7 + -6 * 7 - -4 * 7) + (4 + -4 * 7 - -6 * 4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C - D)) * ((E + F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (9 * 0 * -3 * 2 * 8), B = (6 * -9 * 0 + 5 + 6), C = (0 * 6 + -9 + -2 - -8), D = (-2 * 3 * -5 + 8 - -7), E = (-5 + 8 * -7 * -1 * -7), F = (3 * -3 * 1 - -9 - -8), G = (-7 + -6 * 7 - -4 * 7) and H = (4 + -4 * 7 - -6 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 0 * -3 * 2 * 8) = ((((9 * 0) * -3) * 2) * 8) = (((0 * -3) * 2) * 8) = ((0 * 2) * 8) = (0 * 8) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * -9 * 0 + 5 + 6) = ((((6 * -9) * 0) + 5) + 6) = (((-54 * 0) + 5) + 6) = ((0 + 5) + 6) = (5 + 6) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * 6 + -9 + -2 - -8) = ((((0 * 6) + -9) + -2) - -8) = (((0 + -9) + -2) - -8) = ((-9 + -2) - -8) = (-11 - -8) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * 3 * -5 + 8 - -7) = ((((-2 * 3) * -5) + 8) - -7) = (((-6 * -5) + 8) - -7) = ((30 + 8) - -7) = (38 - -7) = 45.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-5 + 8 * -7 * -1 * -7) = (-5 + (((8 * -7) * -1) * -7)) = (-5 + ((-56 * -1) * -7)) = (-5 + (56 * -7)) = (-5 + -392) = -397.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (3 * -3 * 1 - -9 - -8) = ((((3 * -3) * 1) - -9) - -8) = (((-9 * 1) - -9) - -8) = ((-9 - -9) - -8) = (0 - -8) = 8.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-7 + -6 * 7 - -4 * 7) = ((-7 + (-6 * 7)) - (-4 * 7)) = ((-7 + -42) - (-4 * 7)) = ((-7 + -42) - -28) = (-49 - -28) = -21.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (4 + -4 * 7 - -6 * 4) = ((4 + (-4 * 7)) - (-6 * 4)) = ((4 + -28) - (-6 * 4)) = ((4 + -28) - -24) = (-24 - -24) = 0.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C - D)) * ((E + F) + (G + H))) = (((0 * 11) + (-3 - 45)) * ((-397 + 8) + (-21 + 0))) = ((0 + (-3 - 45)) * ((-397 + 8) + (-21 + 0))) = ((0 + -48) * ((-397 + 8) + (-21 + 0))) = ((0 + -48) * (-389 + (-21 + 0))) = ((0 + -48) * (-389 + -21)) = (-48 * (-389 + -21)) = (-48 * -410) = 19680.\n(Final response) So the answer is 19680.", "correct_answer": "19680", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 323, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 + -3 * 4 * 9) - (8 * 0 + -2 - 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-9 + -3 * 4 * 9) and B = (8 * 0 + -2 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -3 * 4 * 9) = (-9 + ((-3 * 4) * 9)) = (-9 + (-12 * 9)) = (-9 + -108) = -117.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 0 + -2 - 0) = (((8 * 0) + -2) - 0) = ((0 + -2) - 0) = (-2 - 0) = -2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-117 - -2) = -115.\n(Final response) So the answer is -115.", "correct_answer": "-115", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 190, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 * 5 - -7) - (7 + 2 - 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 * 5 - -7) and B = (7 + 2 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 5 - -7) = ((-1 * 5) - -7) = (-5 - -7) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 2 - 4) = ((7 + 2) - 4) = (9 - 4) = 5.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (2 - 5) = -3.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3.", "correct_answer": "-3", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 82, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 * -1 * -9 + 0) + (8 * 4 * -6 - 9)) + ((-9 + 9 * 5 + 1) - (-5 - 0 - -3 + -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (1 * -1 * -9 + 0), B = (8 * 4 * -6 - 9), C = (-9 + 9 * 5 + 1) and D = (-5 - 0 - -3 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * -1 * -9 + 0) = (((1 * -1) * -9) + 0) = ((-1 * -9) + 0) = (9 + 0) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 4 * -6 - 9) = (((8 * 4) * -6) - 9) = ((32 * -6) - 9) = (-192 - 9) = -201.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + 9 * 5 + 1) = ((-9 + (9 * 5)) + 1) = ((-9 + 45) + 1) = (36 + 1) = 37.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - 0 - -3 + -7) = (((-5 - 0) - -3) + -7) = ((-5 - -3) + -7) = (-2 + -7) = -9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((9 + -201) + (37 - -9)) = (-192 + (37 - -9)) = (-192 + 46) = -146.\n(Final response) So the answer is -146.", "correct_answer": "-146", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 520, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 + 7 * 4) - (8 * 1 - -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-5 + 7 * 4) and B = (8 * 1 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + 7 * 4) = (-5 + (7 * 4)) = (-5 + 28) = 23.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 1 - -8) = ((8 * 1) - -8) = (8 - -8) = 16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (23 - 16) = 7.\n(Final response) So the answer is 7.", "correct_answer": "7", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 15, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 - 0 + -7 - 5) - (4 - -6 * -3 * -1)) * ((2 - -4 - 8 - -4) * (9 + -6 + 0 + -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C * D))\", where A = (5 - 0 + -7 - 5), B = (4 - -6 * -3 * -1), C = (2 - -4 - 8 - -4) and D = (9 + -6 + 0 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - 0 + -7 - 5) = (((5 - 0) + -7) - 5) = ((5 + -7) - 5) = (-2 - 5) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - -6 * -3 * -1) = (4 - ((-6 * -3) * -1)) = (4 - (18 * -1)) = (4 - -18) = 22.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - -4 - 8 - -4) = (((2 - -4) - 8) - -4) = ((6 - 8) - -4) = (-2 - -4) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -6 + 0 + -3) = (((9 + -6) + 0) + -3) = ((3 + 0) + -3) = (3 + -3) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C * D)) = ((-7 - 22) * (2 * 0)) = (-29 * (2 * 0)) = (-29 * 0) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 171, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + -7 - -6 - 6) - (2 * 0 + 2 * 2)) * ((-9 - 1 * -9 * 3) + (-8 - 0 * -9 * 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (7 + -7 - -6 - 6), B = (2 * 0 + 2 * 2), C = (-9 - 1 * -9 * 3) and D = (-8 - 0 * -9 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -7 - -6 - 6) = (((7 + -7) - -6) - 6) = ((0 - -6) - 6) = (6 - 6) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 0 + 2 * 2) = ((2 * 0) + (2 * 2)) = (0 + (2 * 2)) = (0 + 4) = 4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 - 1 * -9 * 3) = (-9 - ((1 * -9) * 3)) = (-9 - (-9 * 3)) = (-9 - -27) = 18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - 0 * -9 * 3) = (-8 - ((0 * -9) * 3)) = (-8 - (0 * 3)) = (-8 - 0) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((0 - 4) * (18 + -8)) = (-4 * (18 + -8)) = (-4 * 10) = -40.\n(Final response) So the answer is -40.", "correct_answer": "-40", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 151, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 * 5 * 4 * 4) + (5 + 5 + 7 + -9)) + ((8 - 8 + -1 - 3) * (4 * 3 + -7 + -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (8 * 5 * 4 * 4), B = (5 + 5 + 7 + -9), C = (8 - 8 + -1 - 3) and D = (4 * 3 + -7 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 5 * 4 * 4) = (((8 * 5) * 4) * 4) = ((40 * 4) * 4) = (160 * 4) = 640.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 5 + 7 + -9) = (((5 + 5) + 7) + -9) = ((10 + 7) + -9) = (17 + -9) = 8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 - 8 + -1 - 3) = (((8 - 8) + -1) - 3) = ((0 + -1) - 3) = (-1 - 3) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * 3 + -7 + -9) = (((4 * 3) + -7) + -9) = ((12 + -7) + -9) = (5 + -9) = -4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((640 + 8) + (-4 * -4)) = (648 + (-4 * -4)) = (648 + 16) = 664.\n(Final response) So the answer is 664.", "correct_answer": "664", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 514, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 * -8 * 0 * -3) - (-5 - -6 - -4 - -8)) + ((3 + -3 + -5 + 7) + (5 * -6 * 8 - -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-4 * -8 * 0 * -3), B = (-5 - -6 - -4 - -8), C = (3 + -3 + -5 + 7) and D = (5 * -6 * 8 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -8 * 0 * -3) = (((-4 * -8) * 0) * -3) = ((32 * 0) * -3) = (0 * -3) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -6 - -4 - -8) = (((-5 - -6) - -4) - -8) = ((1 - -4) - -8) = (5 - -8) = 13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + -3 + -5 + 7) = (((3 + -3) + -5) + 7) = ((0 + -5) + 7) = (-5 + 7) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 * -6 * 8 - -7) = (((5 * -6) * 8) - -7) = ((-30 * 8) - -7) = (-240 - -7) = -233.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((0 - 13) + (2 + -233)) = (-13 + (2 + -233)) = (-13 + -231) = -244.\n(Final response) So the answer is -244.", "correct_answer": "-244", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 488, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 + -6 + 4 + 7 + -9 - -8) + (-9 + 4 - 2 + 8 * 9 - 5)) * ((4 + -5 + 6 + -2 * 2 * -4) - (-1 - 8 + 1 * 2 * 9 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (9 + -6 + 4 + 7 + -9 - -8), B = (-9 + 4 - 2 + 8 * 9 - 5), C = (4 + -5 + 6 + -2 * 2 * -4) and D = (-1 - 8 + 1 * 2 * 9 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + -6 + 4 + 7 + -9 - -8) = (((((9 + -6) + 4) + 7) + -9) - -8) = ((((3 + 4) + 7) + -9) - -8) = (((7 + 7) + -9) - -8) = ((14 + -9) - -8) = (5 - -8) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 4 - 2 + 8 * 9 - 5) = ((((-9 + 4) - 2) + (8 * 9)) - 5) = (((-5 - 2) + (8 * 9)) - 5) = (((-5 - 2) + 72) - 5) = ((-7 + 72) - 5) = (65 - 5) = 60.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + -5 + 6 + -2 * 2 * -4) = (((4 + -5) + 6) + ((-2 * 2) * -4)) = ((-1 + 6) + ((-2 * 2) * -4)) = ((-1 + 6) + (-4 * -4)) = (5 + (-4 * -4)) = (5 + 16) = 21.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 - 8 + 1 * 2 * 9 * 0) = ((-1 - 8) + (((1 * 2) * 9) * 0)) = (-9 + (((1 * 2) * 9) * 0)) = (-9 + ((2 * 9) * 0)) = (-9 + (18 * 0)) = (-9 + 0) = -9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((13 + 60) * (21 - -9)) = (73 * (21 - -9)) = (73 * 30) = 2190.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2190.", "correct_answer": "2190", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 211, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * 4 - -1 - 0 - 3) - (-3 * -5 + 8 * 0 - -7)) - ((-5 - 1 * 6 - 1 - -9) + (4 - -3 + -2 + 5 + -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-5 * 4 - -1 - 0 - 3), B = (-3 * -5 + 8 * 0 - -7), C = (-5 - 1 * 6 - 1 - -9) and D = (4 - -3 + -2 + 5 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 4 - -1 - 0 - 3) = ((((-5 * 4) - -1) - 0) - 3) = (((-20 - -1) - 0) - 3) = ((-19 - 0) - 3) = (-19 - 3) = -22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * -5 + 8 * 0 - -7) = (((-3 * -5) + (8 * 0)) - -7) = ((15 + (8 * 0)) - -7) = ((15 + 0) - -7) = (15 - -7) = 22.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - 1 * 6 - 1 - -9) = (((-5 - (1 * 6)) - 1) - -9) = (((-5 - 6) - 1) - -9) = ((-11 - 1) - -9) = (-12 - -9) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 - -3 + -2 + 5 + -5) = ((((4 - -3) + -2) + 5) + -5) = (((7 + -2) + 5) + -5) = ((5 + 5) + -5) = (10 + -5) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-22 - 22) - (-3 + 5)) = (-44 - (-3 + 5)) = (-44 - 2) = -46.\n(Final response) So the answer is -46.", "correct_answer": "-46", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 180, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 + -9 - -9) - (5 + 1 + 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (3 + -9 - -9) and B = (5 + 1 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + -9 - -9) = ((3 + -9) - -9) = (-6 - -9) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 1 + 7) = ((5 + 1) + 7) = (6 + 7) = 13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (3 - 13) = -10.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10.", "correct_answer": "-10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 58, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 - -4 * 4) - (4 - 2 - 6)) - ((-2 + 3 + 7) * (7 * -9 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-5 - -4 * 4), B = (4 - 2 - 6), C = (-2 + 3 + 7) and D = (7 * -9 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -4 * 4) = (-5 - (-4 * 4)) = (-5 - -16) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 2 - 6) = ((4 - 2) - 6) = (2 - 6) = -4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + 3 + 7) = ((-2 + 3) + 7) = (1 + 7) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 * -9 * 4) = ((7 * -9) * 4) = (-63 * 4) = -252.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((11 - -4) - (8 * -252)) = (15 - (8 * -252)) = (15 - -2016) = 2031.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2031.", "correct_answer": "2031", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 321, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 * 0 * -3 * -8 * 2 * 2) - (-7 - -5 * -7 * -5 - 1 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 * 0 * -3 * -8 * 2 * 2) and B = (-7 - -5 * -7 * -5 - 1 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * 0 * -3 * -8 * 2 * 2) = (((((6 * 0) * -3) * -8) * 2) * 2) = ((((0 * -3) * -8) * 2) * 2) = (((0 * -8) * 2) * 2) = ((0 * 2) * 2) = (0 * 2) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -5 * -7 * -5 - 1 * 3) = ((-7 - ((-5 * -7) * -5)) - (1 * 3)) = ((-7 - (35 * -5)) - (1 * 3)) = ((-7 - (35 * -5)) - 3) = ((-7 - -175) - 3) = (168 - 3) = 165.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (0 - 165) = -165.\n(Final response) So the answer is -165.", "correct_answer": "-165", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 116, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + 9 * 9 * 5) + (8 + 0 + 4 * 8)) * ((1 + -2 - 8 + -6) + (3 + -7 + 8 * 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-7 + 9 * 9 * 5), B = (8 + 0 + 4 * 8), C = (1 + -2 - 8 + -6) and D = (3 + -7 + 8 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 9 * 9 * 5) = (-7 + ((9 * 9) * 5)) = (-7 + (81 * 5)) = (-7 + 405) = 398.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + 0 + 4 * 8) = ((8 + 0) + (4 * 8)) = (8 + (4 * 8)) = (8 + 32) = 40.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 + -2 - 8 + -6) = (((1 + -2) - 8) + -6) = ((-1 - 8) + -6) = (-9 + -6) = -15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + -7 + 8 * 9) = ((3 + -7) + (8 * 9)) = (-4 + (8 * 9)) = (-4 + 72) = 68.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((398 + 40) * (-15 + 68)) = (438 * (-15 + 68)) = (438 * 53) = 23214.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23214.", "correct_answer": "23214", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 555, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 + 7 - -3 + 3) * (1 * 0 - 1 + 1)) + ((0 - -5 + -7 * 0) * (-8 + -2 - -1 * 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-2 + 7 - -3 + 3), B = (1 * 0 - 1 + 1), C = (0 - -5 + -7 * 0) and D = (-8 + -2 - -1 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + 7 - -3 + 3) = (((-2 + 7) - -3) + 3) = ((5 - -3) + 3) = (8 + 3) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 0 - 1 + 1) = (((1 * 0) - 1) + 1) = ((0 - 1) + 1) = (-1 + 1) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 - -5 + -7 * 0) = ((0 - -5) + (-7 * 0)) = (5 + (-7 * 0)) = (5 + 0) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + -2 - -1 * 9) = ((-8 + -2) - (-1 * 9)) = (-10 - (-1 * 9)) = (-10 - -9) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((11 * 0) + (5 * -1)) = (0 + (5 * -1)) = (0 + -5) = -5.\n(Final response) So the answer is -5.", "correct_answer": "-5", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 593, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 * -3 * 3) * (-7 - -8 + 8)) + ((3 + 4 + 3) - (3 * 0 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-6 * -3 * 3), B = (-7 - -8 + 8), C = (3 + 4 + 3) and D = (3 * 0 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * -3 * 3) = ((-6 * -3) * 3) = (18 * 3) = 54.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -8 + 8) = ((-7 - -8) + 8) = (1 + 8) = 9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 + 4 + 3) = ((3 + 4) + 3) = (7 + 3) = 10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * 0 * -5) = ((3 * 0) * -5) = (0 * -5) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((54 * 9) + (10 - 0)) = (486 + (10 - 0)) = (486 + 10) = 496.\n(Final response) So the answer is 496.", "correct_answer": "496", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 141, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 + -4 - -8 * -9) - (-4 * 2 * 0 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-2 + -4 - -8 * -9) and B = (-4 * 2 * 0 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -4 - -8 * -9) = ((-2 + -4) - (-8 * -9)) = (-6 - (-8 * -9)) = (-6 - 72) = -78.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 2 * 0 * 3) = (((-4 * 2) * 0) * 3) = ((-8 * 0) * 3) = (0 * 3) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-78 - 0) = -78.\n(Final response) So the answer is -78.", "correct_answer": "-78", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 222, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 * 4 + -4) * (5 + -7 * 3)) - ((-9 * -1 - 8) - (-1 - -9 + 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (0 * 4 + -4), B = (5 + -7 * 3), C = (-9 * -1 - 8) and D = (-1 - -9 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * 4 + -4) = ((0 * 4) + -4) = (0 + -4) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + -7 * 3) = (5 + (-7 * 3)) = (5 + -21) = -16.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * -1 - 8) = ((-9 * -1) - 8) = (9 - 8) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 - -9 + 0) = ((-1 - -9) + 0) = (8 + 0) = 8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((-4 * -16) - (1 - 8)) = (64 - (1 - 8)) = (64 - -7) = 71.\n(Final response) So the answer is 71.", "correct_answer": "71", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 303, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + -9 + -2 - -6) * (-7 - 3 * -9 * 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-1 + -9 + -2 - -6) and B = (-7 - 3 * -9 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + -9 + -2 - -6) = (((-1 + -9) + -2) - -6) = ((-10 + -2) - -6) = (-12 - -6) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - 3 * -9 * 6) = (-7 - ((3 * -9) * 6)) = (-7 - (-27 * 6)) = (-7 - -162) = 155.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-6 * 155) = -930.\n(Final response) So the answer is -930.", "correct_answer": "-930", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 59, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + 8 + 3 * -8) + (-1 - 1 - -9 + 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-1 + 8 + 3 * -8) and B = (-1 - 1 - -9 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + 8 + 3 * -8) = ((-1 + 8) + (3 * -8)) = (7 + (3 * -8)) = (7 + -24) = -17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 1 - -9 + 3) = (((-1 - 1) - -9) + 3) = ((-2 - -9) + 3) = (7 + 3) = 10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-17 + 10) = -7.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7.", "correct_answer": "-7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 158, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 + -5 + 3 * 2) - (-6 - -5 * -6 + 4)) * ((-8 - 3 + 1 - -1) + (-3 - 4 - 4 + 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-4 + -5 + 3 * 2), B = (-6 - -5 * -6 + 4), C = (-8 - 3 + 1 - -1) and D = (-3 - 4 - 4 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -5 + 3 * 2) = ((-4 + -5) + (3 * 2)) = (-9 + (3 * 2)) = (-9 + 6) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - -5 * -6 + 4) = ((-6 - (-5 * -6)) + 4) = ((-6 - 30) + 4) = (-36 + 4) = -32.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 - 3 + 1 - -1) = (((-8 - 3) + 1) - -1) = ((-11 + 1) - -1) = (-10 - -1) = -9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 - 4 - 4 + 3) = (((-3 - 4) - 4) + 3) = ((-7 - 4) + 3) = (-11 + 3) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((-3 - -32) * (-9 + -8)) = (29 * (-9 + -8)) = (29 * -17) = -493.\n(Final response) So the answer is -493.", "correct_answer": "-493", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 498, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - -9 * -5 * -5) + (6 - 8 * 7 + -7)) - ((-6 * -1 * -5 - -1) - (7 * 8 * -1 - -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (1 - -9 * -5 * -5), B = (6 - 8 * 7 + -7), C = (-6 * -1 * -5 - -1) and D = (7 * 8 * -1 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -9 * -5 * -5) = (1 - ((-9 * -5) * -5)) = (1 - (45 * -5)) = (1 - -225) = 226.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - 8 * 7 + -7) = ((6 - (8 * 7)) + -7) = ((6 - 56) + -7) = (-50 + -7) = -57.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 * -1 * -5 - -1) = (((-6 * -1) * -5) - -1) = ((6 * -5) - -1) = (-30 - -1) = -29.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 * 8 * -1 - -4) = (((7 * 8) * -1) - -4) = ((56 * -1) - -4) = (-56 - -4) = -52.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((226 + -57) - (-29 - -52)) = (169 - (-29 - -52)) = (169 - 23) = 146.\n(Final response) So the answer is 146.", "correct_answer": "146", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 569, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 * 2 * 0 * -1 * 5) - (-3 - 8 * -7 + -7 + -4)) * ((-9 + 4 + 0 - 1 * 0) * (-7 - 4 + 3 * -7 - 7))) + (((-4 - 4 * 7 - -7 - -5) + (-1 - 7 * -4 * -7 * 8)) * ((4 + -2 * 9 - -7 + -6) + (7 * -1 - -8 + -9 * 6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C * D)) + ((E + F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (2 * 2 * 0 * -1 * 5), B = (-3 - 8 * -7 + -7 + -4), C = (-9 + 4 + 0 - 1 * 0), D = (-7 - 4 + 3 * -7 - 7), E = (-4 - 4 * 7 - -7 - -5), F = (-1 - 7 * -4 * -7 * 8), G = (4 + -2 * 9 - -7 + -6) and H = (7 * -1 - -8 + -9 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 2 * 0 * -1 * 5) = ((((2 * 2) * 0) * -1) * 5) = (((4 * 0) * -1) * 5) = ((0 * -1) * 5) = (0 * 5) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - 8 * -7 + -7 + -4) = (((-3 - (8 * -7)) + -7) + -4) = (((-3 - -56) + -7) + -4) = ((53 + -7) + -4) = (46 + -4) = 42.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + 4 + 0 - 1 * 0) = (((-9 + 4) + 0) - (1 * 0)) = ((-5 + 0) - (1 * 0)) = ((-5 + 0) - 0) = (-5 - 0) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - 4 + 3 * -7 - 7) = (((-7 - 4) + (3 * -7)) - 7) = ((-11 + (3 * -7)) - 7) = ((-11 + -21) - 7) = (-32 - 7) = -39.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-4 - 4 * 7 - -7 - -5) = (((-4 - (4 * 7)) - -7) - -5) = (((-4 - 28) - -7) - -5) = ((-32 - -7) - -5) = (-25 - -5) = -20.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-1 - 7 * -4 * -7 * 8) = (-1 - (((7 * -4) * -7) * 8)) = (-1 - ((-28 * -7) * 8)) = (-1 - (196 * 8)) = (-1 - 1568) = -1569.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (4 + -2 * 9 - -7 + -6) = (((4 + (-2 * 9)) - -7) + -6) = (((4 + -18) - -7) + -6) = ((-14 - -7) + -6) = (-7 + -6) = -13.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (7 * -1 - -8 + -9 * 6) = (((7 * -1) - -8) + (-9 * 6)) = ((-7 - -8) + (-9 * 6)) = ((-7 - -8) + -54) = (1 + -54) = -53.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C * D)) + ((E + F) * (G + H))) = (((0 - 42) * (-5 * -39)) + ((-20 + -1569) * (-13 + -53))) = ((-42 * (-5 * -39)) + ((-20 + -1569) * (-13 + -53))) = ((-42 * 195) + ((-20 + -1569) * (-13 + -53))) = ((-42 * 195) + (-1589 * (-13 + -53))) = ((-42 * 195) + (-1589 * -66)) = (-8190 + (-1589 * -66)) = (-8190 + 104874) = 96684.\n(Final response) So the answer is 96684.", "correct_answer": "96684", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 319, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 - -4 + 0 + -7) * (5 * 1 * -6 + 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-4 - -4 + 0 + -7) and B = (5 * 1 * -6 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - -4 + 0 + -7) = (((-4 - -4) + 0) + -7) = ((0 + 0) + -7) = (0 + -7) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * 1 * -6 + 2) = (((5 * 1) * -6) + 2) = ((5 * -6) + 2) = (-30 + 2) = -28.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-7 * -28) = 196.\n(Final response) So the answer is 196.", "correct_answer": "196", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 292, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 - 6 * 5 * -8) + (-2 * -4 * 3 * 6)) + ((3 - 6 + 7 * -5) + (6 + 6 - -2 + 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (5 - 6 * 5 * -8), B = (-2 * -4 * 3 * 6), C = (3 - 6 + 7 * -5) and D = (6 + 6 - -2 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - 6 * 5 * -8) = (5 - ((6 * 5) * -8)) = (5 - (30 * -8)) = (5 - -240) = 245.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -4 * 3 * 6) = (((-2 * -4) * 3) * 6) = ((8 * 3) * 6) = (24 * 6) = 144.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 - 6 + 7 * -5) = ((3 - 6) + (7 * -5)) = (-3 + (7 * -5)) = (-3 + -35) = -38.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + 6 - -2 + 3) = (((6 + 6) - -2) + 3) = ((12 - -2) + 3) = (14 + 3) = 17.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((245 + 144) + (-38 + 17)) = (389 + (-38 + 17)) = (389 + -21) = 368.\n(Final response) So the answer is 368.", "correct_answer": "368", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 465, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 * -6 + 2) + (-8 * -1 * -3)) + ((-8 + 8 * 8) * (-2 * 2 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-9 * -6 + 2), B = (-8 * -1 * -3), C = (-8 + 8 * 8) and D = (-2 * 2 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * -6 + 2) = ((-9 * -6) + 2) = (54 + 2) = 56.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * -1 * -3) = ((-8 * -1) * -3) = (8 * -3) = -24.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 + 8 * 8) = (-8 + (8 * 8)) = (-8 + 64) = 56.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * 2 * -1) = ((-2 * 2) * -1) = (-4 * -1) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((56 + -24) + (56 * 4)) = (32 + (56 * 4)) = (32 + 224) = 256.\n(Final response) So the answer is 256.", "correct_answer": "256", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 127, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 - -6 - -7) * (2 + -4 * -8)) - ((-5 * 0 * 1) * (5 - -5 * -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (8 - -6 - -7), B = (2 + -4 * -8), C = (-5 * 0 * 1) and D = (5 - -5 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - -6 - -7) = ((8 - -6) - -7) = (14 - -7) = 21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + -4 * -8) = (2 + (-4 * -8)) = (2 + 32) = 34.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * 0 * 1) = ((-5 * 0) * 1) = (0 * 1) = 0.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - -5 * -2) = (5 - (-5 * -2)) = (5 - 10) = -5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((21 * 34) - (0 * -5)) = (714 - (0 * -5)) = (714 - 0) = 714.\n(Final response) So the answer is 714.", "correct_answer": "714", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 399, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * 0 * 5) - (9 * -7 + 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 * 0 * 5) and B = (9 * -7 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 0 * 5) = ((7 * 0) * 5) = (0 * 5) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * -7 + 9) = ((9 * -7) + 9) = (-63 + 9) = -54.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (0 - -54) = 54.\n(Final response) So the answer is 54.", "correct_answer": "54", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 2, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((1 + 6 - -4) - (7 * -3 - -3)) - ((2 - -9 - -5) + (-3 * -4 - 7))) * (((3 + 4 - -2) * (1 + -9 + -8)) * ((1 - -5 * 6) - (1 - 5 - -9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C + D)) * ((E * F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (1 + 6 - -4), B = (7 * -3 - -3), C = (2 - -9 - -5), D = (-3 * -4 - 7), E = (3 + 4 - -2), F = (1 + -9 + -8), G = (1 - -5 * 6) and H = (1 - 5 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 6 - -4) = ((1 + 6) - -4) = (7 - -4) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * -3 - -3) = ((7 * -3) - -3) = (-21 - -3) = -18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - -9 - -5) = ((2 - -9) - -5) = (11 - -5) = 16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * -4 - 7) = ((-3 * -4) - 7) = (12 - 7) = 5.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (3 + 4 - -2) = ((3 + 4) - -2) = (7 - -2) = 9.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (1 + -9 + -8) = ((1 + -9) + -8) = (-8 + -8) = -16.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (1 - -5 * 6) = (1 - (-5 * 6)) = (1 - -30) = 31.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (1 - 5 - -9) = ((1 - 5) - -9) = (-4 - -9) = 5.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C + D)) * ((E * F) * (G - H))) = (((11 - -18) - (16 + 5)) * ((9 * -16) * (31 - 5))) = ((29 - (16 + 5)) * ((9 * -16) * (31 - 5))) = ((29 - 21) * ((9 * -16) * (31 - 5))) = ((29 - 21) * (-144 * (31 - 5))) = ((29 - 21) * (-144 * 26)) = (8 * (-144 * 26)) = (8 * -3744) = -29952.\n(Final response) So the answer is -29952.", "correct_answer": "-29952", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 248, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 - -4 - 8 - 0) - (3 * -7 - -4 + -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-5 - -4 - 8 - 0) and B = (3 * -7 - -4 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -4 - 8 - 0) = (((-5 - -4) - 8) - 0) = ((-1 - 8) - 0) = (-9 - 0) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * -7 - -4 + -2) = (((3 * -7) - -4) + -2) = ((-21 - -4) + -2) = (-17 + -2) = -19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-9 - -19) = 10.\n(Final response) So the answer is 10.", "correct_answer": "10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 168, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 * -2 - -7 * 5 + -3 * -8) - (8 - 5 - 9 - 9 - 7 - 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-2 * -2 - -7 * 5 + -3 * -8) and B = (8 - 5 - 9 - 9 - 7 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * -2 - -7 * 5 + -3 * -8) = (((-2 * -2) - (-7 * 5)) + (-3 * -8)) = ((4 - (-7 * 5)) + (-3 * -8)) = ((4 - -35) + (-3 * -8)) = ((4 - -35) + 24) = (39 + 24) = 63.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 5 - 9 - 9 - 7 - 9) = (((((8 - 5) - 9) - 9) - 7) - 9) = ((((3 - 9) - 9) - 7) - 9) = (((-6 - 9) - 7) - 9) = ((-15 - 7) - 9) = (-22 - 9) = -31.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (63 - -31) = 94.\n(Final response) So the answer is 94.", "correct_answer": "94", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 97, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 * -7 - 6 + 7 - 9 * 8) - (-5 * 8 - 3 - 1 + 5 * -3)) + ((-3 + -1 - -1 + -8 * 3 - 7) + (-4 + 9 - -8 - 3 - 0 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (8 * -7 - 6 + 7 - 9 * 8), B = (-5 * 8 - 3 - 1 + 5 * -3), C = (-3 + -1 - -1 + -8 * 3 - 7) and D = (-4 + 9 - -8 - 3 - 0 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * -7 - 6 + 7 - 9 * 8) = ((((8 * -7) - 6) + 7) - (9 * 8)) = (((-56 - 6) + 7) - (9 * 8)) = (((-56 - 6) + 7) - 72) = ((-62 + 7) - 72) = (-55 - 72) = -127.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 8 - 3 - 1 + 5 * -3) = ((((-5 * 8) - 3) - 1) + (5 * -3)) = (((-40 - 3) - 1) + (5 * -3)) = (((-40 - 3) - 1) + -15) = ((-43 - 1) + -15) = (-44 + -15) = -59.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -1 - -1 + -8 * 3 - 7) = ((((-3 + -1) - -1) + (-8 * 3)) - 7) = (((-4 - -1) + (-8 * 3)) - 7) = (((-4 - -1) + -24) - 7) = ((-3 + -24) - 7) = (-27 - 7) = -34.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + 9 - -8 - 3 - 0 + -1) = (((((-4 + 9) - -8) - 3) - 0) + -1) = ((((5 - -8) - 3) - 0) + -1) = (((13 - 3) - 0) + -1) = ((10 - 0) + -1) = (10 + -1) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-127 - -59) + (-34 + 9)) = (-68 + (-34 + 9)) = (-68 + -25) = -93.\n(Final response) So the answer is -93.", "correct_answer": "-93", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 233, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - 6 * -2 + -8) - (2 - 2 * 5 + -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 - 6 * -2 + -8) and B = (2 - 2 * 5 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - 6 * -2 + -8) = ((1 - (6 * -2)) + -8) = ((1 - -12) + -8) = (13 + -8) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - 2 * 5 + -8) = ((2 - (2 * 5)) + -8) = ((2 - 10) + -8) = (-8 + -8) = -16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (5 - -16) = 21.\n(Final response) So the answer is 21.", "correct_answer": "21", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 218, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 - -9 - 3 - 8) * (1 - -6 + -6 + 2)) + ((-2 + -7 - 5 + 4) + (-5 - 5 * -7 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-7 - -9 - 3 - 8), B = (1 - -6 + -6 + 2), C = (-2 + -7 - 5 + 4) and D = (-5 - 5 * -7 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - -9 - 3 - 8) = (((-7 - -9) - 3) - 8) = ((2 - 3) - 8) = (-1 - 8) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - -6 + -6 + 2) = (((1 - -6) + -6) + 2) = ((7 + -6) + 2) = (1 + 2) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + -7 - 5 + 4) = (((-2 + -7) - 5) + 4) = ((-9 - 5) + 4) = (-14 + 4) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - 5 * -7 + -1) = ((-5 - (5 * -7)) + -1) = ((-5 - -35) + -1) = (30 + -1) = 29.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((-9 * 3) + (-10 + 29)) = (-27 + (-10 + 29)) = (-27 + 19) = -8.\n(Final response) So the answer is -8.", "correct_answer": "-8", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 492, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - -8 - 9 - -1 - -4 + -6) + (3 + -4 + 9 - 5 * -5 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-2 - -8 - 9 - -1 - -4 + -6) and B = (3 + -4 + 9 - 5 * -5 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -8 - 9 - -1 - -4 + -6) = (((((-2 - -8) - 9) - -1) - -4) + -6) = ((((6 - 9) - -1) - -4) + -6) = (((-3 - -1) - -4) + -6) = ((-2 - -4) + -6) = (2 + -6) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + -4 + 9 - 5 * -5 + 8) = ((((3 + -4) + 9) - (5 * -5)) + 8) = (((-1 + 9) - (5 * -5)) + 8) = (((-1 + 9) - -25) + 8) = ((8 - -25) + 8) = (33 + 8) = 41.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-4 + 41) = 37.\n(Final response) So the answer is 37.", "correct_answer": "37", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 117, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 * -9 * -9 - -2 + 7) - (-2 + 0 - -1 * -7 - -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (3 * -9 * -9 - -2 + 7) and B = (-2 + 0 - -1 * -7 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -9 * -9 - -2 + 7) = ((((3 * -9) * -9) - -2) + 7) = (((-27 * -9) - -2) + 7) = ((243 - -2) + 7) = (245 + 7) = 252.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 0 - -1 * -7 - -3) = (((-2 + 0) - (-1 * -7)) - -3) = ((-2 - (-1 * -7)) - -3) = ((-2 - 7) - -3) = (-9 - -3) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (252 - -6) = 258.\n(Final response) So the answer is 258.", "correct_answer": "258", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 78, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 * -5 + 8 * -4) - (8 - -4 * -8 + 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (2 * -5 + 8 * -4) and B = (8 - -4 * -8 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * -5 + 8 * -4) = ((2 * -5) + (8 * -4)) = (-10 + (8 * -4)) = (-10 + -32) = -42.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - -4 * -8 + 1) = ((8 - (-4 * -8)) + 1) = ((8 - 32) + 1) = (-24 + 1) = -23.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-42 - -23) = -19.\n(Final response) So the answer is -19.", "correct_answer": "-19", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 170, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 + 6 * -8 - 8) * (7 - -3 + 8 + 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (7 + 6 * -8 - 8) and B = (7 - -3 + 8 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 6 * -8 - 8) = ((7 + (6 * -8)) - 8) = ((7 + -48) - 8) = (-41 - 8) = -49.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - -3 + 8 + 4) = (((7 - -3) + 8) + 4) = ((10 + 8) + 4) = (18 + 4) = 22.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-49 * 22) = -1078.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1078.", "correct_answer": "-1078", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 242, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-9 + 8 - 0 - 5 * -3 * -4) * (5 - 0 - 4 - -1 + 9 + 9)) * ((-2 * -6 + -6 - -4 + -3 + 5) * (-7 + 6 - -7 - 6 - -2 - 0))) * (((5 * -1 + 8 * 4 + -2 - 8) - (7 - -3 - -4 + 9 * -1 + -8)) - ((8 - 8 - -8 * -9 + 0 * 6) - (7 - 0 + -6 + 5 * 5 * -9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) * (C * D)) * ((E - F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (-9 + 8 - 0 - 5 * -3 * -4), B = (5 - 0 - 4 - -1 + 9 + 9), C = (-2 * -6 + -6 - -4 + -3 + 5), D = (-7 + 6 - -7 - 6 - -2 - 0), E = (5 * -1 + 8 * 4 + -2 - 8), F = (7 - -3 - -4 + 9 * -1 + -8), G = (8 - 8 - -8 * -9 + 0 * 6) and H = (7 - 0 + -6 + 5 * 5 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + 8 - 0 - 5 * -3 * -4) = (((-9 + 8) - 0) - ((5 * -3) * -4)) = ((-1 - 0) - ((5 * -3) * -4)) = ((-1 - 0) - (-15 * -4)) = (-1 - (-15 * -4)) = (-1 - 60) = -61.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 0 - 4 - -1 + 9 + 9) = (((((5 - 0) - 4) - -1) + 9) + 9) = ((((5 - 4) - -1) + 9) + 9) = (((1 - -1) + 9) + 9) = ((2 + 9) + 9) = (11 + 9) = 20.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 * -6 + -6 - -4 + -3 + 5) = (((((-2 * -6) + -6) - -4) + -3) + 5) = ((((12 + -6) - -4) + -3) + 5) = (((6 - -4) + -3) + 5) = ((10 + -3) + 5) = (7 + 5) = 12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + 6 - -7 - 6 - -2 - 0) = (((((-7 + 6) - -7) - 6) - -2) - 0) = ((((-1 - -7) - 6) - -2) - 0) = (((6 - 6) - -2) - 0) = ((0 - -2) - 0) = (2 - 0) = 2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (5 * -1 + 8 * 4 + -2 - 8) = ((((5 * -1) + (8 * 4)) + -2) - 8) = (((-5 + (8 * 4)) + -2) - 8) = (((-5 + 32) + -2) - 8) = ((27 + -2) - 8) = (25 - 8) = 17.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (7 - -3 - -4 + 9 * -1 + -8) = ((((7 - -3) - -4) + (9 * -1)) + -8) = (((10 - -4) + (9 * -1)) + -8) = (((10 - -4) + -9) + -8) = ((14 + -9) + -8) = (5 + -8) = -3.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 - 8 - -8 * -9 + 0 * 6) = (((8 - 8) - (-8 * -9)) + (0 * 6)) = ((0 - (-8 * -9)) + (0 * 6)) = ((0 - 72) + (0 * 6)) = ((0 - 72) + 0) = (-72 + 0) = -72.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (7 - 0 + -6 + 5 * 5 * -9) = (((7 - 0) + -6) + ((5 * 5) * -9)) = ((7 + -6) + ((5 * 5) * -9)) = ((7 + -6) + (25 * -9)) = (1 + (25 * -9)) = (1 + -225) = -224.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) * (C * D)) * ((E - F) - (G - H))) = (((-61 * 20) * (12 * 2)) * ((17 - -3) - (-72 - -224))) = ((-1220 * (12 * 2)) * ((17 - -3) - (-72 - -224))) = ((-1220 * 24) * ((17 - -3) - (-72 - -224))) = ((-1220 * 24) * (20 - (-72 - -224))) = ((-1220 * 24) * (20 - 152)) = (-29280 * (20 - 152)) = (-29280 * -132) = 3864960.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3864960.", "correct_answer": "3864960", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 340, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 * -1 + 7) - (2 - -3 - -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 * -1 + 7) and B = (2 - -3 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * -1 + 7) = ((0 * -1) + 7) = (0 + 7) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -3 - -7) = ((2 - -3) - -7) = (5 - -7) = 12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (7 - 12) = -5.\n(Final response) So the answer is -5.", "correct_answer": "-5", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 15, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 - -4 + -4 + 9) - (3 - 1 * 3 - -7)) - ((-2 + 5 * 8 * -5) * (5 * -3 + 8 + 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (7 - -4 + -4 + 9), B = (3 - 1 * 3 - -7), C = (-2 + 5 * 8 * -5) and D = (5 * -3 + 8 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -4 + -4 + 9) = (((7 - -4) + -4) + 9) = ((11 + -4) + 9) = (7 + 9) = 16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - 1 * 3 - -7) = ((3 - (1 * 3)) - -7) = ((3 - 3) - -7) = (0 - -7) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + 5 * 8 * -5) = (-2 + ((5 * 8) * -5)) = (-2 + (40 * -5)) = (-2 + -200) = -202.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 * -3 + 8 + 1) = (((5 * -3) + 8) + 1) = ((-15 + 8) + 1) = (-7 + 1) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((16 - 7) - (-202 * -6)) = (9 - (-202 * -6)) = (9 - 1212) = -1203.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1203.", "correct_answer": "-1203", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 553, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 - 9 * -7) + (3 - -2 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (0 - 9 * -7) and B = (3 - -2 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - 9 * -7) = (0 - (9 * -7)) = (0 - -63) = 63.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - -2 + -1) = ((3 - -2) + -1) = (5 + -1) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (63 + 4) = 67.\n(Final response) So the answer is 67.", "correct_answer": "67", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 51, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - 6 + 8 - 8 + -1) * (-2 - 0 - 9 - -7 * 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-2 - 6 + 8 - 8 + -1) and B = (-2 - 0 - 9 - -7 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - 6 + 8 - 8 + -1) = ((((-2 - 6) + 8) - 8) + -1) = (((-8 + 8) - 8) + -1) = ((0 - 8) + -1) = (-8 + -1) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 0 - 9 - -7 * 1) = (((-2 - 0) - 9) - (-7 * 1)) = ((-2 - 9) - (-7 * 1)) = ((-2 - 9) - -7) = (-11 - -7) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-9 * -4) = 36.\n(Final response) So the answer is 36.", "correct_answer": "36", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 66, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 + -4 * 0 + 6) + (0 * -2 * -2 - 0)) - ((0 * -6 + 1 * -5) - (-2 - -8 - -1 - 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (5 + -4 * 0 + 6), B = (0 * -2 * -2 - 0), C = (0 * -6 + 1 * -5) and D = (-2 - -8 - -1 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + -4 * 0 + 6) = ((5 + (-4 * 0)) + 6) = ((5 + 0) + 6) = (5 + 6) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * -2 * -2 - 0) = (((0 * -2) * -2) - 0) = ((0 * -2) - 0) = (0 - 0) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * -6 + 1 * -5) = ((0 * -6) + (1 * -5)) = (0 + (1 * -5)) = (0 + -5) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - -8 - -1 - 3) = (((-2 - -8) - -1) - 3) = ((6 - -1) - 3) = (7 - 3) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((11 + 0) - (-5 - 4)) = (11 - (-5 - 4)) = (11 - -9) = 20.\n(Final response) So the answer is 20.", "correct_answer": "20", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 563, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + -3 * -1 - 5) * (8 - -5 + 3 + 9)) * ((2 * -8 * 5 + -3) + (6 * 6 + -6 - 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (7 + -3 * -1 - 5), B = (8 - -5 + 3 + 9), C = (2 * -8 * 5 + -3) and D = (6 * 6 + -6 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -3 * -1 - 5) = ((7 + (-3 * -1)) - 5) = ((7 + 3) - 5) = (10 - 5) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - -5 + 3 + 9) = (((8 - -5) + 3) + 9) = ((13 + 3) + 9) = (16 + 9) = 25.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 * -8 * 5 + -3) = (((2 * -8) * 5) + -3) = ((-16 * 5) + -3) = (-80 + -3) = -83.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 * 6 + -6 - 8) = (((6 * 6) + -6) - 8) = ((36 + -6) - 8) = (30 - 8) = 22.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((5 * 25) * (-83 + 22)) = (125 * (-83 + 22)) = (125 * -61) = -7625.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7625.", "correct_answer": "-7625", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 453, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 * -2 + -6) * (-4 - 1 * -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 * -2 + -6) and B = (-4 - 1 * -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * -2 + -6) = ((-7 * -2) + -6) = (14 + -6) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - 1 * -4) = (-4 - (1 * -4)) = (-4 - -4) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (8 * 0) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 77, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 + -2 * 1 * 3) * (-2 * -1 * 5 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-8 + -2 * 1 * 3) and B = (-2 * -1 * 5 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + -2 * 1 * 3) = (-8 + ((-2 * 1) * 3)) = (-8 + (-2 * 3)) = (-8 + -6) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -1 * 5 - 2) = (((-2 * -1) * 5) - 2) = ((2 * 5) - 2) = (10 - 2) = 8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-14 * 8) = -112.\n(Final response) So the answer is -112.", "correct_answer": "-112", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 255, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-9 + -8 - 9 - 7 + -2) * (3 * -9 - -7 - -5 - -6)) - ((9 - -6 * -3 * -5 + -6) * (7 + 6 - 6 - 5 - -8))) + (((-1 - -8 * -1 * 3 - -4) * (9 - 5 - 7 + 0 * -5)) - ((-4 * -7 * -9 + 4 - -5) - (-6 - -1 - 0 * 3 - -6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C * D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (-9 + -8 - 9 - 7 + -2), B = (3 * -9 - -7 - -5 - -6), C = (9 - -6 * -3 * -5 + -6), D = (7 + 6 - 6 - 5 - -8), E = (-1 - -8 * -1 * 3 - -4), F = (9 - 5 - 7 + 0 * -5), G = (-4 * -7 * -9 + 4 - -5) and H = (-6 - -1 - 0 * 3 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -8 - 9 - 7 + -2) = ((((-9 + -8) - 9) - 7) + -2) = (((-17 - 9) - 7) + -2) = ((-26 - 7) + -2) = (-33 + -2) = -35.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * -9 - -7 - -5 - -6) = ((((3 * -9) - -7) - -5) - -6) = (((-27 - -7) - -5) - -6) = ((-20 - -5) - -6) = (-15 - -6) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - -6 * -3 * -5 + -6) = ((9 - ((-6 * -3) * -5)) + -6) = ((9 - (18 * -5)) + -6) = ((9 - -90) + -6) = (99 + -6) = 93.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + 6 - 6 - 5 - -8) = ((((7 + 6) - 6) - 5) - -8) = (((13 - 6) - 5) - -8) = ((7 - 5) - -8) = (2 - -8) = 10.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-1 - -8 * -1 * 3 - -4) = ((-1 - ((-8 * -1) * 3)) - -4) = ((-1 - (8 * 3)) - -4) = ((-1 - 24) - -4) = (-25 - -4) = -21.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (9 - 5 - 7 + 0 * -5) = (((9 - 5) - 7) + (0 * -5)) = ((4 - 7) + (0 * -5)) = ((4 - 7) + 0) = (-3 + 0) = -3.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-4 * -7 * -9 + 4 - -5) = ((((-4 * -7) * -9) + 4) - -5) = (((28 * -9) + 4) - -5) = ((-252 + 4) - -5) = (-248 - -5) = -243.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-6 - -1 - 0 * 3 - -6) = (((-6 - -1) - (0 * 3)) - -6) = ((-5 - (0 * 3)) - -6) = ((-5 - 0) - -6) = (-5 - -6) = 1.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C * D)) + ((E * F) - (G - H))) = (((-35 * -9) - (93 * 10)) + ((-21 * -3) - (-243 - 1))) = ((315 - (93 * 10)) + ((-21 * -3) - (-243 - 1))) = ((315 - 930) + ((-21 * -3) - (-243 - 1))) = ((315 - 930) + (63 - (-243 - 1))) = ((315 - 930) + (63 - -244)) = (-615 + (63 - -244)) = (-615 + 307) = -308.\n(Final response) So the answer is -308.", "correct_answer": "-308", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 322, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 * 9 - -3 + 8 - 1) - (-2 + 2 - 8 * 7 - 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-2 * 9 - -3 + 8 - 1) and B = (-2 + 2 - 8 * 7 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * 9 - -3 + 8 - 1) = ((((-2 * 9) - -3) + 8) - 1) = (((-18 - -3) + 8) - 1) = ((-15 + 8) - 1) = (-7 - 1) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 2 - 8 * 7 - 4) = (((-2 + 2) - (8 * 7)) - 4) = ((0 - (8 * 7)) - 4) = ((0 - 56) - 4) = (-56 - 4) = -60.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-8 - -60) = 52.\n(Final response) So the answer is 52.", "correct_answer": "52", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 89, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * 1 - -6 * -8) - (9 + -5 * 4 * -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (9 * 1 - -6 * -8) and B = (9 + -5 * 4 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 1 - -6 * -8) = ((9 * 1) - (-6 * -8)) = (9 - (-6 * -8)) = (9 - 48) = -39.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + -5 * 4 * -7) = (9 + ((-5 * 4) * -7)) = (9 + (-20 * -7)) = (9 + 140) = 149.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-39 - 149) = -188.\n(Final response) So the answer is -188.", "correct_answer": "-188", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 187, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 + 0 - -9 * -3 + 6 + 9) - (-3 - 7 + 9 + -7 - 8 + 1)) + ((-1 + 9 + -4 + -6 + 8 + 2) - (7 * 0 - 7 - 2 * -3 + 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-2 + 0 - -9 * -3 + 6 + 9), B = (-3 - 7 + 9 + -7 - 8 + 1), C = (-1 + 9 + -4 + -6 + 8 + 2) and D = (7 * 0 - 7 - 2 * -3 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + 0 - -9 * -3 + 6 + 9) = ((((-2 + 0) - (-9 * -3)) + 6) + 9) = (((-2 - (-9 * -3)) + 6) + 9) = (((-2 - 27) + 6) + 9) = ((-29 + 6) + 9) = (-23 + 9) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - 7 + 9 + -7 - 8 + 1) = (((((-3 - 7) + 9) + -7) - 8) + 1) = ((((-10 + 9) + -7) - 8) + 1) = (((-1 + -7) - 8) + 1) = ((-8 - 8) + 1) = (-16 + 1) = -15.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + 9 + -4 + -6 + 8 + 2) = (((((-1 + 9) + -4) + -6) + 8) + 2) = ((((8 + -4) + -6) + 8) + 2) = (((4 + -6) + 8) + 2) = ((-2 + 8) + 2) = (6 + 2) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 * 0 - 7 - 2 * -3 + 7) = ((((7 * 0) - 7) - (2 * -3)) + 7) = (((0 - 7) - (2 * -3)) + 7) = (((0 - 7) - -6) + 7) = ((-7 - -6) + 7) = (-1 + 7) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-14 - -15) + (8 - 6)) = (1 + (8 - 6)) = (1 + 2) = 3.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3.", "correct_answer": "3", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 239, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + -4 * -5) * (-9 - -4 * -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 + -4 * -5) and B = (-9 - -4 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + -4 * -5) = (5 + (-4 * -5)) = (5 + 20) = 25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - -4 * -8) = (-9 - (-4 * -8)) = (-9 - 32) = -41.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (25 * -41) = -1025.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1025.", "correct_answer": "-1025", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 143, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-8 - -8 + 3 + -1 * 9) - (0 - -6 * -7 - 1 + -9)) - ((1 - -6 - -7 - 8 * 8) + (-5 - -5 + 8 + 8 * -9))) - (((9 - 5 * 1 - -7 * -3) + (-7 - 9 + -1 + -5 * 7)) * ((-6 - -5 * -1 + 6 * 2) * (7 * 3 + 5 + -9 * -7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G * H)))\", where A = (-8 - -8 + 3 + -1 * 9), B = (0 - -6 * -7 - 1 + -9), C = (1 - -6 - -7 - 8 * 8), D = (-5 - -5 + 8 + 8 * -9), E = (9 - 5 * 1 - -7 * -3), F = (-7 - 9 + -1 + -5 * 7), G = (-6 - -5 * -1 + 6 * 2) and H = (7 * 3 + 5 + -9 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -8 + 3 + -1 * 9) = (((-8 - -8) + 3) + (-1 * 9)) = ((0 + 3) + (-1 * 9)) = ((0 + 3) + -9) = (3 + -9) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - -6 * -7 - 1 + -9) = (((0 - (-6 * -7)) - 1) + -9) = (((0 - 42) - 1) + -9) = ((-42 - 1) + -9) = (-43 + -9) = -52.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - -6 - -7 - 8 * 8) = (((1 - -6) - -7) - (8 * 8)) = ((7 - -7) - (8 * 8)) = ((7 - -7) - 64) = (14 - 64) = -50.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 - -5 + 8 + 8 * -9) = (((-5 - -5) + 8) + (8 * -9)) = ((0 + 8) + (8 * -9)) = ((0 + 8) + -72) = (8 + -72) = -64.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (9 - 5 * 1 - -7 * -3) = ((9 - (5 * 1)) - (-7 * -3)) = ((9 - 5) - (-7 * -3)) = ((9 - 5) - 21) = (4 - 21) = -17.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-7 - 9 + -1 + -5 * 7) = (((-7 - 9) + -1) + (-5 * 7)) = ((-16 + -1) + (-5 * 7)) = ((-16 + -1) + -35) = (-17 + -35) = -52.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-6 - -5 * -1 + 6 * 2) = ((-6 - (-5 * -1)) + (6 * 2)) = ((-6 - 5) + (6 * 2)) = ((-6 - 5) + 12) = (-11 + 12) = 1.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (7 * 3 + 5 + -9 * -7) = (((7 * 3) + 5) + (-9 * -7)) = ((21 + 5) + (-9 * -7)) = ((21 + 5) + 63) = (26 + 63) = 89.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G * H))) = (((-6 - -52) - (-50 + -64)) - ((-17 + -52) * (1 * 89))) = ((46 - (-50 + -64)) - ((-17 + -52) * (1 * 89))) = ((46 - -114) - ((-17 + -52) * (1 * 89))) = ((46 - -114) - (-69 * (1 * 89))) = ((46 - -114) - (-69 * 89)) = (160 - (-69 * 89)) = (160 - -6141) = 6301.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6301.", "correct_answer": "6301", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 326, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 - 0 * 8 * -9) + (9 * -5 - -4 - -3)) * ((-6 - 6 - 5 + -2) - (3 * 7 * 6 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-4 - 0 * 8 * -9), B = (9 * -5 - -4 - -3), C = (-6 - 6 - 5 + -2) and D = (3 * 7 * 6 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 0 * 8 * -9) = (-4 - ((0 * 8) * -9)) = (-4 - (0 * -9)) = (-4 - 0) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * -5 - -4 - -3) = (((9 * -5) - -4) - -3) = ((-45 - -4) - -3) = (-41 - -3) = -38.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 - 6 - 5 + -2) = (((-6 - 6) - 5) + -2) = ((-12 - 5) + -2) = (-17 + -2) = -19.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * 7 * 6 + -8) = (((3 * 7) * 6) + -8) = ((21 * 6) + -8) = (126 + -8) = 118.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((-4 + -38) * (-19 - 118)) = (-42 * (-19 - 118)) = (-42 * -137) = 5754.\n(Final response) So the answer is 5754.", "correct_answer": "5754", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 179, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((0 - -2 * -3 * 2) * (1 + 6 + 6 + -2)) * ((-7 + -7 + -1 + -9) - (9 + 0 - -8 + -7))) * (((-4 * -8 + 7 * 4) + (9 - 6 + 6 * 4)) + ((-3 - -1 * 2 - 5) * (-2 * -8 + -2 - -5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) * (C - D)) * ((E + F) + (G * H)))\", where A = (0 - -2 * -3 * 2), B = (1 + 6 + 6 + -2), C = (-7 + -7 + -1 + -9), D = (9 + 0 - -8 + -7), E = (-4 * -8 + 7 * 4), F = (9 - 6 + 6 * 4), G = (-3 - -1 * 2 - 5) and H = (-2 * -8 + -2 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - -2 * -3 * 2) = (0 - ((-2 * -3) * 2)) = (0 - (6 * 2)) = (0 - 12) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + 6 + 6 + -2) = (((1 + 6) + 6) + -2) = ((7 + 6) + -2) = (13 + -2) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + -7 + -1 + -9) = (((-7 + -7) + -1) + -9) = ((-14 + -1) + -9) = (-15 + -9) = -24.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + 0 - -8 + -7) = (((9 + 0) - -8) + -7) = ((9 - -8) + -7) = (17 + -7) = 10.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-4 * -8 + 7 * 4) = ((-4 * -8) + (7 * 4)) = (32 + (7 * 4)) = (32 + 28) = 60.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (9 - 6 + 6 * 4) = ((9 - 6) + (6 * 4)) = (3 + (6 * 4)) = (3 + 24) = 27.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-3 - -1 * 2 - 5) = ((-3 - (-1 * 2)) - 5) = ((-3 - -2) - 5) = (-1 - 5) = -6.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-2 * -8 + -2 - -5) = (((-2 * -8) + -2) - -5) = ((16 + -2) - -5) = (14 - -5) = 19.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) * (C - D)) * ((E + F) + (G * H))) = (((-12 * 11) * (-24 - 10)) * ((60 + 27) + (-6 * 19))) = ((-132 * (-24 - 10)) * ((60 + 27) + (-6 * 19))) = ((-132 * -34) * ((60 + 27) + (-6 * 19))) = ((-132 * -34) * (87 + (-6 * 19))) = ((-132 * -34) * (87 + -114)) = (4488 * (87 + -114)) = (4488 * -27) = -121176.\n(Final response) So the answer is -121176.", "correct_answer": "-121176", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 280, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((8 + 1 - -7 + 5) - (4 + 8 * -2 - -9)) - ((-2 - 3 - -1 - 9) * (-2 * 9 + 3 + -6))) * (((0 * 1 - 4 - -5) + (5 + 6 + 2 + 9)) * ((-3 * -5 + -6 - -4) * (-6 - 0 * 0 + -7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C * D)) * ((E + F) * (G * H)))\", where A = (8 + 1 - -7 + 5), B = (4 + 8 * -2 - -9), C = (-2 - 3 - -1 - 9), D = (-2 * 9 + 3 + -6), E = (0 * 1 - 4 - -5), F = (5 + 6 + 2 + 9), G = (-3 * -5 + -6 - -4) and H = (-6 - 0 * 0 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 1 - -7 + 5) = (((8 + 1) - -7) + 5) = ((9 - -7) + 5) = (16 + 5) = 21.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + 8 * -2 - -9) = ((4 + (8 * -2)) - -9) = ((4 + -16) - -9) = (-12 - -9) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 - 3 - -1 - 9) = (((-2 - 3) - -1) - 9) = ((-5 - -1) - 9) = (-4 - 9) = -13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * 9 + 3 + -6) = (((-2 * 9) + 3) + -6) = ((-18 + 3) + -6) = (-15 + -6) = -21.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 * 1 - 4 - -5) = (((0 * 1) - 4) - -5) = ((0 - 4) - -5) = (-4 - -5) = 1.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 + 6 + 2 + 9) = (((5 + 6) + 2) + 9) = ((11 + 2) + 9) = (13 + 9) = 22.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-3 * -5 + -6 - -4) = (((-3 * -5) + -6) - -4) = ((15 + -6) - -4) = (9 - -4) = 13.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-6 - 0 * 0 + -7) = ((-6 - (0 * 0)) + -7) = ((-6 - 0) + -7) = (-6 + -7) = -13.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C * D)) * ((E + F) * (G * H))) = (((21 - -3) - (-13 * -21)) * ((1 + 22) * (13 * -13))) = ((24 - (-13 * -21)) * ((1 + 22) * (13 * -13))) = ((24 - 273) * ((1 + 22) * (13 * -13))) = ((24 - 273) * (23 * (13 * -13))) = ((24 - 273) * (23 * -169)) = (-249 * (23 * -169)) = (-249 * -3887) = 967863.\n(Final response) So the answer is 967863.", "correct_answer": "967863", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 284, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 * 1 + -5 - 3) + (-5 * 3 - -5 + 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-2 * 1 + -5 - 3) and B = (-5 * 3 - -5 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * 1 + -5 - 3) = (((-2 * 1) + -5) - 3) = ((-2 + -5) - 3) = (-7 - 3) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 3 - -5 + 6) = (((-5 * 3) - -5) + 6) = ((-15 - -5) + 6) = (-10 + 6) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-10 + -4) = -14.\n(Final response) So the answer is -14.", "correct_answer": "-14", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 254, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 * 1 * -6) + (-3 * -8 * 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 * 1 * -6) and B = (-3 * -8 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * 1 * -6) = ((-6 * 1) * -6) = (-6 * -6) = 36.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * -8 * 5) = ((-3 * -8) * 5) = (24 * 5) = 120.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (36 + 120) = 156.\n(Final response) So the answer is 156.", "correct_answer": "156", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 111, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 + -2 - -4) * (1 - 4 + -1)) - ((-9 + -1 * -6) - (6 + 1 + 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-6 + -2 - -4), B = (1 - 4 + -1), C = (-9 + -1 * -6) and D = (6 + 1 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + -2 - -4) = ((-6 + -2) - -4) = (-8 - -4) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - 4 + -1) = ((1 - 4) + -1) = (-3 + -1) = -4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 + -1 * -6) = (-9 + (-1 * -6)) = (-9 + 6) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + 1 + 5) = ((6 + 1) + 5) = (7 + 5) = 12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((-4 * -4) - (-3 - 12)) = (16 - (-3 - 12)) = (16 - -15) = 31.\n(Final response) So the answer is 31.", "correct_answer": "31", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 347, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 - 7 * 4) * (1 - -2 * 9)) + ((8 + 6 - 6) * (-3 + -9 * -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-3 - 7 * 4), B = (1 - -2 * 9), C = (8 + 6 - 6) and D = (-3 + -9 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - 7 * 4) = (-3 - (7 * 4)) = (-3 - 28) = -31.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - -2 * 9) = (1 - (-2 * 9)) = (1 - -18) = 19.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 + 6 - 6) = ((8 + 6) - 6) = (14 - 6) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 + -9 * -2) = (-3 + (-9 * -2)) = (-3 + 18) = 15.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((-31 * 19) + (8 * 15)) = (-589 + (8 * 15)) = (-589 + 120) = -469.\n(Final response) So the answer is -469.", "correct_answer": "-469", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 412, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 - -2 * -8) - (-7 * 8 + 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (7 - -2 * -8) and B = (-7 * 8 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -2 * -8) = (7 - (-2 * -8)) = (7 - 16) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 8 + 2) = ((-7 * 8) + 2) = (-56 + 2) = -54.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-9 - -54) = 45.\n(Final response) So the answer is 45.", "correct_answer": "45", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 62, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 - -4 * -6) + (-2 + -3 * 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 - -4 * -6) and B = (-2 + -3 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -4 * -6) = (7 - (-4 * -6)) = (7 - 24) = -17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + -3 * 0) = (-2 + (-3 * 0)) = (-2 + 0) = -2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-17 + -2) = -19.\n(Final response) So the answer is -19.", "correct_answer": "-19", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 100, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 - 8 + 8 * -6 + -5) - (6 + 0 - 7 - -3 - -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 - 8 + 8 * -6 + -5) and B = (6 + 0 - 7 - -3 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - 8 + 8 * -6 + -5) = (((-1 - 8) + (8 * -6)) + -5) = ((-9 + (8 * -6)) + -5) = ((-9 + -48) + -5) = (-57 + -5) = -62.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 0 - 7 - -3 - -5) = ((((6 + 0) - 7) - -3) - -5) = (((6 - 7) - -3) - -5) = ((-1 - -3) - -5) = (2 - -5) = 7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-62 - 7) = -69.\n(Final response) So the answer is -69.", "correct_answer": "-69", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 61, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 - 6 - 2) + (-2 - -6 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (2 - 6 - 2) and B = (-2 - -6 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - 6 - 2) = ((2 - 6) - 2) = (-4 - 2) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - -6 - -2) = ((-2 - -6) - -2) = (4 - -2) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-6 + 6) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 55, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 * 0 + 8 - -4) - (0 + -1 + -7 * 4)) + ((9 - 9 + -1 + 5) - (-6 - -3 - 5 - -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-8 * 0 + 8 - -4), B = (0 + -1 + -7 * 4), C = (9 - 9 + -1 + 5) and D = (-6 - -3 - 5 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 0 + 8 - -4) = (((-8 * 0) + 8) - -4) = ((0 + 8) - -4) = (8 - -4) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -1 + -7 * 4) = ((0 + -1) + (-7 * 4)) = (-1 + (-7 * 4)) = (-1 + -28) = -29.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - 9 + -1 + 5) = (((9 - 9) + -1) + 5) = ((0 + -1) + 5) = (-1 + 5) = 4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - -3 - 5 - -3) = (((-6 - -3) - 5) - -3) = ((-3 - 5) - -3) = (-8 - -3) = -5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((12 - -29) + (4 - -5)) = (41 + (4 - -5)) = (41 + 9) = 50.\n(Final response) So the answer is 50.", "correct_answer": "50", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 478, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 - 2 - 4) - (0 - -9 - 5)) - ((-7 - -1 + 5) - (-5 + -3 * 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-7 - 2 - 4), B = (0 - -9 - 5), C = (-7 - -1 + 5) and D = (-5 + -3 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - 2 - 4) = ((-7 - 2) - 4) = (-9 - 4) = -13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - -9 - 5) = ((0 - -9) - 5) = (9 - 5) = 4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - -1 + 5) = ((-7 - -1) + 5) = (-6 + 5) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 + -3 * 6) = (-5 + (-3 * 6)) = (-5 + -18) = -23.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-13 - 4) - (-1 - -23)) = (-17 - (-1 - -23)) = (-17 - 22) = -39.\n(Final response) So the answer is -39.", "correct_answer": "-39", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 420, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 - 5 + 5) * (6 + -9 + -7)) * ((-5 * -9 + 5) * (4 + 3 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (2 - 5 + 5), B = (6 + -9 + -7), C = (-5 * -9 + 5) and D = (4 + 3 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - 5 + 5) = ((2 - 5) + 5) = (-3 + 5) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + -9 + -7) = ((6 + -9) + -7) = (-3 + -7) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * -9 + 5) = ((-5 * -9) + 5) = (45 + 5) = 50.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + 3 * 2) = (4 + (3 * 2)) = (4 + 6) = 10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((2 * -10) * (50 * 10)) = (-20 * (50 * 10)) = (-20 * 500) = -10000.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10000.", "correct_answer": "-10000", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 124, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 * -3 - -4) + (-9 - 4 * -1)) * ((-4 * 7 + 1) + (-6 + -1 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (6 * -3 - -4), B = (-9 - 4 * -1), C = (-4 * 7 + 1) and D = (-6 + -1 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * -3 - -4) = ((6 * -3) - -4) = (-18 - -4) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 4 * -1) = (-9 - (4 * -1)) = (-9 - -4) = -5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 * 7 + 1) = ((-4 * 7) + 1) = (-28 + 1) = -27.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + -1 * -6) = (-6 + (-1 * -6)) = (-6 + 6) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-14 + -5) * (-27 + 0)) = (-19 * (-27 + 0)) = (-19 * -27) = 513.\n(Final response) So the answer is 513.", "correct_answer": "513", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 362, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 * 7 + -9) - (8 + -9 - -6)) + ((-1 + -8 * 5) * (-6 + 7 - -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C * D))\", where A = (7 * 7 + -9), B = (8 + -9 - -6), C = (-1 + -8 * 5) and D = (-6 + 7 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 7 + -9) = ((7 * 7) + -9) = (49 + -9) = 40.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + -9 - -6) = ((8 + -9) - -6) = (-1 - -6) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + -8 * 5) = (-1 + (-8 * 5)) = (-1 + -40) = -41.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + 7 - -1) = ((-6 + 7) - -1) = (1 - -1) = 2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C * D)) = ((40 - 5) + (-41 * 2)) = (35 + (-41 * 2)) = (35 + -82) = -47.\n(Final response) So the answer is -47.", "correct_answer": "-47", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 441, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 - 8 + -3 - -5 * 2) * (5 - 9 * -2 * -3 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-4 - 8 + -3 - -5 * 2) and B = (5 - 9 * -2 * -3 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 8 + -3 - -5 * 2) = (((-4 - 8) + -3) - (-5 * 2)) = ((-12 + -3) - (-5 * 2)) = ((-12 + -3) - -10) = (-15 - -10) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 9 * -2 * -3 * -3) = (5 - (((9 * -2) * -3) * -3)) = (5 - ((-18 * -3) * -3)) = (5 - (54 * -3)) = (5 - -162) = 167.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-5 * 167) = -835.\n(Final response) So the answer is -835.", "correct_answer": "-835", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 74, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-7 - -4 + 6 * -2 * -9) * (2 * 3 - 4 * 4 * 9)) + ((-3 + -5 + 2 + -4 + 2) + (4 - -1 * -7 + 1 + 7))) - (((3 + 9 - 3 - -6 * -9) * (-2 + 6 - -7 + 0 + 0)) - ((8 + -7 - 0 + 5 + -1) * (2 * -8 * -3 * -1 - -8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C + D)) - ((E * F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (-7 - -4 + 6 * -2 * -9), B = (2 * 3 - 4 * 4 * 9), C = (-3 + -5 + 2 + -4 + 2), D = (4 - -1 * -7 + 1 + 7), E = (3 + 9 - 3 - -6 * -9), F = (-2 + 6 - -7 + 0 + 0), G = (8 + -7 - 0 + 5 + -1) and H = (2 * -8 * -3 * -1 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - -4 + 6 * -2 * -9) = ((-7 - -4) + ((6 * -2) * -9)) = (-3 + ((6 * -2) * -9)) = (-3 + (-12 * -9)) = (-3 + 108) = 105.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 3 - 4 * 4 * 9) = ((2 * 3) - ((4 * 4) * 9)) = (6 - ((4 * 4) * 9)) = (6 - (16 * 9)) = (6 - 144) = -138.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -5 + 2 + -4 + 2) = ((((-3 + -5) + 2) + -4) + 2) = (((-8 + 2) + -4) + 2) = ((-6 + -4) + 2) = (-10 + 2) = -8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 - -1 * -7 + 1 + 7) = (((4 - (-1 * -7)) + 1) + 7) = (((4 - 7) + 1) + 7) = ((-3 + 1) + 7) = (-2 + 7) = 5.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (3 + 9 - 3 - -6 * -9) = (((3 + 9) - 3) - (-6 * -9)) = ((12 - 3) - (-6 * -9)) = ((12 - 3) - 54) = (9 - 54) = -45.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-2 + 6 - -7 + 0 + 0) = ((((-2 + 6) - -7) + 0) + 0) = (((4 - -7) + 0) + 0) = ((11 + 0) + 0) = (11 + 0) = 11.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 + -7 - 0 + 5 + -1) = ((((8 + -7) - 0) + 5) + -1) = (((1 - 0) + 5) + -1) = ((1 + 5) + -1) = (6 + -1) = 5.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (2 * -8 * -3 * -1 - -8) = ((((2 * -8) * -3) * -1) - -8) = (((-16 * -3) * -1) - -8) = ((48 * -1) - -8) = (-48 - -8) = -40.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C + D)) - ((E * F) - (G * H))) = (((105 * -138) + (-8 + 5)) - ((-45 * 11) - (5 * -40))) = ((-14490 + (-8 + 5)) - ((-45 * 11) - (5 * -40))) = ((-14490 + -3) - ((-45 * 11) - (5 * -40))) = ((-14490 + -3) - (-495 - (5 * -40))) = ((-14490 + -3) - (-495 - -200)) = (-14493 - (-495 - -200)) = (-14493 - -295) = -14198.\n(Final response) So the answer is -14198.", "correct_answer": "-14198", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 306, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 - -8 * 7) * (2 * 9 - -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-3 - -8 * 7) and B = (2 * 9 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - -8 * 7) = (-3 - (-8 * 7)) = (-3 - -56) = 53.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 9 - -3) = ((2 * 9) - -3) = (18 - -3) = 21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (53 * 21) = 1113.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1113.", "correct_answer": "1113", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 96, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 * -8 + -6 + 9) - (0 + 5 * 9 + -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-6 * -8 + -6 + 9) and B = (0 + 5 * 9 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * -8 + -6 + 9) = (((-6 * -8) + -6) + 9) = ((48 + -6) + 9) = (42 + 9) = 51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + 5 * 9 + -6) = ((0 + (5 * 9)) + -6) = ((0 + 45) + -6) = (45 + -6) = 39.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (51 - 39) = 12.\n(Final response) So the answer is 12.", "correct_answer": "12", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 194, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 + -8 - 6) + (-5 - 8 - -5)) * ((3 * 7 + 8) - (2 - 8 - -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (5 + -8 - 6), B = (-5 - 8 - -5), C = (3 * 7 + 8) and D = (2 - 8 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + -8 - 6) = ((5 + -8) - 6) = (-3 - 6) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - 8 - -5) = ((-5 - 8) - -5) = (-13 - -5) = -8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 * 7 + 8) = ((3 * 7) + 8) = (21 + 8) = 29.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 - 8 - -8) = ((2 - 8) - -8) = (-6 - -8) = 2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((-9 + -8) * (29 - 2)) = (-17 * (29 - 2)) = (-17 * 27) = -459.\n(Final response) So the answer is -459.", "correct_answer": "-459", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 416, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 + 3 + 5 - -2 - -1) + (-1 * 1 - 7 + 1 - -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (9 + 3 + 5 - -2 - -1) and B = (-1 * 1 - 7 + 1 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + 3 + 5 - -2 - -1) = ((((9 + 3) + 5) - -2) - -1) = (((12 + 5) - -2) - -1) = ((17 - -2) - -1) = (19 - -1) = 20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * 1 - 7 + 1 - -6) = ((((-1 * 1) - 7) + 1) - -6) = (((-1 - 7) + 1) - -6) = ((-8 + 1) - -6) = (-7 - -6) = -1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (20 + -1) = 19.\n(Final response) So the answer is 19.", "correct_answer": "19", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 81, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 - 7 + -6 * 4) * (-7 - -2 * -9 - 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (3 - 7 + -6 * 4) and B = (-7 - -2 * -9 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - 7 + -6 * 4) = ((3 - 7) + (-6 * 4)) = (-4 + (-6 * 4)) = (-4 + -24) = -28.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -2 * -9 - 8) = ((-7 - (-2 * -9)) - 8) = ((-7 - 18) - 8) = (-25 - 8) = -33.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-28 * -33) = 924.\n(Final response) So the answer is 924.", "correct_answer": "924", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 248, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + 7 + -8 - -9) * (-6 + -8 * -4 + 5)) * ((0 * -1 + 0 + 2) + (7 - -5 - 1 - 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (1 + 7 + -8 - -9), B = (-6 + -8 * -4 + 5), C = (0 * -1 + 0 + 2) and D = (7 - -5 - 1 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 7 + -8 - -9) = (((1 + 7) + -8) - -9) = ((8 + -8) - -9) = (0 - -9) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -8 * -4 + 5) = ((-6 + (-8 * -4)) + 5) = ((-6 + 32) + 5) = (26 + 5) = 31.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * -1 + 0 + 2) = (((0 * -1) + 0) + 2) = ((0 + 0) + 2) = (0 + 2) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 - -5 - 1 - 0) = (((7 - -5) - 1) - 0) = ((12 - 1) - 0) = (11 - 0) = 11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((9 * 31) * (2 + 11)) = (279 * (2 + 11)) = (279 * 13) = 3627.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3627.", "correct_answer": "3627", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 484, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 * -5 * 8 - -1) - (-3 + 8 - 0 - 3)) + ((-2 - -3 * -2 + -9) * (-9 * 6 - -6 - -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C * D))\", where A = (4 * -5 * 8 - -1), B = (-3 + 8 - 0 - 3), C = (-2 - -3 * -2 + -9) and D = (-9 * 6 - -6 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * -5 * 8 - -1) = (((4 * -5) * 8) - -1) = ((-20 * 8) - -1) = (-160 - -1) = -159.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 8 - 0 - 3) = (((-3 + 8) - 0) - 3) = ((5 - 0) - 3) = (5 - 3) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 - -3 * -2 + -9) = ((-2 - (-3 * -2)) + -9) = ((-2 - 6) + -9) = (-8 + -9) = -17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 * 6 - -6 - -7) = (((-9 * 6) - -6) - -7) = ((-54 - -6) - -7) = (-48 - -7) = -41.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C * D)) = ((-159 - 2) + (-17 * -41)) = (-161 + (-17 * -41)) = (-161 + 697) = 536.\n(Final response) So the answer is 536.", "correct_answer": "536", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 590, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 * 5 - -4 + 1) * (-7 * -9 + 1 - 8)) * ((-3 + 2 + -2 * 1) - (-2 * -6 * 2 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (8 * 5 - -4 + 1), B = (-7 * -9 + 1 - 8), C = (-3 + 2 + -2 * 1) and D = (-2 * -6 * 2 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 5 - -4 + 1) = (((8 * 5) - -4) + 1) = ((40 - -4) + 1) = (44 + 1) = 45.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * -9 + 1 - 8) = (((-7 * -9) + 1) - 8) = ((63 + 1) - 8) = (64 - 8) = 56.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + 2 + -2 * 1) = ((-3 + 2) + (-2 * 1)) = (-1 + (-2 * 1)) = (-1 + -2) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * -6 * 2 * 0) = (((-2 * -6) * 2) * 0) = ((12 * 2) * 0) = (24 * 0) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((45 * 56) * (-3 - 0)) = (2520 * (-3 - 0)) = (2520 * -3) = -7560.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7560.", "correct_answer": "-7560", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 584, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * 0 - 1) + (-3 * 8 - 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (9 * 0 - 1) and B = (-3 * 8 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 0 - 1) = ((9 * 0) - 1) = (0 - 1) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 * 8 - 4) = ((-3 * 8) - 4) = (-24 - 4) = -28.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-1 + -28) = -29.\n(Final response) So the answer is -29.", "correct_answer": "-29", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 135, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - 9 - 6) + (-5 * -4 * 7)) + ((7 * 3 - 3) - (-3 + 4 - -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (6 - 9 - 6), B = (-5 * -4 * 7), C = (7 * 3 - 3) and D = (-3 + 4 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - 9 - 6) = ((6 - 9) - 6) = (-3 - 6) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -4 * 7) = ((-5 * -4) * 7) = (20 * 7) = 140.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 * 3 - 3) = ((7 * 3) - 3) = (21 - 3) = 18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 + 4 - -6) = ((-3 + 4) - -6) = (1 - -6) = 7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((-9 + 140) + (18 - 7)) = (131 + (18 - 7)) = (131 + 11) = 142.\n(Final response) So the answer is 142.", "correct_answer": "142", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 122, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 * 8 - 7 - -4) + (5 * -4 * -9 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (8 * 8 - 7 - -4) and B = (5 * -4 * -9 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 8 - 7 - -4) = (((8 * 8) - 7) - -4) = ((64 - 7) - -4) = (57 - -4) = 61.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * -4 * -9 - 3) = (((5 * -4) * -9) - 3) = ((-20 * -9) - 3) = (180 - 3) = 177.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (61 + 177) = 238.\n(Final response) So the answer is 238.", "correct_answer": "238", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 219, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 + -5 - -7 * 7) - (-7 * 7 + 4 - 6)) + ((1 + -5 + 5 - 6) - (4 + -9 - 1 * 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-5 + -5 - -7 * 7), B = (-7 * 7 + 4 - 6), C = (1 + -5 + 5 - 6) and D = (4 + -9 - 1 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + -5 - -7 * 7) = ((-5 + -5) - (-7 * 7)) = (-10 - (-7 * 7)) = (-10 - -49) = 39.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 7 + 4 - 6) = (((-7 * 7) + 4) - 6) = ((-49 + 4) - 6) = (-45 - 6) = -51.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 + -5 + 5 - 6) = (((1 + -5) + 5) - 6) = ((-4 + 5) - 6) = (1 - 6) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + -9 - 1 * 6) = ((4 + -9) - (1 * 6)) = (-5 - (1 * 6)) = (-5 - 6) = -11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((39 - -51) + (-5 - -11)) = (90 + (-5 - -11)) = (90 + 6) = 96.\n(Final response) So the answer is 96.", "correct_answer": "96", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 167, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 + 1 + 9 * 5 * -3) - (-7 - 3 * -5 * 8 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-5 + 1 + 9 * 5 * -3) and B = (-7 - 3 * -5 * 8 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + 1 + 9 * 5 * -3) = ((-5 + 1) + ((9 * 5) * -3)) = (-4 + ((9 * 5) * -3)) = (-4 + (45 * -3)) = (-4 + -135) = -139.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - 3 * -5 * 8 - -2) = ((-7 - ((3 * -5) * 8)) - -2) = ((-7 - (-15 * 8)) - -2) = ((-7 - -120) - -2) = (113 - -2) = 115.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-139 - 115) = -254.\n(Final response) So the answer is -254.", "correct_answer": "-254", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 85, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 + 3 * 4 + -3) - (5 + -1 - 5 - -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 + 3 * 4 + -3) and B = (5 + -1 - 5 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 3 * 4 + -3) = ((6 + (3 * 4)) + -3) = ((6 + 12) + -3) = (18 + -3) = 15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + -1 - 5 - -5) = (((5 + -1) - 5) - -5) = ((4 - 5) - -5) = (-1 - -5) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (15 - 4) = 11.\n(Final response) So the answer is 11.", "correct_answer": "11", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 285, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 + 1 + 6 * 7) * (5 + 0 * -9 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (8 + 1 + 6 * 7) and B = (5 + 0 * -9 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 1 + 6 * 7) = ((8 + 1) + (6 * 7)) = (9 + (6 * 7)) = (9 + 42) = 51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 0 * -9 + -1) = ((5 + (0 * -9)) + -1) = ((5 + 0) + -1) = (5 + -1) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (51 * 4) = 204.\n(Final response) So the answer is 204.", "correct_answer": "204", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 243, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 - 0 - 7 * 1) - (5 * -3 - 9 + 8)) + ((-9 * 3 - 7 - -9) + (4 * 8 + 2 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-1 - 0 - 7 * 1), B = (5 * -3 - 9 + 8), C = (-9 * 3 - 7 - -9) and D = (4 * 8 + 2 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - 0 - 7 * 1) = ((-1 - 0) - (7 * 1)) = (-1 - (7 * 1)) = (-1 - 7) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * -3 - 9 + 8) = (((5 * -3) - 9) + 8) = ((-15 - 9) + 8) = (-24 + 8) = -16.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * 3 - 7 - -9) = (((-9 * 3) - 7) - -9) = ((-27 - 7) - -9) = (-34 - -9) = -25.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * 8 + 2 * -6) = ((4 * 8) + (2 * -6)) = (32 + (2 * -6)) = (32 + -12) = 20.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-8 - -16) + (-25 + 20)) = (8 + (-25 + 20)) = (8 + -5) = 3.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3.", "correct_answer": "3", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 526, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-6 * -6 - -4) - (-1 + -3 + -9)) - ((0 * -4 - 6) * (3 * 5 - 4))) * (((5 * 1 - -6) * (-5 * -8 * 0)) + ((-2 * 7 * 1) - (0 + -2 + 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C * D)) * ((E * F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (-6 * -6 - -4), B = (-1 + -3 + -9), C = (0 * -4 - 6), D = (3 * 5 - 4), E = (5 * 1 - -6), F = (-5 * -8 * 0), G = (-2 * 7 * 1) and H = (0 + -2 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * -6 - -4) = ((-6 * -6) - -4) = (36 - -4) = 40.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -3 + -9) = ((-1 + -3) + -9) = (-4 + -9) = -13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * -4 - 6) = ((0 * -4) - 6) = (0 - 6) = -6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * 5 - 4) = ((3 * 5) - 4) = (15 - 4) = 11.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (5 * 1 - -6) = ((5 * 1) - -6) = (5 - -6) = 11.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-5 * -8 * 0) = ((-5 * -8) * 0) = (40 * 0) = 0.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-2 * 7 * 1) = ((-2 * 7) * 1) = (-14 * 1) = -14.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (0 + -2 + 3) = ((0 + -2) + 3) = (-2 + 3) = 1.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C * D)) * ((E * F) + (G - H))) = (((40 - -13) - (-6 * 11)) * ((11 * 0) + (-14 - 1))) = ((53 - (-6 * 11)) * ((11 * 0) + (-14 - 1))) = ((53 - -66) * ((11 * 0) + (-14 - 1))) = ((53 - -66) * (0 + (-14 - 1))) = ((53 - -66) * (0 + -15)) = (119 * (0 + -15)) = (119 * -15) = -1785.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1785.", "correct_answer": "-1785", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 259, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * -2 + -2) + (-4 - 3 + -4)) * ((6 - 7 + 2) - (9 - 2 - -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (3 * -2 + -2), B = (-4 - 3 + -4), C = (6 - 7 + 2) and D = (9 - 2 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -2 + -2) = ((3 * -2) + -2) = (-6 + -2) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - 3 + -4) = ((-4 - 3) + -4) = (-7 + -4) = -11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 7 + 2) = ((6 - 7) + 2) = (-1 + 2) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - 2 - -4) = ((9 - 2) - -4) = (7 - -4) = 11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((-8 + -11) * (1 - 11)) = (-19 * (1 - 11)) = (-19 * -10) = 190.\n(Final response) So the answer is 190.", "correct_answer": "190", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 338, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 - 0 + -8 - -7 + 8 * 2) + (-4 * 7 - 6 * 6 + 1 * -4)) * ((2 - 0 * 5 * 6 + 3 * -5) - (9 + -9 - 5 * 0 - 7 + 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (0 - 0 + -8 - -7 + 8 * 2), B = (-4 * 7 - 6 * 6 + 1 * -4), C = (2 - 0 * 5 * 6 + 3 * -5) and D = (9 + -9 - 5 * 0 - 7 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - 0 + -8 - -7 + 8 * 2) = ((((0 - 0) + -8) - -7) + (8 * 2)) = (((0 + -8) - -7) + (8 * 2)) = (((0 + -8) - -7) + 16) = ((-8 - -7) + 16) = (-1 + 16) = 15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 7 - 6 * 6 + 1 * -4) = (((-4 * 7) - (6 * 6)) + (1 * -4)) = ((-28 - (6 * 6)) + (1 * -4)) = ((-28 - 36) + (1 * -4)) = ((-28 - 36) + -4) = (-64 + -4) = -68.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - 0 * 5 * 6 + 3 * -5) = ((2 - ((0 * 5) * 6)) + (3 * -5)) = ((2 - (0 * 6)) + (3 * -5)) = ((2 - (0 * 6)) + -15) = ((2 - 0) + -15) = (2 + -15) = -13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -9 - 5 * 0 - 7 + 7) = ((((9 + -9) - (5 * 0)) - 7) + 7) = (((0 - (5 * 0)) - 7) + 7) = (((0 - 0) - 7) + 7) = ((0 - 7) + 7) = (-7 + 7) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((15 + -68) * (-13 - 0)) = (-53 * (-13 - 0)) = (-53 * -13) = 689.\n(Final response) So the answer is 689.", "correct_answer": "689", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 236, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 + -1 - 4) - (7 - 3 * -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-9 + -1 - 4) and B = (7 - 3 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -1 - 4) = ((-9 + -1) - 4) = (-10 - 4) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - 3 * -1) = (7 - (3 * -1)) = (7 - -3) = 10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-14 - 10) = -24.\n(Final response) So the answer is -24.", "correct_answer": "-24", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 69, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 + -6 * -5 * 9 - -7 * -6) - (4 + -1 * -7 * -9 - 9 - 8)) - ((0 + -7 * -7 + 5 - 6 + -8) - (1 * -4 - 5 - 3 - 2 + 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-8 + -6 * -5 * 9 - -7 * -6), B = (4 + -1 * -7 * -9 - 9 - 8), C = (0 + -7 * -7 + 5 - 6 + -8) and D = (1 * -4 - 5 - 3 - 2 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + -6 * -5 * 9 - -7 * -6) = ((-8 + ((-6 * -5) * 9)) - (-7 * -6)) = ((-8 + (30 * 9)) - (-7 * -6)) = ((-8 + (30 * 9)) - 42) = ((-8 + 270) - 42) = (262 - 42) = 220.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + -1 * -7 * -9 - 9 - 8) = (((4 + ((-1 * -7) * -9)) - 9) - 8) = (((4 + (7 * -9)) - 9) - 8) = (((4 + -63) - 9) - 8) = ((-59 - 9) - 8) = (-68 - 8) = -76.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 + -7 * -7 + 5 - 6 + -8) = ((((0 + (-7 * -7)) + 5) - 6) + -8) = ((((0 + 49) + 5) - 6) + -8) = (((49 + 5) - 6) + -8) = ((54 - 6) + -8) = (48 + -8) = 40.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 * -4 - 5 - 3 - 2 + 4) = (((((1 * -4) - 5) - 3) - 2) + 4) = ((((-4 - 5) - 3) - 2) + 4) = (((-9 - 3) - 2) + 4) = ((-12 - 2) + 4) = (-14 + 4) = -10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((220 - -76) - (40 - -10)) = (296 - (40 - -10)) = (296 - 50) = 246.\n(Final response) So the answer is 246.", "correct_answer": "246", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 237, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 + -5 - -7) + (-5 + -5 - 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 + -5 - -7) and B = (-5 + -5 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -5 - -7) = ((7 + -5) - -7) = (2 - -7) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + -5 - 0) = ((-5 + -5) - 0) = (-10 - 0) = -10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (9 + -10) = -1.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1.", "correct_answer": "-1", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 60, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * -5 - 7 + -8) + (8 + -4 * -4 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 * -5 - 7 + -8) and B = (8 + -4 * -4 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * -5 - 7 + -8) = (((7 * -5) - 7) + -8) = ((-35 - 7) + -8) = (-42 + -8) = -50.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + -4 * -4 - 3) = ((8 + (-4 * -4)) - 3) = ((8 + 16) - 3) = (24 - 3) = 21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-50 + 21) = -29.\n(Final response) So the answer is -29.", "correct_answer": "-29", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 46, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 * 9 * -7) * (4 * 5 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (4 * 9 * -7) and B = (4 * 5 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 9 * -7) = ((4 * 9) * -7) = (36 * -7) = -252.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 5 + 8) = ((4 * 5) + 8) = (20 + 8) = 28.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-252 * 28) = -7056.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7056.", "correct_answer": "-7056", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 72, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + 3 + 5) + (-9 + -3 + -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (5 + 3 + 5) and B = (-9 + -3 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 3 + 5) = ((5 + 3) + 5) = (8 + 5) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + -3 + -9) = ((-9 + -3) + -9) = (-12 + -9) = -21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (13 + -21) = -8.\n(Final response) So the answer is -8.", "correct_answer": "-8", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 7, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((5 + 1 + -1 * 8 + 8) * (-7 + -4 - 1 * -1 + 7)) + ((9 * 4 * 9 + -6 * 5) * (-7 + -9 - 6 * -5 - -2))) * (((-1 + -7 * 8 + -9 * 1) + (-4 + 2 - 4 + 1 + 8)) + ((8 + -5 - -2 + 5 * 6) - (-3 + -4 + -8 + -7 + -1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (5 + 1 + -1 * 8 + 8), B = (-7 + -4 - 1 * -1 + 7), C = (9 * 4 * 9 + -6 * 5), D = (-7 + -9 - 6 * -5 - -2), E = (-1 + -7 * 8 + -9 * 1), F = (-4 + 2 - 4 + 1 + 8), G = (8 + -5 - -2 + 5 * 6) and H = (-3 + -4 + -8 + -7 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 1 + -1 * 8 + 8) = (((5 + 1) + (-1 * 8)) + 8) = ((6 + (-1 * 8)) + 8) = ((6 + -8) + 8) = (-2 + 8) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -4 - 1 * -1 + 7) = (((-7 + -4) - (1 * -1)) + 7) = ((-11 - (1 * -1)) + 7) = ((-11 - -1) + 7) = (-10 + 7) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 * 4 * 9 + -6 * 5) = (((9 * 4) * 9) + (-6 * 5)) = ((36 * 9) + (-6 * 5)) = ((36 * 9) + -30) = (324 + -30) = 294.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + -9 - 6 * -5 - -2) = (((-7 + -9) - (6 * -5)) - -2) = ((-16 - (6 * -5)) - -2) = ((-16 - -30) - -2) = (14 - -2) = 16.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-1 + -7 * 8 + -9 * 1) = ((-1 + (-7 * 8)) + (-9 * 1)) = ((-1 + -56) + (-9 * 1)) = ((-1 + -56) + -9) = (-57 + -9) = -66.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-4 + 2 - 4 + 1 + 8) = ((((-4 + 2) - 4) + 1) + 8) = (((-2 - 4) + 1) + 8) = ((-6 + 1) + 8) = (-5 + 8) = 3.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 + -5 - -2 + 5 * 6) = (((8 + -5) - -2) + (5 * 6)) = ((3 - -2) + (5 * 6)) = ((3 - -2) + 30) = (5 + 30) = 35.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-3 + -4 + -8 + -7 + -1) = ((((-3 + -4) + -8) + -7) + -1) = (((-7 + -8) + -7) + -1) = ((-15 + -7) + -1) = (-22 + -1) = -23.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G - H))) = (((6 * -3) + (294 * 16)) * ((-66 + 3) + (35 - -23))) = ((-18 + (294 * 16)) * ((-66 + 3) + (35 - -23))) = ((-18 + 4704) * ((-66 + 3) + (35 - -23))) = ((-18 + 4704) * (-63 + (35 - -23))) = ((-18 + 4704) * (-63 + 58)) = (4686 * (-63 + 58)) = (4686 * -5) = -23430.\n(Final response) So the answer is -23430.", "correct_answer": "-23430", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 327, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 * 5 * 9 * -1 + -5 * -6) - (-7 - -3 - -2 * -3 - 7 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (4 * 5 * 9 * -1 + -5 * -6) and B = (-7 - -3 - -2 * -3 - 7 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 5 * 9 * -1 + -5 * -6) = ((((4 * 5) * 9) * -1) + (-5 * -6)) = (((20 * 9) * -1) + (-5 * -6)) = (((20 * 9) * -1) + 30) = ((180 * -1) + 30) = (-180 + 30) = -150.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -3 - -2 * -3 - 7 - 2) = ((((-7 - -3) - (-2 * -3)) - 7) - 2) = (((-4 - (-2 * -3)) - 7) - 2) = (((-4 - 6) - 7) - 2) = ((-10 - 7) - 2) = (-17 - 2) = -19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-150 - -19) = -131.\n(Final response) So the answer is -131.", "correct_answer": "-131", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 105, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 + -8 + 3 + 6) - (9 + 5 - 5 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 + -8 + 3 + 6) and B = (9 + 5 - 5 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + -8 + 3 + 6) = (((0 + -8) + 3) + 6) = ((-8 + 3) + 6) = (-5 + 6) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + 5 - 5 * -3) = ((9 + 5) - (5 * -3)) = (14 - (5 * -3)) = (14 - -15) = 29.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (1 - 29) = -28.\n(Final response) So the answer is -28.", "correct_answer": "-28", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 235, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 + 7 + 2 * -2) - (8 * 4 * -5 + 3)) - ((-8 + -9 * 0 - 9) + (3 * -7 + -6 * 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (5 + 7 + 2 * -2), B = (8 * 4 * -5 + 3), C = (-8 + -9 * 0 - 9) and D = (3 * -7 + -6 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 7 + 2 * -2) = ((5 + 7) + (2 * -2)) = (12 + (2 * -2)) = (12 + -4) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 4 * -5 + 3) = (((8 * 4) * -5) + 3) = ((32 * -5) + 3) = (-160 + 3) = -157.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 + -9 * 0 - 9) = ((-8 + (-9 * 0)) - 9) = ((-8 + 0) - 9) = (-8 - 9) = -17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * -7 + -6 * 7) = ((3 * -7) + (-6 * 7)) = (-21 + (-6 * 7)) = (-21 + -42) = -63.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((8 - -157) - (-17 + -63)) = (165 - (-17 + -63)) = (165 - -80) = 245.\n(Final response) So the answer is 245.", "correct_answer": "245", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 567, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 * -1 - 2) - (5 * -3 * 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 * -1 - 2) and B = (5 * -3 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * -1 - 2) = ((-1 * -1) - 2) = (1 - 2) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * -3 * 6) = ((5 * -3) * 6) = (-15 * 6) = -90.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-1 - -90) = 89.\n(Final response) So the answer is 89.", "correct_answer": "89", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 2, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 - 6 + 7) - (-9 - 2 + -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 - 6 + 7) and B = (-9 - 2 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - 6 + 7) = ((6 - 6) + 7) = (0 + 7) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 2 + -5) = ((-9 - 2) + -5) = (-11 + -5) = -16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (7 - -16) = 23.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23.", "correct_answer": "23", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 21, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 + -7 * 6) * (-5 + -3 - 9)) + ((6 - 9 + 8) * (9 - -9 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-1 + -7 * 6), B = (-5 + -3 - 9), C = (6 - 9 + 8) and D = (9 - -9 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + -7 * 6) = (-1 + (-7 * 6)) = (-1 + -42) = -43.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + -3 - 9) = ((-5 + -3) - 9) = (-8 - 9) = -17.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 9 + 8) = ((6 - 9) + 8) = (-3 + 8) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - -9 * -6) = (9 - (-9 * -6)) = (9 - 54) = -45.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((-43 * -17) + (5 * -45)) = (731 + (5 * -45)) = (731 + -225) = 506.\n(Final response) So the answer is 506.", "correct_answer": "506", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 346, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 * -7 + -5 - -1 + -6) + (7 - 2 - -3 + 6 * -8)) * ((-2 + -7 - -2 * -5 - -1) + (-5 * 9 - 9 * 5 * -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (5 * -7 + -5 - -1 + -6), B = (7 - 2 - -3 + 6 * -8), C = (-2 + -7 - -2 * -5 - -1) and D = (-5 * 9 - 9 * 5 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * -7 + -5 - -1 + -6) = ((((5 * -7) + -5) - -1) + -6) = (((-35 + -5) - -1) + -6) = ((-40 - -1) + -6) = (-39 + -6) = -45.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - 2 - -3 + 6 * -8) = (((7 - 2) - -3) + (6 * -8)) = ((5 - -3) + (6 * -8)) = ((5 - -3) + -48) = (8 + -48) = -40.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + -7 - -2 * -5 - -1) = (((-2 + -7) - (-2 * -5)) - -1) = ((-9 - (-2 * -5)) - -1) = ((-9 - 10) - -1) = (-19 - -1) = -18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 * 9 - 9 * 5 * -2) = ((-5 * 9) - ((9 * 5) * -2)) = (-45 - ((9 * 5) * -2)) = (-45 - (45 * -2)) = (-45 - -90) = 45.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-45 + -40) * (-18 + 45)) = (-85 * (-18 + 45)) = (-85 * 27) = -2295.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2295.", "correct_answer": "-2295", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 192, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - 7 * 6 - 1) * (6 + 5 * -1 * 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-2 - 7 * 6 - 1) and B = (6 + 5 * -1 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - 7 * 6 - 1) = ((-2 - (7 * 6)) - 1) = ((-2 - 42) - 1) = (-44 - 1) = -45.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 5 * -1 * 9) = (6 + ((5 * -1) * 9)) = (6 + (-5 * 9)) = (6 + -45) = -39.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-45 * -39) = 1755.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1755.", "correct_answer": "1755", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 230, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 * -6 * 8 + -7) - (-2 * -7 - 0 + 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 * -6 * 8 + -7) and B = (-2 * -7 - 0 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * -6 * 8 + -7) = (((1 * -6) * 8) + -7) = ((-6 * 8) + -7) = (-48 + -7) = -55.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -7 - 0 + 7) = (((-2 * -7) - 0) + 7) = ((14 - 0) + 7) = (14 + 7) = 21.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-55 - 21) = -76.\n(Final response) So the answer is -76.", "correct_answer": "-76", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 253, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 * 0 - -3) + (-9 - 7 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (2 * 0 - -3) and B = (-9 - 7 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 0 - -3) = ((2 * 0) - -3) = (0 - -3) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 7 * 3) = (-9 - (7 * 3)) = (-9 - 21) = -30.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (3 + -30) = -27.\n(Final response) So the answer is -27.", "correct_answer": "-27", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 123, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 - -2 - -8 + 7) - (4 - -9 - -8 + 6)) + ((0 + 1 + 5 * 0) * (-6 - -5 + 1 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-4 - -2 - -8 + 7), B = (4 - -9 - -8 + 6), C = (0 + 1 + 5 * 0) and D = (-6 - -5 + 1 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - -2 - -8 + 7) = (((-4 - -2) - -8) + 7) = ((-2 - -8) + 7) = (6 + 7) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - -9 - -8 + 6) = (((4 - -9) - -8) + 6) = ((13 - -8) + 6) = (21 + 6) = 27.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 + 1 + 5 * 0) = ((0 + 1) + (5 * 0)) = (1 + (5 * 0)) = (1 + 0) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - -5 + 1 * -5) = ((-6 - -5) + (1 * -5)) = (-1 + (1 * -5)) = (-1 + -5) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C * D)) = ((13 - 27) + (1 * -6)) = (-14 + (1 * -6)) = (-14 + -6) = -20.\n(Final response) So the answer is -20.", "correct_answer": "-20", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 462, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 + -3 + 4 - -7) - (1 - 5 - 8 + 5)) * ((5 + 0 * 8 - -2) - (-5 + -2 + 7 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (2 + -3 + 4 - -7), B = (1 - 5 - 8 + 5), C = (5 + 0 * 8 - -2) and D = (-5 + -2 + 7 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + -3 + 4 - -7) = (((2 + -3) + 4) - -7) = ((-1 + 4) - -7) = (3 - -7) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - 5 - 8 + 5) = (((1 - 5) - 8) + 5) = ((-4 - 8) + 5) = (-12 + 5) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 + 0 * 8 - -2) = ((5 + (0 * 8)) - -2) = ((5 + 0) - -2) = (5 - -2) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 + -2 + 7 * -6) = ((-5 + -2) + (7 * -6)) = (-7 + (7 * -6)) = (-7 + -42) = -49.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((10 - -7) * (7 - -49)) = (17 * (7 - -49)) = (17 * 56) = 952.\n(Final response) So the answer is 952.", "correct_answer": "952", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 529, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 + 7 - -1) - (-7 * -9 * 3)) + ((-5 + 6 + -6) * (-1 + -5 + -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C * D))\", where A = (3 + 7 - -1), B = (-7 * -9 * 3), C = (-5 + 6 + -6) and D = (-1 + -5 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + 7 - -1) = ((3 + 7) - -1) = (10 - -1) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * -9 * 3) = ((-7 * -9) * 3) = (63 * 3) = 189.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 + 6 + -6) = ((-5 + 6) + -6) = (1 + -6) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 + -5 + -5) = ((-1 + -5) + -5) = (-6 + -5) = -11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C * D)) = ((11 - 189) + (-5 * -11)) = (-178 + (-5 * -11)) = (-178 + 55) = -123.\n(Final response) So the answer is -123.", "correct_answer": "-123", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 448, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((4 + -1 - 4 * 7 - 6 + -2) + (8 + 1 * -2 - -9 * 7 + -8)) - ((2 + 5 + -4 * -6 + 1 - -5) - (-6 + -7 + -8 * 7 - 2 + 7))) + (((0 + 1 * 4 + -3 * 7 * 6) + (9 - 6 - -8 * 6 - -6 + -9)) + ((-9 - 2 * -3 * -3 + -3 + 6) + (5 * -6 + -2 - -4 + -6 + 2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) - (C - D)) + ((E + F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (4 + -1 - 4 * 7 - 6 + -2), B = (8 + 1 * -2 - -9 * 7 + -8), C = (2 + 5 + -4 * -6 + 1 - -5), D = (-6 + -7 + -8 * 7 - 2 + 7), E = (0 + 1 * 4 + -3 * 7 * 6), F = (9 - 6 - -8 * 6 - -6 + -9), G = (-9 - 2 * -3 * -3 + -3 + 6) and H = (5 * -6 + -2 - -4 + -6 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -1 - 4 * 7 - 6 + -2) = ((((4 + -1) - (4 * 7)) - 6) + -2) = (((3 - (4 * 7)) - 6) + -2) = (((3 - 28) - 6) + -2) = ((-25 - 6) + -2) = (-31 + -2) = -33.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + 1 * -2 - -9 * 7 + -8) = (((8 + (1 * -2)) - (-9 * 7)) + -8) = (((8 + -2) - (-9 * 7)) + -8) = (((8 + -2) - -63) + -8) = ((6 - -63) + -8) = (69 + -8) = 61.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + 5 + -4 * -6 + 1 - -5) = ((((2 + 5) + (-4 * -6)) + 1) - -5) = (((7 + (-4 * -6)) + 1) - -5) = (((7 + 24) + 1) - -5) = ((31 + 1) - -5) = (32 - -5) = 37.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + -7 + -8 * 7 - 2 + 7) = ((((-6 + -7) + (-8 * 7)) - 2) + 7) = (((-13 + (-8 * 7)) - 2) + 7) = (((-13 + -56) - 2) + 7) = ((-69 - 2) + 7) = (-71 + 7) = -64.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 + 1 * 4 + -3 * 7 * 6) = ((0 + (1 * 4)) + ((-3 * 7) * 6)) = ((0 + 4) + ((-3 * 7) * 6)) = ((0 + 4) + (-21 * 6)) = (4 + (-21 * 6)) = (4 + -126) = -122.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (9 - 6 - -8 * 6 - -6 + -9) = ((((9 - 6) - (-8 * 6)) - -6) + -9) = (((3 - (-8 * 6)) - -6) + -9) = (((3 - -48) - -6) + -9) = ((51 - -6) + -9) = (57 + -9) = 48.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-9 - 2 * -3 * -3 + -3 + 6) = (((-9 - ((2 * -3) * -3)) + -3) + 6) = (((-9 - (-6 * -3)) + -3) + 6) = (((-9 - 18) + -3) + 6) = ((-27 + -3) + 6) = (-30 + 6) = -24.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (5 * -6 + -2 - -4 + -6 + 2) = (((((5 * -6) + -2) - -4) + -6) + 2) = ((((-30 + -2) - -4) + -6) + 2) = (((-32 - -4) + -6) + 2) = ((-28 + -6) + 2) = (-34 + 2) = -32.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) - (C - D)) + ((E + F) + (G + H))) = (((-33 + 61) - (37 - -64)) + ((-122 + 48) + (-24 + -32))) = ((28 - (37 - -64)) + ((-122 + 48) + (-24 + -32))) = ((28 - 101) + ((-122 + 48) + (-24 + -32))) = ((28 - 101) + (-74 + (-24 + -32))) = ((28 - 101) + (-74 + -56)) = (-73 + (-74 + -56)) = (-73 + -130) = -203.\n(Final response) So the answer is -203.", "correct_answer": "-203", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 351, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-8 + -3 * -2 * -5 - -2 * -8) - (-4 - 0 - -1 + -3 - 0 * 8)) + ((-5 - -6 * 3 * -4 * -3 - -1) * (6 * 7 * 7 - 5 + 0 - 0))) + (((3 - -8 - 8 + -8 + -4 * 3) - (-2 - -6 - -7 + -7 * -4 + -9)) * ((-7 - -5 * 9 * 0 - -5 - -7) + (7 * 9 - 2 * -6 * -3 + 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C * D)) + ((E - F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (-8 + -3 * -2 * -5 - -2 * -8), B = (-4 - 0 - -1 + -3 - 0 * 8), C = (-5 - -6 * 3 * -4 * -3 - -1), D = (6 * 7 * 7 - 5 + 0 - 0), E = (3 - -8 - 8 + -8 + -4 * 3), F = (-2 - -6 - -7 + -7 * -4 + -9), G = (-7 - -5 * 9 * 0 - -5 - -7) and H = (7 * 9 - 2 * -6 * -3 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + -3 * -2 * -5 - -2 * -8) = ((-8 + ((-3 * -2) * -5)) - (-2 * -8)) = ((-8 + (6 * -5)) - (-2 * -8)) = ((-8 + (6 * -5)) - 16) = ((-8 + -30) - 16) = (-38 - 16) = -54.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - 0 - -1 + -3 - 0 * 8) = ((((-4 - 0) - -1) + -3) - (0 * 8)) = (((-4 - -1) + -3) - (0 * 8)) = (((-4 - -1) + -3) - 0) = ((-3 + -3) - 0) = (-6 - 0) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - -6 * 3 * -4 * -3 - -1) = ((-5 - (((-6 * 3) * -4) * -3)) - -1) = ((-5 - ((-18 * -4) * -3)) - -1) = ((-5 - (72 * -3)) - -1) = ((-5 - -216) - -1) = (211 - -1) = 212.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 * 7 * 7 - 5 + 0 - 0) = (((((6 * 7) * 7) - 5) + 0) - 0) = ((((42 * 7) - 5) + 0) - 0) = (((294 - 5) + 0) - 0) = ((289 + 0) - 0) = (289 - 0) = 289.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (3 - -8 - 8 + -8 + -4 * 3) = ((((3 - -8) - 8) + -8) + (-4 * 3)) = (((11 - 8) + -8) + (-4 * 3)) = (((11 - 8) + -8) + -12) = ((3 + -8) + -12) = (-5 + -12) = -17.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-2 - -6 - -7 + -7 * -4 + -9) = ((((-2 - -6) - -7) + (-7 * -4)) + -9) = (((4 - -7) + (-7 * -4)) + -9) = (((4 - -7) + 28) + -9) = ((11 + 28) + -9) = (39 + -9) = 30.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-7 - -5 * 9 * 0 - -5 - -7) = (((-7 - ((-5 * 9) * 0)) - -5) - -7) = (((-7 - (-45 * 0)) - -5) - -7) = (((-7 - 0) - -5) - -7) = ((-7 - -5) - -7) = (-2 - -7) = 5.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (7 * 9 - 2 * -6 * -3 + 3) = (((7 * 9) - ((2 * -6) * -3)) + 3) = ((63 - ((2 * -6) * -3)) + 3) = ((63 - (-12 * -3)) + 3) = ((63 - 36) + 3) = (27 + 3) = 30.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C * D)) + ((E - F) * (G + H))) = (((-54 - -6) + (212 * 289)) + ((-17 - 30) * (5 + 30))) = ((-48 + (212 * 289)) + ((-17 - 30) * (5 + 30))) = ((-48 + 61268) + ((-17 - 30) * (5 + 30))) = ((-48 + 61268) + (-47 * (5 + 30))) = ((-48 + 61268) + (-47 * 35)) = (61220 + (-47 * 35)) = (61220 + -1645) = 59575.\n(Final response) So the answer is 59575.", "correct_answer": "59575", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 331, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 - -1 - 2 * 7 * -1) * (0 + -3 - 5 - 2 * -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-4 - -1 - 2 * 7 * -1) and B = (0 + -3 - 5 - 2 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - -1 - 2 * 7 * -1) = ((-4 - -1) - ((2 * 7) * -1)) = (-3 - ((2 * 7) * -1)) = (-3 - (14 * -1)) = (-3 - -14) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -3 - 5 - 2 * -7) = (((0 + -3) - 5) - (2 * -7)) = ((-3 - 5) - (2 * -7)) = ((-3 - 5) - -14) = (-8 - -14) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (11 * 6) = 66.\n(Final response) So the answer is 66.", "correct_answer": "66", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 87, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 + -5 - -6 * -8 * 6) + (-4 - 5 + -1 - -7 * 3)) - ((5 * 6 * -4 - 1 - 0) * (-3 * 8 * -4 - 9 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-2 + -5 - -6 * -8 * 6), B = (-4 - 5 + -1 - -7 * 3), C = (5 * 6 * -4 - 1 - 0) and D = (-3 * 8 * -4 - 9 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -5 - -6 * -8 * 6) = ((-2 + -5) - ((-6 * -8) * 6)) = (-7 - ((-6 * -8) * 6)) = (-7 - (48 * 6)) = (-7 - 288) = -295.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - 5 + -1 - -7 * 3) = (((-4 - 5) + -1) - (-7 * 3)) = ((-9 + -1) - (-7 * 3)) = ((-9 + -1) - -21) = (-10 - -21) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 * 6 * -4 - 1 - 0) = ((((5 * 6) * -4) - 1) - 0) = (((30 * -4) - 1) - 0) = ((-120 - 1) - 0) = (-121 - 0) = -121.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * 8 * -4 - 9 * -6) = (((-3 * 8) * -4) - (9 * -6)) = ((-24 * -4) - (9 * -6)) = ((-24 * -4) - -54) = (96 - -54) = 150.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-295 + 11) - (-121 * 150)) = (-284 - (-121 * 150)) = (-284 - -18150) = 17866.\n(Final response) So the answer is 17866.", "correct_answer": "17866", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 208, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + 3 * 9) - (3 * 2 + -1)) * ((-7 - 1 - -9) + (3 - -9 - -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (7 + 3 * 9), B = (3 * 2 + -1), C = (-7 - 1 - -9) and D = (3 - -9 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 3 * 9) = (7 + (3 * 9)) = (7 + 27) = 34.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 2 + -1) = ((3 * 2) + -1) = (6 + -1) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - 1 - -9) = ((-7 - 1) - -9) = (-8 - -9) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 - -9 - -8) = ((3 - -9) - -8) = (12 - -8) = 20.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((34 - 5) * (1 + 20)) = (29 * (1 + 20)) = (29 * 21) = 609.\n(Final response) So the answer is 609.", "correct_answer": "609", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 319, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 - 0 + 0 - -3) + (7 + -1 - 9 + -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 - 0 + 0 - -3) and B = (7 + -1 - 9 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 0 + 0 - -3) = (((-6 - 0) + 0) - -3) = ((-6 + 0) - -3) = (-6 - -3) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + -1 - 9 + -7) = (((7 + -1) - 9) + -7) = ((6 - 9) + -7) = (-3 + -7) = -10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-3 + -10) = -13.\n(Final response) So the answer is -13.", "correct_answer": "-13", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 205, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 - 5 * -5 + -8 + -1 - -1) * (1 + 8 + -9 + 6 - 8 - -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (8 - 5 * -5 + -8 + -1 - -1) and B = (1 + 8 + -9 + 6 - 8 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - 5 * -5 + -8 + -1 - -1) = ((((8 - (5 * -5)) + -8) + -1) - -1) = ((((8 - -25) + -8) + -1) - -1) = (((33 + -8) + -1) - -1) = ((25 + -1) - -1) = (24 - -1) = 25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + 8 + -9 + 6 - 8 - -1) = (((((1 + 8) + -9) + 6) - 8) - -1) = ((((9 + -9) + 6) - 8) - -1) = (((0 + 6) - 8) - -1) = ((6 - 8) - -1) = (-2 - -1) = -1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (25 * -1) = -25.\n(Final response) So the answer is -25.", "correct_answer": "-25", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 106, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 * 7 - -5 * 1) * (7 * -2 * 4 - -3)) - ((7 + 3 * 4 * 8) - (5 - -5 + 3 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-8 * 7 - -5 * 1), B = (7 * -2 * 4 - -3), C = (7 + 3 * 4 * 8) and D = (5 - -5 + 3 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 7 - -5 * 1) = ((-8 * 7) - (-5 * 1)) = (-56 - (-5 * 1)) = (-56 - -5) = -51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * -2 * 4 - -3) = (((7 * -2) * 4) - -3) = ((-14 * 4) - -3) = (-56 - -3) = -53.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + 3 * 4 * 8) = (7 + ((3 * 4) * 8)) = (7 + (12 * 8)) = (7 + 96) = 103.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 - -5 + 3 * -5) = ((5 - -5) + (3 * -5)) = (10 + (3 * -5)) = (10 + -15) = -5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((-51 * -53) - (103 - -5)) = (2703 - (103 - -5)) = (2703 - 108) = 2595.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2595.", "correct_answer": "2595", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 152, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 * -1 * -3 - -1 - 3 - -6) + (4 * -7 + 8 - -2 * 0 + 7)) + ((-3 + -3 * -7 * -6 + -7 * -2) - (4 * 6 - -3 - 2 * -2 * 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (4 * -1 * -3 - -1 - 3 - -6), B = (4 * -7 + 8 - -2 * 0 + 7), C = (-3 + -3 * -7 * -6 + -7 * -2) and D = (4 * 6 - -3 - 2 * -2 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * -1 * -3 - -1 - 3 - -6) = (((((4 * -1) * -3) - -1) - 3) - -6) = ((((-4 * -3) - -1) - 3) - -6) = (((12 - -1) - 3) - -6) = ((13 - 3) - -6) = (10 - -6) = 16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * -7 + 8 - -2 * 0 + 7) = ((((4 * -7) + 8) - (-2 * 0)) + 7) = (((-28 + 8) - (-2 * 0)) + 7) = (((-28 + 8) - 0) + 7) = ((-20 - 0) + 7) = (-20 + 7) = -13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -3 * -7 * -6 + -7 * -2) = ((-3 + ((-3 * -7) * -6)) + (-7 * -2)) = ((-3 + (21 * -6)) + (-7 * -2)) = ((-3 + (21 * -6)) + 14) = ((-3 + -126) + 14) = (-129 + 14) = -115.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * 6 - -3 - 2 * -2 * 1) = (((4 * 6) - -3) - ((2 * -2) * 1)) = ((24 - -3) - ((2 * -2) * 1)) = ((24 - -3) - (-4 * 1)) = (27 - (-4 * 1)) = (27 - -4) = 31.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((16 + -13) + (-115 - 31)) = (3 + (-115 - 31)) = (3 + -146) = -143.\n(Final response) So the answer is -143.", "correct_answer": "-143", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 230, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 - 6 - 0) + (-9 - 2 - 7)) - ((-5 * -5 * 3) + (-9 - -6 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C + D))\", where A = (7 - 6 - 0), B = (-9 - 2 - 7), C = (-5 * -5 * 3) and D = (-9 - -6 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - 6 - 0) = ((7 - 6) - 0) = (1 - 0) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 2 - 7) = ((-9 - 2) - 7) = (-11 - 7) = -18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * -5 * 3) = ((-5 * -5) * 3) = (25 * 3) = 75.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 - -6 + -1) = ((-9 - -6) + -1) = (-3 + -1) = -4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C + D)) = ((1 + -18) - (75 + -4)) = (-17 - (75 + -4)) = (-17 - 71) = -88.\n(Final response) So the answer is -88.", "correct_answer": "-88", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 433, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + -1 + 6) + (-1 + 3 * -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-1 + -1 + 6) and B = (-1 + 3 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + -1 + 6) = ((-1 + -1) + 6) = (-2 + 6) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + 3 * -1) = (-1 + (3 * -1)) = (-1 + -3) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (4 + -4) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 21, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 + 5 - -5 - 6) - (6 + -9 * 0 + 3)) * ((1 * -8 - 1 * -1) - (-6 * 4 - -7 * 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (0 + 5 - -5 - 6), B = (6 + -9 * 0 + 3), C = (1 * -8 - 1 * -1) and D = (-6 * 4 - -7 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + 5 - -5 - 6) = (((0 + 5) - -5) - 6) = ((5 - -5) - 6) = (10 - 6) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + -9 * 0 + 3) = ((6 + (-9 * 0)) + 3) = ((6 + 0) + 3) = (6 + 3) = 9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 * -8 - 1 * -1) = ((1 * -8) - (1 * -1)) = (-8 - (1 * -1)) = (-8 - -1) = -7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * 4 - -7 * 7) = ((-6 * 4) - (-7 * 7)) = (-24 - (-7 * 7)) = (-24 - -49) = 25.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((4 - 9) * (-7 - 25)) = (-5 * (-7 - 25)) = (-5 * -32) = 160.\n(Final response) So the answer is 160.", "correct_answer": "160", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 540, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 - -2 * -3 * 6 * 0 + -9) * (0 - 1 + -1 - -2 - -6 * -5)) - ((-4 - 8 * 1 + -7 - -6 + 0) * (9 + -9 - 1 * -9 + -2 + 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-3 - -2 * -3 * 6 * 0 + -9), B = (0 - 1 + -1 - -2 - -6 * -5), C = (-4 - 8 * 1 + -7 - -6 + 0) and D = (9 + -9 - 1 * -9 + -2 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - -2 * -3 * 6 * 0 + -9) = ((-3 - (((-2 * -3) * 6) * 0)) + -9) = ((-3 - ((6 * 6) * 0)) + -9) = ((-3 - (36 * 0)) + -9) = ((-3 - 0) + -9) = (-3 + -9) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 1 + -1 - -2 - -6 * -5) = ((((0 - 1) + -1) - -2) - (-6 * -5)) = (((-1 + -1) - -2) - (-6 * -5)) = (((-1 + -1) - -2) - 30) = ((-2 - -2) - 30) = (0 - 30) = -30.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - 8 * 1 + -7 - -6 + 0) = ((((-4 - (8 * 1)) + -7) - -6) + 0) = ((((-4 - 8) + -7) - -6) + 0) = (((-12 + -7) - -6) + 0) = ((-19 - -6) + 0) = (-13 + 0) = -13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + -9 - 1 * -9 + -2 + 0) = ((((9 + -9) - (1 * -9)) + -2) + 0) = (((0 - (1 * -9)) + -2) + 0) = (((0 - -9) + -2) + 0) = ((9 + -2) + 0) = (7 + 0) = 7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-12 * -30) - (-13 * 7)) = (360 - (-13 * 7)) = (360 - -91) = 451.\n(Final response) So the answer is 451.", "correct_answer": "451", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 219, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 + 1 + 7 * 3) - (1 * 2 - -1 * 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (2 + 1 + 7 * 3) and B = (1 * 2 - -1 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + 1 + 7 * 3) = ((2 + 1) + (7 * 3)) = (3 + (7 * 3)) = (3 + 21) = 24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * 2 - -1 * 6) = ((1 * 2) - (-1 * 6)) = (2 - (-1 * 6)) = (2 - -6) = 8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (24 - 8) = 16.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16.", "correct_answer": "16", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 169, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 + 2 + 1 + -9) * (-6 + 7 + 9 * 1)) - ((4 - 9 + -3 - 9) + (-1 + 7 - -4 - -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-9 + 2 + 1 + -9), B = (-6 + 7 + 9 * 1), C = (4 - 9 + -3 - 9) and D = (-1 + 7 - -4 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + 2 + 1 + -9) = (((-9 + 2) + 1) + -9) = ((-7 + 1) + -9) = (-6 + -9) = -15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + 7 + 9 * 1) = ((-6 + 7) + (9 * 1)) = (1 + (9 * 1)) = (1 + 9) = 10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - 9 + -3 - 9) = (((4 - 9) + -3) - 9) = ((-5 + -3) - 9) = (-8 - 9) = -17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 + 7 - -4 - -7) = (((-1 + 7) - -4) - -7) = ((6 - -4) - -7) = (10 - -7) = 17.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-15 * 10) - (-17 + 17)) = (-150 - (-17 + 17)) = (-150 - 0) = -150.\n(Final response) So the answer is -150.", "correct_answer": "-150", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 562, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + 6 + 8 * -8) + (-6 + -3 + 5 + 0)) + ((-1 * -1 * -3 + -5) * (3 - 4 - -7 + 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (7 + 6 + 8 * -8), B = (-6 + -3 + 5 + 0), C = (-1 * -1 * -3 + -5) and D = (3 - 4 - -7 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 6 + 8 * -8) = ((7 + 6) + (8 * -8)) = (13 + (8 * -8)) = (13 + -64) = -51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -3 + 5 + 0) = (((-6 + -3) + 5) + 0) = ((-9 + 5) + 0) = (-4 + 0) = -4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * -1 * -3 + -5) = (((-1 * -1) * -3) + -5) = ((1 * -3) + -5) = (-3 + -5) = -8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 - 4 - -7 + 9) = (((3 - 4) - -7) + 9) = ((-1 - -7) + 9) = (6 + 9) = 15.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((-51 + -4) + (-8 * 15)) = (-55 + (-8 * 15)) = (-55 + -120) = -175.\n(Final response) So the answer is -175.", "correct_answer": "-175", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 486, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 - 0 * -1 * 8 + 6) + (0 + 4 + 9 * 5 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (4 - 0 * -1 * 8 + 6) and B = (0 + 4 + 9 * 5 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - 0 * -1 * 8 + 6) = ((4 - ((0 * -1) * 8)) + 6) = ((4 - (0 * 8)) + 6) = ((4 - 0) + 6) = (4 + 6) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + 4 + 9 * 5 * -2) = ((0 + 4) + ((9 * 5) * -2)) = (4 + ((9 * 5) * -2)) = (4 + (45 * -2)) = (4 + -90) = -86.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (10 + -86) = -76.\n(Final response) So the answer is -76.", "correct_answer": "-76", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 75, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 * -8 * -4) * (-5 - 8 - -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (1 * -8 * -4) and B = (-5 - 8 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * -8 * -4) = ((1 * -8) * -4) = (-8 * -4) = 32.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - 8 - -5) = ((-5 - 8) - -5) = (-13 - -5) = -8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (32 * -8) = -256.\n(Final response) So the answer is -256.", "correct_answer": "-256", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 131, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 + -7 - 7) + (0 * 8 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 + -7 - 7) and B = (0 * 8 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -7 - 7) = ((7 + -7) - 7) = (0 - 7) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 8 - 7) = ((0 * 8) - 7) = (0 - 7) = -7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-7 + -7) = -14.\n(Final response) So the answer is -14.", "correct_answer": "-14", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 128, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 * -4 + -6 + -1) + (0 * -2 * -6 - -5)) * ((-4 + 9 - 5 * 8) - (-7 * 0 + 7 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-3 * -4 + -6 + -1), B = (0 * -2 * -6 - -5), C = (-4 + 9 - 5 * 8) and D = (-7 * 0 + 7 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * -4 + -6 + -1) = (((-3 * -4) + -6) + -1) = ((12 + -6) + -1) = (6 + -1) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * -2 * -6 - -5) = (((0 * -2) * -6) - -5) = ((0 * -6) - -5) = (0 - -5) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + 9 - 5 * 8) = ((-4 + 9) - (5 * 8)) = (5 - (5 * 8)) = (5 - 40) = -35.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 * 0 + 7 + -8) = (((-7 * 0) + 7) + -8) = ((0 + 7) + -8) = (7 + -8) = -1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((5 + 5) * (-35 - -1)) = (10 * (-35 - -1)) = (10 * -34) = -340.\n(Final response) So the answer is -340.", "correct_answer": "-340", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 545, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + 5 - 1) * (6 + 7 - -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 + 5 - 1) and B = (6 + 7 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + 5 - 1) = ((5 + 5) - 1) = (10 - 1) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 7 - -6) = ((6 + 7) - -6) = (13 - -6) = 19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (9 * 19) = 171.\n(Final response) So the answer is 171.", "correct_answer": "171", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 70, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 - 2 * 0 + -5) * (-8 - 0 + 9 * -9)) + ((-6 + -4 * -8 - 9) * (-7 - 9 + 6 - 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (5 - 2 * 0 + -5), B = (-8 - 0 + 9 * -9), C = (-6 + -4 * -8 - 9) and D = (-7 - 9 + 6 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - 2 * 0 + -5) = ((5 - (2 * 0)) + -5) = ((5 - 0) + -5) = (5 + -5) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 0 + 9 * -9) = ((-8 - 0) + (9 * -9)) = (-8 + (9 * -9)) = (-8 + -81) = -89.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -4 * -8 - 9) = ((-6 + (-4 * -8)) - 9) = ((-6 + 32) - 9) = (26 - 9) = 17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - 9 + 6 - 2) = (((-7 - 9) + 6) - 2) = ((-16 + 6) - 2) = (-10 - 2) = -12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((0 * -89) + (17 * -12)) = (0 + (17 * -12)) = (0 + -204) = -204.\n(Final response) So the answer is -204.", "correct_answer": "-204", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 497, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 - -4 * -3) * (-2 - 5 * -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 - -4 * -3) and B = (-2 - 5 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - -4 * -3) = (9 - (-4 * -3)) = (9 - 12) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 5 * -9) = (-2 - (5 * -9)) = (-2 - -45) = 43.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-3 * 43) = -129.\n(Final response) So the answer is -129.", "correct_answer": "-129", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 87, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((5 * 2 + 5 * 6) + (9 * 7 - 5 + 7)) + ((-8 * 4 + -6 + 0) + (2 * 8 * 8 - 2))) + (((6 - -9 * 9 + -5) + (0 - -4 + 2 - 2)) - ((-9 - 2 - -4 + 0) * (1 + -5 - 3 - 4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C + D)) + ((E + F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (5 * 2 + 5 * 6), B = (9 * 7 - 5 + 7), C = (-8 * 4 + -6 + 0), D = (2 * 8 * 8 - 2), E = (6 - -9 * 9 + -5), F = (0 - -4 + 2 - 2), G = (-9 - 2 - -4 + 0) and H = (1 + -5 - 3 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 2 + 5 * 6) = ((5 * 2) + (5 * 6)) = (10 + (5 * 6)) = (10 + 30) = 40.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 7 - 5 + 7) = (((9 * 7) - 5) + 7) = ((63 - 5) + 7) = (58 + 7) = 65.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * 4 + -6 + 0) = (((-8 * 4) + -6) + 0) = ((-32 + -6) + 0) = (-38 + 0) = -38.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * 8 * 8 - 2) = (((2 * 8) * 8) - 2) = ((16 * 8) - 2) = (128 - 2) = 126.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (6 - -9 * 9 + -5) = ((6 - (-9 * 9)) + -5) = ((6 - -81) + -5) = (87 + -5) = 82.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (0 - -4 + 2 - 2) = (((0 - -4) + 2) - 2) = ((4 + 2) - 2) = (6 - 2) = 4.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-9 - 2 - -4 + 0) = (((-9 - 2) - -4) + 0) = ((-11 - -4) + 0) = (-7 + 0) = -7.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (1 + -5 - 3 - 4) = (((1 + -5) - 3) - 4) = ((-4 - 3) - 4) = (-7 - 4) = -11.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C + D)) + ((E + F) - (G * H))) = (((40 + 65) + (-38 + 126)) + ((82 + 4) - (-7 * -11))) = ((105 + (-38 + 126)) + ((82 + 4) - (-7 * -11))) = ((105 + 88) + ((82 + 4) - (-7 * -11))) = ((105 + 88) + (86 - (-7 * -11))) = ((105 + 88) + (86 - 77)) = (193 + (86 - 77)) = (193 + 9) = 202.\n(Final response) So the answer is 202.", "correct_answer": "202", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 293, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * 4 * -2 * 2 * 0 - -8) + (0 * 7 + 0 - -4 * -9 + -9)) + ((5 * -9 + 4 + 1 - 1 - 8) + (5 + -2 - 6 - 0 - 2 - 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (3 * 4 * -2 * 2 * 0 - -8), B = (0 * 7 + 0 - -4 * -9 + -9), C = (5 * -9 + 4 + 1 - 1 - 8) and D = (5 + -2 - 6 - 0 - 2 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 4 * -2 * 2 * 0 - -8) = (((((3 * 4) * -2) * 2) * 0) - -8) = ((((12 * -2) * 2) * 0) - -8) = (((-24 * 2) * 0) - -8) = ((-48 * 0) - -8) = (0 - -8) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 7 + 0 - -4 * -9 + -9) = ((((0 * 7) + 0) - (-4 * -9)) + -9) = (((0 + 0) - (-4 * -9)) + -9) = (((0 + 0) - 36) + -9) = ((0 - 36) + -9) = (-36 + -9) = -45.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 * -9 + 4 + 1 - 1 - 8) = (((((5 * -9) + 4) + 1) - 1) - 8) = ((((-45 + 4) + 1) - 1) - 8) = (((-41 + 1) - 1) - 8) = ((-40 - 1) - 8) = (-41 - 8) = -49.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 + -2 - 6 - 0 - 2 - 0) = (((((5 + -2) - 6) - 0) - 2) - 0) = ((((3 - 6) - 0) - 2) - 0) = (((-3 - 0) - 2) - 0) = ((-3 - 2) - 0) = (-5 - 0) = -5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((8 + -45) + (-49 + -5)) = (-37 + (-49 + -5)) = (-37 + -54) = -91.\n(Final response) So the answer is -91.", "correct_answer": "-91", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 229, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 + 3 * -2 + 7) * (9 * 7 + 9 - -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-4 + 3 * -2 + 7) and B = (9 * 7 + 9 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + 3 * -2 + 7) = ((-4 + (3 * -2)) + 7) = ((-4 + -6) + 7) = (-10 + 7) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 7 + 9 - -2) = (((9 * 7) + 9) - -2) = ((63 + 9) - -2) = (72 - -2) = 74.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-3 * 74) = -222.\n(Final response) So the answer is -222.", "correct_answer": "-222", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 246, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 + -8 + -7) * (-9 + 6 * -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (3 + -8 + -7) and B = (-9 + 6 * -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + -8 + -7) = ((3 + -8) + -7) = (-5 + -7) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 6 * -4) = (-9 + (6 * -4)) = (-9 + -24) = -33.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-12 * -33) = 396.\n(Final response) So the answer is 396.", "correct_answer": "396", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 59, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * -2 - 9 * -3) * (7 + -2 * -4 - 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-9 * -2 - 9 * -3) and B = (7 + -2 * -4 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * -2 - 9 * -3) = ((-9 * -2) - (9 * -3)) = (18 - (9 * -3)) = (18 - -27) = 45.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + -2 * -4 - 8) = ((7 + (-2 * -4)) - 8) = ((7 + 8) - 8) = (15 - 8) = 7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (45 * 7) = 315.\n(Final response) So the answer is 315.", "correct_answer": "315", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 245, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 * 5 + 6) * (-2 * 9 - -1)) * ((-6 + -6 * 9) - (6 * 7 - 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-1 * 5 + 6), B = (-2 * 9 - -1), C = (-6 + -6 * 9) and D = (6 * 7 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 5 + 6) = ((-1 * 5) + 6) = (-5 + 6) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * 9 - -1) = ((-2 * 9) - -1) = (-18 - -1) = -17.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -6 * 9) = (-6 + (-6 * 9)) = (-6 + -54) = -60.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 * 7 - 0) = ((6 * 7) - 0) = (42 - 0) = 42.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((1 * -17) * (-60 - 42)) = (-17 * (-60 - 42)) = (-17 * -102) = 1734.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1734.", "correct_answer": "1734", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 314, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + 3 + 3) - (5 * 8 - -8)) * ((1 + 1 * 1) - (6 - 2 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (7 + 3 + 3), B = (5 * 8 - -8), C = (1 + 1 * 1) and D = (6 - 2 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 3 + 3) = ((7 + 3) + 3) = (10 + 3) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * 8 - -8) = ((5 * 8) - -8) = (40 - -8) = 48.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 + 1 * 1) = (1 + (1 * 1)) = (1 + 1) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 - 2 + -1) = ((6 - 2) + -1) = (4 + -1) = 3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((13 - 48) * (2 - 3)) = (-35 * (2 - 3)) = (-35 * -1) = 35.\n(Final response) So the answer is 35.", "correct_answer": "35", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 371, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 * 0 - -5 - 3) + (9 * 6 + -4 - 0)) - ((1 - 0 + 4 * -3) + (1 * 1 - 7 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C + D))\", where A = (1 * 0 - -5 - 3), B = (9 * 6 + -4 - 0), C = (1 - 0 + 4 * -3) and D = (1 * 1 - 7 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * 0 - -5 - 3) = (((1 * 0) - -5) - 3) = ((0 - -5) - 3) = (5 - 3) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 6 + -4 - 0) = (((9 * 6) + -4) - 0) = ((54 + -4) - 0) = (50 - 0) = 50.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - 0 + 4 * -3) = ((1 - 0) + (4 * -3)) = (1 + (4 * -3)) = (1 + -12) = -11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 * 1 - 7 + -1) = (((1 * 1) - 7) + -1) = ((1 - 7) + -1) = (-6 + -1) = -7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C + D)) = ((2 + 50) - (-11 + -7)) = (52 - (-11 + -7)) = (52 - -18) = 70.\n(Final response) So the answer is 70.", "correct_answer": "70", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 174, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 + -7 * -6) * (-7 * 9 * -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-4 + -7 * -6) and B = (-7 * 9 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -7 * -6) = (-4 + (-7 * -6)) = (-4 + 42) = 38.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 9 * -1) = ((-7 * 9) * -1) = (-63 * -1) = 63.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (38 * 63) = 2394.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2394.", "correct_answer": "2394", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 19, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - -3 + 5 + 0) - (-1 + -1 + -3 - -3)) * ((0 * 8 + 6 * -6) + (7 + -5 * 3 * 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (6 - -3 + 5 + 0), B = (-1 + -1 + -3 - -3), C = (0 * 8 + 6 * -6) and D = (7 + -5 * 3 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -3 + 5 + 0) = (((6 - -3) + 5) + 0) = ((9 + 5) + 0) = (14 + 0) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -1 + -3 - -3) = (((-1 + -1) + -3) - -3) = ((-2 + -3) - -3) = (-5 - -3) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * 8 + 6 * -6) = ((0 * 8) + (6 * -6)) = (0 + (6 * -6)) = (0 + -36) = -36.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + -5 * 3 * 7) = (7 + ((-5 * 3) * 7)) = (7 + (-15 * 7)) = (7 + -105) = -98.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((14 - -2) * (-36 + -98)) = (16 * (-36 + -98)) = (16 * -134) = -2144.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2144.", "correct_answer": "-2144", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 500, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 + -3 * 9) * (1 * -6 - 4)) - ((-4 + 6 - -9) + (-9 * 0 - 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C + D))\", where A = (4 + -3 * 9), B = (1 * -6 - 4), C = (-4 + 6 - -9) and D = (-9 * 0 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -3 * 9) = (4 + (-3 * 9)) = (4 + -27) = -23.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -6 - 4) = ((1 * -6) - 4) = (-6 - 4) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + 6 - -9) = ((-4 + 6) - -9) = (2 - -9) = 11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 * 0 - 2) = ((-9 * 0) - 2) = (0 - 2) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C + D)) = ((-23 * -10) - (11 + -2)) = (230 - (11 + -2)) = (230 - 9) = 221.\n(Final response) So the answer is 221.", "correct_answer": "221", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 331, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 * -5 + 7) + (2 * 5 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-5 * -5 + 7) and B = (2 * 5 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * -5 + 7) = ((-5 * -5) + 7) = (25 + 7) = 32.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 5 - 2) = ((2 * 5) - 2) = (10 - 2) = 8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (32 + 8) = 40.\n(Final response) So the answer is 40.", "correct_answer": "40", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 13, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 + 5 * -2) + (-3 - 9 * 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-3 + 5 * -2) and B = (-3 - 9 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 5 * -2) = (-3 + (5 * -2)) = (-3 + -10) = -13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - 9 * 1) = (-3 - (9 * 1)) = (-3 - 9) = -12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-13 + -12) = -25.\n(Final response) So the answer is -25.", "correct_answer": "-25", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 0, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 - 3 * -7 - 0) + (5 * 0 - -2 + -7)) * ((8 * -7 * -8 * 3) - (-2 + 6 - -1 * -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-4 - 3 * -7 - 0), B = (5 * 0 - -2 + -7), C = (8 * -7 * -8 * 3) and D = (-2 + 6 - -1 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 3 * -7 - 0) = ((-4 - (3 * -7)) - 0) = ((-4 - -21) - 0) = (17 - 0) = 17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * 0 - -2 + -7) = (((5 * 0) - -2) + -7) = ((0 - -2) + -7) = (2 + -7) = -5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -7 * -8 * 3) = (((8 * -7) * -8) * 3) = ((-56 * -8) * 3) = (448 * 3) = 1344.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 + 6 - -1 * -9) = ((-2 + 6) - (-1 * -9)) = (4 - (-1 * -9)) = (4 - 9) = -5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((17 + -5) * (1344 - -5)) = (12 * (1344 - -5)) = (12 * 1349) = 16188.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16188.", "correct_answer": "16188", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 543, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 * 3 + 2 * -8) * (-5 + 1 - 8 * 0)) * ((4 * -8 + 3 + 7) * (6 + 0 + 2 + -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (9 * 3 + 2 * -8), B = (-5 + 1 - 8 * 0), C = (4 * -8 + 3 + 7) and D = (6 + 0 + 2 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 3 + 2 * -8) = ((9 * 3) + (2 * -8)) = (27 + (2 * -8)) = (27 + -16) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + 1 - 8 * 0) = ((-5 + 1) - (8 * 0)) = (-4 - (8 * 0)) = (-4 - 0) = -4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 * -8 + 3 + 7) = (((4 * -8) + 3) + 7) = ((-32 + 3) + 7) = (-29 + 7) = -22.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 + 0 + 2 + -5) = (((6 + 0) + 2) + -5) = ((6 + 2) + -5) = (8 + -5) = 3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((11 * -4) * (-22 * 3)) = (-44 * (-22 * 3)) = (-44 * -66) = 2904.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2904.", "correct_answer": "2904", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 552, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 + -5 - 1 * -1) + (2 * 0 + 0 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-2 + -5 - 1 * -1) and B = (2 * 0 + 0 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -5 - 1 * -1) = ((-2 + -5) - (1 * -1)) = (-7 - (1 * -1)) = (-7 - -1) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 0 + 0 * 3) = ((2 * 0) + (0 * 3)) = (0 + (0 * 3)) = (0 + 0) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-6 + 0) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 165, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 + 0 - 2) * (-7 * -7 - -8)) * ((7 + -6 - -8) + (4 - 1 - -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-8 + 0 - 2), B = (-7 * -7 - -8), C = (7 + -6 - -8) and D = (4 - 1 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + 0 - 2) = ((-8 + 0) - 2) = (-8 - 2) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * -7 - -8) = ((-7 * -7) - -8) = (49 - -8) = 57.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + -6 - -8) = ((7 + -6) - -8) = (1 - -8) = 9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 - 1 - -8) = ((4 - 1) - -8) = (3 - -8) = 11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((-10 * 57) * (9 + 11)) = (-570 * (9 + 11)) = (-570 * 20) = -11400.\n(Final response) So the answer is -11400.", "correct_answer": "-11400", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 382, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 + -2 + -5 - 3 + 1) * (3 * 5 - 6 + -2 - 9)) + ((5 - -6 - -2 * 2 - 8) * (-6 + -5 - -3 - 1 + 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (8 + -2 + -5 - 3 + 1), B = (3 * 5 - 6 + -2 - 9), C = (5 - -6 - -2 * 2 - 8) and D = (-6 + -5 - -3 - 1 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + -2 + -5 - 3 + 1) = ((((8 + -2) + -5) - 3) + 1) = (((6 + -5) - 3) + 1) = ((1 - 3) + 1) = (-2 + 1) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 5 - 6 + -2 - 9) = ((((3 * 5) - 6) + -2) - 9) = (((15 - 6) + -2) - 9) = ((9 + -2) - 9) = (7 - 9) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 - -6 - -2 * 2 - 8) = (((5 - -6) - (-2 * 2)) - 8) = ((11 - (-2 * 2)) - 8) = ((11 - -4) - 8) = (15 - 8) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + -5 - -3 - 1 + 1) = ((((-6 + -5) - -3) - 1) + 1) = (((-11 - -3) - 1) + 1) = ((-8 - 1) + 1) = (-9 + 1) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((-1 * -2) + (7 * -8)) = (2 + (7 * -8)) = (2 + -56) = -54.\n(Final response) So the answer is -54.", "correct_answer": "-54", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 198, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((((8 + 2 + -6 - 4 - 7 + 5) * (5 + -8 + -2 * 0 - -6 - -2)) * ((6 + 8 + -6 * -4 + 1 * -6) * (2 * -6 * -5 - -1 - -6 - 5))) * (((-2 * -3 - 2 - 2 - 5 - 6) + (-4 * 8 + 0 * 6 * -1 - 3)) + ((-5 + -9 * -4 * -2 - -4 * -1) * (-2 + -2 - -8 + -1 - 3 - 9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G * H)))\", where A = (8 + 2 + -6 - 4 - 7 + 5), B = (5 + -8 + -2 * 0 - -6 - -2), C = (6 + 8 + -6 * -4 + 1 * -6), D = (2 * -6 * -5 - -1 - -6 - 5), E = (-2 * -3 - 2 - 2 - 5 - 6), F = (-4 * 8 + 0 * 6 * -1 - 3), G = (-5 + -9 * -4 * -2 - -4 * -1) and H = (-2 + -2 - -8 + -1 - 3 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 2 + -6 - 4 - 7 + 5) = (((((8 + 2) + -6) - 4) - 7) + 5) = ((((10 + -6) - 4) - 7) + 5) = (((4 - 4) - 7) + 5) = ((0 - 7) + 5) = (-7 + 5) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + -8 + -2 * 0 - -6 - -2) = ((((5 + -8) + (-2 * 0)) - -6) - -2) = (((-3 + (-2 * 0)) - -6) - -2) = (((-3 + 0) - -6) - -2) = ((-3 - -6) - -2) = (3 - -2) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + 8 + -6 * -4 + 1 * -6) = (((6 + 8) + (-6 * -4)) + (1 * -6)) = ((14 + (-6 * -4)) + (1 * -6)) = ((14 + 24) + (1 * -6)) = ((14 + 24) + -6) = (38 + -6) = 32.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * -6 * -5 - -1 - -6 - 5) = (((((2 * -6) * -5) - -1) - -6) - 5) = ((((-12 * -5) - -1) - -6) - 5) = (((60 - -1) - -6) - 5) = ((61 - -6) - 5) = (67 - 5) = 62.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-2 * -3 - 2 - 2 - 5 - 6) = (((((-2 * -3) - 2) - 2) - 5) - 6) = ((((6 - 2) - 2) - 5) - 6) = (((4 - 2) - 5) - 6) = ((2 - 5) - 6) = (-3 - 6) = -9.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-4 * 8 + 0 * 6 * -1 - 3) = (((-4 * 8) + ((0 * 6) * -1)) - 3) = ((-32 + ((0 * 6) * -1)) - 3) = ((-32 + (0 * -1)) - 3) = ((-32 + 0) - 3) = (-32 - 3) = -35.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-5 + -9 * -4 * -2 - -4 * -1) = ((-5 + ((-9 * -4) * -2)) - (-4 * -1)) = ((-5 + (36 * -2)) - (-4 * -1)) = ((-5 + (36 * -2)) - 4) = ((-5 + -72) - 4) = (-77 - 4) = -81.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-2 + -2 - -8 + -1 - 3 - 9) = (((((-2 + -2) - -8) + -1) - 3) - 9) = ((((-4 - -8) + -1) - 3) - 9) = (((4 + -1) - 3) - 9) = ((3 - 3) - 9) = (0 - 9) = -9.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G * H))) = (((-2 * 5) * (32 * 62)) * ((-9 + -35) + (-81 * -9))) = ((-10 * (32 * 62)) * ((-9 + -35) + (-81 * -9))) = ((-10 * 1984) * ((-9 + -35) + (-81 * -9))) = ((-10 * 1984) * (-44 + (-81 * -9))) = ((-10 * 1984) * (-44 + 729)) = (-19840 * (-44 + 729)) = (-19840 * 685) = -13590400.\n(Final response) So the answer is -13590400.", "correct_answer": "-13590400", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 333, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 + -1 - 5) - (0 - 8 * -1)) + ((8 + -7 + 0) + (-7 + -1 + 6))) - (((8 - -4 + 0) - (-9 * -4 + 6)) - ((-1 + 3 * -9) * (-7 * 9 + 2)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C + D)) - ((E - F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (2 + -1 - 5), B = (0 - 8 * -1), C = (8 + -7 + 0), D = (-7 + -1 + 6), E = (8 - -4 + 0), F = (-9 * -4 + 6), G = (-1 + 3 * -9) and H = (-7 * 9 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + -1 - 5) = ((2 + -1) - 5) = (1 - 5) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - 8 * -1) = (0 - (8 * -1)) = (0 - -8) = 8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 + -7 + 0) = ((8 + -7) + 0) = (1 + 0) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + -1 + 6) = ((-7 + -1) + 6) = (-8 + 6) = -2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (8 - -4 + 0) = ((8 - -4) + 0) = (12 + 0) = 12.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-9 * -4 + 6) = ((-9 * -4) + 6) = (36 + 6) = 42.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-1 + 3 * -9) = (-1 + (3 * -9)) = (-1 + -27) = -28.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-7 * 9 + 2) = ((-7 * 9) + 2) = (-63 + 2) = -61.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C + D)) - ((E - F) - (G * H))) = (((-4 - 8) + (1 + -2)) - ((12 - 42) - (-28 * -61))) = ((-12 + (1 + -2)) - ((12 - 42) - (-28 * -61))) = ((-12 + -1) - ((12 - 42) - (-28 * -61))) = ((-12 + -1) - (-30 - (-28 * -61))) = ((-12 + -1) - (-30 - 1708)) = (-13 - (-30 - 1708)) = (-13 - -1738) = 1725.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1725.", "correct_answer": "1725", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 256, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 - -3 * 5 + -7) - (-3 + 6 + -1 + -9)) - ((1 - -5 * -3 + 4) * (2 - 5 * 1 * 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (4 - -3 * 5 + -7), B = (-3 + 6 + -1 + -9), C = (1 - -5 * -3 + 4) and D = (2 - 5 * 1 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - -3 * 5 + -7) = ((4 - (-3 * 5)) + -7) = ((4 - -15) + -7) = (19 + -7) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 6 + -1 + -9) = (((-3 + 6) + -1) + -9) = ((3 + -1) + -9) = (2 + -9) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - -5 * -3 + 4) = ((1 - (-5 * -3)) + 4) = ((1 - 15) + 4) = (-14 + 4) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 - 5 * 1 * 7) = (2 - ((5 * 1) * 7)) = (2 - (5 * 7)) = (2 - 35) = -33.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((12 - -7) - (-10 * -33)) = (19 - (-10 * -33)) = (19 - 330) = -311.\n(Final response) So the answer is -311.", "correct_answer": "-311", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 163, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 * 5 - 2 * 9 + -6 + -5) - (5 * 6 + 0 * 4 * 3 - 7)) + ((6 + 1 * 4 - 1 * 2 - -7) - (4 + 7 + 6 - -6 + -2 * -1))) * (((0 + -8 * -9 + 9 * -2 - -7) * (3 * -3 - 2 * -5 - 6 - 0)) - ((9 * 4 - 5 * -4 - 2 - -4) * (4 + 7 - -9 - 7 + 0 - 1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E * F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (2 * 5 - 2 * 9 + -6 + -5), B = (5 * 6 + 0 * 4 * 3 - 7), C = (6 + 1 * 4 - 1 * 2 - -7), D = (4 + 7 + 6 - -6 + -2 * -1), E = (0 + -8 * -9 + 9 * -2 - -7), F = (3 * -3 - 2 * -5 - 6 - 0), G = (9 * 4 - 5 * -4 - 2 - -4) and H = (4 + 7 - -9 - 7 + 0 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 * 5 - 2 * 9 + -6 + -5) = ((((2 * 5) - (2 * 9)) + -6) + -5) = (((10 - (2 * 9)) + -6) + -5) = (((10 - 18) + -6) + -5) = ((-8 + -6) + -5) = (-14 + -5) = -19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * 6 + 0 * 4 * 3 - 7) = (((5 * 6) + ((0 * 4) * 3)) - 7) = ((30 + ((0 * 4) * 3)) - 7) = ((30 + (0 * 3)) - 7) = ((30 + 0) - 7) = (30 - 7) = 23.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + 1 * 4 - 1 * 2 - -7) = (((6 + (1 * 4)) - (1 * 2)) - -7) = (((6 + 4) - (1 * 2)) - -7) = (((6 + 4) - 2) - -7) = ((10 - 2) - -7) = (8 - -7) = 15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + 7 + 6 - -6 + -2 * -1) = ((((4 + 7) + 6) - -6) + (-2 * -1)) = (((11 + 6) - -6) + (-2 * -1)) = (((11 + 6) - -6) + 2) = ((17 - -6) + 2) = (23 + 2) = 25.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 + -8 * -9 + 9 * -2 - -7) = (((0 + (-8 * -9)) + (9 * -2)) - -7) = (((0 + 72) + (9 * -2)) - -7) = (((0 + 72) + -18) - -7) = ((72 + -18) - -7) = (54 - -7) = 61.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (3 * -3 - 2 * -5 - 6 - 0) = ((((3 * -3) - (2 * -5)) - 6) - 0) = (((-9 - (2 * -5)) - 6) - 0) = (((-9 - -10) - 6) - 0) = ((1 - 6) - 0) = (-5 - 0) = -5.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (9 * 4 - 5 * -4 - 2 - -4) = ((((9 * 4) - (5 * -4)) - 2) - -4) = (((36 - (5 * -4)) - 2) - -4) = (((36 - -20) - 2) - -4) = ((56 - 2) - -4) = (54 - -4) = 58.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (4 + 7 - -9 - 7 + 0 - 1) = (((((4 + 7) - -9) - 7) + 0) - 1) = ((((11 - -9) - 7) + 0) - 1) = (((20 - 7) + 0) - 1) = ((13 + 0) - 1) = (13 - 1) = 12.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E * F) - (G * H))) = (((-19 - 23) + (15 - 25)) * ((61 * -5) - (58 * 12))) = ((-42 + (15 - 25)) * ((61 * -5) - (58 * 12))) = ((-42 + -10) * ((61 * -5) - (58 * 12))) = ((-42 + -10) * (-305 - (58 * 12))) = ((-42 + -10) * (-305 - 696)) = (-52 * (-305 - 696)) = (-52 * -1001) = 52052.\n(Final response) So the answer is 52052.", "correct_answer": "52052", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 359, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 * -8 - 9) - (9 - 6 + 6)) - ((-2 - 3 + -3) + (8 - -1 + -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-8 * -8 - 9), B = (9 - 6 + 6), C = (-2 - 3 + -3) and D = (8 - -1 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * -8 - 9) = ((-8 * -8) - 9) = (64 - 9) = 55.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - 6 + 6) = ((9 - 6) + 6) = (3 + 6) = 9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 - 3 + -3) = ((-2 - 3) + -3) = (-5 + -3) = -8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - -1 + -4) = ((8 - -1) + -4) = (9 + -4) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((55 - 9) - (-8 + 5)) = (46 - (-8 + 5)) = (46 - -3) = 49.\n(Final response) So the answer is 49.", "correct_answer": "49", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 305, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 * 3 + -5 + 8) * (8 - 0 * 3 - 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-4 * 3 + -5 + 8) and B = (8 - 0 * 3 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * 3 + -5 + 8) = (((-4 * 3) + -5) + 8) = ((-12 + -5) + 8) = (-17 + 8) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 0 * 3 - 5) = ((8 - (0 * 3)) - 5) = ((8 - 0) - 5) = (8 - 5) = 3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-9 * 3) = -27.\n(Final response) So the answer is -27.", "correct_answer": "-27", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 40, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 - -5 * -4) - (0 + -4 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (3 - -5 * -4) and B = (0 + -4 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - -5 * -4) = (3 - (-5 * -4)) = (3 - 20) = -17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -4 - 7) = ((0 + -4) - 7) = (-4 - 7) = -11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-17 - -11) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 108, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - -7 - 6 + 6) + (3 - 7 + 7 - -2)) * ((4 - 8 + 9 - 4) - (-9 + 8 + 7 - 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (1 - -7 - 6 + 6), B = (3 - 7 + 7 - -2), C = (4 - 8 + 9 - 4) and D = (-9 + 8 + 7 - 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -7 - 6 + 6) = (((1 - -7) - 6) + 6) = ((8 - 6) + 6) = (2 + 6) = 8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - 7 + 7 - -2) = (((3 - 7) + 7) - -2) = ((-4 + 7) - -2) = (3 - -2) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - 8 + 9 - 4) = (((4 - 8) + 9) - 4) = ((-4 + 9) - 4) = (5 - 4) = 1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 + 8 + 7 - 6) = (((-9 + 8) + 7) - 6) = ((-1 + 7) - 6) = (6 - 6) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((8 + 5) * (1 - 0)) = (13 * (1 - 0)) = (13 * 1) = 13.\n(Final response) So the answer is 13.", "correct_answer": "13", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 519, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * 0 - -8 * -1) + (1 - 7 * -5 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 * 0 - -8 * -1) and B = (1 - 7 * -5 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 0 - -8 * -1) = ((7 * 0) - (-8 * -1)) = (0 - (-8 * -1)) = (0 - 8) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - 7 * -5 - 7) = ((1 - (7 * -5)) - 7) = ((1 - -35) - 7) = (36 - 7) = 29.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-8 + 29) = 21.\n(Final response) So the answer is 21.", "correct_answer": "21", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 182, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 - 0 + -9 + 5) - (-9 * -1 * 6 + 0)) - ((-1 + 3 * 5 - 0) + (-7 * 6 + 5 + -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (2 - 0 + -9 + 5), B = (-9 * -1 * 6 + 0), C = (-1 + 3 * 5 - 0) and D = (-7 * 6 + 5 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - 0 + -9 + 5) = (((2 - 0) + -9) + 5) = ((2 + -9) + 5) = (-7 + 5) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -1 * 6 + 0) = (((-9 * -1) * 6) + 0) = ((9 * 6) + 0) = (54 + 0) = 54.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + 3 * 5 - 0) = ((-1 + (3 * 5)) - 0) = ((-1 + 15) - 0) = (14 - 0) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 * 6 + 5 + -7) = (((-7 * 6) + 5) + -7) = ((-42 + 5) + -7) = (-37 + -7) = -44.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-2 - 54) - (14 + -44)) = (-56 - (14 + -44)) = (-56 - -30) = -26.\n(Final response) So the answer is -26.", "correct_answer": "-26", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 512, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 - -1 * 4 * -2 + -4 - -7) - (7 * -6 * -3 * 4 * 3 * 7)) + ((0 * 7 - 2 * 0 * -2 - 5) - (8 * 3 - 6 - 3 * 9 - 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-1 - -1 * 4 * -2 + -4 - -7), B = (7 * -6 * -3 * 4 * 3 * 7), C = (0 * 7 - 2 * 0 * -2 - 5) and D = (8 * 3 - 6 - 3 * 9 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - -1 * 4 * -2 + -4 - -7) = (((-1 - ((-1 * 4) * -2)) + -4) - -7) = (((-1 - (-4 * -2)) + -4) - -7) = (((-1 - 8) + -4) - -7) = ((-9 + -4) - -7) = (-13 - -7) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * -6 * -3 * 4 * 3 * 7) = (((((7 * -6) * -3) * 4) * 3) * 7) = ((((-42 * -3) * 4) * 3) * 7) = (((126 * 4) * 3) * 7) = ((504 * 3) * 7) = (1512 * 7) = 10584.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * 7 - 2 * 0 * -2 - 5) = (((0 * 7) - ((2 * 0) * -2)) - 5) = ((0 - ((2 * 0) * -2)) - 5) = ((0 - (0 * -2)) - 5) = ((0 - 0) - 5) = (0 - 5) = -5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * 3 - 6 - 3 * 9 - 2) = ((((8 * 3) - 6) - (3 * 9)) - 2) = (((24 - 6) - (3 * 9)) - 2) = (((24 - 6) - 27) - 2) = ((18 - 27) - 2) = (-9 - 2) = -11.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-6 - 10584) + (-5 - -11)) = (-10590 + (-5 - -11)) = (-10590 + 6) = -10584.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10584.", "correct_answer": "-10584", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 213, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 + -4 - -7) - (-6 + 9 + 8)) + ((6 - 9 + 0) - (4 - -7 * 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (2 + -4 - -7), B = (-6 + 9 + 8), C = (6 - 9 + 0) and D = (4 - -7 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + -4 - -7) = ((2 + -4) - -7) = (-2 - -7) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + 9 + 8) = ((-6 + 9) + 8) = (3 + 8) = 11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 9 + 0) = ((6 - 9) + 0) = (-3 + 0) = -3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 - -7 * 6) = (4 - (-7 * 6)) = (4 - -42) = 46.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((5 - 11) + (-3 - 46)) = (-6 + (-3 - 46)) = (-6 + -49) = -55.\n(Final response) So the answer is -55.", "correct_answer": "-55", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 136, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 * 3 + 3) - (-4 - 2 + -2)) - ((-7 * -2 * 1) - (0 - 2 + -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (5 * 3 + 3), B = (-4 - 2 + -2), C = (-7 * -2 * 1) and D = (0 - 2 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 3 + 3) = ((5 * 3) + 3) = (15 + 3) = 18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - 2 + -2) = ((-4 - 2) + -2) = (-6 + -2) = -8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * -2 * 1) = ((-7 * -2) * 1) = (14 * 1) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 - 2 + -2) = ((0 - 2) + -2) = (-2 + -2) = -4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((18 - -8) - (14 - -4)) = (26 - (14 - -4)) = (26 - 18) = 8.\n(Final response) So the answer is 8.", "correct_answer": "8", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 139, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 + -1 * 8) + (4 - -1 - -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-3 + -1 * 8) and B = (4 - -1 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + -1 * 8) = (-3 + (-1 * 8)) = (-3 + -8) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - -1 - -8) = ((4 - -1) - -8) = (5 - -8) = 13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-11 + 13) = 2.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2.", "correct_answer": "2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 3, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((7 - -6 + 3 + 0) * (-5 - 8 + 0 + -7)) * ((1 * 1 * -6 * 2) + (-2 - 6 * 5 - 1))) - (((-3 * 8 * 6 - -7) + (-4 + -9 * 1 - -7)) * ((-4 * 9 - 6 + 0) - (-5 - 2 - -7 + -7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) * (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (7 - -6 + 3 + 0), B = (-5 - 8 + 0 + -7), C = (1 * 1 * -6 * 2), D = (-2 - 6 * 5 - 1), E = (-3 * 8 * 6 - -7), F = (-4 + -9 * 1 - -7), G = (-4 * 9 - 6 + 0) and H = (-5 - 2 - -7 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -6 + 3 + 0) = (((7 - -6) + 3) + 0) = ((13 + 3) + 0) = (16 + 0) = 16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - 8 + 0 + -7) = (((-5 - 8) + 0) + -7) = ((-13 + 0) + -7) = (-13 + -7) = -20.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 * 1 * -6 * 2) = (((1 * 1) * -6) * 2) = ((1 * -6) * 2) = (-6 * 2) = -12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - 6 * 5 - 1) = ((-2 - (6 * 5)) - 1) = ((-2 - 30) - 1) = (-32 - 1) = -33.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-3 * 8 * 6 - -7) = (((-3 * 8) * 6) - -7) = ((-24 * 6) - -7) = (-144 - -7) = -137.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-4 + -9 * 1 - -7) = ((-4 + (-9 * 1)) - -7) = ((-4 + -9) - -7) = (-13 - -7) = -6.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-4 * 9 - 6 + 0) = (((-4 * 9) - 6) + 0) = ((-36 - 6) + 0) = (-42 + 0) = -42.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-5 - 2 - -7 + -7) = (((-5 - 2) - -7) + -7) = ((-7 - -7) + -7) = (0 + -7) = -7.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) * (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G - H))) = (((16 * -20) * (-12 + -33)) - ((-137 + -6) * (-42 - -7))) = ((-320 * (-12 + -33)) - ((-137 + -6) * (-42 - -7))) = ((-320 * -45) - ((-137 + -6) * (-42 - -7))) = ((-320 * -45) - (-143 * (-42 - -7))) = ((-320 * -45) - (-143 * -35)) = (14400 - (-143 * -35)) = (14400 - 5005) = 9395.\n(Final response) So the answer is 9395.", "correct_answer": "9395", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 270, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 - 0 * -7 * -4) + (2 - 1 + -6 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 - 0 * -7 * -4) and B = (2 - 1 + -6 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 0 * -7 * -4) = (-6 - ((0 * -7) * -4)) = (-6 - (0 * -4)) = (-6 - 0) = -6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - 1 + -6 - -4) = (((2 - 1) + -6) - -4) = ((1 + -6) - -4) = (-5 - -4) = -1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-6 + -1) = -7.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7.", "correct_answer": "-7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 161, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * 9 * -4) * (4 + -8 + 1)) - ((-3 + 4 - -9) - (2 * -5 - -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-5 * 9 * -4), B = (4 + -8 + 1), C = (-3 + 4 - -9) and D = (2 * -5 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 9 * -4) = ((-5 * 9) * -4) = (-45 * -4) = 180.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + -8 + 1) = ((4 + -8) + 1) = (-4 + 1) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + 4 - -9) = ((-3 + 4) - -9) = (1 - -9) = 10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * -5 - -2) = ((2 * -5) - -2) = (-10 - -2) = -8.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((180 * -3) - (10 - -8)) = (-540 - (10 - -8)) = (-540 - 18) = -558.\n(Final response) So the answer is -558.", "correct_answer": "-558", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 445, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((0 - 1 - -1 - -1) * (4 - 2 * 1 - -6)) - ((8 + -4 + 0 * 1) + (6 - 0 * 2 * 0))) - (((-8 + -9 - -9 - -8) + (7 + -4 - 0 - -5)) * ((-8 - -9 * -4 + -8) - (-4 * -9 * 7 + 8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (0 - 1 - -1 - -1), B = (4 - 2 * 1 - -6), C = (8 + -4 + 0 * 1), D = (6 - 0 * 2 * 0), E = (-8 + -9 - -9 - -8), F = (7 + -4 - 0 - -5), G = (-8 - -9 * -4 + -8) and H = (-4 * -9 * 7 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - 1 - -1 - -1) = (((0 - 1) - -1) - -1) = ((-1 - -1) - -1) = (0 - -1) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 2 * 1 - -6) = ((4 - (2 * 1)) - -6) = ((4 - 2) - -6) = (2 - -6) = 8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 + -4 + 0 * 1) = ((8 + -4) + (0 * 1)) = (4 + (0 * 1)) = (4 + 0) = 4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 - 0 * 2 * 0) = (6 - ((0 * 2) * 0)) = (6 - (0 * 0)) = (6 - 0) = 6.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-8 + -9 - -9 - -8) = (((-8 + -9) - -9) - -8) = ((-17 - -9) - -8) = (-8 - -8) = 0.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (7 + -4 - 0 - -5) = (((7 + -4) - 0) - -5) = ((3 - 0) - -5) = (3 - -5) = 8.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-8 - -9 * -4 + -8) = ((-8 - (-9 * -4)) + -8) = ((-8 - 36) + -8) = (-44 + -8) = -52.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-4 * -9 * 7 + 8) = (((-4 * -9) * 7) + 8) = ((36 * 7) + 8) = (252 + 8) = 260.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G - H))) = (((1 * 8) - (4 + 6)) - ((0 + 8) * (-52 - 260))) = ((8 - (4 + 6)) - ((0 + 8) * (-52 - 260))) = ((8 - 10) - ((0 + 8) * (-52 - 260))) = ((8 - 10) - (8 * (-52 - 260))) = ((8 - 10) - (8 * -312)) = (-2 - (8 * -312)) = (-2 - -2496) = 2494.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2494.", "correct_answer": "2494", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 291, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((8 * 8 * 9 * 4 * 3 + 9) * (-8 + 4 - 2 + 4 - 3 * 4)) - ((0 + 1 * 0 - -2 - -6 + 0) - (3 * -2 * 2 - -7 + -6 + -1))) + (((2 + 5 * -6 - -8 + 8 - -3) - (2 + 6 - 5 - 8 - 6 * -3)) + ((7 * -5 * -9 + 8 * -6 + -1) + (-5 - 7 + 7 * -1 - 7 * 8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C - D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (8 * 8 * 9 * 4 * 3 + 9), B = (-8 + 4 - 2 + 4 - 3 * 4), C = (0 + 1 * 0 - -2 - -6 + 0), D = (3 * -2 * 2 - -7 + -6 + -1), E = (2 + 5 * -6 - -8 + 8 - -3), F = (2 + 6 - 5 - 8 - 6 * -3), G = (7 * -5 * -9 + 8 * -6 + -1) and H = (-5 - 7 + 7 * -1 - 7 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 8 * 9 * 4 * 3 + 9) = (((((8 * 8) * 9) * 4) * 3) + 9) = ((((64 * 9) * 4) * 3) + 9) = (((576 * 4) * 3) + 9) = ((2304 * 3) + 9) = (6912 + 9) = 6921.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 4 - 2 + 4 - 3 * 4) = ((((-8 + 4) - 2) + 4) - (3 * 4)) = (((-4 - 2) + 4) - (3 * 4)) = (((-4 - 2) + 4) - 12) = ((-6 + 4) - 12) = (-2 - 12) = -14.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 + 1 * 0 - -2 - -6 + 0) = ((((0 + (1 * 0)) - -2) - -6) + 0) = ((((0 + 0) - -2) - -6) + 0) = (((0 - -2) - -6) + 0) = ((2 - -6) + 0) = (8 + 0) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * -2 * 2 - -7 + -6 + -1) = (((((3 * -2) * 2) - -7) + -6) + -1) = ((((-6 * 2) - -7) + -6) + -1) = (((-12 - -7) + -6) + -1) = ((-5 + -6) + -1) = (-11 + -1) = -12.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (2 + 5 * -6 - -8 + 8 - -3) = ((((2 + (5 * -6)) - -8) + 8) - -3) = ((((2 + -30) - -8) + 8) - -3) = (((-28 - -8) + 8) - -3) = ((-20 + 8) - -3) = (-12 - -3) = -9.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (2 + 6 - 5 - 8 - 6 * -3) = ((((2 + 6) - 5) - 8) - (6 * -3)) = (((8 - 5) - 8) - (6 * -3)) = (((8 - 5) - 8) - -18) = ((3 - 8) - -18) = (-5 - -18) = 13.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 * -5 * -9 + 8 * -6 + -1) = ((((7 * -5) * -9) + (8 * -6)) + -1) = (((-35 * -9) + (8 * -6)) + -1) = (((-35 * -9) + -48) + -1) = ((315 + -48) + -1) = (267 + -1) = 266.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-5 - 7 + 7 * -1 - 7 * 8) = (((-5 - 7) + (7 * -1)) - (7 * 8)) = ((-12 + (7 * -1)) - (7 * 8)) = ((-12 + -7) - (7 * 8)) = ((-12 + -7) - 56) = (-19 - 56) = -75.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C - D)) + ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((6921 * -14) - (8 - -12)) + ((-9 - 13) + (266 + -75))) = ((-96894 - (8 - -12)) + ((-9 - 13) + (266 + -75))) = ((-96894 - 20) + ((-9 - 13) + (266 + -75))) = ((-96894 - 20) + (-22 + (266 + -75))) = ((-96894 - 20) + (-22 + 191)) = (-96914 + (-22 + 191)) = (-96914 + 169) = -96745.\n(Final response) So the answer is -96745.", "correct_answer": "-96745", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 358, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((1 * 5 - 1 - -2 * -6) - (-5 * -3 - -8 * 2 - -2)) + ((-5 + 0 * 1 + -6 - -5) - (-1 * -9 * 2 + -6 + 2))) * (((-9 - 5 + -8 + 1 * -8) + (0 - -6 * 8 * 2 * -3)) * ((-3 - 4 * 4 - -7 + 6) + (-7 - 8 - -7 + 4 * -8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E + F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (1 * 5 - 1 - -2 * -6), B = (-5 * -3 - -8 * 2 - -2), C = (-5 + 0 * 1 + -6 - -5), D = (-1 * -9 * 2 + -6 + 2), E = (-9 - 5 + -8 + 1 * -8), F = (0 - -6 * 8 * 2 * -3), G = (-3 - 4 * 4 - -7 + 6) and H = (-7 - 8 - -7 + 4 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * 5 - 1 - -2 * -6) = (((1 * 5) - 1) - (-2 * -6)) = ((5 - 1) - (-2 * -6)) = ((5 - 1) - 12) = (4 - 12) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -3 - -8 * 2 - -2) = (((-5 * -3) - (-8 * 2)) - -2) = ((15 - (-8 * 2)) - -2) = ((15 - -16) - -2) = (31 - -2) = 33.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 + 0 * 1 + -6 - -5) = (((-5 + (0 * 1)) + -6) - -5) = (((-5 + 0) + -6) - -5) = ((-5 + -6) - -5) = (-11 - -5) = -6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * -9 * 2 + -6 + 2) = ((((-1 * -9) * 2) + -6) + 2) = (((9 * 2) + -6) + 2) = ((18 + -6) + 2) = (12 + 2) = 14.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-9 - 5 + -8 + 1 * -8) = (((-9 - 5) + -8) + (1 * -8)) = ((-14 + -8) + (1 * -8)) = ((-14 + -8) + -8) = (-22 + -8) = -30.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (0 - -6 * 8 * 2 * -3) = (0 - (((-6 * 8) * 2) * -3)) = (0 - ((-48 * 2) * -3)) = (0 - (-96 * -3)) = (0 - 288) = -288.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-3 - 4 * 4 - -7 + 6) = (((-3 - (4 * 4)) - -7) + 6) = (((-3 - 16) - -7) + 6) = ((-19 - -7) + 6) = (-12 + 6) = -6.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-7 - 8 - -7 + 4 * -8) = (((-7 - 8) - -7) + (4 * -8)) = ((-15 - -7) + (4 * -8)) = ((-15 - -7) + -32) = (-8 + -32) = -40.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C - D)) * ((E + F) * (G + H))) = (((-8 - 33) + (-6 - 14)) * ((-30 + -288) * (-6 + -40))) = ((-41 + (-6 - 14)) * ((-30 + -288) * (-6 + -40))) = ((-41 + -20) * ((-30 + -288) * (-6 + -40))) = ((-41 + -20) * (-318 * (-6 + -40))) = ((-41 + -20) * (-318 * -46)) = (-61 * (-318 * -46)) = (-61 * 14628) = -892308.\n(Final response) So the answer is -892308.", "correct_answer": "-892308", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 315, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 - 9 + 6 * -2) * (-2 - 6 * 0 + 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-3 - 9 + 6 * -2) and B = (-2 - 6 * 0 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - 9 + 6 * -2) = ((-3 - 9) + (6 * -2)) = (-12 + (6 * -2)) = (-12 + -12) = -24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 6 * 0 + 3) = ((-2 - (6 * 0)) + 3) = ((-2 - 0) + 3) = (-2 + 3) = 1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-24 * 1) = -24.\n(Final response) So the answer is -24.", "correct_answer": "-24", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 56, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((4 * -1 * -9) + (9 * 8 - -5)) + ((7 + -8 * -8) + (-6 + 4 * -1))) - (((6 * -1 * -4) * (-4 + 4 * 9)) - ((3 + -3 - 2) + (-8 * -5 - 4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C + D)) - ((E * F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (4 * -1 * -9), B = (9 * 8 - -5), C = (7 + -8 * -8), D = (-6 + 4 * -1), E = (6 * -1 * -4), F = (-4 + 4 * 9), G = (3 + -3 - 2) and H = (-8 * -5 - 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * -1 * -9) = ((4 * -1) * -9) = (-4 * -9) = 36.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 8 - -5) = ((9 * 8) - -5) = (72 - -5) = 77.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + -8 * -8) = (7 + (-8 * -8)) = (7 + 64) = 71.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + 4 * -1) = (-6 + (4 * -1)) = (-6 + -4) = -10.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (6 * -1 * -4) = ((6 * -1) * -4) = (-6 * -4) = 24.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-4 + 4 * 9) = (-4 + (4 * 9)) = (-4 + 36) = 32.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 + -3 - 2) = ((3 + -3) - 2) = (0 - 2) = -2.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 * -5 - 4) = ((-8 * -5) - 4) = (40 - 4) = 36.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C + D)) - ((E * F) - (G + H))) = (((36 + 77) + (71 + -10)) - ((24 * 32) - (-2 + 36))) = ((113 + (71 + -10)) - ((24 * 32) - (-2 + 36))) = ((113 + 61) - ((24 * 32) - (-2 + 36))) = ((113 + 61) - (768 - (-2 + 36))) = ((113 + 61) - (768 - 34)) = (174 - (768 - 34)) = (174 - 734) = -560.\n(Final response) So the answer is -560.", "correct_answer": "-560", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 261, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + 7 + 4 - -8) - (-1 + 1 * -8 - -6)) - ((4 + 3 + -5 - 4) - (-2 * 7 + 1 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-7 + 7 + 4 - -8), B = (-1 + 1 * -8 - -6), C = (4 + 3 + -5 - 4) and D = (-2 * 7 + 1 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 7 + 4 - -8) = (((-7 + 7) + 4) - -8) = ((0 + 4) - -8) = (4 - -8) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + 1 * -8 - -6) = ((-1 + (1 * -8)) - -6) = ((-1 + -8) - -6) = (-9 - -6) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + 3 + -5 - 4) = (((4 + 3) + -5) - 4) = ((7 + -5) - 4) = (2 - 4) = -2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * 7 + 1 * 0) = ((-2 * 7) + (1 * 0)) = (-14 + (1 * 0)) = (-14 + 0) = -14.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((12 - -3) - (-2 - -14)) = (15 - (-2 - -14)) = (15 - 12) = 3.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3.", "correct_answer": "3", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 168, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((3 * 8 - 8 - 7) + (-2 * -4 - -2 * 5)) * ((9 - -6 * -3 + -8) * (-8 - 4 + -3 - -5))) - (((9 - -9 - 1 * -1) - (-2 + -9 + 2 - -9)) + ((-8 * 8 * 8 * 5) + (-2 * 0 + 1 + 9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (3 * 8 - 8 - 7), B = (-2 * -4 - -2 * 5), C = (9 - -6 * -3 + -8), D = (-8 - 4 + -3 - -5), E = (9 - -9 - 1 * -1), F = (-2 + -9 + 2 - -9), G = (-8 * 8 * 8 * 5) and H = (-2 * 0 + 1 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 8 - 8 - 7) = (((3 * 8) - 8) - 7) = ((24 - 8) - 7) = (16 - 7) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -4 - -2 * 5) = ((-2 * -4) - (-2 * 5)) = (8 - (-2 * 5)) = (8 - -10) = 18.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - -6 * -3 + -8) = ((9 - (-6 * -3)) + -8) = ((9 - 18) + -8) = (-9 + -8) = -17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - 4 + -3 - -5) = (((-8 - 4) + -3) - -5) = ((-12 + -3) - -5) = (-15 - -5) = -10.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (9 - -9 - 1 * -1) = ((9 - -9) - (1 * -1)) = (18 - (1 * -1)) = (18 - -1) = 19.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-2 + -9 + 2 - -9) = (((-2 + -9) + 2) - -9) = ((-11 + 2) - -9) = (-9 - -9) = 0.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-8 * 8 * 8 * 5) = (((-8 * 8) * 8) * 5) = ((-64 * 8) * 5) = (-512 * 5) = -2560.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-2 * 0 + 1 + 9) = (((-2 * 0) + 1) + 9) = ((0 + 1) + 9) = (1 + 9) = 10.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G + H))) = (((9 + 18) * (-17 * -10)) - ((19 - 0) + (-2560 + 10))) = ((27 * (-17 * -10)) - ((19 - 0) + (-2560 + 10))) = ((27 * 170) - ((19 - 0) + (-2560 + 10))) = ((27 * 170) - (19 + (-2560 + 10))) = ((27 * 170) - (19 + -2550)) = (4590 - (19 + -2550)) = (4590 - -2531) = 7121.\n(Final response) So the answer is 7121.", "correct_answer": "7121", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 296, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 + 9 + 9 * 1 + 7 * -2) - (2 - 3 - 8 - 9 + 6 + -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 + 9 + 9 * 1 + 7 * -2) and B = (2 - 3 - 8 - 9 + 6 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 9 + 9 * 1 + 7 * -2) = (((6 + 9) + (9 * 1)) + (7 * -2)) = ((15 + (9 * 1)) + (7 * -2)) = ((15 + 9) + (7 * -2)) = ((15 + 9) + -14) = (24 + -14) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - 3 - 8 - 9 + 6 + -7) = (((((2 - 3) - 8) - 9) + 6) + -7) = ((((-1 - 8) - 9) + 6) + -7) = (((-9 - 9) + 6) + -7) = ((-18 + 6) + -7) = (-12 + -7) = -19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (10 - -19) = 29.\n(Final response) So the answer is 29.", "correct_answer": "29", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 98, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 + 2 * -1) + (5 - 6 * 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (8 + 2 * -1) and B = (5 - 6 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + 2 * -1) = (8 + (2 * -1)) = (8 + -2) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 6 * 7) = (5 - (6 * 7)) = (5 - 42) = -37.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (6 + -37) = -31.\n(Final response) So the answer is -31.", "correct_answer": "-31", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 117, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 * 9 + 7) + (8 - 1 * 7)) + ((8 * -3 * -9) - (-2 * -8 + 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-2 * 9 + 7), B = (8 - 1 * 7), C = (8 * -3 * -9) and D = (-2 * -8 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * 9 + 7) = ((-2 * 9) + 7) = (-18 + 7) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 1 * 7) = (8 - (1 * 7)) = (8 - 7) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -3 * -9) = ((8 * -3) * -9) = (-24 * -9) = 216.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * -8 + 1) = ((-2 * -8) + 1) = (16 + 1) = 17.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((-11 + 1) + (216 - 17)) = (-10 + (216 - 17)) = (-10 + 199) = 189.\n(Final response) So the answer is 189.", "correct_answer": "189", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 138, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - 5 * -9 - 9 + -8) + (-4 * 5 + -9 - -8 - 4)) - ((-2 + 6 * -4 - 9 - -4) - (0 + 9 * -7 - 7 - 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-9 - 5 * -9 - 9 + -8), B = (-4 * 5 + -9 - -8 - 4), C = (-2 + 6 * -4 - 9 - -4) and D = (0 + 9 * -7 - 7 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 5 * -9 - 9 + -8) = (((-9 - (5 * -9)) - 9) + -8) = (((-9 - -45) - 9) + -8) = ((36 - 9) + -8) = (27 + -8) = 19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 5 + -9 - -8 - 4) = ((((-4 * 5) + -9) - -8) - 4) = (((-20 + -9) - -8) - 4) = ((-29 - -8) - 4) = (-21 - 4) = -25.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + 6 * -4 - 9 - -4) = (((-2 + (6 * -4)) - 9) - -4) = (((-2 + -24) - 9) - -4) = ((-26 - 9) - -4) = (-35 - -4) = -31.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + 9 * -7 - 7 - 0) = (((0 + (9 * -7)) - 7) - 0) = (((0 + -63) - 7) - 0) = ((-63 - 7) - 0) = (-70 - 0) = -70.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((19 + -25) - (-31 - -70)) = (-6 - (-31 - -70)) = (-6 - 39) = -45.\n(Final response) So the answer is -45.", "correct_answer": "-45", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 195, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * 0 + 9) * (-3 + -6 - -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 * 0 + 9) and B = (-3 + -6 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 0 + 9) = ((5 * 0) + 9) = (0 + 9) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + -6 - -5) = ((-3 + -6) - -5) = (-9 - -5) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (9 * -4) = -36.\n(Final response) So the answer is -36.", "correct_answer": "-36", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 11, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 * 8 + 8 + 0) + (-2 * -7 * -1 - 9)) - ((-2 - -2 + -4 - 0) * (-6 * -1 * 6 + 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (1 * 8 + 8 + 0), B = (-2 * -7 * -1 - 9), C = (-2 - -2 + -4 - 0) and D = (-6 * -1 * 6 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * 8 + 8 + 0) = (((1 * 8) + 8) + 0) = ((8 + 8) + 0) = (16 + 0) = 16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * -7 * -1 - 9) = (((-2 * -7) * -1) - 9) = ((14 * -1) - 9) = (-14 - 9) = -23.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 - -2 + -4 - 0) = (((-2 - -2) + -4) - 0) = ((0 + -4) - 0) = (-4 - 0) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * -1 * 6 + 6) = (((-6 * -1) * 6) + 6) = ((6 * 6) + 6) = (36 + 6) = 42.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((16 + -23) - (-4 * 42)) = (-7 - (-4 * 42)) = (-7 - -168) = 161.\n(Final response) So the answer is 161.", "correct_answer": "161", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 566, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 + 6 - 5 + 7) - (3 + -4 + 6 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-7 + 6 - 5 + 7) and B = (3 + -4 + 6 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 6 - 5 + 7) = (((-7 + 6) - 5) + 7) = ((-1 - 5) + 7) = (-6 + 7) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + -4 + 6 - 3) = (((3 + -4) + 6) - 3) = ((-1 + 6) - 3) = (5 - 3) = 2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (1 - 2) = -1.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1.", "correct_answer": "-1", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 257, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * -8 + 0 * -1) + (-6 * 4 + 8 - -4)) * ((9 + 7 - 1 * 8) - (-2 - -8 + 0 * 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (3 * -8 + 0 * -1), B = (-6 * 4 + 8 - -4), C = (9 + 7 - 1 * 8) and D = (-2 - -8 + 0 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -8 + 0 * -1) = ((3 * -8) + (0 * -1)) = (-24 + (0 * -1)) = (-24 + 0) = -24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 4 + 8 - -4) = (((-6 * 4) + 8) - -4) = ((-24 + 8) - -4) = (-16 - -4) = -12.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 + 7 - 1 * 8) = ((9 + 7) - (1 * 8)) = (16 - (1 * 8)) = (16 - 8) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - -8 + 0 * 3) = ((-2 - -8) + (0 * 3)) = (6 + (0 * 3)) = (6 + 0) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((-24 + -12) * (8 - 6)) = (-36 * (8 - 6)) = (-36 * 2) = -72.\n(Final response) So the answer is -72.", "correct_answer": "-72", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 541, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + 3 - -7 + -1) - (9 - -5 - 4 + 7)) * ((-3 + -5 * 3 + -3) - (-2 - -9 * -9 * -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-7 + 3 - -7 + -1), B = (9 - -5 - 4 + 7), C = (-3 + -5 * 3 + -3) and D = (-2 - -9 * -9 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 3 - -7 + -1) = (((-7 + 3) - -7) + -1) = ((-4 - -7) + -1) = (3 + -1) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - -5 - 4 + 7) = (((9 - -5) - 4) + 7) = ((14 - 4) + 7) = (10 + 7) = 17.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -5 * 3 + -3) = ((-3 + (-5 * 3)) + -3) = ((-3 + -15) + -3) = (-18 + -3) = -21.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - -9 * -9 * -8) = (-2 - ((-9 * -9) * -8)) = (-2 - (81 * -8)) = (-2 - -648) = 646.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((2 - 17) * (-21 - 646)) = (-15 * (-21 - 646)) = (-15 * -667) = 10005.\n(Final response) So the answer is 10005.", "correct_answer": "10005", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 479, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - 1 * 8 * 5 - -6) + (-9 - -1 + 7 + 8 * 7)) + ((-3 - -1 + 8 * 8 + -3) * (-7 - -4 - -4 * -9 + 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-9 - 1 * 8 * 5 - -6), B = (-9 - -1 + 7 + 8 * 7), C = (-3 - -1 + 8 * 8 + -3) and D = (-7 - -4 - -4 * -9 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 1 * 8 * 5 - -6) = ((-9 - ((1 * 8) * 5)) - -6) = ((-9 - (8 * 5)) - -6) = ((-9 - 40) - -6) = (-49 - -6) = -43.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - -1 + 7 + 8 * 7) = (((-9 - -1) + 7) + (8 * 7)) = ((-8 + 7) + (8 * 7)) = ((-8 + 7) + 56) = (-1 + 56) = 55.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - -1 + 8 * 8 + -3) = (((-3 - -1) + (8 * 8)) + -3) = ((-2 + (8 * 8)) + -3) = ((-2 + 64) + -3) = (62 + -3) = 59.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -4 - -4 * -9 + 7) = (((-7 - -4) - (-4 * -9)) + 7) = ((-3 - (-4 * -9)) + 7) = ((-3 - 36) + 7) = (-39 + 7) = -32.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((-43 + 55) + (59 * -32)) = (12 + (59 * -32)) = (12 + -1888) = -1876.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1876.", "correct_answer": "-1876", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 193, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 * 2 + 2) - (2 * 4 - 3)) - ((-3 + -7 + 2) + (2 + -7 + -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (-2 * 2 + 2), B = (2 * 4 - 3), C = (-3 + -7 + 2) and D = (2 + -7 + -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * 2 + 2) = ((-2 * 2) + 2) = (-4 + 2) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 4 - 3) = ((2 * 4) - 3) = (8 - 3) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -7 + 2) = ((-3 + -7) + 2) = (-10 + 2) = -8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 + -7 + -9) = ((2 + -7) + -9) = (-5 + -9) = -14.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-2 - 5) - (-8 + -14)) = (-7 - (-8 + -14)) = (-7 - -22) = 15.\n(Final response) So the answer is 15.", "correct_answer": "15", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 390, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 + -9 - -1) - (-5 - -4 * -4)) - ((6 * -7 + -4) - (-4 - 9 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (5 + -9 - -1), B = (-5 - -4 * -4), C = (6 * -7 + -4) and D = (-4 - 9 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + -9 - -1) = ((5 + -9) - -1) = (-4 - -1) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -4 * -4) = (-5 - (-4 * -4)) = (-5 - 16) = -21.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 * -7 + -4) = ((6 * -7) + -4) = (-42 + -4) = -46.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - 9 * 5) = (-4 - (9 * 5)) = (-4 - 45) = -49.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-3 - -21) - (-46 - -49)) = (18 - (-46 - -49)) = (18 - 3) = 15.\n(Final response) So the answer is 15.", "correct_answer": "15", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 394, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 + -4 + 5) - (0 * 7 + -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-8 + -4 + 5) and B = (0 * 7 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + -4 + 5) = ((-8 + -4) + 5) = (-12 + 5) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 7 + -6) = ((0 * 7) + -6) = (0 + -6) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-7 - -6) = -1.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1.", "correct_answer": "-1", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 65, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 - -3 + -8) * (-4 + -8 * -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 - -3 + -8) and B = (-4 + -8 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - -3 + -8) = ((5 - -3) + -8) = (8 + -8) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + -8 * -5) = (-4 + (-8 * -5)) = (-4 + 40) = 36.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (0 * 36) = 0.\n(Final response) So the answer is 0.", "correct_answer": "0", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 10, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((6 * 3 + 5 - 8 - 5) - (-5 * 3 + 8 * 3 + 0)) + ((-4 + 1 * -4 - 7 + -1) - (8 + -4 + 4 - -8 - -9))) - (((8 - -9 * 1 - 5 + 4) + (-6 - -1 + -7 + 1 - -1)) + ((3 + -8 - 8 * -7 * -3) * (-8 * 6 - -2 - -5 * -3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C - D)) - ((E + F) + (G * H)))\", where A = (6 * 3 + 5 - 8 - 5), B = (-5 * 3 + 8 * 3 + 0), C = (-4 + 1 * -4 - 7 + -1), D = (8 + -4 + 4 - -8 - -9), E = (8 - -9 * 1 - 5 + 4), F = (-6 - -1 + -7 + 1 - -1), G = (3 + -8 - 8 * -7 * -3) and H = (-8 * 6 - -2 - -5 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * 3 + 5 - 8 - 5) = ((((6 * 3) + 5) - 8) - 5) = (((18 + 5) - 8) - 5) = ((23 - 8) - 5) = (15 - 5) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 3 + 8 * 3 + 0) = (((-5 * 3) + (8 * 3)) + 0) = ((-15 + (8 * 3)) + 0) = ((-15 + 24) + 0) = (9 + 0) = 9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + 1 * -4 - 7 + -1) = (((-4 + (1 * -4)) - 7) + -1) = (((-4 + -4) - 7) + -1) = ((-8 - 7) + -1) = (-15 + -1) = -16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 + -4 + 4 - -8 - -9) = ((((8 + -4) + 4) - -8) - -9) = (((4 + 4) - -8) - -9) = ((8 - -8) - -9) = (16 - -9) = 25.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (8 - -9 * 1 - 5 + 4) = (((8 - (-9 * 1)) - 5) + 4) = (((8 - -9) - 5) + 4) = ((17 - 5) + 4) = (12 + 4) = 16.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-6 - -1 + -7 + 1 - -1) = ((((-6 - -1) + -7) + 1) - -1) = (((-5 + -7) + 1) - -1) = ((-12 + 1) - -1) = (-11 - -1) = -10.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 + -8 - 8 * -7 * -3) = ((3 + -8) - ((8 * -7) * -3)) = (-5 - ((8 * -7) * -3)) = (-5 - (-56 * -3)) = (-5 - 168) = -173.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 * 6 - -2 - -5 * -3) = (((-8 * 6) - -2) - (-5 * -3)) = ((-48 - -2) - (-5 * -3)) = ((-48 - -2) - 15) = (-46 - 15) = -61.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C - D)) - ((E + F) + (G * H))) = (((10 - 9) + (-16 - 25)) - ((16 + -10) + (-173 * -61))) = ((1 + (-16 - 25)) - ((16 + -10) + (-173 * -61))) = ((1 + -41) - ((16 + -10) + (-173 * -61))) = ((1 + -41) - (6 + (-173 * -61))) = ((1 + -41) - (6 + 10553)) = (-40 - (6 + 10553)) = (-40 - 10559) = -10599.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10599.", "correct_answer": "-10599", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 316, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 * 8 * 9 + -3 + 0 - 0) - (4 + -4 + 3 + 3 + 4 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 * 8 * 9 + -3 + 0 - 0) and B = (4 + -4 + 3 + 3 + 4 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 8 * 9 + -3 + 0 - 0) = (((((-1 * 8) * 9) + -3) + 0) - 0) = ((((-8 * 9) + -3) + 0) - 0) = (((-72 + -3) + 0) - 0) = ((-75 + 0) - 0) = (-75 - 0) = -75.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + -4 + 3 + 3 + 4 + -1) = (((((4 + -4) + 3) + 3) + 4) + -1) = ((((0 + 3) + 3) + 4) + -1) = (((3 + 3) + 4) + -1) = ((6 + 4) + -1) = (10 + -1) = 9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-75 - 9) = -84.\n(Final response) So the answer is -84.", "correct_answer": "-84", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 96, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 + -1 + -3 - 9 - -2) * (-9 - 5 * 9 - -5 - 2)) + ((6 + 1 * 0 + 1 * 9) + (1 + -4 * 6 - 1 + 2))) + (((1 * -9 + -4 - -2 - 4) * (9 + -3 * -4 * 1 + -4)) + ((8 - 7 + -8 + 2 * -5) + (-3 - -1 * 1 + -8 * 8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C + D)) + ((E * F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (2 + -1 + -3 - 9 - -2), B = (-9 - 5 * 9 - -5 - 2), C = (6 + 1 * 0 + 1 * 9), D = (1 + -4 * 6 - 1 + 2), E = (1 * -9 + -4 - -2 - 4), F = (9 + -3 * -4 * 1 + -4), G = (8 - 7 + -8 + 2 * -5) and H = (-3 - -1 * 1 + -8 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + -1 + -3 - 9 - -2) = ((((2 + -1) + -3) - 9) - -2) = (((1 + -3) - 9) - -2) = ((-2 - 9) - -2) = (-11 - -2) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - 5 * 9 - -5 - 2) = (((-9 - (5 * 9)) - -5) - 2) = (((-9 - 45) - -5) - 2) = ((-54 - -5) - 2) = (-49 - 2) = -51.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + 1 * 0 + 1 * 9) = ((6 + (1 * 0)) + (1 * 9)) = ((6 + 0) + (1 * 9)) = ((6 + 0) + 9) = (6 + 9) = 15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + -4 * 6 - 1 + 2) = (((1 + (-4 * 6)) - 1) + 2) = (((1 + -24) - 1) + 2) = ((-23 - 1) + 2) = (-24 + 2) = -22.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (1 * -9 + -4 - -2 - 4) = ((((1 * -9) + -4) - -2) - 4) = (((-9 + -4) - -2) - 4) = ((-13 - -2) - 4) = (-11 - 4) = -15.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (9 + -3 * -4 * 1 + -4) = ((9 + ((-3 * -4) * 1)) + -4) = ((9 + (12 * 1)) + -4) = ((9 + 12) + -4) = (21 + -4) = 17.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (8 - 7 + -8 + 2 * -5) = (((8 - 7) + -8) + (2 * -5)) = ((1 + -8) + (2 * -5)) = ((1 + -8) + -10) = (-7 + -10) = -17.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-3 - -1 * 1 + -8 * 8) = ((-3 - (-1 * 1)) + (-8 * 8)) = ((-3 - -1) + (-8 * 8)) = ((-3 - -1) + -64) = (-2 + -64) = -66.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C + D)) + ((E * F) + (G + H))) = (((-9 * -51) + (15 + -22)) + ((-15 * 17) + (-17 + -66))) = ((459 + (15 + -22)) + ((-15 * 17) + (-17 + -66))) = ((459 + -7) + ((-15 * 17) + (-17 + -66))) = ((459 + -7) + (-255 + (-17 + -66))) = ((459 + -7) + (-255 + -83)) = (452 + (-255 + -83)) = (452 + -338) = 114.\n(Final response) So the answer is 114.", "correct_answer": "114", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 318, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * 9 - 2 * -9) * (7 + -7 - -7 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 * 9 - 2 * -9) and B = (7 + -7 - -7 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 9 - 2 * -9) = ((9 * 9) - (2 * -9)) = (81 - (2 * -9)) = (81 - -18) = 99.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + -7 - -7 - 3) = (((7 + -7) - -7) - 3) = ((0 - -7) - 3) = (7 - 3) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (99 * 4) = 396.\n(Final response) So the answer is 396.", "correct_answer": "396", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 42, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * 1 + -5 + 2) * (7 * -1 + 9 * 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 * 1 + -5 + 2) and B = (7 * -1 + 9 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 1 + -5 + 2) = (((5 * 1) + -5) + 2) = ((5 + -5) + 2) = (0 + 2) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * -1 + 9 * 2) = ((7 * -1) + (9 * 2)) = (-7 + (9 * 2)) = (-7 + 18) = 11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (2 * 11) = 22.\n(Final response) So the answer is 22.", "correct_answer": "22", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 156, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 + -6 * 9) * (1 + 3 * -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 + -6 * 9) and B = (1 + 3 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + -6 * 9) = (-5 + (-6 * 9)) = (-5 + -54) = -59.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + 3 * -8) = (1 + (3 * -8)) = (1 + -24) = -23.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-59 * -23) = 1357.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1357.", "correct_answer": "1357", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 112, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 - 5 + 0) - (2 + -4 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (1 - 5 + 0) and B = (2 + -4 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - 5 + 0) = ((1 - 5) + 0) = (-4 + 0) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + -4 * 4) = (2 + (-4 * 4)) = (2 + -16) = -14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-4 - -14) = 10.\n(Final response) So the answer is 10.", "correct_answer": "10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 48, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 - 7 * 2 + 9) + (-2 - 7 - -7 - 8)) + ((5 + 7 * 4 + 4) + (-5 * -6 - -9 * -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (4 - 7 * 2 + 9), B = (-2 - 7 - -7 - 8), C = (5 + 7 * 4 + 4) and D = (-5 * -6 - -9 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - 7 * 2 + 9) = ((4 - (7 * 2)) + 9) = ((4 - 14) + 9) = (-10 + 9) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 7 - -7 - 8) = (((-2 - 7) - -7) - 8) = ((-9 - -7) - 8) = (-2 - 8) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 + 7 * 4 + 4) = ((5 + (7 * 4)) + 4) = ((5 + 28) + 4) = (33 + 4) = 37.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 * -6 - -9 * -7) = ((-5 * -6) - (-9 * -7)) = (30 - (-9 * -7)) = (30 - 63) = -33.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((-1 + -10) + (37 + -33)) = (-11 + (37 + -33)) = (-11 + 4) = -7.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7.", "correct_answer": "-7", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 173, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 + -5 * 0) + (-1 - 9 + 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (1 + -5 * 0) and B = (-1 - 9 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + -5 * 0) = (1 + (-5 * 0)) = (1 + 0) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 9 + 4) = ((-1 - 9) + 4) = (-10 + 4) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (1 + -6) = -5.\n(Final response) So the answer is -5.", "correct_answer": "-5", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 93, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 + -3 * -7 + 5) + (8 - -9 * 1 + 5)) + ((-3 + -4 * 5 * -7) - (-1 * -4 + -9 + 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (9 + -3 * -7 + 5), B = (8 - -9 * 1 + 5), C = (-3 + -4 * 5 * -7) and D = (-1 * -4 + -9 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + -3 * -7 + 5) = ((9 + (-3 * -7)) + 5) = ((9 + 21) + 5) = (30 + 5) = 35.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - -9 * 1 + 5) = ((8 - (-9 * 1)) + 5) = ((8 - -9) + 5) = (17 + 5) = 22.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 + -4 * 5 * -7) = (-3 + ((-4 * 5) * -7)) = (-3 + (-20 * -7)) = (-3 + 140) = 137.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * -4 + -9 + 2) = (((-1 * -4) + -9) + 2) = ((4 + -9) + 2) = (-5 + 2) = -3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((35 + 22) + (137 - -3)) = (57 + (137 - -3)) = (57 + 140) = 197.\n(Final response) So the answer is 197.", "correct_answer": "197", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 505, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - 7 * -5 - 6) * (4 * 9 + -9 - 0)) * ((3 - 1 - -7 + -2) * (-7 + 4 + 9 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-9 - 7 * -5 - 6), B = (4 * 9 + -9 - 0), C = (3 - 1 - -7 + -2) and D = (-7 + 4 + 9 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 7 * -5 - 6) = ((-9 - (7 * -5)) - 6) = ((-9 - -35) - 6) = (26 - 6) = 20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 9 + -9 - 0) = (((4 * 9) + -9) - 0) = ((36 + -9) - 0) = (27 - 0) = 27.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 - 1 - -7 + -2) = (((3 - 1) - -7) + -2) = ((2 - -7) + -2) = (9 + -2) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + 4 + 9 + -8) = (((-7 + 4) + 9) + -8) = ((-3 + 9) + -8) = (6 + -8) = -2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((20 * 27) * (7 * -2)) = (540 * (7 * -2)) = (540 * -14) = -7560.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7560.", "correct_answer": "-7560", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 521, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * -8 - -8) + (-6 + -7 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (9 * -8 - -8) and B = (-6 + -7 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * -8 - -8) = ((9 * -8) - -8) = (-72 - -8) = -64.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -7 + -1) = ((-6 + -7) + -1) = (-13 + -1) = -14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-64 + -14) = -78.\n(Final response) So the answer is -78.", "correct_answer": "-78", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 141, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((1 + 6 - -8) - (7 + -6 * -4)) + ((-5 - -1 + -6) + (-5 + 5 + 5))) + (((-6 - 9 - -9) - (-7 * -7 - -2)) * ((2 + -5 * -6) * (-5 + -7 - 9)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C + D)) + ((E - F) * (G * H)))\", where A = (1 + 6 - -8), B = (7 + -6 * -4), C = (-5 - -1 + -6), D = (-5 + 5 + 5), E = (-6 - 9 - -9), F = (-7 * -7 - -2), G = (2 + -5 * -6) and H = (-5 + -7 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 6 - -8) = ((1 + 6) - -8) = (7 - -8) = 15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + -6 * -4) = (7 + (-6 * -4)) = (7 + 24) = 31.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - -1 + -6) = ((-5 - -1) + -6) = (-4 + -6) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 + 5 + 5) = ((-5 + 5) + 5) = (0 + 5) = 5.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-6 - 9 - -9) = ((-6 - 9) - -9) = (-15 - -9) = -6.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-7 * -7 - -2) = ((-7 * -7) - -2) = (49 - -2) = 51.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (2 + -5 * -6) = (2 + (-5 * -6)) = (2 + 30) = 32.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-5 + -7 - 9) = ((-5 + -7) - 9) = (-12 - 9) = -21.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C + D)) + ((E - F) * (G * H))) = (((15 - 31) + (-10 + 5)) + ((-6 - 51) * (32 * -21))) = ((-16 + (-10 + 5)) + ((-6 - 51) * (32 * -21))) = ((-16 + -5) + ((-6 - 51) * (32 * -21))) = ((-16 + -5) + (-57 * (32 * -21))) = ((-16 + -5) + (-57 * -672)) = (-21 + (-57 * -672)) = (-21 + 38304) = 38283.\n(Final response) So the answer is 38283.", "correct_answer": "38283", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 243, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((0 * 9 + -4 + 6) - (0 * 9 * 5 + -6)) * ((9 - -2 * -9 * 3) * (-8 + 9 + 7 + 8))) - (((-9 * 9 * 9 - -5) * (-7 + -3 * 7 + -6)) + ((-1 - 8 + 9 * 0) + (3 - 2 * 5 + -3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C * D)) - ((E * F) + (G + H)))\", where A = (0 * 9 + -4 + 6), B = (0 * 9 * 5 + -6), C = (9 - -2 * -9 * 3), D = (-8 + 9 + 7 + 8), E = (-9 * 9 * 9 - -5), F = (-7 + -3 * 7 + -6), G = (-1 - 8 + 9 * 0) and H = (3 - 2 * 5 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * 9 + -4 + 6) = (((0 * 9) + -4) + 6) = ((0 + -4) + 6) = (-4 + 6) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 * 9 * 5 + -6) = (((0 * 9) * 5) + -6) = ((0 * 5) + -6) = (0 + -6) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 - -2 * -9 * 3) = (9 - ((-2 * -9) * 3)) = (9 - (18 * 3)) = (9 - 54) = -45.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + 9 + 7 + 8) = (((-8 + 9) + 7) + 8) = ((1 + 7) + 8) = (8 + 8) = 16.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-9 * 9 * 9 - -5) = (((-9 * 9) * 9) - -5) = ((-81 * 9) - -5) = (-729 - -5) = -724.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-7 + -3 * 7 + -6) = ((-7 + (-3 * 7)) + -6) = ((-7 + -21) + -6) = (-28 + -6) = -34.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-1 - 8 + 9 * 0) = ((-1 - 8) + (9 * 0)) = (-9 + (9 * 0)) = (-9 + 0) = -9.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (3 - 2 * 5 + -3) = ((3 - (2 * 5)) + -3) = ((3 - 10) + -3) = (-7 + -3) = -10.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C * D)) - ((E * F) + (G + H))) = (((2 - -6) * (-45 * 16)) - ((-724 * -34) + (-9 + -10))) = ((8 * (-45 * 16)) - ((-724 * -34) + (-9 + -10))) = ((8 * -720) - ((-724 * -34) + (-9 + -10))) = ((8 * -720) - (24616 + (-9 + -10))) = ((8 * -720) - (24616 + -19)) = (-5760 - (24616 + -19)) = (-5760 - 24597) = -30357.\n(Final response) So the answer is -30357.", "correct_answer": "-30357", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 286, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 * -7 + -8) + (7 - -5 - -9)) - ((-9 * -6 * 4) - (8 - -9 + 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C - D))\", where A = (7 * -7 + -8), B = (7 - -5 - -9), C = (-9 * -6 * 4) and D = (8 - -9 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * -7 + -8) = ((7 * -7) + -8) = (-49 + -8) = -57.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 - -5 - -9) = ((7 - -5) - -9) = (12 - -9) = 21.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 * -6 * 4) = ((-9 * -6) * 4) = (54 * 4) = 216.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - -9 + 6) = ((8 - -9) + 6) = (17 + 6) = 23.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C - D)) = ((-57 + 21) - (216 - 23)) = (-36 - (216 - 23)) = (-36 - 193) = -229.\n(Final response) So the answer is -229.", "correct_answer": "-229", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 408, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 - -2 * 2 + -7) - (-9 + -7 * 8 - -8)) + ((0 * -5 + -1 - 3) + (-9 + -2 * 7 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (8 - -2 * 2 + -7), B = (-9 + -7 * 8 - -8), C = (0 * -5 + -1 - 3) and D = (-9 + -2 * 7 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - -2 * 2 + -7) = ((8 - (-2 * 2)) + -7) = ((8 - -4) + -7) = (12 + -7) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + -7 * 8 - -8) = ((-9 + (-7 * 8)) - -8) = ((-9 + -56) - -8) = (-65 - -8) = -57.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * -5 + -1 - 3) = (((0 * -5) + -1) - 3) = ((0 + -1) - 3) = (-1 - 3) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 + -2 * 7 * 2) = (-9 + ((-2 * 7) * 2)) = (-9 + (-14 * 2)) = (-9 + -28) = -37.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((5 - -57) + (-4 + -37)) = (62 + (-4 + -37)) = (62 + -41) = 21.\n(Final response) So the answer is 21.", "correct_answer": "21", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 597, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 * -8 * -8) - (5 - 9 - 3)) - ((1 - -8 + 3) - (-9 - -5 + -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-9 * -8 * -8), B = (5 - 9 - 3), C = (1 - -8 + 3) and D = (-9 - -5 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * -8 * -8) = ((-9 * -8) * -8) = (72 * -8) = -576.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 9 - 3) = ((5 - 9) - 3) = (-4 - 3) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 - -8 + 3) = ((1 - -8) + 3) = (9 + 3) = 12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 - -5 + -3) = ((-9 - -5) + -3) = (-4 + -3) = -7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-576 - -7) - (12 - -7)) = (-569 - (12 - -7)) = (-569 - 19) = -588.\n(Final response) So the answer is -588.", "correct_answer": "-588", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 438, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 - 1 * 6 * -6) * (8 * 1 * -1 * 7)) * ((-6 + -2 - 7 - -1) - (-2 * 8 * -5 - -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (8 - 1 * 6 * -6), B = (8 * 1 * -1 * 7), C = (-6 + -2 - 7 - -1) and D = (-2 * 8 * -5 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - 1 * 6 * -6) = (8 - ((1 * 6) * -6)) = (8 - (6 * -6)) = (8 - -36) = 44.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 1 * -1 * 7) = (((8 * 1) * -1) * 7) = ((8 * -1) * 7) = (-8 * 7) = -56.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -2 - 7 - -1) = (((-6 + -2) - 7) - -1) = ((-8 - 7) - -1) = (-15 - -1) = -14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * 8 * -5 - -9) = (((-2 * 8) * -5) - -9) = ((-16 * -5) - -9) = (80 - -9) = 89.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((44 * -56) * (-14 - 89)) = (-2464 * (-14 - 89)) = (-2464 * -103) = 253792.\n(Final response) So the answer is 253792.", "correct_answer": "253792", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 598, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 + -2 * 0 * 2) * (8 + 2 * -5 - 0)) - ((6 + 1 * -2 * 8) - (2 - 3 + 8 * 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-4 + -2 * 0 * 2), B = (8 + 2 * -5 - 0), C = (6 + 1 * -2 * 8) and D = (2 - 3 + 8 * 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + -2 * 0 * 2) = (-4 + ((-2 * 0) * 2)) = (-4 + (0 * 2)) = (-4 + 0) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + 2 * -5 - 0) = ((8 + (2 * -5)) - 0) = ((8 + -10) - 0) = (-2 - 0) = -2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 + 1 * -2 * 8) = (6 + ((1 * -2) * 8)) = (6 + (-2 * 8)) = (6 + -16) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 - 3 + 8 * 5) = ((2 - 3) + (8 * 5)) = (-1 + (8 * 5)) = (-1 + 40) = 39.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C - D)) = ((-4 * -2) - (-10 - 39)) = (8 - (-10 - 39)) = (8 - -49) = 57.\n(Final response) So the answer is 57.", "correct_answer": "57", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 164, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 * 1 + 3 * 7) - (-8 + 0 - 1 + 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-7 * 1 + 3 * 7) and B = (-8 + 0 - 1 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * 1 + 3 * 7) = ((-7 * 1) + (3 * 7)) = (-7 + (3 * 7)) = (-7 + 21) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 0 - 1 + 9) = (((-8 + 0) - 1) + 9) = ((-8 - 1) + 9) = (-9 + 9) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (14 - 0) = 14.\n(Final response) So the answer is 14.", "correct_answer": "14", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 269, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((5 * 3 * 2 + 6) + (-4 * 3 + -2 + -6)) + ((-8 * -5 - 8 + 4) + (-8 * -2 * -5 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C + D))\", where A = (5 * 3 * 2 + 6), B = (-4 * 3 + -2 + -6), C = (-8 * -5 - 8 + 4) and D = (-8 * -2 * -5 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 3 * 2 + 6) = (((5 * 3) * 2) + 6) = ((15 * 2) + 6) = (30 + 6) = 36.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 3 + -2 + -6) = (((-4 * 3) + -2) + -6) = ((-12 + -2) + -6) = (-14 + -6) = -20.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * -5 - 8 + 4) = (((-8 * -5) - 8) + 4) = ((40 - 8) + 4) = (32 + 4) = 36.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 * -2 * -5 * 2) = (((-8 * -2) * -5) * 2) = ((16 * -5) * 2) = (-80 * 2) = -160.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C + D)) = ((36 + -20) + (36 + -160)) = (16 + (36 + -160)) = (16 + -124) = -108.\n(Final response) So the answer is -108.", "correct_answer": "-108", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 551, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-7 + -7 + 0 - -4 + -4 + -3) * (5 + 2 * -4 + -7 * 2 + 5)) + ((2 - -8 - -1 - 4 * 2 - -2) * (5 * -8 - -3 - 5 + 3 * 0))) - (((5 + 0 + -2 - 6 + -9 * -8) - (-9 * 0 + 7 * -4 - 1 - -7)) + ((5 - 5 - 2 - -6 * -8 * 8) - (2 + -1 + -7 * 8 - 7 - 1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (-7 + -7 + 0 - -4 + -4 + -3), B = (5 + 2 * -4 + -7 * 2 + 5), C = (2 - -8 - -1 - 4 * 2 - -2), D = (5 * -8 - -3 - 5 + 3 * 0), E = (5 + 0 + -2 - 6 + -9 * -8), F = (-9 * 0 + 7 * -4 - 1 - -7), G = (5 - 5 - 2 - -6 * -8 * 8) and H = (2 + -1 + -7 * 8 - 7 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + -7 + 0 - -4 + -4 + -3) = (((((-7 + -7) + 0) - -4) + -4) + -3) = ((((-14 + 0) - -4) + -4) + -3) = (((-14 - -4) + -4) + -3) = ((-10 + -4) + -3) = (-14 + -3) = -17.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 2 * -4 + -7 * 2 + 5) = (((5 + (2 * -4)) + (-7 * 2)) + 5) = (((5 + -8) + (-7 * 2)) + 5) = (((5 + -8) + -14) + 5) = ((-3 + -14) + 5) = (-17 + 5) = -12.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - -8 - -1 - 4 * 2 - -2) = ((((2 - -8) - -1) - (4 * 2)) - -2) = (((10 - -1) - (4 * 2)) - -2) = (((10 - -1) - 8) - -2) = ((11 - 8) - -2) = (3 - -2) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (5 * -8 - -3 - 5 + 3 * 0) = ((((5 * -8) - -3) - 5) + (3 * 0)) = (((-40 - -3) - 5) + (3 * 0)) = (((-40 - -3) - 5) + 0) = ((-37 - 5) + 0) = (-42 + 0) = -42.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (5 + 0 + -2 - 6 + -9 * -8) = ((((5 + 0) + -2) - 6) + (-9 * -8)) = (((5 + -2) - 6) + (-9 * -8)) = (((5 + -2) - 6) + 72) = ((3 - 6) + 72) = (-3 + 72) = 69.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-9 * 0 + 7 * -4 - 1 - -7) = ((((-9 * 0) + (7 * -4)) - 1) - -7) = (((0 + (7 * -4)) - 1) - -7) = (((0 + -28) - 1) - -7) = ((-28 - 1) - -7) = (-29 - -7) = -22.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (5 - 5 - 2 - -6 * -8 * 8) = (((5 - 5) - 2) - ((-6 * -8) * 8)) = ((0 - 2) - ((-6 * -8) * 8)) = ((0 - 2) - (48 * 8)) = (-2 - (48 * 8)) = (-2 - 384) = -386.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (2 + -1 + -7 * 8 - 7 - 1) = ((((2 + -1) + (-7 * 8)) - 7) - 1) = (((1 + (-7 * 8)) - 7) - 1) = (((1 + -56) - 7) - 1) = ((-55 - 7) - 1) = (-62 - 1) = -63.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C * D)) - ((E - F) + (G - H))) = (((-17 * -12) + (5 * -42)) - ((69 - -22) + (-386 - -63))) = ((204 + (5 * -42)) - ((69 - -22) + (-386 - -63))) = ((204 + -210) - ((69 - -22) + (-386 - -63))) = ((204 + -210) - (91 + (-386 - -63))) = ((204 + -210) - (91 + -323)) = (-6 - (91 + -323)) = (-6 - -232) = 226.\n(Final response) So the answer is 226.", "correct_answer": "226", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 334, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 - 3 - -2 * 2) * (2 - -8 + -9 * -8)) * ((-2 * 5 - -8 + 7) * (-4 + -6 * -3 * 4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-2 - 3 - -2 * 2), B = (2 - -8 + -9 * -8), C = (-2 * 5 - -8 + 7) and D = (-4 + -6 * -3 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - 3 - -2 * 2) = ((-2 - 3) - (-2 * 2)) = (-5 - (-2 * 2)) = (-5 - -4) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -8 + -9 * -8) = ((2 - -8) + (-9 * -8)) = (10 + (-9 * -8)) = (10 + 72) = 82.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 * 5 - -8 + 7) = (((-2 * 5) - -8) + 7) = ((-10 - -8) + 7) = (-2 + 7) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + -6 * -3 * 4) = (-4 + ((-6 * -3) * 4)) = (-4 + (18 * 4)) = (-4 + 72) = 68.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((-1 * 82) * (5 * 68)) = (-82 * (5 * 68)) = (-82 * 340) = -27880.\n(Final response) So the answer is -27880.", "correct_answer": "-27880", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 162, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 - 7 - -9 - 5) - (4 * 4 + -5 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-7 - 7 - -9 - 5) and B = (4 * 4 + -5 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - 7 - -9 - 5) = (((-7 - 7) - -9) - 5) = ((-14 - -9) - 5) = (-5 - 5) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 4 + -5 - 7) = (((4 * 4) + -5) - 7) = ((16 + -5) - 7) = (11 - 7) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-10 - 4) = -14.\n(Final response) So the answer is -14.", "correct_answer": "-14", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 252, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((5 - 4 + 5 - -8 - 2 + 2) + (1 - -6 * -5 - 7 * 2 * -3)) * ((-7 + -5 + -7 + -1 * -1 + -5) * (-4 * 2 * 9 * -2 * 4 * 2))) * (((-4 - 5 - 6 * -3 + 4 + 7) + (2 * -4 - -3 - -2 * -5 + 5)) + ((2 * 1 + -4 - 2 * 1 * -9) * (2 * 5 + 8 - -3 * -5 - -4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G * H)))\", where A = (5 - 4 + 5 - -8 - 2 + 2), B = (1 - -6 * -5 - 7 * 2 * -3), C = (-7 + -5 + -7 + -1 * -1 + -5), D = (-4 * 2 * 9 * -2 * 4 * 2), E = (-4 - 5 - 6 * -3 + 4 + 7), F = (2 * -4 - -3 - -2 * -5 + 5), G = (2 * 1 + -4 - 2 * 1 * -9) and H = (2 * 5 + 8 - -3 * -5 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - 4 + 5 - -8 - 2 + 2) = (((((5 - 4) + 5) - -8) - 2) + 2) = ((((1 + 5) - -8) - 2) + 2) = (((6 - -8) - 2) + 2) = ((14 - 2) + 2) = (12 + 2) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - -6 * -5 - 7 * 2 * -3) = ((1 - (-6 * -5)) - ((7 * 2) * -3)) = ((1 - 30) - ((7 * 2) * -3)) = ((1 - 30) - (14 * -3)) = (-29 - (14 * -3)) = (-29 - -42) = 13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + -5 + -7 + -1 * -1 + -5) = ((((-7 + -5) + -7) + (-1 * -1)) + -5) = (((-12 + -7) + (-1 * -1)) + -5) = (((-12 + -7) + 1) + -5) = ((-19 + 1) + -5) = (-18 + -5) = -23.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * 2 * 9 * -2 * 4 * 2) = (((((-4 * 2) * 9) * -2) * 4) * 2) = ((((-8 * 9) * -2) * 4) * 2) = (((-72 * -2) * 4) * 2) = ((144 * 4) * 2) = (576 * 2) = 1152.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-4 - 5 - 6 * -3 + 4 + 7) = ((((-4 - 5) - (6 * -3)) + 4) + 7) = (((-9 - (6 * -3)) + 4) + 7) = (((-9 - -18) + 4) + 7) = ((9 + 4) + 7) = (13 + 7) = 20.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (2 * -4 - -3 - -2 * -5 + 5) = ((((2 * -4) - -3) - (-2 * -5)) + 5) = (((-8 - -3) - (-2 * -5)) + 5) = (((-8 - -3) - 10) + 5) = ((-5 - 10) + 5) = (-15 + 5) = -10.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (2 * 1 + -4 - 2 * 1 * -9) = (((2 * 1) + -4) - ((2 * 1) * -9)) = ((2 + -4) - (2 * -9)) = ((2 + -4) - (2 * -9)) = (-2 - (2 * -9)) = (-2 - -18) = 16.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (2 * 5 + 8 - -3 * -5 - -4) = ((((2 * 5) + 8) - (-3 * -5)) - -4) = (((10 + 8) - (-3 * -5)) - -4) = (((10 + 8) - 15) - -4) = ((18 - 15) - -4) = (3 - -4) = 7.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G * H))) = (((14 + 13) * (-23 * 1152)) * ((20 + -10) + (16 * 7))) = ((27 * (-23 * 1152)) * ((20 + -10) + (16 * 7))) = ((27 * -26496) * ((20 + -10) + (16 * 7))) = ((27 * -26496) * (10 + (16 * 7))) = ((27 * -26496) * (10 + 112)) = (-715392 * (10 + 112)) = (-715392 * 122) = -87277824.\n(Final response) So the answer is -87277824.", "correct_answer": "-87277824", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 352, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * -2 * 5 * 4) * (-2 + 1 + 7 + -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 * -2 * 5 * 4) and B = (-2 + 1 + 7 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * -2 * 5 * 4) = (((5 * -2) * 5) * 4) = ((-10 * 5) * 4) = (-50 * 4) = -200.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 1 + 7 + -2) = (((-2 + 1) + 7) + -2) = ((-1 + 7) + -2) = (6 + -2) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-200 * 4) = -800.\n(Final response) So the answer is -800.", "correct_answer": "-800", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 271, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 * 7 - 2) + (-4 + -8 * 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (4 * 7 - 2) and B = (-4 + -8 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 7 - 2) = ((4 * 7) - 2) = (28 - 2) = 26.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + -8 * 3) = (-4 + (-8 * 3)) = (-4 + -24) = -28.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (26 + -28) = -2.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2.", "correct_answer": "-2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 146, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 * 2 + 1 * -8) - (7 + -9 - 5 * 5)) + ((-8 - -6 - -1 - -8) - (7 + -2 - -8 + 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (6 * 2 + 1 * -8), B = (7 + -9 - 5 * 5), C = (-8 - -6 - -1 - -8) and D = (7 + -2 - -8 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * 2 + 1 * -8) = ((6 * 2) + (1 * -8)) = (12 + (1 * -8)) = (12 + -8) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + -9 - 5 * 5) = ((7 + -9) - (5 * 5)) = (-2 - (5 * 5)) = (-2 - 25) = -27.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 - -6 - -1 - -8) = (((-8 - -6) - -1) - -8) = ((-2 - -1) - -8) = (-1 - -8) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + -2 - -8 + 2) = (((7 + -2) - -8) + 2) = ((5 - -8) + 2) = (13 + 2) = 15.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((4 - -27) + (7 - 15)) = (31 + (7 - 15)) = (31 + -8) = 23.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23.", "correct_answer": "23", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 469, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-8 * 1 - 4 * 6) + (-3 - -2 * 6 - -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-8 * 1 - 4 * 6) and B = (-3 - -2 * 6 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * 1 - 4 * 6) = ((-8 * 1) - (4 * 6)) = (-8 - (4 * 6)) = (-8 - 24) = -32.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 - -2 * 6 - -3) = ((-3 - (-2 * 6)) - -3) = ((-3 - -12) - -3) = (9 - -3) = 12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-32 + 12) = -20.\n(Final response) So the answer is -20.", "correct_answer": "-20", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 58, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-9 - 8 * 9) - (-7 + 0 + 1)) + ((-8 - -2 * -4) + (-9 * 8 - 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-9 - 8 * 9), B = (-7 + 0 + 1), C = (-8 - -2 * -4) and D = (-9 * 8 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 8 * 9) = (-9 - (8 * 9)) = (-9 - 72) = -81.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + 0 + 1) = ((-7 + 0) + 1) = (-7 + 1) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 - -2 * -4) = (-8 - (-2 * -4)) = (-8 - 8) = -16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 * 8 - 2) = ((-9 * 8) - 2) = (-72 - 2) = -74.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C + D)) = ((-81 - -6) + (-16 + -74)) = (-75 + (-16 + -74)) = (-75 + -90) = -165.\n(Final response) So the answer is -165.", "correct_answer": "-165", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 405, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * 9 + -3 - -7) * (-8 * -1 + 2 - 0)) * ((9 + 0 + 5 + -7) - (9 + 0 + 3 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-5 * 9 + -3 - -7), B = (-8 * -1 + 2 - 0), C = (9 + 0 + 5 + -7) and D = (9 + 0 + 3 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 9 + -3 - -7) = (((-5 * 9) + -3) - -7) = ((-45 + -3) - -7) = (-48 - -7) = -41.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * -1 + 2 - 0) = (((-8 * -1) + 2) - 0) = ((8 + 2) - 0) = (10 - 0) = 10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 + 0 + 5 + -7) = (((9 + 0) + 5) + -7) = ((9 + 5) + -7) = (14 + -7) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + 0 + 3 * 0) = ((9 + 0) + (3 * 0)) = (9 + (3 * 0)) = (9 + 0) = 9.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C - D)) = ((-41 * 10) * (7 - 9)) = (-410 * (7 - 9)) = (-410 * -2) = 820.\n(Final response) So the answer is 820.", "correct_answer": "820", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 511, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * 4 - 7 - -4 * -4) * (8 + -4 - -2 * 5 * -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (7 * 4 - 7 - -4 * -4) and B = (8 + -4 - -2 * 5 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * 4 - 7 - -4 * -4) = (((7 * 4) - 7) - (-4 * -4)) = ((28 - 7) - (-4 * -4)) = ((28 - 7) - 16) = (21 - 16) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 + -4 - -2 * 5 * -9) = ((8 + -4) - ((-2 * 5) * -9)) = (4 - ((-2 * 5) * -9)) = (4 - (-10 * -9)) = (4 - 90) = -86.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (5 * -86) = -430.\n(Final response) So the answer is -430.", "correct_answer": "-430", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 71, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 * -4 + 7 * -7) + (-6 - -5 + 0 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-1 * -4 + 7 * -7) and B = (-6 - -5 + 0 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * -4 + 7 * -7) = ((-1 * -4) + (7 * -7)) = (4 + (7 * -7)) = (4 + -49) = -45.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - -5 + 0 - 3) = (((-6 - -5) + 0) - 3) = ((-1 + 0) - 3) = (-1 - 3) = -4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-45 + -4) = -49.\n(Final response) So the answer is -49.", "correct_answer": "-49", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 217, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + -8 * 4) + (-5 * 9 - 4)) * ((-5 + -8 - -1) * (0 - 8 - 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (7 + -8 * 4), B = (-5 * 9 - 4), C = (-5 + -8 - -1) and D = (0 - 8 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -8 * 4) = (7 + (-8 * 4)) = (7 + -32) = -25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 9 - 4) = ((-5 * 9) - 4) = (-45 - 4) = -49.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 + -8 - -1) = ((-5 + -8) - -1) = (-13 - -1) = -12.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 - 8 - 7) = ((0 - 8) - 7) = (-8 - 7) = -15.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((-25 + -49) * (-12 * -15)) = (-74 * (-12 * -15)) = (-74 * 180) = -13320.\n(Final response) So the answer is -13320.", "correct_answer": "-13320", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 322, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + 4 + -3) + (-6 - 0 * 2)) + ((-7 * 2 - 5) - (-9 * 1 + -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (1 + 4 + -3), B = (-6 - 0 * 2), C = (-7 * 2 - 5) and D = (-9 * 1 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + 4 + -3) = ((1 + 4) + -3) = (5 + -3) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - 0 * 2) = (-6 - (0 * 2)) = (-6 - 0) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * 2 - 5) = ((-7 * 2) - 5) = (-14 - 5) = -19.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 * 1 + -3) = ((-9 * 1) + -3) = (-9 + -3) = -12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((2 + -6) + (-19 - -12)) = (-4 + (-19 - -12)) = (-4 + -7) = -11.\n(Final response) So the answer is -11.", "correct_answer": "-11", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 135, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 - -4 * -8 - 4) - (-4 + 9 * 4 - 3)) * ((-5 + -4 - 9 * 6) + (2 + -8 - 5 * 7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (3 - -4 * -8 - 4), B = (-4 + 9 * 4 - 3), C = (-5 + -4 - 9 * 6) and D = (2 + -8 - 5 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - -4 * -8 - 4) = ((3 - (-4 * -8)) - 4) = ((3 - 32) - 4) = (-29 - 4) = -33.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + 9 * 4 - 3) = ((-4 + (9 * 4)) - 3) = ((-4 + 36) - 3) = (32 - 3) = 29.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 + -4 - 9 * 6) = ((-5 + -4) - (9 * 6)) = (-9 - (9 * 6)) = (-9 - 54) = -63.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 + -8 - 5 * 7) = ((2 + -8) - (5 * 7)) = (-6 - (5 * 7)) = (-6 - 35) = -41.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((-33 - 29) * (-63 + -41)) = (-62 * (-63 + -41)) = (-62 * -104) = 6448.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6448.", "correct_answer": "6448", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 580, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + -6 + -5 + -3) - (7 * -5 * 2 + -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (5 + -6 + -5 + -3) and B = (7 * -5 * 2 + -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + -6 + -5 + -3) = (((5 + -6) + -5) + -3) = ((-1 + -5) + -3) = (-6 + -3) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * -5 * 2 + -3) = (((7 * -5) * 2) + -3) = ((-35 * 2) + -3) = (-70 + -3) = -73.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-9 - -73) = 64.\n(Final response) So the answer is 64.", "correct_answer": "64", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 216, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((1 * 9 * 6) * (1 - 6 + -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (1 * 9 * 6) and B = (1 - 6 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * 9 * 6) = ((1 * 9) * 6) = (9 * 6) = 54.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - 6 + -7) = ((1 - 6) + -7) = (-5 + -7) = -12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (54 * -12) = -648.\n(Final response) So the answer is -648.", "correct_answer": "-648", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 67, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 - 3 * -8 + 1) - (-6 - 5 + -3 * 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-6 - 3 * -8 + 1) and B = (-6 - 5 + -3 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 3 * -8 + 1) = ((-6 - (3 * -8)) + 1) = ((-6 - -24) + 1) = (18 + 1) = 19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - 5 + -3 * 9) = ((-6 - 5) + (-3 * 9)) = (-11 + (-3 * 9)) = (-11 + -27) = -38.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (19 - -38) = 57.\n(Final response) So the answer is 57.", "correct_answer": "57", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 274, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 + 9 - 2) + (8 * -8 * 0)) * ((-7 + 2 - 6) + (1 - -7 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-8 + 9 - 2), B = (8 * -8 * 0), C = (-7 + 2 - 6) and D = (1 - -7 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + 9 - 2) = ((-8 + 9) - 2) = (1 - 2) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * -8 * 0) = ((8 * -8) * 0) = (-64 * 0) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + 2 - 6) = ((-7 + 2) - 6) = (-5 - 6) = -11.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 - -7 * -1) = (1 - (-7 * -1)) = (1 - 7) = -6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-1 + 0) * (-11 + -6)) = (-1 * (-11 + -6)) = (-1 * -17) = 17.\n(Final response) So the answer is 17.", "correct_answer": "17", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 410, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - -3 + -9) - (-6 * -6 + -4)) * ((-4 + -3 + -6) + (-4 + 3 * -6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C + D))\", where A = (6 - -3 + -9), B = (-6 * -6 + -4), C = (-4 + -3 + -6) and D = (-4 + 3 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -3 + -9) = ((6 - -3) + -9) = (9 + -9) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * -6 + -4) = ((-6 * -6) + -4) = (36 + -4) = 32.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + -3 + -6) = ((-4 + -3) + -6) = (-7 + -6) = -13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + 3 * -6) = (-4 + (3 * -6)) = (-4 + -18) = -22.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C + D)) = ((0 - 32) * (-13 + -22)) = (-32 * (-13 + -22)) = (-32 * -35) = 1120.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1120.", "correct_answer": "1120", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 323, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 + -9 - 7 * -2 - 6 + -4) - (-8 + -6 * 9 + -9 - 7 - -7)) + ((2 + -5 - -4 + 6 - 3 + 1) - (4 * -5 - 0 + 5 * -7 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (0 + -9 - 7 * -2 - 6 + -4), B = (-8 + -6 * 9 + -9 - 7 - -7), C = (2 + -5 - -4 + 6 - 3 + 1) and D = (4 * -5 - 0 + 5 * -7 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + -9 - 7 * -2 - 6 + -4) = ((((0 + -9) - (7 * -2)) - 6) + -4) = (((-9 - (7 * -2)) - 6) + -4) = (((-9 - -14) - 6) + -4) = ((5 - 6) + -4) = (-1 + -4) = -5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + -6 * 9 + -9 - 7 - -7) = ((((-8 + (-6 * 9)) + -9) - 7) - -7) = ((((-8 + -54) + -9) - 7) - -7) = (((-62 + -9) - 7) - -7) = ((-71 - 7) - -7) = (-78 - -7) = -71.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + -5 - -4 + 6 - 3 + 1) = (((((2 + -5) - -4) + 6) - 3) + 1) = ((((-3 - -4) + 6) - 3) + 1) = (((1 + 6) - 3) + 1) = ((7 - 3) + 1) = (4 + 1) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * -5 - 0 + 5 * -7 * -1) = (((4 * -5) - 0) + ((5 * -7) * -1)) = ((-20 - 0) + ((5 * -7) * -1)) = ((-20 - 0) + (-35 * -1)) = (-20 + (-35 * -1)) = (-20 + 35) = 15.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-5 - -71) + (5 - 15)) = (66 + (5 - 15)) = (66 + -10) = 56.\n(Final response) So the answer is 56.", "correct_answer": "56", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 224, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 + 8 + 4 - -6 - 6 + 6) + (6 + 6 * -9 + -3 - -9 + 9)) + ((-8 + 7 * -4 * -4 * 3 * 8) + (-3 - -1 * 7 - -5 - 0 - -5))) * (((2 - 2 - -2 - 6 * 2 * 7) + (-5 * -2 + -5 * -3 * -2 - -7)) * ((6 * -8 - 7 * 4 + -3 * 2) - (8 - 3 - 0 + 9 - 3 * 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C + D)) * ((E + F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (2 + 8 + 4 - -6 - 6 + 6), B = (6 + 6 * -9 + -3 - -9 + 9), C = (-8 + 7 * -4 * -4 * 3 * 8), D = (-3 - -1 * 7 - -5 - 0 - -5), E = (2 - 2 - -2 - 6 * 2 * 7), F = (-5 * -2 + -5 * -3 * -2 - -7), G = (6 * -8 - 7 * 4 + -3 * 2) and H = (8 - 3 - 0 + 9 - 3 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + 8 + 4 - -6 - 6 + 6) = (((((2 + 8) + 4) - -6) - 6) + 6) = ((((10 + 4) - -6) - 6) + 6) = (((14 - -6) - 6) + 6) = ((20 - 6) + 6) = (14 + 6) = 20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 6 * -9 + -3 - -9 + 9) = ((((6 + (6 * -9)) + -3) - -9) + 9) = ((((6 + -54) + -3) - -9) + 9) = (((-48 + -3) - -9) + 9) = ((-51 - -9) + 9) = (-42 + 9) = -33.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 + 7 * -4 * -4 * 3 * 8) = (-8 + ((((7 * -4) * -4) * 3) * 8)) = (-8 + (((-28 * -4) * 3) * 8)) = (-8 + ((112 * 3) * 8)) = (-8 + (336 * 8)) = (-8 + 2688) = 2680.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 - -1 * 7 - -5 - 0 - -5) = ((((-3 - (-1 * 7)) - -5) - 0) - -5) = ((((-3 - -7) - -5) - 0) - -5) = (((4 - -5) - 0) - -5) = ((9 - 0) - -5) = (9 - -5) = 14.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (2 - 2 - -2 - 6 * 2 * 7) = (((2 - 2) - -2) - ((6 * 2) * 7)) = ((0 - -2) - ((6 * 2) * 7)) = ((0 - -2) - (12 * 7)) = (2 - (12 * 7)) = (2 - 84) = -82.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-5 * -2 + -5 * -3 * -2 - -7) = (((-5 * -2) + ((-5 * -3) * -2)) - -7) = ((10 + ((-5 * -3) * -2)) - -7) = ((10 + (15 * -2)) - -7) = ((10 + -30) - -7) = (-20 - -7) = -13.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (6 * -8 - 7 * 4 + -3 * 2) = (((6 * -8) - (7 * 4)) + (-3 * 2)) = ((-48 - (7 * 4)) + (-3 * 2)) = ((-48 - 28) + (-3 * 2)) = ((-48 - 28) + -6) = (-76 + -6) = -82.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 - 3 - 0 + 9 - 3 * 3) = ((((8 - 3) - 0) + 9) - (3 * 3)) = (((5 - 0) + 9) - (3 * 3)) = (((5 - 0) + 9) - 9) = ((5 + 9) - 9) = (14 - 9) = 5.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C + D)) * ((E + F) * (G - H))) = (((20 + -33) + (2680 + 14)) * ((-82 + -13) * (-82 - 5))) = ((-13 + (2680 + 14)) * ((-82 + -13) * (-82 - 5))) = ((-13 + 2694) * ((-82 + -13) * (-82 - 5))) = ((-13 + 2694) * (-95 * (-82 - 5))) = ((-13 + 2694) * (-95 * -87)) = (2681 * (-95 * -87)) = (2681 * 8265) = 22158465.\n(Final response) So the answer is 22158465.", "correct_answer": "22158465", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 342, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 * -8 * 1 - -5) - (0 - -7 - 7 + 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-4 * -8 * 1 - -5) and B = (0 - -7 - 7 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -8 * 1 - -5) = (((-4 * -8) * 1) - -5) = ((32 * 1) - -5) = (32 - -5) = 37.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 - -7 - 7 + 0) = (((0 - -7) - 7) + 0) = ((7 - 7) + 0) = (0 + 0) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (37 - 0) = 37.\n(Final response) So the answer is 37.", "correct_answer": "37", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 234, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 * -4 - 9) + (5 + -8 - 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (4 * -4 - 9) and B = (5 + -8 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * -4 - 9) = ((4 * -4) - 9) = (-16 - 9) = -25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + -8 - 8) = ((5 + -8) - 8) = (-3 - 8) = -11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-25 + -11) = -36.\n(Final response) So the answer is -36.", "correct_answer": "-36", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 57, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - -8 + -1 * -4 + -3) * (-8 - 0 + 6 - -9 + 0)) + ((6 * -6 * 3 + 5 + 0) - (1 + -9 + -6 - 0 - 5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (1 - -8 + -1 * -4 + -3), B = (-8 - 0 + 6 - -9 + 0), C = (6 * -6 * 3 + 5 + 0) and D = (1 + -9 + -6 - 0 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - -8 + -1 * -4 + -3) = (((1 - -8) + (-1 * -4)) + -3) = ((9 + (-1 * -4)) + -3) = ((9 + 4) + -3) = (13 + -3) = 10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 - 0 + 6 - -9 + 0) = ((((-8 - 0) + 6) - -9) + 0) = (((-8 + 6) - -9) + 0) = ((-2 - -9) + 0) = (7 + 0) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 * -6 * 3 + 5 + 0) = ((((6 * -6) * 3) + 5) + 0) = (((-36 * 3) + 5) + 0) = ((-108 + 5) + 0) = (-103 + 0) = -103.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + -9 + -6 - 0 - 5) = ((((1 + -9) + -6) - 0) - 5) = (((-8 + -6) - 0) - 5) = ((-14 - 0) - 5) = (-14 - 5) = -19.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((10 * 7) + (-103 - -19)) = (70 + (-103 - -19)) = (70 + -84) = -14.\n(Final response) So the answer is -14.", "correct_answer": "-14", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 194, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 - -9 * -9 - -9 + -6) + (2 * -6 - 0 * -4 - 2)) * ((5 - 1 + 4 - -4 - 7) * (0 + 0 - 7 + 5 * -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-7 - -9 * -9 - -9 + -6), B = (2 * -6 - 0 * -4 - 2), C = (5 - 1 + 4 - -4 - 7) and D = (0 + 0 - 7 + 5 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - -9 * -9 - -9 + -6) = (((-7 - (-9 * -9)) - -9) + -6) = (((-7 - 81) - -9) + -6) = ((-88 - -9) + -6) = (-79 + -6) = -85.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * -6 - 0 * -4 - 2) = (((2 * -6) - (0 * -4)) - 2) = ((-12 - (0 * -4)) - 2) = ((-12 - 0) - 2) = (-12 - 2) = -14.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 - 1 + 4 - -4 - 7) = ((((5 - 1) + 4) - -4) - 7) = (((4 + 4) - -4) - 7) = ((8 - -4) - 7) = (12 - 7) = 5.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (0 + 0 - 7 + 5 * -8) = (((0 + 0) - 7) + (5 * -8)) = ((0 - 7) + (5 * -8)) = ((0 - 7) + -40) = (-7 + -40) = -47.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((-85 + -14) * (5 * -47)) = (-99 * (5 * -47)) = (-99 * -235) = 23265.\n(Final response) So the answer is 23265.", "correct_answer": "23265", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 186, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + -2 - 0) - (-1 + -8 * -8)) - ((2 - 9 * 9) - (6 - 1 + -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (7 + -2 - 0), B = (-1 + -8 * -8), C = (2 - 9 * 9) and D = (6 - 1 + -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + -2 - 0) = ((7 + -2) - 0) = (5 - 0) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -8 * -8) = (-1 + (-8 * -8)) = (-1 + 64) = 63.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - 9 * 9) = (2 - (9 * 9)) = (2 - 81) = -79.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 - 1 + -4) = ((6 - 1) + -4) = (5 + -4) = 1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((5 - 63) - (-79 - 1)) = (-58 - (-79 - 1)) = (-58 - -80) = 22.\n(Final response) So the answer is 22.", "correct_answer": "22", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 332, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 - 7 + 9 - -5 - 2 * 6) + (-1 + -7 * -1 - 9 + 4 * -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (6 - 7 + 9 - -5 - 2 * 6) and B = (-1 + -7 * -1 - 9 + 4 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - 7 + 9 - -5 - 2 * 6) = ((((6 - 7) + 9) - -5) - (2 * 6)) = (((-1 + 9) - -5) - (2 * 6)) = (((-1 + 9) - -5) - 12) = ((8 - -5) - 12) = (13 - 12) = 1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -7 * -1 - 9 + 4 * -3) = (((-1 + (-7 * -1)) - 9) + (4 * -3)) = (((-1 + 7) - 9) + (4 * -3)) = (((-1 + 7) - 9) + -12) = ((6 - 9) + -12) = (-3 + -12) = -15.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (1 + -15) = -14.\n(Final response) So the answer is -14.", "correct_answer": "-14", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 101, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 * 4 - 7 * 5) * (-7 * 6 + 0 * -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-4 * 4 - 7 * 5) and B = (-7 * 6 + 0 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * 4 - 7 * 5) = ((-4 * 4) - (7 * 5)) = (-16 - (7 * 5)) = (-16 - 35) = -51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 6 + 0 * -6) = ((-7 * 6) + (0 * -6)) = (-42 + (0 * -6)) = (-42 + 0) = -42.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-51 * -42) = 2142.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2142.", "correct_answer": "2142", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 224, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + -7 * 2 * -3) + (8 - 5 - -1 * 6)) * ((-5 * -8 - -6 * -1) - (2 + 9 - -9 - 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C - D))\", where A = (1 + -7 * 2 * -3), B = (8 - 5 - -1 * 6), C = (-5 * -8 - -6 * -1) and D = (2 + 9 - -9 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + -7 * 2 * -3) = (1 + ((-7 * 2) * -3)) = (1 + (-14 * -3)) = (1 + 42) = 43.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - 5 - -1 * 6) = ((8 - 5) - (-1 * 6)) = (3 - (-1 * 6)) = (3 - -6) = 9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 * -8 - -6 * -1) = ((-5 * -8) - (-6 * -1)) = (40 - (-6 * -1)) = (40 - 6) = 34.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 + 9 - -9 - 0) = (((2 + 9) - -9) - 0) = ((11 - -9) - 0) = (20 - 0) = 20.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C - D)) = ((43 + 9) * (34 - 20)) = (52 * (34 - 20)) = (52 * 14) = 728.\n(Final response) So the answer is 728.", "correct_answer": "728", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 570, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 - -1 - 3 * -6 - -6 + 0) - (-1 - -9 + 8 * -8 * 4 - 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-7 - -1 - 3 * -6 - -6 + 0) and B = (-1 - -9 + 8 * -8 * 4 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - -1 - 3 * -6 - -6 + 0) = ((((-7 - -1) - (3 * -6)) - -6) + 0) = (((-6 - (3 * -6)) - -6) + 0) = (((-6 - -18) - -6) + 0) = ((12 - -6) + 0) = (18 + 0) = 18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - -9 + 8 * -8 * 4 - 5) = (((-1 - -9) + ((8 * -8) * 4)) - 5) = ((8 + ((8 * -8) * 4)) - 5) = ((8 + (-64 * 4)) - 5) = ((8 + -256) - 5) = (-248 - 5) = -253.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (18 - -253) = 271.\n(Final response) So the answer is 271.", "correct_answer": "271", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 104, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 - 6 + -6 * 2) * (-7 * 4 + 9 - -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 - 6 + -6 * 2) and B = (-7 * 4 + 9 - -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - 6 + -6 * 2) = ((5 - 6) + (-6 * 2)) = (-1 + (-6 * 2)) = (-1 + -12) = -13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 4 + 9 - -6) = (((-7 * 4) + 9) - -6) = ((-28 + 9) - -6) = (-19 - -6) = -13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-13 * -13) = 169.\n(Final response) So the answer is 169.", "correct_answer": "169", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 55, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 + 0 * -3 * 0) - (-7 + 9 * -8 * 0)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 + 0 * -3 * 0) and B = (-7 + 9 * -8 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + 0 * -3 * 0) = (0 + ((0 * -3) * 0)) = (0 + (0 * 0)) = (0 + 0) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + 9 * -8 * 0) = (-7 + ((9 * -8) * 0)) = (-7 + (-72 * 0)) = (-7 + 0) = -7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (0 - -7) = 7.\n(Final response) So the answer is 7.", "correct_answer": "7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 276, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 - -9 - -6) + (-5 * 0 - -3)) - ((1 + 5 + 8) * (-2 - 1 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-4 - -9 - -6), B = (-5 * 0 - -3), C = (1 + 5 + 8) and D = (-2 - 1 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - -9 - -6) = ((-4 - -9) - -6) = (5 - -6) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 0 - -3) = ((-5 * 0) - -3) = (0 - -3) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (1 + 5 + 8) = ((1 + 5) + 8) = (6 + 8) = 14.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - 1 + -1) = ((-2 - 1) + -1) = (-3 + -1) = -4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((11 + 3) - (14 * -4)) = (14 - (14 * -4)) = (14 - -56) = 70.\n(Final response) So the answer is 70.", "correct_answer": "70", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 388, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 - 8 + 6 - -6) - (-6 - 1 + -2 + 6)) - ((-1 * -8 + 3 - -6) - (1 - -7 + -3 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (1 - 8 + 6 - -6), B = (-6 - 1 + -2 + 6), C = (-1 * -8 + 3 - -6) and D = (1 - -7 + -3 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - 8 + 6 - -6) = (((1 - 8) + 6) - -6) = ((-7 + 6) - -6) = (-1 - -6) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 - 1 + -2 + 6) = (((-6 - 1) + -2) + 6) = ((-7 + -2) + 6) = (-9 + 6) = -3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * -8 + 3 - -6) = (((-1 * -8) + 3) - -6) = ((8 + 3) - -6) = (11 - -6) = 17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 - -7 + -3 * 2) = ((1 - -7) + (-3 * 2)) = (8 + (-3 * 2)) = (8 + -6) = 2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((5 - -3) - (17 - 2)) = (8 - (17 - 2)) = (8 - 15) = -7.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7.", "correct_answer": "-7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 473, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 - 7 - -5 + 1) - (-9 - -4 * -8 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (4 - 7 - -5 + 1) and B = (-9 - -4 * -8 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - 7 - -5 + 1) = (((4 - 7) - -5) + 1) = ((-3 - -5) + 1) = (2 + 1) = 3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - -4 * -8 * 4) = (-9 - ((-4 * -8) * 4)) = (-9 - (32 * 4)) = (-9 - 128) = -137.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (3 - -137) = 140.\n(Final response) So the answer is 140.", "correct_answer": "140", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 167, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((3 * 7 + 2 + -5 * -1 + 3) - (2 * 8 * -2 * -4 - 1 + -3)) * ((6 - 3 * 8 - 8 - 9 * -5) - (9 * -3 * 3 + -8 * -8 + 1))) + (((-4 + 6 * -1 + 4 + 0 + -8) * (-7 * 9 * 8 - 7 * -8 - 5)) - ((7 - 5 - -7 - 9 - -1 * 5) + (-4 - -9 * -4 * 3 + 2 + 6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C - D)) + ((E * F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (3 * 7 + 2 + -5 * -1 + 3), B = (2 * 8 * -2 * -4 - 1 + -3), C = (6 - 3 * 8 - 8 - 9 * -5), D = (9 * -3 * 3 + -8 * -8 + 1), E = (-4 + 6 * -1 + 4 + 0 + -8), F = (-7 * 9 * 8 - 7 * -8 - 5), G = (7 - 5 - -7 - 9 - -1 * 5) and H = (-4 - -9 * -4 * 3 + 2 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * 7 + 2 + -5 * -1 + 3) = ((((3 * 7) + 2) + (-5 * -1)) + 3) = (((21 + 2) + (-5 * -1)) + 3) = (((21 + 2) + 5) + 3) = ((23 + 5) + 3) = (28 + 3) = 31.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 * 8 * -2 * -4 - 1 + -3) = (((((2 * 8) * -2) * -4) - 1) + -3) = ((((16 * -2) * -4) - 1) + -3) = (((-32 * -4) - 1) + -3) = ((128 - 1) + -3) = (127 + -3) = 124.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 3 * 8 - 8 - 9 * -5) = (((6 - (3 * 8)) - 8) - (9 * -5)) = (((6 - 24) - 8) - (9 * -5)) = (((6 - 24) - 8) - -45) = ((-18 - 8) - -45) = (-26 - -45) = 19.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 * -3 * 3 + -8 * -8 + 1) = ((((9 * -3) * 3) + (-8 * -8)) + 1) = (((-27 * 3) + (-8 * -8)) + 1) = (((-27 * 3) + 64) + 1) = ((-81 + 64) + 1) = (-17 + 1) = -16.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-4 + 6 * -1 + 4 + 0 + -8) = ((((-4 + (6 * -1)) + 4) + 0) + -8) = ((((-4 + -6) + 4) + 0) + -8) = (((-10 + 4) + 0) + -8) = ((-6 + 0) + -8) = (-6 + -8) = -14.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-7 * 9 * 8 - 7 * -8 - 5) = ((((-7 * 9) * 8) - (7 * -8)) - 5) = (((-63 * 8) - (7 * -8)) - 5) = (((-63 * 8) - -56) - 5) = ((-504 - -56) - 5) = (-448 - 5) = -453.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 - 5 - -7 - 9 - -1 * 5) = ((((7 - 5) - -7) - 9) - (-1 * 5)) = (((2 - -7) - 9) - (-1 * 5)) = (((2 - -7) - 9) - -5) = ((9 - 9) - -5) = (0 - -5) = 5.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-4 - -9 * -4 * 3 + 2 + 6) = (((-4 - ((-9 * -4) * 3)) + 2) + 6) = (((-4 - (36 * 3)) + 2) + 6) = (((-4 - 108) + 2) + 6) = ((-112 + 2) + 6) = (-110 + 6) = -104.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C - D)) + ((E * F) - (G + H))) = (((31 - 124) * (19 - -16)) + ((-14 * -453) - (5 + -104))) = ((-93 * (19 - -16)) + ((-14 * -453) - (5 + -104))) = ((-93 * 35) + ((-14 * -453) - (5 + -104))) = ((-93 * 35) + (6342 - (5 + -104))) = ((-93 * 35) + (6342 - -99)) = (-3255 + (6342 - -99)) = (-3255 + 6441) = 3186.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3186.", "correct_answer": "3186", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 354, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 * -3 + -6) + (-2 - -3 * 7)) + ((4 - 3 * -1) * (3 * 3 + 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (6 * -3 + -6), B = (-2 - -3 * 7), C = (4 - 3 * -1) and D = (3 * 3 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * -3 + -6) = ((6 * -3) + -6) = (-18 + -6) = -24.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - -3 * 7) = (-2 - (-3 * 7)) = (-2 - -21) = 19.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 - 3 * -1) = (4 - (3 * -1)) = (4 - -3) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * 3 + 8) = ((3 * 3) + 8) = (9 + 8) = 17.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((-24 + 19) + (7 * 17)) = (-5 + (7 * 17)) = (-5 + 119) = 114.\n(Final response) So the answer is 114.", "correct_answer": "114", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 146, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * -5 - 2 + 6) - (-9 - -1 * 5 - 2)) - ((-7 - 6 + 2 - 2) - (3 * 3 + -8 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (3 * -5 - 2 + 6), B = (-9 - -1 * 5 - 2), C = (-7 - 6 + 2 - 2) and D = (3 * 3 + -8 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -5 - 2 + 6) = (((3 * -5) - 2) + 6) = ((-15 - 2) + 6) = (-17 + 6) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 - -1 * 5 - 2) = ((-9 - (-1 * 5)) - 2) = ((-9 - -5) - 2) = (-4 - 2) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 - 6 + 2 - 2) = (((-7 - 6) + 2) - 2) = ((-13 + 2) - 2) = (-11 - 2) = -13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * 3 + -8 * -1) = ((3 * 3) + (-8 * -1)) = (9 + (-8 * -1)) = (9 + 8) = 17.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-11 - -6) - (-13 - 17)) = (-5 - (-13 - 17)) = (-5 - -30) = 25.\n(Final response) So the answer is 25.", "correct_answer": "25", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 546, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 - 3 * 0 * 1) + (-1 + -9 + -8 + -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-9 - 3 * 0 * 1) and B = (-1 + -9 + -8 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 3 * 0 * 1) = (-9 - ((3 * 0) * 1)) = (-9 - (0 * 1)) = (-9 - 0) = -9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -9 + -8 + -1) = (((-1 + -9) + -8) + -1) = ((-10 + -8) + -1) = (-18 + -1) = -19.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-9 + -19) = -28.\n(Final response) So the answer is -28.", "correct_answer": "-28", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 175, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-1 * 6 - -3) + (6 + 1 - 0)) * ((-4 - 8 - -2) + (-6 - 3 * 4))) + (((5 * 4 - 5) - (9 - -4 * 1)) + ((-1 + -1 * 8) - (-6 + 8 - -4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C + D)) + ((E - F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (-1 * 6 - -3), B = (6 + 1 - 0), C = (-4 - 8 - -2), D = (-6 - 3 * 4), E = (5 * 4 - 5), F = (9 - -4 * 1), G = (-1 + -1 * 8) and H = (-6 + 8 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 6 - -3) = ((-1 * 6) - -3) = (-6 - -3) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + 1 - 0) = ((6 + 1) - 0) = (7 - 0) = 7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 - 8 - -2) = ((-4 - 8) - -2) = (-12 - -2) = -10.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 - 3 * 4) = (-6 - (3 * 4)) = (-6 - 12) = -18.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (5 * 4 - 5) = ((5 * 4) - 5) = (20 - 5) = 15.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (9 - -4 * 1) = (9 - (-4 * 1)) = (9 - -4) = 13.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-1 + -1 * 8) = (-1 + (-1 * 8)) = (-1 + -8) = -9.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-6 + 8 - -4) = ((-6 + 8) - -4) = (2 - -4) = 6.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C + D)) + ((E - F) + (G - H))) = (((-3 + 7) * (-10 + -18)) + ((15 - 13) + (-9 - 6))) = ((4 * (-10 + -18)) + ((15 - 13) + (-9 - 6))) = ((4 * -28) + ((15 - 13) + (-9 - 6))) = ((4 * -28) + (2 + (-9 - 6))) = ((4 * -28) + (2 + -15)) = (-112 + (2 + -15)) = (-112 + -13) = -125.\n(Final response) So the answer is -125.", "correct_answer": "-125", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 269, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 * 9 + 1) + (-3 + 5 + 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-1 * 9 + 1) and B = (-3 + 5 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 * 9 + 1) = ((-1 * 9) + 1) = (-9 + 1) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 5 + 2) = ((-3 + 5) + 2) = (2 + 2) = 4.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-8 + 4) = -4.\n(Final response) So the answer is -4.", "correct_answer": "-4", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 23, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 * 9 * -5) - (-3 + 7 * 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-4 * 9 * -5) and B = (-3 + 7 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * 9 * -5) = ((-4 * 9) * -5) = (-36 * -5) = 180.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 7 * 2) = (-3 + (7 * 2)) = (-3 + 14) = 11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (180 - 11) = 169.\n(Final response) So the answer is 169.", "correct_answer": "169", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 73, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 + -3 - -1 + 7 * -4) * (-5 - -6 - 0 + 1 * 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (4 + -3 - -1 + 7 * -4) and B = (-5 - -6 - 0 + 1 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -3 - -1 + 7 * -4) = (((4 + -3) - -1) + (7 * -4)) = ((1 - -1) + (7 * -4)) = ((1 - -1) + -28) = (2 + -28) = -26.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 - -6 - 0 + 1 * 6) = (((-5 - -6) - 0) + (1 * 6)) = ((1 - 0) + (1 * 6)) = ((1 - 0) + 6) = (1 + 6) = 7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-26 * 7) = -182.\n(Final response) So the answer is -182.", "correct_answer": "-182", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 63, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 - -8 + -2 * 7 * -1 * 5) + (-1 - 6 * 7 * 3 + 5 * -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (5 - -8 + -2 * 7 * -1 * 5) and B = (-1 - 6 * 7 * 3 + 5 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 - -8 + -2 * 7 * -1 * 5) = ((5 - -8) + (((-2 * 7) * -1) * 5)) = (13 + (((-2 * 7) * -1) * 5)) = (13 + ((-14 * -1) * 5)) = (13 + (14 * 5)) = (13 + 70) = 83.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 6 * 7 * 3 + 5 * -9) = ((-1 - ((6 * 7) * 3)) + (5 * -9)) = ((-1 - (42 * 3)) + (5 * -9)) = ((-1 - (42 * 3)) + -45) = ((-1 - 126) + -45) = (-127 + -45) = -172.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (83 + -172) = -89.\n(Final response) So the answer is -89.", "correct_answer": "-89", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 99, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((2 - -4 + 7 * 0 + 0 + 7) + (-6 * 4 + -2 * 9 + -3 - 0)) + ((7 + 2 - -9 + 8 - -2 + 4) + (-6 + 4 - 3 + 2 + -2 * 5))) + (((-1 - 3 + -1 - 5 * -6 * 5) * (-4 - 0 * -9 + -5 + 3 * 9)) + ((2 * 8 - 2 + 9 + -3 + -4) - (8 + -9 - -1 + 8 + -4 - -4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) + (C + D)) + ((E * F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (2 - -4 + 7 * 0 + 0 + 7), B = (-6 * 4 + -2 * 9 + -3 - 0), C = (7 + 2 - -9 + 8 - -2 + 4), D = (-6 + 4 - 3 + 2 + -2 * 5), E = (-1 - 3 + -1 - 5 * -6 * 5), F = (-4 - 0 * -9 + -5 + 3 * 9), G = (2 * 8 - 2 + 9 + -3 + -4) and H = (8 + -9 - -1 + 8 + -4 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 - -4 + 7 * 0 + 0 + 7) = ((((2 - -4) + (7 * 0)) + 0) + 7) = (((6 + (7 * 0)) + 0) + 7) = (((6 + 0) + 0) + 7) = ((6 + 0) + 7) = (6 + 7) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * 4 + -2 * 9 + -3 - 0) = ((((-6 * 4) + (-2 * 9)) + -3) - 0) = (((-24 + (-2 * 9)) + -3) - 0) = (((-24 + -18) + -3) - 0) = ((-42 + -3) - 0) = (-45 - 0) = -45.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + 2 - -9 + 8 - -2 + 4) = (((((7 + 2) - -9) + 8) - -2) + 4) = ((((9 - -9) + 8) - -2) + 4) = (((18 + 8) - -2) + 4) = ((26 - -2) + 4) = (28 + 4) = 32.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 + 4 - 3 + 2 + -2 * 5) = ((((-6 + 4) - 3) + 2) + (-2 * 5)) = (((-2 - 3) + 2) + (-2 * 5)) = (((-2 - 3) + 2) + -10) = ((-5 + 2) + -10) = (-3 + -10) = -13.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-1 - 3 + -1 - 5 * -6 * 5) = (((-1 - 3) + -1) - ((5 * -6) * 5)) = ((-4 + -1) - ((5 * -6) * 5)) = ((-4 + -1) - (-30 * 5)) = (-5 - (-30 * 5)) = (-5 - -150) = 145.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-4 - 0 * -9 + -5 + 3 * 9) = (((-4 - (0 * -9)) + -5) + (3 * 9)) = (((-4 - 0) + -5) + (3 * 9)) = (((-4 - 0) + -5) + 27) = ((-4 + -5) + 27) = (-9 + 27) = 18.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (2 * 8 - 2 + 9 + -3 + -4) = (((((2 * 8) - 2) + 9) + -3) + -4) = ((((16 - 2) + 9) + -3) + -4) = (((14 + 9) + -3) + -4) = ((23 + -3) + -4) = (20 + -4) = 16.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 + -9 - -1 + 8 + -4 - -4) = (((((8 + -9) - -1) + 8) + -4) - -4) = ((((-1 - -1) + 8) + -4) - -4) = (((0 + 8) + -4) - -4) = ((8 + -4) - -4) = (4 - -4) = 8.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) + (C + D)) + ((E * F) + (G - H))) = (((13 + -45) + (32 + -13)) + ((145 * 18) + (16 - 8))) = ((-32 + (32 + -13)) + ((145 * 18) + (16 - 8))) = ((-32 + 19) + ((145 * 18) + (16 - 8))) = ((-32 + 19) + (2610 + (16 - 8))) = ((-32 + 19) + (2610 + 8)) = (-13 + (2610 + 8)) = (-13 + 2618) = 2605.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2605.", "correct_answer": "2605", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 330, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 * 4 * 3 - -5) * (-4 * -6 - 6 - -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (5 * 4 * 3 - -5) and B = (-4 * -6 - 6 - -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 * 4 * 3 - -5) = (((5 * 4) * 3) - -5) = ((20 * 3) - -5) = (60 - -5) = 65.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * -6 - 6 - -5) = (((-4 * -6) - 6) - -5) = ((24 - 6) - -5) = (18 - -5) = 23.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (65 * 23) = 1495.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1495.", "correct_answer": "1495", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 273, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 * -9 - 7 - 2 - 6) * (0 + 7 * 8 + 6 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (7 * -9 - 7 - 2 - 6) and B = (0 + 7 * 8 + 6 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 * -9 - 7 - 2 - 6) = ((((7 * -9) - 7) - 2) - 6) = (((-63 - 7) - 2) - 6) = ((-70 - 2) - 6) = (-72 - 6) = -78.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + 7 * 8 + 6 * -2) = ((0 + (7 * 8)) + (6 * -2)) = ((0 + 56) + (6 * -2)) = ((0 + 56) + -12) = (56 + -12) = 44.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-78 * 44) = -3432.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3432.", "correct_answer": "-3432", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 86, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 * -2 * 7 + 8) - (3 + 5 + 0 + -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-4 * -2 * 7 + 8) and B = (3 + 5 + 0 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -2 * 7 + 8) = (((-4 * -2) * 7) + 8) = ((8 * 7) + 8) = (56 + 8) = 64.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + 5 + 0 + -7) = (((3 + 5) + 0) + -7) = ((8 + 0) + -7) = (8 + -7) = 1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (64 - 1) = 63.\n(Final response) So the answer is 63.", "correct_answer": "63", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 214, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + 9 + -9) * (-4 - -7 * 6)) - ((7 * 3 * 0) * (-4 + 7 + 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-7 + 9 + -9), B = (-4 - -7 * 6), C = (7 * 3 * 0) and D = (-4 + 7 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 9 + -9) = ((-7 + 9) + -9) = (2 + -9) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - -7 * 6) = (-4 - (-7 * 6)) = (-4 - -42) = 38.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 * 3 * 0) = ((7 * 3) * 0) = (21 * 0) = 0.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + 7 + 2) = ((-4 + 7) + 2) = (3 + 2) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-7 * 38) - (0 * 5)) = (-266 - (0 * 5)) = (-266 - 0) = -266.\n(Final response) So the answer is -266.", "correct_answer": "-266", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 363, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 + 9 * -3) * (5 * -8 * 9)) + ((5 + 5 * 2) * (-3 * 1 + -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-3 + 9 * -3), B = (5 * -8 * 9), C = (5 + 5 * 2) and D = (-3 * 1 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 9 * -3) = (-3 + (9 * -3)) = (-3 + -27) = -30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * -8 * 9) = ((5 * -8) * 9) = (-40 * 9) = -360.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 + 5 * 2) = (5 + (5 * 2)) = (5 + 10) = 15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * 1 + -7) = ((-3 * 1) + -7) = (-3 + -7) = -10.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((-30 * -360) + (15 * -10)) = (10800 + (15 * -10)) = (10800 + -150) = 10650.\n(Final response) So the answer is 10650.", "correct_answer": "10650", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 379, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * 3 + -2 * 1) * (-9 + 5 - 5 * -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 * 3 + -2 * 1) and B = (-9 + 5 - 5 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 3 + -2 * 1) = ((9 * 3) + (-2 * 1)) = (27 + (-2 * 1)) = (27 + -2) = 25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 5 - 5 * -1) = ((-9 + 5) - (5 * -1)) = (-4 - (5 * -1)) = (-4 - -5) = 1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (25 * 1) = 25.\n(Final response) So the answer is 25.", "correct_answer": "25", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 166, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-1 - 3 - 0) + (8 * -8 * -6)) * ((-7 + 0 - -3) * (9 - 4 + 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-1 - 3 - 0), B = (8 * -8 * -6), C = (-7 + 0 - -3) and D = (9 - 4 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 - 3 - 0) = ((-1 - 3) - 0) = (-4 - 0) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * -8 * -6) = ((8 * -8) * -6) = (-64 * -6) = 384.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 + 0 - -3) = ((-7 + 0) - -3) = (-7 - -3) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 - 4 + 1) = ((9 - 4) + 1) = (5 + 1) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((-4 + 384) * (-4 * 6)) = (380 * (-4 * 6)) = (380 * -24) = -9120.\n(Final response) So the answer is -9120.", "correct_answer": "-9120", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 373, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-4 + 8 * -7) * (-7 + -8 * -9)) - ((3 * 1 * 0) * (-1 - 0 * 3))) - (((8 + 8 - 7) + (-5 + 2 + 9)) * ((2 + -2 - 9) + (-7 * 2 + 7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C * D)) - ((E + F) * (G + H)))\", where A = (-4 + 8 * -7), B = (-7 + -8 * -9), C = (3 * 1 * 0), D = (-1 - 0 * 3), E = (8 + 8 - 7), F = (-5 + 2 + 9), G = (2 + -2 - 9) and H = (-7 * 2 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + 8 * -7) = (-4 + (8 * -7)) = (-4 + -56) = -60.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + -8 * -9) = (-7 + (-8 * -9)) = (-7 + 72) = 65.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 * 1 * 0) = ((3 * 1) * 0) = (3 * 0) = 0.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 - 0 * 3) = (-1 - (0 * 3)) = (-1 - 0) = -1.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (8 + 8 - 7) = ((8 + 8) - 7) = (16 - 7) = 9.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-5 + 2 + 9) = ((-5 + 2) + 9) = (-3 + 9) = 6.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (2 + -2 - 9) = ((2 + -2) - 9) = (0 - 9) = -9.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-7 * 2 + 7) = ((-7 * 2) + 7) = (-14 + 7) = -7.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C * D)) - ((E + F) * (G + H))) = (((-60 * 65) - (0 * -1)) - ((9 + 6) * (-9 + -7))) = ((-3900 - (0 * -1)) - ((9 + 6) * (-9 + -7))) = ((-3900 - 0) - ((9 + 6) * (-9 + -7))) = ((-3900 - 0) - (15 * (-9 + -7))) = ((-3900 - 0) - (15 * -16)) = (-3900 - (15 * -16)) = (-3900 - -240) = -3660.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3660.", "correct_answer": "-3660", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 254, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 - 8 + -1 * 5) * (-2 + 3 + -6 + 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (0 - 8 + -1 * 5) and B = (-2 + 3 + -6 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - 8 + -1 * 5) = ((0 - 8) + (-1 * 5)) = (-8 + (-1 * 5)) = (-8 + -5) = -13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 3 + -6 + 6) = (((-2 + 3) + -6) + 6) = ((1 + -6) + 6) = (-5 + 6) = 1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-13 * 1) = -13.\n(Final response) So the answer is -13.", "correct_answer": "-13", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 50, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 + 5 + -6 + -3) * (-6 + 5 - -5 * 7)) * ((-2 + 0 * -9 * -2) * (2 - 0 + -3 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (6 + 5 + -6 + -3), B = (-6 + 5 - -5 * 7), C = (-2 + 0 * -9 * -2) and D = (2 - 0 + -3 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 + 5 + -6 + -3) = (((6 + 5) + -6) + -3) = ((11 + -6) + -3) = (5 + -3) = 2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + 5 - -5 * 7) = ((-6 + 5) - (-5 * 7)) = (-1 - (-5 * 7)) = (-1 - -35) = 34.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + 0 * -9 * -2) = (-2 + ((0 * -9) * -2)) = (-2 + (0 * -2)) = (-2 + 0) = -2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 - 0 + -3 * -1) = ((2 - 0) + (-3 * -1)) = (2 + (-3 * -1)) = (2 + 3) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((2 * 34) * (-2 * 5)) = (68 * (-2 * 5)) = (68 * -10) = -680.\n(Final response) So the answer is -680.", "correct_answer": "-680", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 464, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((0 + -1 - 2 + 3 * 0) - (5 - 7 * -8 * -2 + 9)) - ((2 - 3 + 3 + -6 * 3) * (-2 * -2 * -2 + -1 + -9))) + (((-1 * 8 * 0 + 2 + 9) * (7 + 9 + -9 * -1 + -6)) * ((-8 - 4 - -9 - 9 + -7) - (-2 - 7 + -3 + 7 + -8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C * D)) + ((E * F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (0 + -1 - 2 + 3 * 0), B = (5 - 7 * -8 * -2 + 9), C = (2 - 3 + 3 + -6 * 3), D = (-2 * -2 * -2 + -1 + -9), E = (-1 * 8 * 0 + 2 + 9), F = (7 + 9 + -9 * -1 + -6), G = (-8 - 4 - -9 - 9 + -7) and H = (-2 - 7 + -3 + 7 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + -1 - 2 + 3 * 0) = (((0 + -1) - 2) + (3 * 0)) = ((-1 - 2) + (3 * 0)) = ((-1 - 2) + 0) = (-3 + 0) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 7 * -8 * -2 + 9) = ((5 - ((7 * -8) * -2)) + 9) = ((5 - (-56 * -2)) + 9) = ((5 - 112) + 9) = (-107 + 9) = -98.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - 3 + 3 + -6 * 3) = (((2 - 3) + 3) + (-6 * 3)) = ((-1 + 3) + (-6 * 3)) = ((-1 + 3) + -18) = (2 + -18) = -16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 * -2 * -2 + -1 + -9) = ((((-2 * -2) * -2) + -1) + -9) = (((4 * -2) + -1) + -9) = ((-8 + -1) + -9) = (-9 + -9) = -18.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-1 * 8 * 0 + 2 + 9) = ((((-1 * 8) * 0) + 2) + 9) = (((-8 * 0) + 2) + 9) = ((0 + 2) + 9) = (2 + 9) = 11.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (7 + 9 + -9 * -1 + -6) = (((7 + 9) + (-9 * -1)) + -6) = ((16 + (-9 * -1)) + -6) = ((16 + 9) + -6) = (25 + -6) = 19.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-8 - 4 - -9 - 9 + -7) = ((((-8 - 4) - -9) - 9) + -7) = (((-12 - -9) - 9) + -7) = ((-3 - 9) + -7) = (-12 + -7) = -19.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-2 - 7 + -3 + 7 + -8) = ((((-2 - 7) + -3) + 7) + -8) = (((-9 + -3) + 7) + -8) = ((-12 + 7) + -8) = (-5 + -8) = -13.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C * D)) + ((E * F) * (G - H))) = (((-3 - -98) - (-16 * -18)) + ((11 * 19) * (-19 - -13))) = ((95 - (-16 * -18)) + ((11 * 19) * (-19 - -13))) = ((95 - 288) + ((11 * 19) * (-19 - -13))) = ((95 - 288) + (209 * (-19 - -13))) = ((95 - 288) + (209 * -6)) = (-193 + (209 * -6)) = (-193 + -1254) = -1447.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1447.", "correct_answer": "-1447", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 314, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((((0 - -3 - -4 * 9 * 3) - (0 + -9 - 6 - -8 - 0)) - ((-7 * -6 + -1 * 8 - 5) - (3 - 4 + -3 - -1 + -5))) + (((-1 * -4 - -4 - 4 - -9) + (3 * -6 * 5 * 7 - 7)) * ((2 * 5 + -4 + -2 - -7) - (9 + 7 - -3 * 1 + 8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C - D)) + ((E + F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (0 - -3 - -4 * 9 * 3), B = (0 + -9 - 6 - -8 - 0), C = (-7 * -6 + -1 * 8 - 5), D = (3 - 4 + -3 - -1 + -5), E = (-1 * -4 - -4 - 4 - -9), F = (3 * -6 * 5 * 7 - 7), G = (2 * 5 + -4 + -2 - -7) and H = (9 + 7 - -3 * 1 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - -3 - -4 * 9 * 3) = ((0 - -3) - ((-4 * 9) * 3)) = (3 - ((-4 * 9) * 3)) = (3 - (-36 * 3)) = (3 - -108) = 111.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -9 - 6 - -8 - 0) = ((((0 + -9) - 6) - -8) - 0) = (((-9 - 6) - -8) - 0) = ((-15 - -8) - 0) = (-7 - 0) = -7.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * -6 + -1 * 8 - 5) = (((-7 * -6) + (-1 * 8)) - 5) = ((42 + (-1 * 8)) - 5) = ((42 + -8) - 5) = (34 - 5) = 29.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 - 4 + -3 - -1 + -5) = ((((3 - 4) + -3) - -1) + -5) = (((-1 + -3) - -1) + -5) = ((-4 - -1) + -5) = (-3 + -5) = -8.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-1 * -4 - -4 - 4 - -9) = ((((-1 * -4) - -4) - 4) - -9) = (((4 - -4) - 4) - -9) = ((8 - 4) - -9) = (4 - -9) = 13.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (3 * -6 * 5 * 7 - 7) = ((((3 * -6) * 5) * 7) - 7) = (((-18 * 5) * 7) - 7) = ((-90 * 7) - 7) = (-630 - 7) = -637.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (2 * 5 + -4 + -2 - -7) = ((((2 * 5) + -4) + -2) - -7) = (((10 + -4) + -2) - -7) = ((6 + -2) - -7) = (4 - -7) = 11.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (9 + 7 - -3 * 1 + 8) = (((9 + 7) - (-3 * 1)) + 8) = ((16 - (-3 * 1)) + 8) = ((16 - -3) + 8) = (19 + 8) = 27.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C - D)) + ((E + F) * (G - H))) = (((111 - -7) - (29 - -8)) + ((13 + -637) * (11 - 27))) = ((118 - (29 - -8)) + ((13 + -637) * (11 - 27))) = ((118 - 37) + ((13 + -637) * (11 - 27))) = ((118 - 37) + (-624 * (11 - 27))) = ((118 - 37) + (-624 * -16)) = (81 + (-624 * -16)) = (81 + 9984) = 10065.\n(Final response) So the answer is 10065.", "correct_answer": "10065", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 307, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 - 1 + 4) * (6 - -3 - -3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (4 - 1 + 4) and B = (6 - -3 - -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - 1 + 4) = ((4 - 1) + 4) = (3 + 4) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - -3 - -3) = ((6 - -3) - -3) = (9 - -3) = 12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (7 * 12) = 84.\n(Final response) So the answer is 84.", "correct_answer": "84", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 103, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-9 - 8 + 4 + 5 + -2 * -2) - (7 + 8 + -7 - 6 * 7 - 4)) * ((4 * 6 - -9 - 0 - 1 * 8) * (4 - -5 * 2 + 6 * 1 + 6))) * (((-2 - -6 * -1 + 3 - -4 * -6) * (2 * -5 + 1 * 4 + 7 * -3)) - ((-7 - 4 + 7 * -8 - 8 + 9) - (9 + 8 * -8 + -5 - 8 * 6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C * D)) * ((E * F) - (G - H)))\", where A = (-9 - 8 + 4 + 5 + -2 * -2), B = (7 + 8 + -7 - 6 * 7 - 4), C = (4 * 6 - -9 - 0 - 1 * 8), D = (4 - -5 * 2 + 6 * 1 + 6), E = (-2 - -6 * -1 + 3 - -4 * -6), F = (2 * -5 + 1 * 4 + 7 * -3), G = (-7 - 4 + 7 * -8 - 8 + 9) and H = (9 + 8 * -8 + -5 - 8 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 - 8 + 4 + 5 + -2 * -2) = ((((-9 - 8) + 4) + 5) + (-2 * -2)) = (((-17 + 4) + 5) + (-2 * -2)) = (((-17 + 4) + 5) + 4) = ((-13 + 5) + 4) = (-8 + 4) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 8 + -7 - 6 * 7 - 4) = ((((7 + 8) + -7) - (6 * 7)) - 4) = (((15 + -7) - (6 * 7)) - 4) = (((15 + -7) - 42) - 4) = ((8 - 42) - 4) = (-34 - 4) = -38.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 * 6 - -9 - 0 - 1 * 8) = ((((4 * 6) - -9) - 0) - (1 * 8)) = (((24 - -9) - 0) - (1 * 8)) = (((24 - -9) - 0) - 8) = ((33 - 0) - 8) = (33 - 8) = 25.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 - -5 * 2 + 6 * 1 + 6) = (((4 - (-5 * 2)) + (6 * 1)) + 6) = (((4 - -10) + (6 * 1)) + 6) = (((4 - -10) + 6) + 6) = ((14 + 6) + 6) = (20 + 6) = 26.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-2 - -6 * -1 + 3 - -4 * -6) = (((-2 - (-6 * -1)) + 3) - (-4 * -6)) = (((-2 - 6) + 3) - (-4 * -6)) = (((-2 - 6) + 3) - 24) = ((-8 + 3) - 24) = (-5 - 24) = -29.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (2 * -5 + 1 * 4 + 7 * -3) = (((2 * -5) + (1 * 4)) + (7 * -3)) = ((-10 + (1 * 4)) + (7 * -3)) = ((-10 + 4) + (7 * -3)) = ((-10 + 4) + -21) = (-6 + -21) = -27.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-7 - 4 + 7 * -8 - 8 + 9) = ((((-7 - 4) + (7 * -8)) - 8) + 9) = (((-11 + (7 * -8)) - 8) + 9) = (((-11 + -56) - 8) + 9) = ((-67 - 8) + 9) = (-75 + 9) = -66.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (9 + 8 * -8 + -5 - 8 * 6) = (((9 + (8 * -8)) + -5) - (8 * 6)) = (((9 + -64) + -5) - (8 * 6)) = (((9 + -64) + -5) - 48) = ((-55 + -5) - 48) = (-60 - 48) = -108.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C * D)) * ((E * F) - (G - H))) = (((-4 - -38) * (25 * 26)) * ((-29 * -27) - (-66 - -108))) = ((34 * (25 * 26)) * ((-29 * -27) - (-66 - -108))) = ((34 * 650) * ((-29 * -27) - (-66 - -108))) = ((34 * 650) * (783 - (-66 - -108))) = ((34 * 650) * (783 - 42)) = (22100 * (783 - 42)) = (22100 * 741) = 16376100.\n(Final response) So the answer is 16376100.", "correct_answer": "16376100", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 338, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((((0 - 9 * -3 - 5) * (-4 + -6 - -3 * 2)) - ((4 * -8 * -7 + 0) - (-3 + 8 + -4 - 2))) - (((-9 * -6 * -8 * -7) * (7 - 3 * 0 * -6)) - ((-7 * 7 * -2 + 5) + (4 - -6 * -7 * 3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C - D)) - ((E * F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (0 - 9 * -3 - 5), B = (-4 + -6 - -3 * 2), C = (4 * -8 * -7 + 0), D = (-3 + 8 + -4 - 2), E = (-9 * -6 * -8 * -7), F = (7 - 3 * 0 * -6), G = (-7 * 7 * -2 + 5) and H = (4 - -6 * -7 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 - 9 * -3 - 5) = ((0 - (9 * -3)) - 5) = ((0 - -27) - 5) = (27 - 5) = 22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + -6 - -3 * 2) = ((-4 + -6) - (-3 * 2)) = (-10 - (-3 * 2)) = (-10 - -6) = -4.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 * -8 * -7 + 0) = (((4 * -8) * -7) + 0) = ((-32 * -7) + 0) = (224 + 0) = 224.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 + 8 + -4 - 2) = (((-3 + 8) + -4) - 2) = ((5 + -4) - 2) = (1 - 2) = -1.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-9 * -6 * -8 * -7) = (((-9 * -6) * -8) * -7) = ((54 * -8) * -7) = (-432 * -7) = 3024.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (7 - 3 * 0 * -6) = (7 - ((3 * 0) * -6)) = (7 - (0 * -6)) = (7 - 0) = 7.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-7 * 7 * -2 + 5) = (((-7 * 7) * -2) + 5) = ((-49 * -2) + 5) = (98 + 5) = 103.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (4 - -6 * -7 * 3) = (4 - ((-6 * -7) * 3)) = (4 - (42 * 3)) = (4 - 126) = -122.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C - D)) - ((E * F) - (G + H))) = (((22 * -4) - (224 - -1)) - ((3024 * 7) - (103 + -122))) = ((-88 - (224 - -1)) - ((3024 * 7) - (103 + -122))) = ((-88 - 225) - ((3024 * 7) - (103 + -122))) = ((-88 - 225) - (21168 - (103 + -122))) = ((-88 - 225) - (21168 - -19)) = (-313 - (21168 - -19)) = (-313 - 21187) = -21500.\n(Final response) So the answer is -21500.", "correct_answer": "-21500", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 275, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 + 0 - 3) - (-9 * -5 + 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (0 + 0 - 3) and B = (-9 * -5 + 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 + 0 - 3) = ((0 + 0) - 3) = (0 - 3) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -5 + 7) = ((-9 * -5) + 7) = (45 + 7) = 52.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-3 - 52) = -55.\n(Final response) So the answer is -55.", "correct_answer": "-55", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 81, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((5 + -4 * 0 * 7) - (7 + 0 - -3 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (5 + -4 * 0 * 7) and B = (7 + 0 - -3 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (5 + -4 * 0 * 7) = (5 + ((-4 * 0) * 7)) = (5 + (0 * 7)) = (5 + 0) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 0 - -3 + 8) = (((7 + 0) - -3) + 8) = ((7 - -3) + 8) = (10 + 8) = 18.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (5 - 18) = -13.\n(Final response) So the answer is -13.", "correct_answer": "-13", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 296, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 + -5 * 3 - 1 - 1) - (-1 - 9 - 2 + -1 * 0)) + ((-1 * 8 - 7 - 0 - -6) - (8 + -1 - 6 - 6 + 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-2 + -5 * 3 - 1 - 1), B = (-1 - 9 - 2 + -1 * 0), C = (-1 * 8 - 7 - 0 - -6) and D = (8 + -1 - 6 - 6 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -5 * 3 - 1 - 1) = (((-2 + (-5 * 3)) - 1) - 1) = (((-2 + -15) - 1) - 1) = ((-17 - 1) - 1) = (-18 - 1) = -19.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 9 - 2 + -1 * 0) = (((-1 - 9) - 2) + (-1 * 0)) = ((-10 - 2) + (-1 * 0)) = ((-10 - 2) + 0) = (-12 + 0) = -12.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * 8 - 7 - 0 - -6) = ((((-1 * 8) - 7) - 0) - -6) = (((-8 - 7) - 0) - -6) = ((-15 - 0) - -6) = (-15 - -6) = -9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 + -1 - 6 - 6 + 1) = ((((8 + -1) - 6) - 6) + 1) = (((7 - 6) - 6) + 1) = ((1 - 6) + 1) = (-5 + 1) = -4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((-19 - -12) + (-9 - -4)) = (-7 + (-9 - -4)) = (-7 + -5) = -12.\n(Final response) So the answer is -12.", "correct_answer": "-12", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 191, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 * -2 * 4 + 0) * (7 + 3 + -6 * 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-2 * -2 * 4 + 0) and B = (7 + 3 + -6 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 * -2 * 4 + 0) = (((-2 * -2) * 4) + 0) = ((4 * 4) + 0) = (16 + 0) = 16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 + 3 + -6 * 8) = ((7 + 3) + (-6 * 8)) = (10 + (-6 * 8)) = (10 + -48) = -38.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (16 * -38) = -608.\n(Final response) So the answer is -608.", "correct_answer": "-608", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 233, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 * -2 + -8 + 5 - -9) - (-8 * -2 + -9 * -4 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-4 * -2 + -8 + 5 - -9) and B = (-8 * -2 + -9 * -4 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -2 + -8 + 5 - -9) = ((((-4 * -2) + -8) + 5) - -9) = (((8 + -8) + 5) - -9) = ((0 + 5) - -9) = (5 - -9) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 * -2 + -9 * -4 * -2) = ((-8 * -2) + ((-9 * -4) * -2)) = (16 + ((-9 * -4) * -2)) = (16 + (36 * -2)) = (16 + -72) = -56.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (14 - -56) = 70.\n(Final response) So the answer is 70.", "correct_answer": "70", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 77, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 * 9 - 5) + (-5 * 2 + -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (4 * 9 - 5) and B = (-5 * 2 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 * 9 - 5) = ((4 * 9) - 5) = (36 - 5) = 31.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 2 + -6) = ((-5 * 2) + -6) = (-10 + -6) = -16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (31 + -16) = 15.\n(Final response) So the answer is 15.", "correct_answer": "15", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 46, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 + -7 + 5) * (4 - 4 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-9 + -7 + 5) and B = (4 - 4 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 + -7 + 5) = ((-9 + -7) + 5) = (-16 + 5) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 4 - 3) = ((4 - 4) - 3) = (0 - 3) = -3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-11 * -3) = 33.\n(Final response) So the answer is 33.", "correct_answer": "33", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 71, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 * 4 + -2) * (-1 - 2 - -4)) * ((-8 - -2 - -6) + (3 + 3 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (-7 * 4 + -2), B = (-1 - 2 - -4), C = (-8 - -2 - -6) and D = (3 + 3 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * 4 + -2) = ((-7 * 4) + -2) = (-28 + -2) = -30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 - 2 - -4) = ((-1 - 2) - -4) = (-3 - -4) = 1.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 - -2 - -6) = ((-8 - -2) - -6) = (-6 - -6) = 0.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + 3 + -1) = ((3 + 3) + -1) = (6 + -1) = 5.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((-30 * 1) * (0 + 5)) = (-30 * (0 + 5)) = (-30 * 5) = -150.\n(Final response) So the answer is -150.", "correct_answer": "-150", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 121, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-1 + 4 - -4 - 7) - (8 * 8 * 5 * -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-1 + 4 - -4 - 7) and B = (8 * 8 * 5 * -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-1 + 4 - -4 - 7) = (((-1 + 4) - -4) - 7) = ((3 - -4) - 7) = (7 - 7) = 0.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 8 * 5 * -6) = (((8 * 8) * 5) * -6) = ((64 * 5) * -6) = (320 * -6) = -1920.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (0 - -1920) = 1920.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1920.", "correct_answer": "1920", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 196, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 + 8 + -7 - -4) + (-2 - 6 + -4 * -2)) + ((-2 + 9 + -6 - -2) * (2 - -1 * -6 - -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-6 + 8 + -7 - -4), B = (-2 - 6 + -4 * -2), C = (-2 + 9 + -6 - -2) and D = (2 - -1 * -6 - -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 8 + -7 - -4) = (((-6 + 8) + -7) - -4) = ((2 + -7) - -4) = (-5 - -4) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 - 6 + -4 * -2) = ((-2 - 6) + (-4 * -2)) = (-8 + (-4 * -2)) = (-8 + 8) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + 9 + -6 - -2) = (((-2 + 9) + -6) - -2) = ((7 + -6) - -2) = (1 - -2) = 3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 - -1 * -6 - -1) = ((2 - (-1 * -6)) - -1) = ((2 - 6) - -1) = (-4 - -1) = -3.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C * D)) = ((-1 + 0) + (3 * -3)) = (-1 + (3 * -3)) = (-1 + -9) = -10.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10.", "correct_answer": "-10", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 591, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-7 + 8 * -3) - (9 + 6 * -6)) - ((-5 - -4 - -8) - (-1 + 2 + 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-7 + 8 * -3), B = (9 + 6 * -6), C = (-5 - -4 - -8) and D = (-1 + 2 + 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 + 8 * -3) = (-7 + (8 * -3)) = (-7 + -24) = -31.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + 6 * -6) = (9 + (6 * -6)) = (9 + -36) = -27.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-5 - -4 - -8) = ((-5 - -4) - -8) = (-1 - -8) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 + 2 + 3) = ((-1 + 2) + 3) = (1 + 3) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-31 - -27) - (7 - 4)) = (-4 - (7 - 4)) = (-4 - 3) = -7.\n(Final response) So the answer is -7.", "correct_answer": "-7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 370, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-2 + -5 + 5 * 0) * (-7 * 6 * 5 - -4)) - ((-3 * -5 * -7 - -8) * (-8 - 9 - -9 + 6))) - (((-2 - 1 - 0 * 6) + (-3 + 4 + 4 * -1)) - ((1 - -6 * 0 + -9) + (3 * 0 + -9 + -1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) - (C * D)) - ((E + F) - (G + H)))\", where A = (-2 + -5 + 5 * 0), B = (-7 * 6 * 5 - -4), C = (-3 * -5 * -7 - -8), D = (-8 - 9 - -9 + 6), E = (-2 - 1 - 0 * 6), F = (-3 + 4 + 4 * -1), G = (1 - -6 * 0 + -9) and H = (3 * 0 + -9 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + -5 + 5 * 0) = ((-2 + -5) + (5 * 0)) = (-7 + (5 * 0)) = (-7 + 0) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 6 * 5 - -4) = (((-7 * 6) * 5) - -4) = ((-42 * 5) - -4) = (-210 - -4) = -206.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 * -5 * -7 - -8) = (((-3 * -5) * -7) - -8) = ((15 * -7) - -8) = (-105 - -8) = -97.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 - 9 - -9 + 6) = (((-8 - 9) - -9) + 6) = ((-17 - -9) + 6) = (-8 + 6) = -2.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-2 - 1 - 0 * 6) = ((-2 - 1) - (0 * 6)) = (-3 - (0 * 6)) = (-3 - 0) = -3.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-3 + 4 + 4 * -1) = ((-3 + 4) + (4 * -1)) = (1 + (4 * -1)) = (1 + -4) = -3.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (1 - -6 * 0 + -9) = ((1 - (-6 * 0)) + -9) = ((1 - 0) + -9) = (1 + -9) = -8.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (3 * 0 + -9 + -1) = (((3 * 0) + -9) + -1) = ((0 + -9) + -1) = (-9 + -1) = -10.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) - (C * D)) - ((E + F) - (G + H))) = (((-7 * -206) - (-97 * -2)) - ((-3 + -3) - (-8 + -10))) = ((1442 - (-97 * -2)) - ((-3 + -3) - (-8 + -10))) = ((1442 - 194) - ((-3 + -3) - (-8 + -10))) = ((1442 - 194) - (-6 - (-8 + -10))) = ((1442 - 194) - (-6 - -18)) = (1248 - (-6 - -18)) = (1248 - 12) = 1236.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1236.", "correct_answer": "1236", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 282, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 + -8 + -8 * -4) - (6 * 4 * 9 * 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-6 + -8 + -8 * -4) and B = (6 * 4 * 9 * 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + -8 + -8 * -4) = ((-6 + -8) + (-8 * -4)) = (-14 + (-8 * -4)) = (-14 + 32) = 18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 * 4 * 9 * 7) = (((6 * 4) * 9) * 7) = ((24 * 9) * 7) = (216 * 7) = 1512.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (18 - 1512) = -1494.\n(Final response) So the answer is -1494.", "correct_answer": "-1494", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 33, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 * 3 - -2 * -2) + (-1 + -4 * 9 * 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (6 * 3 - -2 * -2) and B = (-1 + -4 * 9 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * 3 - -2 * -2) = ((6 * 3) - (-2 * -2)) = (18 - (-2 * -2)) = (18 - 4) = 14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + -4 * 9 * 1) = (-1 + ((-4 * 9) * 1)) = (-1 + (-36 * 1)) = (-1 + -36) = -37.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (14 + -37) = -23.\n(Final response) So the answer is -23.", "correct_answer": "-23", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 43, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-3 + 1 * 7) - (-9 * 5 * 8)) + ((-6 + 9 + 4) * (3 * 9 * 6))) - (((9 + 0 * -8) * (9 * -6 + 9)) * ((-1 + 6 * -1) * (8 + -3 * 6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) + (C * D)) - ((E * F) * (G * H)))\", where A = (-3 + 1 * 7), B = (-9 * 5 * 8), C = (-6 + 9 + 4), D = (3 * 9 * 6), E = (9 + 0 * -8), F = (9 * -6 + 9), G = (-1 + 6 * -1) and H = (8 + -3 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 1 * 7) = (-3 + (1 * 7)) = (-3 + 7) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * 5 * 8) = ((-9 * 5) * 8) = (-45 * 8) = -360.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + 9 + 4) = ((-6 + 9) + 4) = (3 + 4) = 7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 * 9 * 6) = ((3 * 9) * 6) = (27 * 6) = 162.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (9 + 0 * -8) = (9 + (0 * -8)) = (9 + 0) = 9.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (9 * -6 + 9) = ((9 * -6) + 9) = (-54 + 9) = -45.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-1 + 6 * -1) = (-1 + (6 * -1)) = (-1 + -6) = -7.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (8 + -3 * 6) = (8 + (-3 * 6)) = (8 + -18) = -10.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) + (C * D)) - ((E * F) * (G * H))) = (((4 - -360) + (7 * 162)) - ((9 * -45) * (-7 * -10))) = ((364 + (7 * 162)) - ((9 * -45) * (-7 * -10))) = ((364 + 1134) - ((9 * -45) * (-7 * -10))) = ((364 + 1134) - (-405 * (-7 * -10))) = ((364 + 1134) - (-405 * 70)) = (1498 - (-405 * 70)) = (1498 - -28350) = 29848.\n(Final response) So the answer is 29848.", "correct_answer": "29848", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 249, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 + -4 - 5) + (8 * -1 + -2)) * ((8 - -7 + -6) + (8 * 5 * -4))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (1 + -4 - 5), B = (8 * -1 + -2), C = (8 - -7 + -6) and D = (8 * 5 * -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 + -4 - 5) = ((1 + -4) - 5) = (-3 - 5) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * -1 + -2) = ((8 * -1) + -2) = (-8 + -2) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 - -7 + -6) = ((8 - -7) + -6) = (15 + -6) = 9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * 5 * -4) = ((8 * 5) * -4) = (40 * -4) = -160.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((-8 + -10) * (9 + -160)) = (-18 * (9 + -160)) = (-18 * -151) = 2718.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2718.", "correct_answer": "2718", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 300, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 * -3 * -3 + -2) * (-5 + 3 - -2 - -3)) * ((0 - 1 - 3 + 4) + (9 + 0 + -1 + -7))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C + D))\", where A = (0 * -3 * -3 + -2), B = (-5 + 3 - -2 - -3), C = (0 - 1 - 3 + 4) and D = (9 + 0 + -1 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * -3 * -3 + -2) = (((0 * -3) * -3) + -2) = ((0 * -3) + -2) = (0 + -2) = -2.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + 3 - -2 - -3) = (((-5 + 3) - -2) - -3) = ((-2 - -2) - -3) = (0 - -3) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 - 1 - 3 + 4) = (((0 - 1) - 3) + 4) = ((-1 - 3) + 4) = (-4 + 4) = 0.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (9 + 0 + -1 + -7) = (((9 + 0) + -1) + -7) = ((9 + -1) + -7) = (8 + -7) = 1.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C + D)) = ((-2 * 3) * (0 + 1)) = (-6 * (0 + 1)) = (-6 * 1) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 565, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 + 1 * -6) + (1 * -9 - 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-4 + 1 * -6) and B = (1 * -9 - 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 + 1 * -6) = (-4 + (1 * -6)) = (-4 + -6) = -10.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -9 - 8) = ((1 * -9) - 8) = (-9 - 8) = -17.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-10 + -17) = -27.\n(Final response) So the answer is -27.", "correct_answer": "-27", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 80, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 + 0 * 4) * (-9 * -6 * 6)) - ((0 * 6 - -6) * (-6 * 7 + -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-8 + 0 * 4), B = (-9 * -6 * 6), C = (0 * 6 - -6) and D = (-6 * 7 + -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 + 0 * 4) = (-8 + (0 * 4)) = (-8 + 0) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -6 * 6) = ((-9 * -6) * 6) = (54 * 6) = 324.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 * 6 - -6) = ((0 * 6) - -6) = (0 - -6) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * 7 + -8) = ((-6 * 7) + -8) = (-42 + -8) = -50.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-8 * 324) - (6 * -50)) = (-2592 - (6 * -50)) = (-2592 - -300) = -2292.\n(Final response) So the answer is -2292.", "correct_answer": "-2292", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 387, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((0 * -8 + -1) + (-7 - -5 + 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (0 * -8 + -1) and B = (-7 - -5 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * -8 + -1) = ((0 * -8) + -1) = (0 + -1) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - -5 + 5) = ((-7 - -5) + 5) = (-2 + 5) = 3.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-1 + 3) = 2.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2.", "correct_answer": "2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 127, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - -7 * -1 - 3) - (3 + 5 + 6 * 9)) - ((2 - -4 + -1 * -3) - (-9 + 4 - 2 + -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (6 - -7 * -1 - 3), B = (3 + 5 + 6 * 9), C = (2 - -4 + -1 * -3) and D = (-9 + 4 - 2 + -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -7 * -1 - 3) = ((6 - (-7 * -1)) - 3) = ((6 - 7) - 3) = (-1 - 3) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + 5 + 6 * 9) = ((3 + 5) + (6 * 9)) = (8 + (6 * 9)) = (8 + 54) = 62.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - -4 + -1 * -3) = ((2 - -4) + (-1 * -3)) = (6 + (-1 * -3)) = (6 + 3) = 9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 + 4 - 2 + -5) = (((-9 + 4) - 2) + -5) = ((-5 - 2) + -5) = (-7 + -5) = -12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-4 - 62) - (9 - -12)) = (-66 - (9 - -12)) = (-66 - 21) = -87.\n(Final response) So the answer is -87.", "correct_answer": "-87", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 549, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((6 - -8 + -6 - -1) * (9 - 6 * -2 * 3)) - ((3 * -2 * -1 * -7) * (4 * -1 * -3 * 8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (6 - -8 + -6 - -1), B = (9 - 6 * -2 * 3), C = (3 * -2 * -1 * -7) and D = (4 * -1 * -3 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 - -8 + -6 - -1) = (((6 - -8) + -6) - -1) = ((14 + -6) - -1) = (8 - -1) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - 6 * -2 * 3) = (9 - ((6 * -2) * 3)) = (9 - (-12 * 3)) = (9 - -36) = 45.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (3 * -2 * -1 * -7) = (((3 * -2) * -1) * -7) = ((-6 * -1) * -7) = (6 * -7) = -42.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 * -1 * -3 * 8) = (((4 * -1) * -3) * 8) = ((-4 * -3) * 8) = (12 * 8) = 96.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((9 * 45) - (-42 * 96)) = (405 - (-42 * 96)) = (405 - -4032) = 4437.\n(Final response) So the answer is 4437.", "correct_answer": "4437", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 470, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * -8 + -6) - (8 * 2 * 6)) + ((-7 * 6 + -3) * (-7 * 2 + 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C * D))\", where A = (-5 * -8 + -6), B = (8 * 2 * 6), C = (-7 * 6 + -3) and D = (-7 * 2 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * -8 + -6) = ((-5 * -8) + -6) = (40 + -6) = 34.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 2 * 6) = ((8 * 2) * 6) = (16 * 6) = 96.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-7 * 6 + -3) = ((-7 * 6) + -3) = (-42 + -3) = -45.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 * 2 + 2) = ((-7 * 2) + 2) = (-14 + 2) = -12.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C * D)) = ((34 - 96) + (-45 * -12)) = (-62 + (-45 * -12)) = (-62 + 540) = 478.\n(Final response) So the answer is 478.", "correct_answer": "478", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 147, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 * -5 + 3) * (-7 + 7 + 6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-3 * -5 + 3) and B = (-7 + 7 + 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * -5 + 3) = ((-3 * -5) + 3) = (15 + 3) = 18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + 7 + 6) = ((-7 + 7) + 6) = (0 + 6) = 6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (18 * 6) = 108.\n(Final response) So the answer is 108.", "correct_answer": "108", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 44, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((4 + 1 * -8 - 5 * -9 - 8) + (-7 + 2 + -5 * -3 + -2 * 5)) * ((-2 + 1 * 0 - -1 + -4 - -8) + (-4 + 4 + -3 * -5 * -7 * 3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C + D))\", where A = (4 + 1 * -8 - 5 * -9 - 8), B = (-7 + 2 + -5 * -3 + -2 * 5), C = (-2 + 1 * 0 - -1 + -4 - -8) and D = (-4 + 4 + -3 * -5 * -7 * 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + 1 * -8 - 5 * -9 - 8) = (((4 + (1 * -8)) - (5 * -9)) - 8) = (((4 + -8) - (5 * -9)) - 8) = (((4 + -8) - -45) - 8) = ((-4 - -45) - 8) = (41 - 8) = 33.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 + 2 + -5 * -3 + -2 * 5) = (((-7 + 2) + (-5 * -3)) + (-2 * 5)) = ((-5 + (-5 * -3)) + (-2 * 5)) = ((-5 + 15) + (-2 * 5)) = ((-5 + 15) + -10) = (10 + -10) = 0.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 + 1 * 0 - -1 + -4 - -8) = ((((-2 + (1 * 0)) - -1) + -4) - -8) = ((((-2 + 0) - -1) + -4) - -8) = (((-2 - -1) + -4) - -8) = ((-1 + -4) - -8) = (-5 - -8) = 3.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 + 4 + -3 * -5 * -7 * 3) = ((-4 + 4) + (((-3 * -5) * -7) * 3)) = (0 + (((-3 * -5) * -7) * 3)) = (0 + ((15 * -7) * 3)) = (0 + (-105 * 3)) = (0 + -315) = -315.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C + D)) = ((33 + 0) * (3 + -315)) = (33 * (3 + -315)) = (33 * -312) = -10296.\n(Final response) So the answer is -10296.", "correct_answer": "-10296", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 226, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 * 6 - 2 * 5) * (6 - 2 + -6 * -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (8 * 6 - 2 * 5) and B = (6 - 2 + -6 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 6 - 2 * 5) = ((8 * 6) - (2 * 5)) = (48 - (2 * 5)) = (48 - 10) = 38.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - 2 + -6 * -8) = ((6 - 2) + (-6 * -8)) = (4 + (-6 * -8)) = (4 + 48) = 52.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (38 * 52) = 1976.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1976.", "correct_answer": "1976", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 270, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 * 5 - -9) * (1 - 8 - 7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 * 5 - -9) and B = (1 - 8 - 7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 5 - -9) = ((-5 * 5) - -9) = (-25 - -9) = -16.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - 8 - 7) = ((1 - 8) - 7) = (-7 - 7) = -14.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-16 * -14) = 224.\n(Final response) So the answer is 224.", "correct_answer": "224", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 18, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 - -9 * -6) + (5 * -4 + 7)) - ((-6 + 4 * -9) * (1 + 2 + -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-5 - -9 * -6), B = (5 * -4 + 7), C = (-6 + 4 * -9) and D = (1 + 2 + -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 - -9 * -6) = (-5 - (-9 * -6)) = (-5 - 54) = -59.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 * -4 + 7) = ((5 * -4) + 7) = (-20 + 7) = -13.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + 4 * -9) = (-6 + (4 * -9)) = (-6 + -36) = -42.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 + 2 + -1) = ((1 + 2) + -1) = (3 + -1) = 2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) - (C * D)) = ((-59 + -13) - (-42 * 2)) = (-72 - (-42 * 2)) = (-72 - -84) = 12.\n(Final response) So the answer is 12.", "correct_answer": "12", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 352, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((3 - 2 - 5) + (-9 + 8 * -4)) * ((-9 - 0 - 9) + (-2 - 3 * 7))) - (((2 - -3 + 4) + (3 - 9 + -1)) * ((0 * 9 * -3) * (-5 * 5 - 1)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G * H)))\", where A = (3 - 2 - 5), B = (-9 + 8 * -4), C = (-9 - 0 - 9), D = (-2 - 3 * 7), E = (2 - -3 + 4), F = (3 - 9 + -1), G = (0 * 9 * -3) and H = (-5 * 5 - 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - 2 - 5) = ((3 - 2) - 5) = (1 - 5) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 + 8 * -4) = (-9 + (8 * -4)) = (-9 + -32) = -41.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-9 - 0 - 9) = ((-9 - 0) - 9) = (-9 - 9) = -18.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-2 - 3 * 7) = (-2 - (3 * 7)) = (-2 - 21) = -23.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (2 - -3 + 4) = ((2 - -3) + 4) = (5 + 4) = 9.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (3 - 9 + -1) = ((3 - 9) + -1) = (-6 + -1) = -7.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (0 * 9 * -3) = ((0 * 9) * -3) = (0 * -3) = 0.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-5 * 5 - 1) = ((-5 * 5) - 1) = (-25 - 1) = -26.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C + D)) - ((E + F) * (G * H))) = (((-4 + -41) * (-18 + -23)) - ((9 + -7) * (0 * -26))) = ((-45 * (-18 + -23)) - ((9 + -7) * (0 * -26))) = ((-45 * -41) - ((9 + -7) * (0 * -26))) = ((-45 * -41) - (2 * (0 * -26))) = ((-45 * -41) - (2 * 0)) = (1845 - (2 * 0)) = (1845 - 0) = 1845.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1845.", "correct_answer": "1845", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 267, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 * -8 - 0) * (5 - 2 * 7)) - ((4 + 5 * 6) * (-4 - -8 - -2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-8 * -8 - 0), B = (5 - 2 * 7), C = (4 + 5 * 6) and D = (-4 - -8 - -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 * -8 - 0) = ((-8 * -8) - 0) = (64 - 0) = 64.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 - 2 * 7) = (5 - (2 * 7)) = (5 - 14) = -9.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + 5 * 6) = (4 + (5 * 6)) = (4 + 30) = 34.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -8 - -2) = ((-4 - -8) - -2) = (4 - -2) = 6.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((64 * -9) - (34 * 6)) = (-576 - (34 * 6)) = (-576 - 204) = -780.\n(Final response) So the answer is -780.", "correct_answer": "-780", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 367, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 + 6 * 8) + (4 * 5 - -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (7 + 6 * 8) and B = (4 * 5 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 6 * 8) = (7 + (6 * 8)) = (7 + 48) = 55.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 5 - -8) = ((4 * 5) - -8) = (20 - -8) = 28.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (55 + 28) = 83.\n(Final response) So the answer is 83.", "correct_answer": "83", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 99, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-5 * 5 + -6) * (3 + -9 - 4)) + ((2 - -1 - 4) + (-8 + -9 + 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C + D))\", where A = (-5 * 5 + -6), B = (3 + -9 - 4), C = (2 - -1 - 4) and D = (-8 + -9 + 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 * 5 + -6) = ((-5 * 5) + -6) = (-25 + -6) = -31.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + -9 - 4) = ((3 + -9) - 4) = (-6 - 4) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 - -1 - 4) = ((2 - -1) - 4) = (3 - 4) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + -9 + 0) = ((-8 + -9) + 0) = (-17 + 0) = -17.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C + D)) = ((-31 * -10) + (-1 + -17)) = (310 + (-1 + -17)) = (310 + -18) = 292.\n(Final response) So the answer is 292.", "correct_answer": "292", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 389, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 + 1 * -9) - (-5 + 4 - -9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-2 + 1 * -9) and B = (-5 + 4 - -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 + 1 * -9) = (-2 + (1 * -9)) = (-2 + -9) = -11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + 4 - -9) = ((-5 + 4) - -9) = (-1 - -9) = 8.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-11 - 8) = -19.\n(Final response) So the answer is -19.", "correct_answer": "-19", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 94, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-3 - 8 * -2 - -3 + 4 - 0) * (9 - -4 - 2 - 7 + 2 * -7)) + ((-1 * 0 - -8 - -1 - 2 - -6) * (8 * 1 * 4 + -8 * -2 + 2))) * (((-1 + -7 + 1 - -2 + 5 + 9) + (-8 * -1 - -4 * 4 + 4 + 1)) + ((-5 * -3 * -5 * 6 + 7 * -1) * (-6 + 0 - -5 - -7 - 5 * 8)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G * H)))\", where A = (-3 - 8 * -2 - -3 + 4 - 0), B = (9 - -4 - 2 - 7 + 2 * -7), C = (-1 * 0 - -8 - -1 - 2 - -6), D = (8 * 1 * 4 + -8 * -2 + 2), E = (-1 + -7 + 1 - -2 + 5 + 9), F = (-8 * -1 - -4 * 4 + 4 + 1), G = (-5 * -3 * -5 * 6 + 7 * -1) and H = (-6 + 0 - -5 - -7 - 5 * 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - 8 * -2 - -3 + 4 - 0) = ((((-3 - (8 * -2)) - -3) + 4) - 0) = ((((-3 - -16) - -3) + 4) - 0) = (((13 - -3) + 4) - 0) = ((16 + 4) - 0) = (20 - 0) = 20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - -4 - 2 - 7 + 2 * -7) = ((((9 - -4) - 2) - 7) + (2 * -7)) = (((13 - 2) - 7) + (2 * -7)) = (((13 - 2) - 7) + -14) = ((11 - 7) + -14) = (4 + -14) = -10.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 * 0 - -8 - -1 - 2 - -6) = (((((-1 * 0) - -8) - -1) - 2) - -6) = ((((0 - -8) - -1) - 2) - -6) = (((8 - -1) - 2) - -6) = ((9 - 2) - -6) = (7 - -6) = 13.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 * 1 * 4 + -8 * -2 + 2) = ((((8 * 1) * 4) + (-8 * -2)) + 2) = (((8 * 4) + (-8 * -2)) + 2) = (((8 * 4) + 16) + 2) = ((32 + 16) + 2) = (48 + 2) = 50.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-1 + -7 + 1 - -2 + 5 + 9) = (((((-1 + -7) + 1) - -2) + 5) + 9) = ((((-8 + 1) - -2) + 5) + 9) = (((-7 - -2) + 5) + 9) = ((-5 + 5) + 9) = (0 + 9) = 9.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (-8 * -1 - -4 * 4 + 4 + 1) = ((((-8 * -1) - (-4 * 4)) + 4) + 1) = (((8 - (-4 * 4)) + 4) + 1) = (((8 - -16) + 4) + 1) = ((24 + 4) + 1) = (28 + 1) = 29.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (-5 * -3 * -5 * 6 + 7 * -1) = ((((-5 * -3) * -5) * 6) + (7 * -1)) = (((15 * -5) * 6) + (7 * -1)) = (((15 * -5) * 6) + -7) = ((-75 * 6) + -7) = (-450 + -7) = -457.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-6 + 0 - -5 - -7 - 5 * 8) = ((((-6 + 0) - -5) - -7) - (5 * 8)) = (((-6 - -5) - -7) - (5 * 8)) = (((-6 - -5) - -7) - 40) = ((-1 - -7) - 40) = (6 - 40) = -34.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C * D)) * ((E + F) + (G * H))) = (((20 * -10) + (13 * 50)) * ((9 + 29) + (-457 * -34))) = ((-200 + (13 * 50)) * ((9 + 29) + (-457 * -34))) = ((-200 + 650) * ((9 + 29) + (-457 * -34))) = ((-200 + 650) * (38 + (-457 * -34))) = ((-200 + 650) * (38 + 15538)) = (450 * (38 + 15538)) = (450 * 15576) = 7009200.\n(Final response) So the answer is 7009200.", "correct_answer": "7009200", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 350, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * -4 - -8) - (-5 * 1 - 3)) - ((-2 * 2 * -5) - (-8 + 7 - -8))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (3 * -4 - -8), B = (-5 * 1 - 3), C = (-2 * 2 * -5) and D = (-8 + 7 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -4 - -8) = ((3 * -4) - -8) = (-12 - -8) = -4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 1 - 3) = ((-5 * 1) - 3) = (-5 - 3) = -8.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-2 * 2 * -5) = ((-2 * 2) * -5) = (-4 * -5) = 20.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-8 + 7 - -8) = ((-8 + 7) - -8) = (-1 - -8) = 7.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-4 - -8) - (20 - 7)) = (4 - (20 - 7)) = (4 - 13) = -9.\n(Final response) So the answer is -9.", "correct_answer": "-9", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 344, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 * -8 + -5 - 6 - -5) * (-9 * -7 * 5 * -2 * -9)) - ((7 + -9 * -4 + -7 * 5) * (-4 - -1 - 1 - 8 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (3 * -8 + -5 - 6 - -5), B = (-9 * -7 * 5 * -2 * -9), C = (7 + -9 * -4 + -7 * 5) and D = (-4 - -1 - 1 - 8 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 * -8 + -5 - 6 - -5) = ((((3 * -8) + -5) - 6) - -5) = (((-24 + -5) - 6) - -5) = ((-29 - 6) - -5) = (-35 - -5) = -30.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-9 * -7 * 5 * -2 * -9) = ((((-9 * -7) * 5) * -2) * -9) = (((63 * 5) * -2) * -9) = ((315 * -2) * -9) = (-630 * -9) = 5670.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 + -9 * -4 + -7 * 5) = ((7 + (-9 * -4)) + (-7 * 5)) = ((7 + 36) + (-7 * 5)) = ((7 + 36) + -35) = (43 + -35) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 - -1 - 1 - 8 * -1) = (((-4 - -1) - 1) - (8 * -1)) = ((-3 - 1) - (8 * -1)) = ((-3 - 1) - -8) = (-4 - -8) = 4.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-30 * 5670) - (8 * 4)) = (-170100 - (8 * 4)) = (-170100 - 32) = -170132.\n(Final response) So the answer is -170132.", "correct_answer": "-170132", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 181, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 + -6 * 0 * 5) * (-6 * -4 - -5 + -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (4 + -6 * 0 * 5) and B = (-6 * -4 - -5 + -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 + -6 * 0 * 5) = (4 + ((-6 * 0) * 5)) = (4 + (0 * 5)) = (4 + 0) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * -4 - -5 + -2) = (((-6 * -4) - -5) + -2) = ((24 - -5) + -2) = (29 + -2) = 27.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (4 * 27) = 108.\n(Final response) So the answer is 108.", "correct_answer": "108", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 220, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 - -1 * -6 - -7) - (2 + -2 - -9 + 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (3 - -1 * -6 - -7) and B = (2 + -2 - -9 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - -1 * -6 - -7) = ((3 - (-1 * -6)) - -7) = ((3 - 6) - -7) = (-3 - -7) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + -2 - -9 + 1) = (((2 + -2) - -9) + 1) = ((0 - -9) + 1) = (9 + 1) = 10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (4 - 10) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 159, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((7 - -7 * 3 - 4 + -2) * (2 - -9 - -8 * 9 + 2)) + ((0 + -5 + 1 - -1 * 6) + (-3 * -1 + 9 + 2 + 0))) + (((0 + -4 + 6 * -4 + -4) - (4 + 8 + 7 + 7 + 5)) * ((1 * 7 * 9 * -1 + -6) - (9 + 5 + 0 - -2 * -3)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A * B) + (C + D)) + ((E - F) * (G - H)))\", where A = (7 - -7 * 3 - 4 + -2), B = (2 - -9 - -8 * 9 + 2), C = (0 + -5 + 1 - -1 * 6), D = (-3 * -1 + 9 + 2 + 0), E = (0 + -4 + 6 * -4 + -4), F = (4 + 8 + 7 + 7 + 5), G = (1 * 7 * 9 * -1 + -6) and H = (9 + 5 + 0 - -2 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -7 * 3 - 4 + -2) = (((7 - (-7 * 3)) - 4) + -2) = (((7 - -21) - 4) + -2) = ((28 - 4) + -2) = (24 + -2) = 22.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 - -9 - -8 * 9 + 2) = (((2 - -9) - (-8 * 9)) + 2) = ((11 - (-8 * 9)) + 2) = ((11 - -72) + 2) = (83 + 2) = 85.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (0 + -5 + 1 - -1 * 6) = (((0 + -5) + 1) - (-1 * 6)) = ((-5 + 1) - (-1 * 6)) = ((-5 + 1) - -6) = (-4 - -6) = 2.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-3 * -1 + 9 + 2 + 0) = ((((-3 * -1) + 9) + 2) + 0) = (((3 + 9) + 2) + 0) = ((12 + 2) + 0) = (14 + 0) = 14.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (0 + -4 + 6 * -4 + -4) = (((0 + -4) + (6 * -4)) + -4) = ((-4 + (6 * -4)) + -4) = ((-4 + -24) + -4) = (-28 + -4) = -32.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (4 + 8 + 7 + 7 + 5) = ((((4 + 8) + 7) + 7) + 5) = (((12 + 7) + 7) + 5) = ((19 + 7) + 5) = (26 + 5) = 31.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (1 * 7 * 9 * -1 + -6) = ((((1 * 7) * 9) * -1) + -6) = (((7 * 9) * -1) + -6) = ((63 * -1) + -6) = (-63 + -6) = -69.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (9 + 5 + 0 - -2 * -3) = (((9 + 5) + 0) - (-2 * -3)) = ((14 + 0) - (-2 * -3)) = ((14 + 0) - 6) = (14 - 6) = 8.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A * B) + (C + D)) + ((E - F) * (G - H))) = (((22 * 85) + (2 + 14)) + ((-32 - 31) * (-69 - 8))) = ((1870 + (2 + 14)) + ((-32 - 31) * (-69 - 8))) = ((1870 + 16) + ((-32 - 31) * (-69 - 8))) = ((1870 + 16) + (-63 * (-69 - 8))) = ((1870 + 16) + (-63 * -77)) = (1886 + (-63 * -77)) = (1886 + 4851) = 6737.\n(Final response) So the answer is 6737.", "correct_answer": "6737", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 324, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-6 * 8 + -3) - (3 + 0 * -9)) - ((7 - -7 + 2) - (2 - 0 * 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C - D))\", where A = (-6 * 8 + -3), B = (3 + 0 * -9), C = (7 - -7 + 2) and D = (2 - 0 * 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 * 8 + -3) = ((-6 * 8) + -3) = (-48 + -3) = -51.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 + 0 * -9) = (3 + (0 * -9)) = (3 + 0) = 3.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (7 - -7 + 2) = ((7 - -7) + 2) = (14 + 2) = 16.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 - 0 * 0) = (2 - (0 * 0)) = (2 - 0) = 2.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C - D)) = ((-51 - 3) - (16 - 2)) = (-54 - (16 - 2)) = (-54 - 14) = -68.\n(Final response) So the answer is -68.", "correct_answer": "-68", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 348, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((3 + 2 * 7 - -9 * 6 * 8) - (2 + 9 * 3 * -1 - 0 - -1)) * ((-6 + -2 * 0 - 8 - -5 - 8) * (-5 + 6 + -2 - 4 * -6 - 1))) - (((9 - 5 * 3 + -6 * -9 - -7) + (6 + 7 + 7 + -2 * 2 - -3)) + ((3 * 7 - 8 * -5 + 3 - 3) * (9 - -4 - -7 + 3 - 6 + -6)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C * D)) - ((E + F) + (G * H)))\", where A = (3 + 2 * 7 - -9 * 6 * 8), B = (2 + 9 * 3 * -1 - 0 - -1), C = (-6 + -2 * 0 - 8 - -5 - 8), D = (-5 + 6 + -2 - 4 * -6 - 1), E = (9 - 5 * 3 + -6 * -9 - -7), F = (6 + 7 + 7 + -2 * 2 - -3), G = (3 * 7 - 8 * -5 + 3 - 3) and H = (9 - -4 - -7 + 3 - 6 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 + 2 * 7 - -9 * 6 * 8) = ((3 + (2 * 7)) - ((-9 * 6) * 8)) = ((3 + 14) - ((-9 * 6) * 8)) = ((3 + 14) - (-54 * 8)) = (17 - (-54 * 8)) = (17 - -432) = 449.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (2 + 9 * 3 * -1 - 0 - -1) = (((2 + ((9 * 3) * -1)) - 0) - -1) = (((2 + (27 * -1)) - 0) - -1) = (((2 + -27) - 0) - -1) = ((-25 - 0) - -1) = (-25 - -1) = -24.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + -2 * 0 - 8 - -5 - 8) = ((((-6 + (-2 * 0)) - 8) - -5) - 8) = ((((-6 + 0) - 8) - -5) - 8) = (((-6 - 8) - -5) - 8) = ((-14 - -5) - 8) = (-9 - 8) = -17.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-5 + 6 + -2 - 4 * -6 - 1) = ((((-5 + 6) + -2) - (4 * -6)) - 1) = (((1 + -2) - (4 * -6)) - 1) = (((1 + -2) - -24) - 1) = ((-1 - -24) - 1) = (23 - 1) = 22.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (9 - 5 * 3 + -6 * -9 - -7) = (((9 - (5 * 3)) + (-6 * -9)) - -7) = (((9 - 15) + (-6 * -9)) - -7) = (((9 - 15) + 54) - -7) = ((-6 + 54) - -7) = (48 - -7) = 55.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (6 + 7 + 7 + -2 * 2 - -3) = ((((6 + 7) + 7) + (-2 * 2)) - -3) = (((13 + 7) + (-2 * 2)) - -3) = (((13 + 7) + -4) - -3) = ((20 + -4) - -3) = (16 - -3) = 19.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (3 * 7 - 8 * -5 + 3 - 3) = ((((3 * 7) - (8 * -5)) + 3) - 3) = (((21 - (8 * -5)) + 3) - 3) = (((21 - -40) + 3) - 3) = ((61 + 3) - 3) = (64 - 3) = 61.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (9 - -4 - -7 + 3 - 6 + -6) = (((((9 - -4) - -7) + 3) - 6) + -6) = ((((13 - -7) + 3) - 6) + -6) = (((20 + 3) - 6) + -6) = ((23 - 6) + -6) = (17 + -6) = 11.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C * D)) - ((E + F) + (G * H))) = (((449 - -24) * (-17 * 22)) - ((55 + 19) + (61 * 11))) = ((473 * (-17 * 22)) - ((55 + 19) + (61 * 11))) = ((473 * -374) - ((55 + 19) + (61 * 11))) = ((473 * -374) - (74 + (61 * 11))) = ((473 * -374) - (74 + 671)) = (-176902 - (74 + 671)) = (-176902 - 745) = -177647.\n(Final response) So the answer is -177647.", "correct_answer": "-177647", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 343, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-5 + -4 - -8 * 6 - -5 + 2) * (6 - 5 * 6 + 2 - 4 * -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-5 + -4 - -8 * 6 - -5 + 2) and B = (6 - 5 * 6 + 2 - 4 * -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-5 + -4 - -8 * 6 - -5 + 2) = ((((-5 + -4) - (-8 * 6)) - -5) + 2) = (((-9 - (-8 * 6)) - -5) + 2) = (((-9 - -48) - -5) + 2) = ((39 - -5) + 2) = (44 + 2) = 46.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 - 5 * 6 + 2 - 4 * -8) = (((6 - (5 * 6)) + 2) - (4 * -8)) = (((6 - 30) + 2) - (4 * -8)) = (((6 - 30) + 2) - -32) = ((-24 + 2) - -32) = (-22 - -32) = 10.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (46 * 10) = 460.\n(Final response) So the answer is 460.", "correct_answer": "460", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 114, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-4 * -9 * -3 + 2) * (-6 + -3 * 9 + 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-4 * -9 * -3 + 2) and B = (-6 + -3 * 9 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * -9 * -3 + 2) = (((-4 * -9) * -3) + 2) = ((36 * -3) + 2) = (-108 + 2) = -106.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 + -3 * 9 + 1) = ((-6 + (-3 * 9)) + 1) = ((-6 + -27) + 1) = (-33 + 1) = -32.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-106 * -32) = 3392.\n(Final response) So the answer is 3392.", "correct_answer": "3392", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 163, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((0 * -6 - 8 + 4 + 6 * -8) * (-3 + 7 * -6 + -5 * 0 - -7)) + ((-4 + -2 + -2 - 9 + -6 + -4) * (-6 * -6 + 5 - 8 - 2 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (0 * -6 - 8 + 4 + 6 * -8), B = (-3 + 7 * -6 + -5 * 0 - -7), C = (-4 + -2 + -2 - 9 + -6 + -4) and D = (-6 * -6 + 5 - 8 - 2 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (0 * -6 - 8 + 4 + 6 * -8) = ((((0 * -6) - 8) + 4) + (6 * -8)) = (((0 - 8) + 4) + (6 * -8)) = (((0 - 8) + 4) + -48) = ((-8 + 4) + -48) = (-4 + -48) = -52.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + 7 * -6 + -5 * 0 - -7) = (((-3 + (7 * -6)) + (-5 * 0)) - -7) = (((-3 + -42) + (-5 * 0)) - -7) = (((-3 + -42) + 0) - -7) = ((-45 + 0) - -7) = (-45 - -7) = -38.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + -2 + -2 - 9 + -6 + -4) = (((((-4 + -2) + -2) - 9) + -6) + -4) = ((((-6 + -2) - 9) + -6) + -4) = (((-8 - 9) + -6) + -4) = ((-17 + -6) + -4) = (-23 + -4) = -27.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-6 * -6 + 5 - 8 - 2 * 2) = ((((-6 * -6) + 5) - 8) - (2 * 2)) = (((36 + 5) - 8) - (2 * 2)) = (((36 + 5) - 8) - 4) = ((41 - 8) - 4) = (33 - 4) = 29.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((-52 * -38) + (-27 * 29)) = (1976 + (-27 * 29)) = (1976 + -783) = 1193.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1193.", "correct_answer": "1193", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 225, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: (((-8 - -1 + -8 + -3) * (-4 * 6 - 2 - 3)) * ((4 + 1 + -1 - -4) * (-7 - -9 * 5 + 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) * (C * D))\", where A = (-8 - -1 + -8 + -3), B = (-4 * 6 - 2 - 3), C = (4 + 1 + -1 - -4) and D = (-7 - -9 * 5 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-8 - -1 + -8 + -3) = (((-8 - -1) + -8) + -3) = ((-7 + -8) + -3) = (-15 + -3) = -18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * 6 - 2 - 3) = (((-4 * 6) - 2) - 3) = ((-24 - 2) - 3) = (-26 - 3) = -29.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (4 + 1 + -1 - -4) = (((4 + 1) + -1) - -4) = ((5 + -1) - -4) = (4 - -4) = 8.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 - -9 * 5 + 1) = ((-7 - (-9 * 5)) + 1) = ((-7 - -45) + 1) = (38 + 1) = 39.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) * (C * D)) = ((-18 * -29) * (8 * 39)) = (522 * (8 * 39)) = (522 * 312) = 162864.\n(Final response) So the answer is 162864.", "correct_answer": "162864", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 177, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 - 6 * -2) - (-2 + 6 + 8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-6 - 6 * -2) and B = (-2 + 6 + 8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - 6 * -2) = (-6 - (6 * -2)) = (-6 - -12) = 6.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 + 6 + 8) = ((-2 + 6) + 8) = (4 + 8) = 12.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (6 - 12) = -6.\n(Final response) So the answer is -6.", "correct_answer": "-6", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 6, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((7 - -1 * 3 * 7) + (6 + -2 - 0 - -1)) * ((-6 + 6 + 8 - 9) + (-9 * -7 - -8 - 7))) - (((-5 - 1 + -6 * 3) * (7 - -5 * 8 + 8)) * ((4 * 3 * 1 * 5) * (7 * -9 + 2 * -5)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A + B) * (C + D)) - ((E * F) * (G * H)))\", where A = (7 - -1 * 3 * 7), B = (6 + -2 - 0 - -1), C = (-6 + 6 + 8 - 9), D = (-9 * -7 - -8 - 7), E = (-5 - 1 + -6 * 3), F = (7 - -5 * 8 + 8), G = (4 * 3 * 1 * 5) and H = (7 * -9 + 2 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - -1 * 3 * 7) = (7 - ((-1 * 3) * 7)) = (7 - (-3 * 7)) = (7 - -21) = 28.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (6 + -2 - 0 - -1) = (((6 + -2) - 0) - -1) = ((4 - 0) - -1) = (4 - -1) = 5.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 + 6 + 8 - 9) = (((-6 + 6) + 8) - 9) = ((0 + 8) - 9) = (8 - 9) = -1.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 * -7 - -8 - 7) = (((-9 * -7) - -8) - 7) = ((63 - -8) - 7) = (71 - 7) = 64.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-5 - 1 + -6 * 3) = ((-5 - 1) + (-6 * 3)) = (-6 + (-6 * 3)) = (-6 + -18) = -24.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (7 - -5 * 8 + 8) = ((7 - (-5 * 8)) + 8) = ((7 - -40) + 8) = (47 + 8) = 55.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (4 * 3 * 1 * 5) = (((4 * 3) * 1) * 5) = ((12 * 1) * 5) = (12 * 5) = 60.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (7 * -9 + 2 * -5) = ((7 * -9) + (2 * -5)) = (-63 + (2 * -5)) = (-63 + -10) = -73.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A + B) * (C + D)) - ((E * F) * (G * H))) = (((28 + 5) * (-1 + 64)) - ((-24 * 55) * (60 * -73))) = ((33 * (-1 + 64)) - ((-24 * 55) * (60 * -73))) = ((33 * 63) - ((-24 * 55) * (60 * -73))) = ((33 * 63) - (-1320 * (60 * -73))) = ((33 * 63) - (-1320 * -4380)) = (2079 - (-1320 * -4380)) = (2079 - 5781600) = -5779521.\n(Final response) So the answer is -5779521.", "correct_answer": "-5779521", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 290, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 - 7 * -5 * -4 + 6 * 6) + (-4 + -6 - -4 - 4 * 7 * -2)) + ((-6 * 6 - 1 * 8 - -6 + -7) - (4 + 4 - -7 + 4 * -3 * -3))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) + (C - D))\", where A = (8 - 7 * -5 * -4 + 6 * 6), B = (-4 + -6 - -4 - 4 * 7 * -2), C = (-6 * 6 - 1 * 8 - -6 + -7) and D = (4 + 4 - -7 + 4 * -3 * -3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 - 7 * -5 * -4 + 6 * 6) = ((8 - ((7 * -5) * -4)) + (6 * 6)) = ((8 - (-35 * -4)) + (6 * 6)) = ((8 - (-35 * -4)) + 36) = ((8 - 140) + 36) = (-132 + 36) = -96.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 + -6 - -4 - 4 * 7 * -2) = (((-4 + -6) - -4) - ((4 * 7) * -2)) = ((-10 - -4) - ((4 * 7) * -2)) = ((-10 - -4) - (28 * -2)) = (-6 - (28 * -2)) = (-6 - -56) = 50.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 * 6 - 1 * 8 - -6 + -7) = ((((-6 * 6) - (1 * 8)) - -6) + -7) = (((-36 - (1 * 8)) - -6) + -7) = (((-36 - 8) - -6) + -7) = ((-44 - -6) + -7) = (-38 + -7) = -45.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (4 + 4 - -7 + 4 * -3 * -3) = (((4 + 4) - -7) + ((4 * -3) * -3)) = ((8 - -7) + ((4 * -3) * -3)) = ((8 - -7) + (-12 * -3)) = (15 + (-12 * -3)) = (15 + 36) = 51.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) + (C - D)) = ((-96 + 50) + (-45 - 51)) = (-46 + (-45 - 51)) = (-46 + -96) = -142.\n(Final response) So the answer is -142.", "correct_answer": "-142", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 228, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 * 3 * 6 * -5) + (-2 * 4 * 4 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-7 * 3 * 6 * -5) and B = (-2 * 4 * 4 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * 3 * 6 * -5) = (((-7 * 3) * 6) * -5) = ((-21 * 6) * -5) = (-126 * -5) = 630.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-2 * 4 * 4 - 2) = (((-2 * 4) * 4) - 2) = ((-8 * 4) - 2) = (-32 - 2) = -34.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (630 + -34) = 596.\n(Final response) So the answer is 596.", "correct_answer": "596", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 284, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 - -7 * -1) - (4 * 8 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-6 - -7 * -1) and B = (4 * 8 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - -7 * -1) = (-6 - (-7 * -1)) = (-6 - 7) = -13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 * 8 - 2) = ((4 * 8) - 2) = (32 - 2) = 30.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-13 - 30) = -43.\n(Final response) So the answer is -43.", "correct_answer": "-43", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 3, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 - 2 + -6 * 1) - (-6 * -9 * -2 + -5)) - ((8 * -8 + 6 - 6) * (7 * -5 * 5 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-4 - 2 + -6 * 1), B = (-6 * -9 * -2 + -5), C = (8 * -8 + 6 - 6) and D = (7 * -5 * 5 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 2 + -6 * 1) = ((-4 - 2) + (-6 * 1)) = (-6 + (-6 * 1)) = (-6 + -6) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-6 * -9 * -2 + -5) = (((-6 * -9) * -2) + -5) = ((54 * -2) + -5) = (-108 + -5) = -113.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (8 * -8 + 6 - 6) = (((8 * -8) + 6) - 6) = ((-64 + 6) - 6) = (-58 - 6) = -64.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 * -5 * 5 * -5) = (((7 * -5) * 5) * -5) = ((-35 * 5) * -5) = (-175 * -5) = 875.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C * D)) = ((-12 - -113) - (-64 * 875)) = (101 - (-64 * 875)) = (101 - -56000) = 56101.\n(Final response) So the answer is 56101.", "correct_answer": "56101", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 459, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * -8 - 1 + 6) * (1 - -8 * -5 * -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 * -8 - 1 + 6) and B = (1 - -8 * -5 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * -8 - 1 + 6) = (((9 * -8) - 1) + 6) = ((-72 - 1) + 6) = (-73 + 6) = -67.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 - -8 * -5 * -5) = (1 - ((-8 * -5) * -5)) = (1 - (40 * -5)) = (1 - -200) = 201.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-67 * 201) = -13467.\n(Final response) So the answer is -13467.", "correct_answer": "-13467", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 225, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((-2 - -6 - -9) - (-4 - 4 * 7)) + ((-3 - 7 + -5) - (-4 * 7 * -1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) + (C - D))\", where A = (-2 - -6 - -9), B = (-4 - 4 * 7), C = (-3 - 7 + -5) and D = (-4 * 7 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -6 - -9) = ((-2 - -6) - -9) = (4 - -9) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - 4 * 7) = (-4 - (4 * 7)) = (-4 - 28) = -32.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-3 - 7 + -5) = ((-3 - 7) + -5) = (-10 + -5) = -15.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * 7 * -1) = ((-4 * 7) * -1) = (-28 * -1) = 28.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) + (C - D)) = ((13 - -32) + (-15 - 28)) = (45 + (-15 - 28)) = (45 + -43) = 2.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2.", "correct_answer": "2", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 429, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((((-4 - 9 - -5 + -6 - 4 - 9) - (8 - -4 - -9 - -5 - 1 + 6)) * ((2 + -5 * -9 * 1 * -4 - 8) * (-9 - -7 - 1 + 8 + -3 * 7))) * (((6 * -7 - -9 * -5 * -9 + 2) + (5 - 6 * 7 + 9 + 3 - -9)) - ((1 - 2 - -5 + -1 * 6 * 2) * (-8 - 0 + -8 - 7 - 5 - -7)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) - (G * H)))\", where A = (-4 - 9 - -5 + -6 - 4 - 9), B = (8 - -4 - -9 - -5 - 1 + 6), C = (2 + -5 * -9 * 1 * -4 - 8), D = (-9 - -7 - 1 + 8 + -3 * 7), E = (6 * -7 - -9 * -5 * -9 + 2), F = (5 - 6 * 7 + 9 + 3 - -9), G = (1 - 2 - -5 + -1 * 6 * 2) and H = (-8 - 0 + -8 - 7 - 5 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 - 9 - -5 + -6 - 4 - 9) = (((((-4 - 9) - -5) + -6) - 4) - 9) = ((((-13 - -5) + -6) - 4) - 9) = (((-8 + -6) - 4) - 9) = ((-14 - 4) - 9) = (-18 - 9) = -27.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - -4 - -9 - -5 - 1 + 6) = (((((8 - -4) - -9) - -5) - 1) + 6) = ((((12 - -9) - -5) - 1) + 6) = (((21 - -5) - 1) + 6) = ((26 - 1) + 6) = (25 + 6) = 31.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + -5 * -9 * 1 * -4 - 8) = ((2 + (((-5 * -9) * 1) * -4)) - 8) = ((2 + ((45 * 1) * -4)) - 8) = ((2 + (45 * -4)) - 8) = ((2 + -180) - 8) = (-178 - 8) = -186.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-9 - -7 - 1 + 8 + -3 * 7) = ((((-9 - -7) - 1) + 8) + (-3 * 7)) = (((-2 - 1) + 8) + (-3 * 7)) = (((-2 - 1) + 8) + -21) = ((-3 + 8) + -21) = (5 + -21) = -16.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (6 * -7 - -9 * -5 * -9 + 2) = (((6 * -7) - ((-9 * -5) * -9)) + 2) = ((-42 - ((-9 * -5) * -9)) + 2) = ((-42 - (45 * -9)) + 2) = ((-42 - -405) + 2) = (363 + 2) = 365.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (5 - 6 * 7 + 9 + 3 - -9) = ((((5 - (6 * 7)) + 9) + 3) - -9) = ((((5 - 42) + 9) + 3) - -9) = (((-37 + 9) + 3) - -9) = ((-28 + 3) - -9) = (-25 - -9) = -16.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (1 - 2 - -5 + -1 * 6 * 2) = (((1 - 2) - -5) + ((-1 * 6) * 2)) = ((-1 - -5) + ((-1 * 6) * 2)) = ((-1 - -5) + (-6 * 2)) = (4 + (-6 * 2)) = (4 + -12) = -8.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-8 - 0 + -8 - 7 - 5 - -7) = (((((-8 - 0) + -8) - 7) - 5) - -7) = ((((-8 + -8) - 7) - 5) - -7) = (((-16 - 7) - 5) - -7) = ((-23 - 5) - -7) = (-28 - -7) = -21.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) * (C * D)) * ((E + F) - (G * H))) = (((-27 - 31) * (-186 * -16)) * ((365 + -16) - (-8 * -21))) = ((-58 * (-186 * -16)) * ((365 + -16) - (-8 * -21))) = ((-58 * 2976) * ((365 + -16) - (-8 * -21))) = ((-58 * 2976) * (349 - (-8 * -21))) = ((-58 * 2976) * (349 - 168)) = (-172608 * (349 - 168)) = (-172608 * 181) = -31242048.\n(Final response) So the answer is -31242048.", "correct_answer": "-31242048", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 346, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((4 - -1 * -3 - -4 + 5 - -2) + (7 * -5 - 6 * -3 - 8 - 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (4 - -1 * -3 - -4 + 5 - -2) and B = (7 * -5 - 6 * -3 - 8 - 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (4 - -1 * -3 - -4 + 5 - -2) = ((((4 - (-1 * -3)) - -4) + 5) - -2) = ((((4 - 3) - -4) + 5) - -2) = (((1 - -4) + 5) - -2) = ((5 + 5) - -2) = (10 - -2) = 12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (7 * -5 - 6 * -3 - 8 - 5) = ((((7 * -5) - (6 * -3)) - 8) - 5) = (((-35 - (6 * -3)) - 8) - 5) = (((-35 - -18) - 8) - 5) = ((-17 - 8) - 5) = (-25 - 5) = -30.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (12 + -30) = -18.\n(Final response) So the answer is -18.", "correct_answer": "-18", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 118, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 - -3 + -9 + -4 + -8) * (5 + 4 - -3 - 0 + 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 - -3 + -9 + -4 + -8) and B = (5 + 4 - -3 - 0 + 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - -3 + -9 + -4 + -8) = ((((-7 - -3) + -9) + -4) + -8) = (((-4 + -9) + -4) + -8) = ((-13 + -4) + -8) = (-17 + -8) = -25.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + 4 - -3 - 0 + 4) = ((((5 + 4) - -3) - 0) + 4) = (((9 - -3) - 0) + 4) = ((12 - 0) + 4) = (12 + 4) = 16.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-25 * 16) = -400.\n(Final response) So the answer is -400.", "correct_answer": "-400", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 65, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((1 * -3 - 9) - (3 * 7 * -1)) * ((-1 + 4 + 1) - (-7 + -2 - 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (1 * -3 - 9), B = (3 * 7 * -1), C = (-1 + 4 + 1) and D = (-7 + -2 - 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 * -3 - 9) = ((1 * -3) - 9) = (-3 - 9) = -12.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 * 7 * -1) = ((3 * 7) * -1) = (21 * -1) = -21.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 + 4 + 1) = ((-1 + 4) + 1) = (3 + 1) = 4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-7 + -2 - 9) = ((-7 + -2) - 9) = (-9 - 9) = -18.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((-12 - -21) * (4 - -18)) = (9 * (4 - -18)) = (9 * 22) = 198.\n(Final response) So the answer is 198.", "correct_answer": "198", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 133, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 + -9 - -4 + 6) + (-5 + 0 + 8 * -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (8 + -9 - -4 + 6) and B = (-5 + 0 + 8 * -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + -9 - -4 + 6) = (((8 + -9) - -4) + 6) = ((-1 - -4) + 6) = (3 + 6) = 9.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + 0 + 8 * -7) = ((-5 + 0) + (8 * -7)) = (-5 + (8 * -7)) = (-5 + -56) = -61.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (9 + -61) = -52.\n(Final response) So the answer is -52.", "correct_answer": "-52", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 203, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((2 + -8 - -5 * 2) + (-3 + -7 * 3 - 0)) * ((-6 - -5 * -1 + 7) * (3 + 1 + -2 * -5))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A + B) * (C * D))\", where A = (2 + -8 - -5 * 2), B = (-3 + -7 * 3 - 0), C = (-6 - -5 * -1 + 7) and D = (3 + 1 + -2 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + -8 - -5 * 2) = ((2 + -8) - (-5 * 2)) = (-6 - (-5 * 2)) = (-6 - -10) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-3 + -7 * 3 - 0) = ((-3 + (-7 * 3)) - 0) = ((-3 + -21) - 0) = (-24 - 0) = -24.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-6 - -5 * -1 + 7) = ((-6 - (-5 * -1)) + 7) = ((-6 - 5) + 7) = (-11 + 7) = -4.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (3 + 1 + -2 * -5) = ((3 + 1) + (-2 * -5)) = (4 + (-2 * -5)) = (4 + 10) = 14.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A + B) * (C * D)) = ((4 + -24) * (-4 * 14)) = (-20 * (-4 * 14)) = (-20 * -56) = 1120.\n(Final response) So the answer is 1120.", "correct_answer": "1120", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 574, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((7 - 4 + -4) * (-1 + 7 - -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (7 - 4 + -4) and B = (-1 + 7 - -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 - 4 + -4) = ((7 - 4) + -4) = (3 + -4) = -1.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 + 7 - -7) = ((-1 + 7) - -7) = (6 - -7) = 13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-1 * 13) = -13.\n(Final response) So the answer is -13.", "correct_answer": "-13", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 27, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((8 + -3 * 5) * (8 * 2 - 3)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (8 + -3 * 5) and B = (8 * 2 - 3).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 + -3 * 5) = (8 + (-3 * 5)) = (8 + -15) = -7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 * 2 - 3) = ((8 * 2) - 3) = (16 - 3) = 13.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-7 * 13) = -91.\n(Final response) So the answer is -91.", "correct_answer": "-91", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 16, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((7 + 6 - 9 - -7) * (-4 - 1 * -3 * -9)) + ((5 + -1 + -2 + -9) * (1 * 3 - 3 * 1))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (7 + 6 - 9 - -7), B = (-4 - 1 * -3 * -9), C = (5 + -1 + -2 + -9) and D = (1 * 3 - 3 * 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (7 + 6 - 9 - -7) = (((7 + 6) - 9) - -7) = ((13 - 9) - -7) = (4 - -7) = 11.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - 1 * -3 * -9) = (-4 - ((1 * -3) * -9)) = (-4 - (-3 * -9)) = (-4 - 27) = -31.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (5 + -1 + -2 + -9) = (((5 + -1) + -2) + -9) = ((4 + -2) + -9) = (2 + -9) = -7.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (1 * 3 - 3 * 1) = ((1 * 3) - (3 * 1)) = (3 - (3 * 1)) = (3 - 3) = 0.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((11 * -31) + (-7 * 0)) = (-341 + (-7 * 0)) = (-341 + 0) = -341.\n(Final response) So the answer is -341.", "correct_answer": "-341", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 517, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 + 3 * -4 * -4) + (-7 * 3 - -8 - -4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-3 + 3 * -4 * -4) and B = (-7 * 3 - -8 - -4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 3 * -4 * -4) = (-3 + ((3 * -4) * -4)) = (-3 + (-12 * -4)) = (-3 + 48) = 45.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 * 3 - -8 - -4) = (((-7 * 3) - -8) - -4) = ((-21 - -8) - -4) = (-13 - -4) = -9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (45 + -9) = 36.\n(Final response) So the answer is 36.", "correct_answer": "36", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 238, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 * 5 + 3 + -7) * (9 - 1 - 6 + -7)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 * 5 + 3 + -7) and B = (9 - 1 - 6 + -7).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 * 5 + 3 + -7) = (((-7 * 5) + 3) + -7) = ((-35 + 3) + -7) = (-32 + -7) = -39.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 - 1 - 6 + -7) = (((9 - 1) - 6) + -7) = ((8 - 6) + -7) = (2 + -7) = -5.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-39 * -5) = 195.\n(Final response) So the answer is 195.", "correct_answer": "195", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 223, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 * 5 + -1) - (-1 * 1 - -8)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (9 * 5 + -1) and B = (-1 * 1 - -8).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 * 5 + -1) = ((9 * 5) + -1) = (45 + -1) = 44.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-1 * 1 - -8) = ((-1 * 1) - -8) = (-1 - -8) = 7.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (44 - 7) = 37.\n(Final response) So the answer is 37.", "correct_answer": "37", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 95, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 + 0 * -7) - (3 - -3 + -6)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-3 + 0 * -7) and B = (3 - -3 + -6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 + 0 * -7) = (-3 + (0 * -7)) = (-3 + 0) = -3.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (3 - -3 + -6) = ((3 - -3) + -6) = (6 + -6) = 0.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-3 - 0) = -3.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3.", "correct_answer": "-3", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 30, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((9 + 7 - -4) * (1 + -9 + 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (9 + 7 - -4) and B = (1 + -9 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 + 7 - -4) = ((9 + 7) - -4) = (16 - -4) = 20.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 + -9 + 2) = ((1 + -9) + 2) = (-8 + 2) = -6.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (20 * -6) = -120.\n(Final response) So the answer is -120.", "correct_answer": "-120", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 32, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((-3 - -6 - -2) - (9 + -7 + -8)) * ((6 - 5 * 0) - (-4 * 4 - 0))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) * (C - D))\", where A = (-3 - -6 - -2), B = (9 + -7 + -8), C = (6 - 5 * 0) and D = (-4 * 4 - 0).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 - -6 - -2) = ((-3 - -6) - -2) = (3 - -2) = 5.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 + -7 + -8) = ((9 + -7) + -8) = (2 + -8) = -6.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (6 - 5 * 0) = (6 - (5 * 0)) = (6 - 0) = 6.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-4 * 4 - 0) = ((-4 * 4) - 0) = (-16 - 0) = -16.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) * (C - D)) = ((5 - -6) * (6 - -16)) = (11 * (6 - -16)) = (11 * 22) = 242.\n(Final response) So the answer is 242.", "correct_answer": "242", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 432, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 + 3 * 9) * (4 + -2 + 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (2 + 3 * 9) and B = (4 + -2 + 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + 3 * 9) = (2 + (3 * 9)) = (2 + 27) = 29.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 + -2 + 9) = ((4 + -2) + 9) = (2 + 9) = 11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (29 * 11) = 319.\n(Final response) So the answer is 319.", "correct_answer": "319", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 4, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 - -8 - -5) * (0 + -4 + 5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-6 - -8 - -5) and B = (0 + -4 + 5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 - -8 - -5) = ((-6 - -8) - -5) = (2 - -5) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (0 + -4 + 5) = ((0 + -4) + 5) = (-4 + 5) = 1.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (7 * 1) = 7.\n(Final response) So the answer is 7.", "correct_answer": "7", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 89, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((3 - 6 - 0 + 7) * (5 + -3 + 0 * -9)) + ((2 + 5 * 4 * 9) * (8 - 4 * -1 * 2))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C * D))\", where A = (3 - 6 - 0 + 7), B = (5 + -3 + 0 * -9), C = (2 + 5 * 4 * 9) and D = (8 - 4 * -1 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - 6 - 0 + 7) = (((3 - 6) - 0) + 7) = ((-3 - 0) + 7) = (-3 + 7) = 4.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (5 + -3 + 0 * -9) = ((5 + -3) + (0 * -9)) = (2 + (0 * -9)) = (2 + 0) = 2.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (2 + 5 * 4 * 9) = (2 + ((5 * 4) * 9)) = (2 + (20 * 9)) = (2 + 180) = 182.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (8 - 4 * -1 * 2) = (8 - ((4 * -1) * 2)) = (8 - (-4 * 2)) = (8 - -8) = 16.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C * D)) = ((4 * 2) + (182 * 16)) = (8 + (182 * 16)) = (8 + 2912) = 2920.\n(Final response) So the answer is 2920.", "correct_answer": "2920", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 558, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((((1 - 3 - -4 * -6 * 7) - (-5 + 0 - -5 + -8 * -7)) - ((9 + -6 + -7 - -9 * -2) * (2 * -6 + -9 - -7 * -4))) * (((-5 - 1 * -4 + 9 - 0) - (6 + -6 - -5 - 4 + 8)) + ((7 * 3 + 6 * 6 - 6) - (-3 + -8 - 6 + 3 * 4)))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(((A - B) - (C * D)) * ((E - F) + (G - H)))\", where A = (1 - 3 - -4 * -6 * 7), B = (-5 + 0 - -5 + -8 * -7), C = (9 + -6 + -7 - -9 * -2), D = (2 * -6 + -9 - -7 * -4), E = (-5 - 1 * -4 + 9 - 0), F = (6 + -6 - -5 - 4 + 8), G = (7 * 3 + 6 * 6 - 6) and H = (-3 + -8 - 6 + 3 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (1 - 3 - -4 * -6 * 7) = ((1 - 3) - ((-4 * -6) * 7)) = (-2 - ((-4 * -6) * 7)) = (-2 - (24 * 7)) = (-2 - 168) = -170.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 + 0 - -5 + -8 * -7) = (((-5 + 0) - -5) + (-8 * -7)) = ((-5 - -5) + (-8 * -7)) = ((-5 - -5) + 56) = (0 + 56) = 56.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (9 + -6 + -7 - -9 * -2) = (((9 + -6) + -7) - (-9 * -2)) = ((3 + -7) - (-9 * -2)) = ((3 + -7) - 18) = (-4 - 18) = -22.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (2 * -6 + -9 - -7 * -4) = (((2 * -6) + -9) - (-7 * -4)) = ((-12 + -9) - (-7 * -4)) = ((-12 + -9) - 28) = (-21 - 28) = -49.\n(6) Let's calculate E = (-5 - 1 * -4 + 9 - 0) = (((-5 - (1 * -4)) + 9) - 0) = (((-5 - -4) + 9) - 0) = ((-1 + 9) - 0) = (8 - 0) = 8.\n(7) Let's calculate F = (6 + -6 - -5 - 4 + 8) = ((((6 + -6) - -5) - 4) + 8) = (((0 - -5) - 4) + 8) = ((5 - 4) + 8) = (1 + 8) = 9.\n(8) Let's calculate G = (7 * 3 + 6 * 6 - 6) = (((7 * 3) + (6 * 6)) - 6) = ((21 + (6 * 6)) - 6) = ((21 + 36) - 6) = (57 - 6) = 51.\n(9) Let's calculate H = (-3 + -8 - 6 + 3 * 4) = (((-3 + -8) - 6) + (3 * 4)) = ((-11 - 6) + (3 * 4)) = ((-11 - 6) + 12) = (-17 + 12) = -5.\n(10) Then, the final equation is (((A - B) - (C * D)) * ((E - F) + (G - H))) = (((-170 - 56) - (-22 * -49)) * ((8 - 9) + (51 - -5))) = ((-226 - (-22 * -49)) * ((8 - 9) + (51 - -5))) = ((-226 - 1078) * ((8 - 9) + (51 - -5))) = ((-226 - 1078) * (-1 + (51 - -5))) = ((-226 - 1078) * (-1 + 56)) = (-1304 * (-1 + 56)) = (-1304 * 55) = -71720.\n(Final response) So the answer is -71720.", "correct_answer": "-71720", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 313, "depth_levels": [2, 2, 2], "length": 5}}
{"question": "Q: (((-4 * 6 * 8 + 7) * (9 * 5 - -2 + -6)) - ((-8 * -2 - -3 + 8) * (7 + 2 + -3 * -9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) - (C * D))\", where A = (-4 * 6 * 8 + 7), B = (9 * 5 - -2 + -6), C = (-8 * -2 - -3 + 8) and D = (7 + 2 + -3 * -9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-4 * 6 * 8 + 7) = (((-4 * 6) * 8) + 7) = ((-24 * 8) + 7) = (-192 + 7) = -185.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (9 * 5 - -2 + -6) = (((9 * 5) - -2) + -6) = ((45 - -2) + -6) = (47 + -6) = 41.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-8 * -2 - -3 + 8) = (((-8 * -2) - -3) + 8) = ((16 - -3) + 8) = (19 + 8) = 27.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (7 + 2 + -3 * -9) = ((7 + 2) + (-3 * -9)) = (9 + (-3 * -9)) = (9 + 27) = 36.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) - (C * D)) = ((-185 * 41) - (27 * 36)) = (-7585 - (27 * 36)) = (-7585 - 972) = -8557.\n(Final response) So the answer is -8557.", "correct_answer": "-8557", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 158, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 - 6 - -1 * 5 * 6 - 2) * (-5 * -1 + 8 + -2 - 0 * -1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 - 6 - -1 * 5 * 6 - 2) and B = (-5 * -1 + 8 + -2 - 0 * -1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - 6 - -1 * 5 * 6 - 2) = (((-7 - 6) - ((-1 * 5) * 6)) - 2) = ((-13 - ((-1 * 5) * 6)) - 2) = ((-13 - (-5 * 6)) - 2) = ((-13 - -30) - 2) = (17 - 2) = 15.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -1 + 8 + -2 - 0 * -1) = ((((-5 * -1) + 8) + -2) - (0 * -1)) = (((5 + 8) + -2) - (0 * -1)) = (((5 + 8) + -2) - 0) = ((13 + -2) - 0) = (11 - 0) = 11.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (15 * 11) = 165.\n(Final response) So the answer is 165.", "correct_answer": "165", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 92, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 6}}
{"question": "Q: ((-9 * 9 + 9) + (8 - -9 * -5)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-9 * 9 + 9) and B = (8 - -9 * -5).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-9 * 9 + 9) = ((-9 * 9) + 9) = (-81 + 9) = -72.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (8 - -9 * -5) = (8 - (-9 * -5)) = (8 - 45) = -37.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-72 + -37) = -109.\n(Final response) So the answer is -109.", "correct_answer": "-109", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 104, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: (((8 * 4 - -8 + -6) * (-7 - 7 + -2 - -5)) + ((-4 + -2 - 8 + 5) - (6 - 4 * -6 * 9))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A * B) + (C - D))\", where A = (8 * 4 - -8 + -6), B = (-7 - 7 + -2 - -5), C = (-4 + -2 - 8 + 5) and D = (6 - 4 * -6 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (8 * 4 - -8 + -6) = (((8 * 4) - -8) + -6) = ((32 - -8) + -6) = (40 + -6) = 34.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - 7 + -2 - -5) = (((-7 - 7) + -2) - -5) = ((-14 + -2) - -5) = (-16 - -5) = -11.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-4 + -2 - 8 + 5) = (((-4 + -2) - 8) + 5) = ((-6 - 8) + 5) = (-14 + 5) = -9.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (6 - 4 * -6 * 9) = (6 - ((4 * -6) * 9)) = (6 - (-24 * 9)) = (6 - -216) = 222.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A * B) + (C - D)) = ((34 * -11) + (-9 - 222)) = (-374 + (-9 - 222)) = (-374 + -231) = -605.\n(Final response) So the answer is -605.", "correct_answer": "-605", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 154, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-3 * 1 - 5) - (1 * -7 + 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-3 * 1 - 5) and B = (1 * -7 + 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-3 * 1 - 5) = ((-3 * 1) - 5) = (-3 - 5) = -8.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (1 * -7 + 2) = ((1 * -7) + 2) = (-7 + 2) = -5.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-8 - -5) = -3.\n(Final response) So the answer is -3.", "correct_answer": "-3", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 142, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-6 + 5 - 8 * 7) + (4 - 8 - 6 + 1)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A + B)\", where A = (-6 + 5 - 8 * 7) and B = (4 - 8 - 6 + 1).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-6 + 5 - 8 * 7) = ((-6 + 5) - (8 * 7)) = (-1 - (8 * 7)) = (-1 - 56) = -57.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (4 - 8 - 6 + 1) = (((4 - 8) - 6) + 1) = ((-4 - 6) + 1) = (-10 + 1) = -9.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A + B) = (-57 + -9) = -66.\n(Final response) So the answer is -66.", "correct_answer": "-66", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 228, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((-7 - 0 + -2 - 9) * (-5 * 6 + 5 * 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (-7 - 0 + -2 - 9) and B = (-5 * 6 + 5 * 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-7 - 0 + -2 - 9) = (((-7 - 0) + -2) - 9) = ((-7 + -2) - 9) = (-9 - 9) = -18.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * 6 + 5 * 2) = ((-5 * 6) + (5 * 2)) = (-30 + (5 * 2)) = (-30 + 10) = -20.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (-18 * -20) = 360.\n(Final response) So the answer is 360.", "correct_answer": "360", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 250, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((2 + 2 - -1 - -8) * (-8 + 9 - -8 * 4)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (2 + 2 - -1 - -8) and B = (-8 + 9 - -8 * 4).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (2 + 2 - -1 - -8) = (((2 + 2) - -1) - -8) = ((4 - -1) - -8) = (5 - -8) = 13.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-8 + 9 - -8 * 4) = ((-8 + 9) - (-8 * 4)) = (1 - (-8 * 4)) = (1 - -32) = 33.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (13 * 33) = 429.\n(Final response) So the answer is 429.", "correct_answer": "429", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 281, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: (((9 - -4 * -6 + 1) - (-4 * -2 + 4 - -8)) - ((-1 - -2 - -7 - 8) + (-1 * 3 + 7 * 6))) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"((A - B) - (C + D))\", where A = (9 - -4 * -6 + 1), B = (-4 * -2 + 4 - -8), C = (-1 - -2 - -7 - 8) and D = (-1 * 3 + 7 * 6).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (9 - -4 * -6 + 1) = ((9 - (-4 * -6)) + 1) = ((9 - 24) + 1) = (-15 + 1) = -14.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 * -2 + 4 - -8) = (((-4 * -2) + 4) - -8) = ((8 + 4) - -8) = (12 - -8) = 20.\n(4) Let's calculate C = (-1 - -2 - -7 - 8) = (((-1 - -2) - -7) - 8) = ((1 - -7) - 8) = (8 - 8) = 0.\n(5) Let's calculate D = (-1 * 3 + 7 * 6) = ((-1 * 3) + (7 * 6)) = (-3 + (7 * 6)) = (-3 + 42) = 39.\n(6) Then, the final equation is ((A - B) - (C + D)) = ((-14 - 20) - (0 + 39)) = (-34 - (0 + 39)) = (-34 - 39) = -73.\n(Final response) So the answer is -73.", "correct_answer": "-73", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 159, "depth_levels": [2, 2], "length": 4}}
{"question": "Q: ((6 * 9 - 4) - (-4 - 3 * -2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (6 * 9 - 4) and B = (-4 - 3 * -2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (6 * 9 - 4) = ((6 * 9) - 4) = (54 - 4) = 50.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-4 - 3 * -2) = (-4 - (3 * -2)) = (-4 - -6) = 2.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (50 - 2) = 48.\n(Final response) So the answer is 48.", "correct_answer": "48", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 25, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((-2 - -3 * -7) - (-5 * -4 - 2)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A - B)\", where A = (-2 - -3 * -7) and B = (-5 * -4 - 2).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (-2 - -3 * -7) = (-2 - (-3 * -7)) = (-2 - 21) = -23.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-5 * -4 - 2) = ((-5 * -4) - 2) = (20 - 2) = 18.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A - B) = (-23 - 18) = -41.\n(Final response) So the answer is -41.", "correct_answer": "-41", "meta_data": {"split": "train", "new_split": "train", "idx": 114, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 3}}
{"question": "Q: ((3 - 3 - -3 - -4) * (-7 - 1 - -5 * 9)) = ", "rationale": "(1) This equation can be written as \"(A * B)\", where A = (3 - 3 - -3 - -4) and B = (-7 - 1 - -5 * 9).\n(2) Let's calculate A = (3 - 3 - -3 - -4) = (((3 - 3) - -3) - -4) = ((0 - -3) - -4) = (3 - -4) = 7.\n(3) Let's calculate B = (-7 - 1 - -5 * 9) = ((-7 - 1) - (-5 * 9)) = (-8 - (-5 * 9)) = (-8 - -45) = 37.\n(4) Then, the final equation is (A * B) = (7 * 37) = 259.\n(Final response) So the answer is 259.", "correct_answer": "259", "meta_data": {"split": "validation", "new_split": "validation", "idx": 54, "depth_levels": [2], "length": 4}}
